<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CrossFit on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/crossfit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CrossFit on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/crossfit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Judge the Newbs</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dont-judge-the-newbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dont-judge-the-newbs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/5770042200_bc1b1f00c3.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3160&#34; alt=&#34;5770042200_bc1b1f00c3&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5770042200_bc1b1f00c3-300x160.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;It saddens me when I see people who have accomplished something judging others who are trying to do the same thing. I see this a lot among trainers, particularly those in unorthodox fitness methods like CrossFit and MovNat. We like to remind other people what they are doing wrong, how they are ignorant, unskilled, or lazy, too focused on strength/flexibility/skill and neglecting our pet trait, how they are clearly too wimpy to do &#39;real&#39; exercise, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is only natural. We&#39;ve put a lot of effort into unlocking the secretes of superpowers, so we want to enjoy the status that gives us. I did it all the time, until I remembered how incompetent I was when I started. &lt;/strong&gt;But it doesn&#39;t actually help anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;For example, I was working out with some friends the other day while another gym-goer was loudly, clumsily, doing his own workout. My buddies noticed and snickered, whispering among themselves how what he was doing was both dangerous and inappropriate for his apparent level of fitness.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wasn&#39;t the first time this particular group of friends had indulged in this kind of behavior, so I spoke up. &lt;strong&gt;First, I reminded them that the fact that he was out there at all, clearly pushing his limits and trying something new and challenging, was a good thing. Second, every single one of us in that group had gone through a similar phase when we did things that we realized were stupid in retrospect&lt;/strong&gt;. I tried a lot of weird things, some stupid and some legitimate but misplaced in my training:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitness is Not Health</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/fitness-is-not-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/fitness-is-not-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2008&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/tomsaint/3752937440/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-2008 &#34; title=&#34;Tired Runners&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3752937440_4641fa806d.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Rennett Stowe on Flickr[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In writing my fitness book and thinking about how I want to explain my views to others, I&#39;ve realized that I was never really comfortable with fitness as we normally conceive it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitness is a confusing term these days. It has become so confusing, in fact, that you can have Fitness without Health. You can be very good at the Fitness thing, exercising religiously, following the right diet, wearing the right $70 Yoga pants, and be completely miserable. Originally meant to be a means to promote our holistic health, Fitness has taken on a life of its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To define Fitness, I want put aside dictionary definitions and focus on what most people mean when they talk about Fitness. I&#39;m concerned with ideas and conceptions, not academic or scientific definitions that have little to do with how people interact with the term in their real lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most, fitness is synonymous with athletic performance: the better your fitness, the better athlete you are. It is also synonymous with health: the better your fitness, the healthier you are. So, the assumption is that athletes are healthy, meaning their bodies express the full range of human function, painlessly, and for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Unhealthy Athlete&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we know that not all great athletes are healthy. The standards of a sport do not always require holistic human health to perform well (think golf), and sometimes the requirements of excellence in a sport actually favor adaptations that cause health problems. When an elite runner dies of heart failure, what do we make of it? How do we reconcile the awe-inspiring performance of gymnasts with the spine and shoulder problems that come with the intensive practice?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Understanding of Fitness and the Human Body</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-new-understanding-of-fitness-and-the-human-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-new-understanding-of-fitness-and-the-human-body/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/245952551_797503484e.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright  wp-image-1995&#34; title=&#34;Bodies in Motion&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/245952551_797503484e.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;360&#34; height=&#34;270&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Many people treat their bodies as if they were rented from Hertz--something they are using to get around in but nothing they genuinely care about understanding. - Chungliang Al Huang&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until recently, it was thought that a human being could be perfectly healthy eating only parts of food, as long as they were in sufficient quantities and ratios. The nutrient model of diet claimed that we simply needed sufficient protein, carbohydrates, and fats, plus vitamins, in order to be healthy. Foods were broken down, proteins, vitamins, and minerals extracted, removed, concentrated, and added back in sufficient quantities. We had mastered the science of nutrition and were entering a golden age of health and convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much for that...the nutrient model has been discredited lately, as it became more and more obvious that the benefits of whole foods, eaten fresh and close to the source, simply could not be copied by even the most carefully scientifically balanced meals. Sometimes this was because of the limits of our technology, but just as often, there were factors we hadn&#39;t even identified that seemed to make the difference between health-promoting and obesity-inducing food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitness and exercise is where nutrition was a few years ago. We are only now starting to pull out of the mistaken belief that movement-related health can be broken down into its constituent parts and fed in concentrations to promote certain kinds of growth. Happily, we have mostly discarded the notion that the body can respond to training muscles in isolation on weight machines. Unfortunately, we still pull movement apart into elements like strength, speed, power, agility, coordination, balance, and flexibility, just as we used to think of food only in terms of its proteins, carbohydrates, fats, vitamins, and minerals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Gentle, Be Powerful</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/be-gentle-be-powerful/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/be-gentle-be-powerful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1884&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Espara on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/esparta/2214658212/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1884&#34; title=&#34;Sleeping Tiger&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/2214658212_9d9183226f-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I have never taken any exercise except sleeping and resting.” - Mark Twain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intensity in exercise is good. Most of us aren’t getting enough of it. Instead we settle for lifting weights we can handle comfortably and running at speeds that just break a sweat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then there are those of us who do nothing but high intensity exercise. We’re CrossFitters and Traceurs, MMA fighters and sprinters. We only have one speed, and that’s insane! We are not know for our gentleness, with others or ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to be one of those. Until I got injured, which happened a lot actually. When you’re body is constantly working near its limits, there is not much time for healing or recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My most recent injury was a pulled muscle in my hip that immobilized my lower back. I couldn’t even bend over to tie my shoes. I had zero flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of options and fed up with being in pain all the time, I started practicing yoga to regain my flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started it only as a therapeutic form of exercise, but I noticed that I felt much better on days I started with some yoga than those without. Clearly yoga was addressing some aspect of my physical training I’d been neglecting with all the CrossFit and gymnastics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intense stretching didn&#39;t help at all. The painful deep tissue massage didn&#39;t help, either. But slow, comfortable, gentle yoga slowly untied my back and improved my flexibility in other areas as well. When I finally started being gentle and kind to my body, it stopped punishing me with pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Truth About My Training and Diet</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-truth-about-my-training-and-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-truth-about-my-training-and-diet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1699&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;I&amp;#39;d rather be able to do this than have a fast Fran time. Source: Raphael Goetter on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/goetter/2567497624/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1699&#34; title=&#34;ironcross&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/ironcross-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a CrossFit trainer, I sometimes feel like I&#39;m not allowed to use, much less espouse, alternative forms of physical training or diet. But since I&#39;ve been caught so many times doing very un-CrossFit-like things, and a lot of people ask me what my training program is, or what my diet is, I thought I&#39;d come clean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Warrior Spirit</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-warrior-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-warrior-spirit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Hello World&#34;]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/20110331-213409.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/20110331-213409.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20110331-213409.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d like to inject a little more of me into my posts. After all, this blog was started by me as a sort of online journal. I was reluctant to assume that all my readers found my life all that interesting, but I thought I&#39;d just write about it. I am a storyteller, after all, not just an essayist. Since the story I know best is my own, I wanted to tell that story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the way, I got swept up by all these other great blogs that also tell stories, but which also provide lots of useful information besides. Somehow, the information stuck out more than the stories, and I focused on that. As a result, I feel that Warrior Spirit has kind of drifted from being personal to trying too hard to be useful. The result I think has been less connection with my readers. The blog has grown and grown, and for that I&#39;m thankful, but I feel a little like I&#39;ve sold out (except without the monetary rewards).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&#39;m going to try to tell more of my stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Enemy of the Good</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-enemy-of-the-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-enemy-of-the-good/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;﻿&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;350&#34; caption=&#34;linh.ngân on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3515/3295481102_6b38448f44.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; &#34; title=&#34;Imperfect Flower&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3295481102_6b38448f44.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;350&#34; height=&#34;350&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my chosen fitness niche, there is a tendency to only focus on what gets results and ignore the rest. CrossFitters tend to scoff at bodybuilders and pro football players alike. The belief is that these individuals are wasting their time as far as fitness is concerned because they are too specialized and not lined up for optimal health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, strict adherents of the Paleo diet tend to dismiss those who only follow it partially. Anyone who knows anything about nutrition wouldn’t go near a loaf of bread, ever! If you do, you don’t take your health seriously. You should either change your ways or give up completely. So say the perfectly fit. Go the whole 9 yards, or not at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remember to Value Your Strengths</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/remember-to-value-your-strengths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/remember-to-value-your-strengths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1328&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;RightIndex on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/leomei/2652108834/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1328&#34; title=&#34;muscle&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/muscle-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an exercise program, CrossFit demands that its participants expose themselves to a wide variety of different challenges; you learn very quickly what you&#39;re good at and what you&#39;re not. Often, one weakness can derail an entire workout as you struggle to make up the slack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Instant Under the Bar</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/an-instant-under-the-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/an-instant-under-the-bar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1274&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Marc-Andre Casavant on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/casavant/4415188448/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1274&#34; title=&#34;olylift&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/olylift-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, over the course of something like two hours and 15-20 failed attempts, I managed to snatch 165 lbs, which is significant because that is my bodyweight (a snatch is an Olympic weightlifting movement in which you take a bar from the ground to overhead in one motion). I had set a bodyweight snatch as a goal almost a year ago, and had gotten to 160 lbs long before, but that elusive 5 lbs seemed impossible. Yesterday, I decided I would nail it, and in the end, it was mostly this determination that made the difference, rather than any actual performance improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Left My Job: To Start Again</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-i-left-my-job-to-start-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-i-left-my-job-to-start-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1177&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Stevie Rocco on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stevier/4114137266/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1177&#34; title=&#34;road&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/road-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To learn something new, take the path that you took yesterday.” - John Burroughs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was my last day at the CrossFit gym where I had worked for the past year as a coach and personal trainer. I decided several weeks ago to leave the gym and pursue other opportunities on my own, and I finally took the step of leaving. It was a difficult decision, not so much because of financial reasons, but more because I loved working with the amazing athletes and dedicated individuals who came to train with us. Nevertheless, I am excited to be moving forward with my plans, even though there is a great degree of apprehension regarding my financial security. I feel that sometimes we have to pull apart everything we&#39;ve built for ourselves to build something new, or backtrack the path we&#39;ve already been down to look for new turn-offs with a better idea of where we want to go this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Limits of My Experience</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/learning-the-limits-of-my-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/learning-the-limits-of-my-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;mceTemp&#34; style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1035&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Johan J.Ingles-Le Nobel on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jingleslenobel/4326713557/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1035&#34; title=&#34;river&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/river-300x204.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;204&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As I have said, the first thing is to be honest with yourself. You can never have an impact on society if you have not changed yourself... Great peacemakers are all people of integrity, of honesty, but humility.” -&lt;em&gt;Nelson Mandela&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went for a 5k run today, the first I&#39;ve undertaken in over a year. Despite all the intense anaerobic exercise I do at CrossFit, the fact that I can run a 5:05 mile, and my powerful legs, I found it extremely difficult. So difficult, in fact, that I walked near the end and got a time that was worse than my best high school time. My ankles are sore and I feel more beat up than usual. But really, I&#39;m not that surprised I didn&#39;t do as well as I thought I could. After all, I may be a very well-rounded athlete, but I know that distance running has become a definite area of neglect in my training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Athleticism Good for Your Health?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/is-athleticism-good-for-your-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/is-athleticism-good-for-your-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; caption=&#34;Source: RobW_ on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/48/136462415_5455bf750a.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Statue of an Athlete from the Ancient Olympic Games&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/136462415_5455bf750a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent visit to my sports doctor, brought on by yet another overuse injury, prompted me to wonder if being an athlete is actually good for one&#39;s health and fitness. After all, the only reason I was at the doctor was because I am an athlete. I had injured my shoulder on a leisurely kayak tour of a small Connecticut lake. The shoulder was prone to such a pansy injury because I regularly engage in extreme fitness, aka, CrossFit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you are probably wondering, as was I, how can an athlete with shoulders capable of doing multiple strict muscle-ups be completely incapacitated by something as tame as kayaking? I honestly don&#39;t have an answer. But the experience got me to wondering about the distinctions between fitness, health, and athleticism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Engine is Bigger than Yours: Efficiency vs. Effectiveness in CrossFit</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-engine-is-bigger-than-yours-efficiency-vs-effectiveness-in-crossfit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-engine-is-bigger-than-yours-efficiency-vs-effectiveness-in-crossfit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/060910_1718_myengineisb1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt;Generally, when presented with any given task, we seek out the most efficient way to complete that task. The less time it takes, the less effort involved, the better. Not so often do we ask ourselves whether we&#39;re doing the right task or not. Is what we are doing actually the most effective way to reach our goals, or is it just busy-work? A Honda is more efficient than a Ferrari, but a Ferrari will get your where you&#39;re going much, much faster, making it more effective if your goal is saving time in transit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ll Never Be Good Enough...Until You Are</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/youll-never-be-good-enough-until-you-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/youll-never-be-good-enough-until-you-are/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/05/barbell.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-574&#34; title=&#34;barbell&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/barbell.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;221&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an athlete, one of the most common de-motivators I deal with is the assertion, made either by myself or well-meaning friends trying to help me deal with frustration at limited progress, that professional and Olympic athletes (those I aspire to be like) are genetic abnormalities. Thus, I should not expect myself to perform at their level, and should not hold myself to similar expectations of progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, I have agreed with this statement. After all, I&#39;m just a genetically average human, right? Even with all the determination in the world (and I have plenty of that) I just don&#39;t have the right bone length, muscle fiber ratios, metabolic eccentricities, to make it to the big leagues. So I shouldn&#39;t even try, and certainly not become frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I realized I have no idea what my genetic make-up is. For all I know, I am an Olympic sprinter who just needs the right training to unleash his genetic potential. People tell me I&#39;m too tall to be a gymnast, too lanky to be a good lifter, but there have been unlikely champions in every sport imaginable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with Injury</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dealing-with-injury/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dealing-with-injury/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_557&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;It would be easier if they could put a cone on me to keep me from exercising when I&amp;#39;m injured&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/05/cat.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-557&#34; title=&#34;cat&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/cat.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;268&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have times in our lives when we find ourselves unable to do the things we love, often because we did too much of the things we love. Whether it&#39;s cutting back on delicious pies because we had too many in one sitting last winter or cutting back our training load because we hurt ourselves, we get ourselves into situations that we regret, doing something we knew we shouldn&#39;t have done at the time, but did anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the Aftermath of Wino</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/in-the-aftermath-of-wino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/in-the-aftermath-of-wino/</guid>
      <description>Five rounds for time:
 21 thrusters @ 75lb 21 double unders</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrity: There is more to Life than Winning...There&#39;s being Awesome!</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/integrity-there-is-more-to-life-than-winning-theres-being-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/integrity-there-is-more-to-life-than-winning-theres-being-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/handstand.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-493&#34; title=&#34;handstand&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/handstand.jpg?w=199&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Since the CrossFit sectionals I&#39;ve been feeling considerably less motivated about my training. You&#39;d think that making it to regionals would give me a message that I have some potential, and that I should work hard to realize it. Instead, I feel oppressed by the prospect of competing again. All my training is geared towards this one event, an event that has a very narrow definition of success (even by the standards of CrossFit), and in which I will undoubtedly be one of the smallest, puniest, guys there. Maybe I&#39;m over-dramatizing here, but I definitely feel like an underdog - I&#39;m young, relatively weak (most guys at these things can deadlift 400+ lbs, I&#39;m around 315lb on a good day), and pretty inexperienced. If it&#39;s all about who can move the most weight, I&#39;m screwed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills and Wills</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/skills-and-wills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/skills-and-wills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/job.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-487&#34; title=&#34;job&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/job.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;142&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2010/04/accepting-limits.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed:+typepad/sethsmainblog+(Seth&#39;s+Blog)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cool blog post by Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt; inspired me to think a bit about something that has been on my mind since I was a kid. In my conception of my future were two warring images of my adult self. One was an extremely independent explorer/traveler/innovator who set his own schedule, had plenty of free time, and an inexplicable, substantial source of monetary income. The other image was one of a diligent, creative and hardworking member of a larger organization with an obvious source of substantial income and less free time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossfit New England Sectionals: Play-by-Play</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/crossfit-new-england-sectionals-play-by-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/crossfit-new-england-sectionals-play-by-play/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/cfsheader.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-482&#34; title=&#34;CFSHeader&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/cfsheader.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;118&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Okay, here it is, for everyone who wonders why I haven&#39;t been able to walk for the past two weeks (for the busy, the important bits are at the end, but workouts 2 and 4 are pretty juicy):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 1:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workout 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run 800m&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 Snatches at 115 lbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run 800m</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Toughness, and the CrossFit Northeast Sectionals</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/mental-toughness-and-the-crossfit-northeast-sectionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/mental-toughness-and-the-crossfit-northeast-sectionals/</guid>
      <description>I just got back from two days of the most intense physical and mental challenges of my life, the CrossFit Northeast Sectionals, the first step on the road to the 2010 CrossFit games, the winners of which are considered the fittest man and woman on Earth.
I&#39;m too tired right now to write a detailed play-by-play, so right now, I just want to share some thoughts.
I was certainly one of the smaller guys going into this competition, and I have only been CrossFitting for a little over a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Point of the Clock</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-point-of-the-clock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-point-of-the-clock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/clock.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-462&#34; title=&#34;clock&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/clock.jpg?w=199&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, after our workout, Kristi, my coach, Nick, a fellow CrossFitter, and myself stuck around to discuss the upcoming sectionals.  Somewhere in the discussion, the topic of different gyms&#39; methodologies came up. The other Stamford-based CrossFit gym, Hybrid Fitness, believes that extreme strength is pretty much the fundamental requirement for a good athelete. As such, they utilize a lot of strongman programming and training. We do not, and generally we aren&#39;t as strong on average. Does that mean we are worse than them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epic Fail</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/epic-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/epic-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/failure.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-438&#34; title=&#34;failure&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/failure.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, I failed epically. The workout for today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many rounds as possible, in 10 minutes, of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 deadlifts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 hang cleans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 front squats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 push jerks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All with 95 lbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, it&#39;s a ton of work, and much of it involving very technical movements. I was aiming to complete 7 rounds (so 49 of everything) because the previous record was 6 and change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I completed 6 rounds with about a minute and a half left. I was already dying. My vision was blurry and my legs felt like jelly, but I pushed through the sets. I got to the push jerks with 30 seconds left and without taking any rest, started into them. As the clock ticked to 0 seconds, I became distanced from my body, aware of but not feeling the burning in every muscle (a sensation that I had never experienced before), until the very last rep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acknowledging My Spiritual Debts</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/acknowledging-my-spiritual-debts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/acknowledging-my-spiritual-debts/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&#34;attachment_427&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;180&#34; caption=&#34;Martin Prechtel&#34;][/caption]
An old friend sent me a link to a really profound article yesterday. The article is an interview with a Pueblo-turned-Mayan-shaman, Martin Prechtel. In the interview Prechtel discusses his relationship with the spiritual world of indigenous cultures that have a respect for, and connection to, the land and environment around them. He also draws some really ominous connections between the utter lack - some would say, outright denial - of spirituality in Western civilization and the cultural malaise we experience in the form of endemic depression, poverty, loneliness, and even physical ailment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ties That Bind</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-ties-that-bind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-ties-that-bind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/web.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-424&#34; title=&#34;web&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/web.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;224&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my path down alternative fitness and nutrition and spirituality, I&#39;m discovering that members of my various communities all seem to agree on certain things. Most CrossFitters tend to agree that we should move as our bodies were meant to, and often think in terms of evolutionary biology and anatomy. This parallels a similar trend in the local and traditional food community to look back to how our ancestors ate to determine the best way to eat now. In fact, the CrossFitters also extend this mentality to nutrition, and I&#39;m sure many traditional foodies would as well if fitness were as central to their lives as nutrition is to a CrossFitter&#39;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Paleo Journey</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-paleo-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-paleo-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/paleo.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-414&#34; title=&#34;paleo&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/paleo.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;My gym&#39;s 30 Day Paleo Challenge has come to an end, though I know many of us will continue to stick to the diet, having seen a lot of progress in the last month. A number of my fellow CrossFitters didn&#39;t make it all the way though. The same attitude that gets them through grueling workouts is now making them very frustrated with themselves and their perceived inability to stick to a simple diet plan. They can&#39;t understand why a slice of toast is more difficult to overcome than a 250lb barbell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traits of a Warrior: Humility</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-humility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-humility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/humility.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-407&#34; title=&#34;humility&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/humility.jpg?w=210&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;210&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most important lessons I&#39;ve learned from CrossFit is humility. Workouts that sound easy never are, and I am always amazed at how quickly my muscles will tire, how a weight that sounds light quickly becomes unbearable. To make things worse, we are always talking about how some crazy CrossFitter completed the same WOD in unrealistically fast times. CrossFit is a community, and so we know that the same workout that destroyed everyone at our gym was a walk in the park for someone else. Personally, this is hard to swallow. I know I&#39;ve made amazing strides since I started, but an unweighted barbell still gets painfully heavy after a few minutes, and burpees can still leave me begging for mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make things worse, I&#39;ve come to learn that getting frustrated does not make things any better. After 5 months of training, my snatch max hasn&#39;t changed a single pound. But trying to use frustration to motivate myself only causes my technique to fall apart. There is a fine line between determination and frustration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When it Rains it Pours</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/when-it-rains-it-pours/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/when-it-rains-it-pours/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/rain.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-347 alignright&#34; title=&#34;Rain&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/rain.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I&#39;ve been out of college for a little over six months now, and looking for a job since September with zero luck. Sent out dozens of applications, trolled family contacts, bugged family friends, tried my hand at insurance, utilized alumni connections, everything I could think of. I don&#39;t even know how many Craigslist ads I responded to (in quite a bit of detail I might add). I went through a long and intense interview process for a job that would have set me down an amazing career in diplomacy and provided an astounding starting salary, only to be told eventually I lacked experience. My hopes have been dashed against the rocks more times than I want to count, but, with nothing else to do, I kept at it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Superhero Training</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/superhero-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/superhero-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/khaledbatman.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-339&#34; title=&#34;khaledbatman&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/khaledbatman.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People ask me why I train so hard. The answer is simple. I&#39;m training to be Batman... (as Superman was technically an alien, it would be a bit ridiculous for me to train to be him, since there&#39;s no way I could ever achieve that level of strength and fitness as an Earthling).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My CrossFit coaches have offered to pay my registration fee for the New England CrossFit Sectionals in March. While those who know me can attest to the fact that I didn&#39;t really need much motivation to train hard in the past, going to the Sectionals has given me a new kind of motivation and intensity to train. Knowing that I am going to be competing against some of the fittest people in New England, many of them bigger and stronger than me, has gotten me to really kick my training into high gear.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
