<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>homesteading on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/homesteading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in homesteading on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/homesteading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Missing What I Never Had: My Connection to the Real Food Community</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/missing-what-i-never-had-my-connection-to-the-real-food-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/missing-what-i-never-had-my-connection-to-the-real-food-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/countryside.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-478&#34; title=&#34;countryside&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/countryside.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I have an interesting relationship with the sustainable food community. I am deeply passionate about it, but I have never actually been a part of it. I can practically come to tears reading Mother Earth News and get lost in stories about people raising heritage chickens, constructing their own homes,, tending gardens, living in harmony with nature and experiencing a familial closeness that few Americans ever experience anymore. But I have never done any of these things. I think I grew some bean sprouts once in elementary school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this apparent lack of connection, every time I read these stories or talk with people who live these lives, I feel an unmistakable sense of nostalgia. It seems strange to feel nostalgic for something I&#39;ve never experienced, but I strongly &lt;em&gt;miss&lt;/em&gt; these things. I miss raising chickens, I miss knowing the names of the trees and what they are good for, I miss being in tune with the seasons. It is as if a quiet part of me, long dormant, stirs every time it hears something related to how things used to be. There is a spiritual connection to that life of harmony that is so powerful in me it almost hurts to live a life that is not in accordance to its desires. But where did it come from? Has it always been there, as a primordial connection to the land and community inherent in all humans? Or is it something that grew in me in response to the decay I see in our disharmonious world and the hope offered by a return to a different lifestyle whose values so closely mirror my deepest ideals?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
