<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>paleo on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/paleo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in paleo on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/paleo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Are You Too Stupid to Understand Your Health?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/are-you-too-stupid-to-understand-your-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/are-you-too-stupid-to-understand-your-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/paleomeal.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3055&#34; alt=&#34;paleomeal&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/paleomeal-300x200.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wild lettuce is nearly inedible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How strange that this food, touted as one of the healthiest icons of a simple, wholesome diet, is not a food humans regularly consumed prior to the advent of agriculture. Wild carrots are woody and fibrous; wild avocados had hardly enough meat to be worth eating; bananas were so full of seeds they would be inedible to modern people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently learned all this watching a video entitled, &#34;&lt;a title=&#34;Debunking the Paleo Diet&#34; href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BMOjVYgYaG8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Debunking the Paleo Myth&lt;/a&gt;&#34; (as usual, I&#39;m way behind the curve). I knew that much of Paleo was based on romantic  but unrealistic notions of Paleolithic cavemen and women living in an edenic utopia chasing mammoth for exercise and eating garden salads, but I had no idea how far off we were.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story of Humanity and Civilization</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-story-of-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-story-of-humanity/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I can&#39;t sleep. My mind whirls around, jumping from one thing to the next, sometimes so fast it scares me and I have to open my eyes to stare at the blackness of my room. Viewing the world in distinct categories, I end up feeling overwhelmed because there is too much to keep track of. When my mind finally relaxes, the artificial distinctions I use to categorize the world dissolve, and it is all revealed to be One.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Things That Matter</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-things-that-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-things-that-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-things-that-matter/737679_940187808960_3223248_o1/&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2674&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter  wp-image-2674&#34; title=&#34;A moment of pure bliss&#34; alt=&#34;Two dogs and a glass of wine&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/737679_940187808960_3223248_o1-1024x576.jpg&#34; width=&#34;574&#34; height=&#34;322&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started as a way to live responsibly. Knowing all the suffering and pollution caused by industrial farming and how that impacted my health, I made the commitment to eating organic and supporting local food whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To simplify my decision-making, I made up all sorts of rules about what I could and couldn&#39;t eat. Soon, adhering to the rules became more important than what the rules were meant to help me accomplish, which was eating in harmony. This harmonious way of eating would naturally give rise to health, but when I ran into the Paleo and Primal communities, health itself took the top priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all the obsession over good vs. bad carbs, optimal post-workout nutrition, and coconut substitutions for everything, I realized my diet had become meaningless. By all accounts, I ate well. My food was high quality and nutritious, but all this was lost on me. &lt;strong&gt;I didn&#39;t even taste my meals anymore.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I don&#39;t know how common this is among Paleo eaters and I hope you will leave comments sharing your experiences. It seems to me that obsessing over the health aspects of Paleo (dangerously easy to do given the mindset of the community) could lead us to forget how to enjoy our food for its own sake.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eventually, I came to believe that &lt;a title=&#34;You Can’t Afford to be Attached to Your Health, So Make it About Others&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/you-cant-afford-to-be-attached-to-your-health-so-make-it-about-others/&#34;&gt;my health doesn&#39;t matter&lt;/a&gt;, per se. I didn&#39;t live to be healthy. I was healthy in order to live well. &lt;/strong&gt;How I ate needed to be a reflection of that goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I believe that the very purpose of our life is to seek happiness. That is clear.&#34; - His Holiness the 14th Dalai Lama&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I realized that, I stopped getting so upset with the dietary rules. Eventually, I was able to reconnect with the enjoyment of my food again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, as you get deeper into Paleo, you realize that optimal health requires eating and living sustainably. So, even if your main priority is health, you are forced to aim higher, to prioritize something more general, in order to achieve that. The reality forces a widening of your concerns. If you refuse to see this, you end up chasing your own tail in a never-ended spiral of healthy living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Myth of Control in (Paleo) Health</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-myth-of-control-in-paleo-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-myth-of-control-in-paleo-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“The closest to being in control we will ever be is in that moment that we realize we&#39;re not.” - Brian Kessler&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/?attachment_id=2611&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2611&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-2611&#34; alt=&#34;LettingGo&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/LettingGo.jpg&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Last year, my&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/in-memory-of-auntie-phyllis/&#34;&gt; Aunt Phyllis&lt;/a&gt; succumbed to leukemia. I have often wondered if a change in diet could have improved her quality of life, given her more time, or even reversed the disease, based on anecdotes from  the Paleo community. Uncertainty kept me silent. Would it have made things better, or just given her more to worry about? Would I be trivializing her disease or the advice of her doctors? Would it mean I was &lt;i&gt;blaming&lt;/i&gt; her for the leukemia or its progression, by attributing the disease to lifestyle choices? Would it have made her feel ashamed that she had cancer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many, the suggestion that we can directly impact our health, even influencing such big-name diseases as cancer, diabetes, alzhiemer’s, and MS, is unwelcome. &lt;b&gt;It implies that our suffering is our fault, and can lead to a sense of guilt or shame.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if health is a critical factor in our ability to positively impact the world, it is not the final determinant of a person’s worth. Better to judge a person by what they have contributed to the lives of others and how they have made the world a better place. This may seem obvious, but in practice, many of us forget it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, someone else close to me has been diagnosed with a potentially life-threatening condition. Given my knowledge and experience, I&#39;m not sure how to help, or even if I should help at all. How we live if up to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Far do You Take Paleo?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-far-do-you-take-paleo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-far-do-you-take-paleo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Tell me the place you were born, the lives your ancestors led/&lt;br /&gt;
The ground that surrounded the people you love, the streams from which you were fed/&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s the wind that carries the seed, and the seed that carries the song/&lt;br /&gt;
The food that we&#39;re eating is rooted in soil, and it&#39;s soil that is keeping us strong/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Libby Roderick, &#34;Low to the Ground&#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/3736382830_a6cb6c31ed.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2473&#34; title=&#34;Hunters&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3736382830_a6cb6c31ed-300x175.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;175&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where do you draw the line in Paleo? Is it just a diet fad your gym is following, or do you place a higher importance on healthy eating? Do you keep The Paleo in the kitchen, or does it encompass all health behavior? If it is about health, is it restricted to your personal health, or does it encompass the health of your community? Is it more than just a set of health habits, but a lifestyle and a philosophy of living?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many people, Paleo only goes as far as practical. They eat the bacon avocado salads, are quick to find recipes for Paleo-pancakes and are happy to be only as strict their tastes allow. Paleo is confined to the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many more, following the principles of Paleo extends a little beyond convenience and diet. These people are willing to endure inconvenience because Paleo isn’t just a fashionable diet that happens to work. Paleo is about their health. They make an effort to eliminate stress, get enough sleep, and go out of their way to find grassfed meat and locally grown vegetables. Paleo extends to the way they exercise and move, keeping things spontaneous, playful, and intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people push Paleo even further (but not many). They allow Paleo to seep out of their ‘health and fitness’ lives. When it does, Paleo starts to become a lifestyle instead of a diet-and-exercise program. It stops fitting in that convenient compartment we have scheduled for an hour in the morning and after work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a funny thing starts to happen when you let Paleo expand beyond the bounds set by social convenience. &lt;strong&gt;It starts to define it’s own rules of social convenience. It starts to change the way we see the world, instead of itself being limited by the world&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Optimism of Ancestral Health</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-optimism-of-ancestral-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-optimism-of-ancestral-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/7478267850_38dff958ff.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-2396&#34; title=&#34;Optimistic Flower&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/7478267850_38dff958ff.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;334&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I am an optimist. It does not seem too much use being anything else. - Winston Churchill&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans break down. This is an accepted truth. Eventually (all too soon), we lose function. We become decrepit, slow, weak, riddled with pain, and ugly. Instead of crystallizing our wisdom &lt;a title=&#34;Aging Gloriously&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/aging-gloriously/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;as we age&lt;/a&gt;, our minds decay. Injuries do not heal, at least not without external intervention, and the greatest triumph of humankind is the medical and pharmaceutical industries that graciously prolong our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is the mainstream view on the human body. Athletes are exceptional (they get their own label, after all), a healthy lifestyle requires a specifying adjective, &lt;a title=&#34;Fitness is Not Health&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/fitness-is-not-health/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;isn&#39;t even that healthy&lt;/a&gt;, and sickness is the norm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrast that with the view of the Ancestral Health communities. &lt;strong&gt;We believe that a human being, in its pristine state, is a force to be reckoned with, a marvel of biological engineering, ecological integrity, and spiritual subtlety.&lt;/strong&gt; We heal ourselves, not via magic or superfoods, but because healing is what a healthy body does, and we&#39;ve done everything in our power to remove the obstacles to being normal, which is to say, ridiculously, vibrantly, off-the-wall healthy. Fitness is not even a sufficient term to encompass &lt;a title=&#34;A New Understanding of Fitness and the Human Body&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/a-new-understanding-of-fitness-and-the-human-body/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;what we meant&lt;/a&gt; by movement/&lt;a title=&#34;Fitness is Play&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/fitness-is-play/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;play&lt;/a&gt;/physically expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among those in the Ancestral Health communities--Paleo, &lt;a title=&#34;Freeing the Zoo Humans: Why I Want to Become a MovNat Instructor&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/movnat-instructor/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MovNat&lt;/a&gt;, Primal, Weston A. Price, barefoot runners--there is a belief in the inherent durability and resilience of the human being. Not only can it move and survive without reliance on extensive protection, but it can actually thrive without such crutches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t speak for everyone; there is a fair amount of division, &lt;a title=&#34;Why I Left Paleo Behind, and Why I’m Returning&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/why-i-left-paleo-behind-and-why-im-returning/&#34;&gt;which led me to wander alone for a while&lt;/a&gt;. But it is safe to say there are many who see these ideas as a path to something greater than a simple advantage in the rat-race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Left Paleo Behind, and Why I&#39;m Returning</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-i-left-paleo-behind-and-why-im-returning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-i-left-paleo-behind-and-why-im-returning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/3234878244_e7e5dbef88.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2338&#34; title=&#34;Walking Away&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3234878244_e7e5dbef88-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;They are asking us to pay more for less shoe, calling it a &#39;barefoot&#39; shoe, and we are happily handing over the money! -- Bryant Rolfe, to me, on a trail run with our new $100 Merrell Trailgloves&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got into Paleo, I came through Mark Sisson&#39;s Primal Blueprint. The MDA community was never exclusively about diet, but focused on a &lt;em&gt;lifestyle&lt;/em&gt; of health, vitality, and playfulness. Sure it was a bit tongue-in-cheek and insular, but it was a community with plenty of room for whatever your views might be. There were the hardcore, live-in-the-woods-naked eco-warriors, and there were those who simply wanted to sneak their Vibrams into their cubicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, I thought I ought to grow up and go Paleo. Primal seemed like a softer version of the real deal. I attended a Whole9 workshop at my CrossFit box. It didn&#39;t entirely mesh with what I knew about nutrition at the time from my study of Weston A. Price principles and the Primal Blueprint, but I signed on (since then, our beliefs about nutrition have come closer together). As my whole box went into it together, I was swept into the world of Paleo eating and CrossFit exercise, &lt;a title=&#34;Fitness is Not Health&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/fitness-is-not-health/&#34;&gt;two movements totally divorced from a holistic view on life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&#39;m sure the blame lies in how I implemented things, not in the methods themselves, but the way I saw the methods being presented, it didn&#39;t seem like there was much leeway. The segment of the community I was in, which I took to represent all of it, was decidedly narrow-minded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Truth About My Training and Diet</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-truth-about-my-training-and-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-truth-about-my-training-and-diet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1699&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;I&amp;#39;d rather be able to do this than have a fast Fran time. Source: Raphael Goetter on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/goetter/2567497624/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1699&#34; title=&#34;ironcross&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/ironcross-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a CrossFit trainer, I sometimes feel like I&#39;m not allowed to use, much less espouse, alternative forms of physical training or diet. But since I&#39;ve been caught so many times doing very un-CrossFit-like things, and a lot of people ask me what my training program is, or what my diet is, I thought I&#39;d come clean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Enemy of the Good</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-enemy-of-the-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-enemy-of-the-good/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;﻿&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;350&#34; caption=&#34;linh.ngân on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3515/3295481102_6b38448f44.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; &#34; title=&#34;Imperfect Flower&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3295481102_6b38448f44.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;350&#34; height=&#34;350&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my chosen fitness niche, there is a tendency to only focus on what gets results and ignore the rest. CrossFitters tend to scoff at bodybuilders and pro football players alike. The belief is that these individuals are wasting their time as far as fitness is concerned because they are too specialized and not lined up for optimal health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, strict adherents of the Paleo diet tend to dismiss those who only follow it partially. Anyone who knows anything about nutrition wouldn’t go near a loaf of bread, ever! If you do, you don’t take your health seriously. You should either change your ways or give up completely. So say the perfectly fit. Go the whole 9 yards, or not at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthy Ice Cream Alternatives</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/healthy-ice-cream-alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/healthy-ice-cream-alternatives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_988&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;jessicafm on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jessicafm/855848513/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-988&#34; title=&#34;ice cream&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/ice-cream-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;You scream, I scream, we all scream for ice cream!&#34; - American Proverb&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ice cream is probably the greatest food ever invented by humankind. But it is also probably one of the least healthy. It is basically milk and sugar, plus any flavorings and toppings. Of course, ice cream isn&#39;t meant to be healthy, so it should be an occasional treat, but sometimes you just have a craving for it when you know you can&#39;t or shouldn&#39;t break out the scoop and fudge sauce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are What Your Ancestors Ate</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/you-are-what-your-ancestors-ate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/you-are-what-your-ancestors-ate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_962&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: alexdecarvalho on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/adc/2344498516/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-962&#34; title=&#34;caveman&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/caveman-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meat and veggies, nuts and seeds, some fruit, little starch, and no sugar -&lt;em&gt;The Paleo Diet in a nutshell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of my friends know I &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/my-paleo-journey/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;follow an approximately Paleo diet&lt;/a&gt;, and a lot of people argue with me as to why it is silly to eat like Paleolithic humans. I thought I would take the time to dispel some myths and misunderstandings about this &#39;diet&#39;, and hopefully win a few converts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just One Bite Won&#39;t Hurt, Will It?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/just-one-bite-wont-hurt-will-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/just-one-bite-wont-hurt-will-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/cake.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-452&#34; title=&#34;cake&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/cake.jpg?w=225&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Working at Zara has gotten me thinking about the ethical place of fashion (what, you mean you don&#39;t develop philosophical treatises when you fold clothes?). Basically, my dilemma is this: should I invest my time and money in looking stylish and thus promoting myself socially, potentially leading to financial and personal success as a result of my social finesse, or should I spare the environment and my checkbook by only buying functional, practical, and minimal clothing?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
