<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>joseph campbell on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/joseph-campbell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in joseph campbell on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/joseph-campbell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Call to Write</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-call-to-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-call-to-write/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1822&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;229&#34; caption=&#34;aussiegall in Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/aussiegall/5630368331/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1822&#34; title=&#34;bloom&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/bloom-229x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;229&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As long as we are persistence in our pursuit of our deepest destiny, we will continue to grow. We cannot choose the day or time when we will fully bloom. It happens in its own time.” --Denis Waitley&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I haven’t posted to Warrior Spirit in a very long time. My concern was that the topic of the blog was becoming too vague and nebulous. I aspire to write stories for adventure magazines and grand science-fiction epics, neither of which were things this blog showcased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides that, I haven’t found Warrior Spirit to be especially rewarding. There is very little community interaction on the blog. Articles don’t get shared often, nobody links to the blog, and I don’t get many comments. Sometimes I felt like I was writing in a vacuum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to put it to rest and focus on other, more concrete projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then, I received a direct request to continue Warrior Spirit&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Myth&#39;s to Live By</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-myths-to-live-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-myths-to-live-by/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/mythstoliveby.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-1814&#34; title=&#34;mythstoliveby&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/mythstoliveby.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;128&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We are all the heroes of our own personal myths. No surprise there. What is really surprising is that all of our myths follow the same basic story arc. At least, this is the claim of Joseph Campbell, whose research into the mythologies of the world over has revealed that all cultures have strikingly similar myth’s underlying the basic fabric of society, the guide the development of the members of that society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Compete Human Being</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-compete-human-being/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-compete-human-being/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A  human being should be able to change a diaper, plan an invasion,  butcher a hog, conn a ship, design a building, write a sonnet, balance  accounts, build a wall, set a bone, comfort the dying, take orders, give  orders, cooperate, act alone, solve equations, analyze a new problem,  pitch manure, program a computer, cook a tasty meal, fight efficiently,  die gallantly. Specialization is for insects.” - Lazarus Long&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Campbell pointed out in his book &lt;em&gt;Myths to Live By &lt;/em&gt;that,  as humans have become more and more specialized, they have started to  feel like bigger and bigger chunks of their being are empty. When all  you are comfortable doing is studying and researching and you can’t feel  capable in the physical or social realm, you discover big areas of life  completely closed off to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow Your Own Path</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/follow-your-own-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/follow-your-own-path/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1268&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;198&#34; caption=&#34;anjamation on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/anjamation/2774936688/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1268&#34; title=&#34;celestial path&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/celestial-path-198x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;anjamation on Flickr&#34; width=&#34;198&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Your vision will become clear only when you look into your heart. Who looks outside, dreams. Who looks inside, awakens.” - Carl G. Jung&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reading an excerpt out of a book by Carl Jung last night, and was interested to find a concept that parallels one of the ideas in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/four-books-that-changed-my-life-this-summer/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Hero with a Thousand Faces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Namely, that every individual must find and undergo their own path to individual self-actualization, rather than being able to follow some generalized path. This probably explains why we can spend so much time reading how-to&#39;s and inspirational blogs and never actually get around to doing something; we are reading about someone else&#39;s hero journey, and trying to take it as the direction for our own. Jung&#39;s point was that there is no universal psychological concept that can be applied to every person&#39;s situation and specific problem, despite the modern trend to try to put everyone under a general diagnosis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
