<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>problems on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/problems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in problems on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/problems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Warrior Mindset Part 1: Turn Problems Into Challenges</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/part-i-of-the-warrior-mindset-turn-problems-into-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/part-i-of-the-warrior-mindset-turn-problems-into-challenges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2726&#34; alt=&#34;5646268901_1d5d96a8e1&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5646268901_1d5d96a8e1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-2723 alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;rhodessmaller&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/rhodessmaller-200x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;151&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post from Shawn Rhodes, founder of Shoshin Consulting. Shawn is a traveler, teacher and above all, a lifelong student. After growing up in the mountains training in martial arts and eastern philosophy, he followed his own warrior&#39;s calling and joined the U.S. Marines. There, he accompanied infantry Marines through two combat tours in Iraq, documenting their trials and victories for international news outlets like CNN and TIME. While living and fighting alongside this tribe of modern-day warriors, he discovered the link between the warrior&#39;s path and mastery in life. He returned to the U.S. with the passion to share a vision of what humans are capable of when they embrace their own inner warrior and return to a mindset where all paths are possible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is the first in a three-part series on The Warrior&#39;s Path. Each installment will explore the evolution of the warrior mindset.  Rooted in ancient methods warriors followed for thousands of years, these installments will give readers a glimpse into how traditional and modern warriors see the world.  Adopting this mindset can help anyone regain balance, direction, and control of their health, success, and life.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional role of the fighter - the person who trains from a young age to be skilled in combat - is disappearing. For better or worse, the mindset learned from a lifetime of turning problems to one’s advantage on the battlefield or the boardroom is being lost. Technology is changing the face of war and our world. The traditional warrior&#39;s path - years of intense physical training, exposure to the elements, mental exhaustion, moments that burn into memory - is not for everyone. That doesn&#39;t mean you can&#39;t benefit from the way warriors learn to see themselves and the world, however. I believe this valiant spirit lives inside everyone, and that we can all benefit from learning how to approach the world like a warrior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;A select few still hear the call to embrace warriorhood; not the call to control others with force, but to turn their focus inward to the battlefield of their own lives. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This calling is universal to every place and age. As we allow ourselves to become dependent on external distractions to fill our inner voids, the call to seize control of our destinies and live with a courageous spirit is louder than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many of us turn to television, alcohol, drugs, and even chronic exercise in the hope it will distract us from our responsibility as human beings and warriors: the mission of the warrior is to discover all they are capable of being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn to Stand Alone</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learn-to-stand-alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learn-to-stand-alone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_998&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;faungg on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/44534236@N00/3255156612/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-998&#34; title=&#34;tree&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/tree-300x201.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;Never tell your problems to anyone...20% don&#39;t care and the other 80% are glad you have them..&#34; &lt;em&gt;- Lou Holtz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most frustrating aspects of life is that whenever you become passionate about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/dont-be-afraid-to-reach-for-your-goals/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;pursuing some extraordinary goal&lt;/a&gt; or lifestyle, people waste no time in trying to hold you back. I find it odd that people rarely go out of their way to encourage your ambitions, but they will eagerly jump into a conversation to provide reasons you are wrong, might fail, or wasting your time. Especially if they have to change some aspect of their lives to accommodate you, they will do their utmost to convince you that your desire to run off and contribute to world peace will absolutely end their livliehoods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
