<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>change on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/change/</link>
    <description>Recent content in change on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re Not the One Who Will Achieve Your Dreams</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/youre-not-the-one-who-will-achieve-your-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/youre-not-the-one-who-will-achieve-your-dreams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“The recipe for perpetual ignorance is: Be satisfied with your opinions and content with your knowledge.” -Elbert Hubbard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We know what we are, but know now what we may be.” - William Shakespeare&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/6527715119_b568570ab2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2499&#34; title=&#34;The Illusion of the Self&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/6527715119_b568570ab2-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest obstacles to accomplishing our greatest dreams and goals is the fear of growth. We are unwilling to change, even in a positive way, because growth is painful. Even when we get stronger as a result, we tend to shy away from the necessary discomfort that comes with the process of improving ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After all, growth only comes as the result of learning to deal with challenges that are slightly beyond us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem is that,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;in order to accomplish our goals, we must grow.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we didn&#39;t need to grow, we would already be doing what we dream about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on our particular dream, the kind of change and growth we need will be different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to get stronger, faster, healthier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to make more connections and meet more people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to gain deeper insight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to learn new ideas and master new theories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to see the world in a slightly different way that empowers us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to play a bigger game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We need to be comfortable with the things that scare us at the moment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To a large extent, that last one covers all the others, and it is significant because it is integral to our sense of who we are. &lt;strong&gt;Our fears create our limiting image of ourselves&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tell a Story, Change the World</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/tell-a-story-change-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/tell-a-story-change-the-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/5989736193_952566e542.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2436&#34; title=&#34;Storytelling&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5989736193_952566e542-300x204.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;204&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Storytelling is the most powerful way to put ideas into the world today. - Robert McAfee Brown&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To create a better reality, first tell as story about it so real and compelling that all uncertainty and fear is replaced by excitement and a desire for something better.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are funny sometimes. Even when we want something better than what we have, we are reluctant to move towards it until we are assured it is safe. Most people will always prefer the known reality they have over the unknown they might have, even if could be better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncertainty is a huge demotivator&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was starting to change my life for the better, the biggest obstacle to progress was the inability to see the reality I wanted to become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No matter how much I pushed myself to meet people, I could not see myself as socially confident, and so I never became comfortable with it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No matter how many pushups I did, I never saw myself as strong, and so they were always hard and my progress was painfully slow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No matter how much I wrote, I never saw myself as a writer, and so I had only marginal success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eventually, I realized the problem wasn&#39;t my lack of practice. It was the fact that I was clinging to the wrong picture of who I was.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, instead of focusing on the logistics, I started to focus on the image in my head, the vision I had of what and who I was. I started to imagine myself doing all the great things I was trying to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I imagined every detail of the me who was socially confident and engaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I painted a detailed image of a strong, muscular, fast, athletic me, doing all the cool things I wanted to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I called myself a writer, over and over, and talked as if that was how I made my living.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when my mind became comfortable with the image, my reality started to conform to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Going to Make It</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/were-going-to-make-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/were-going-to-make-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1836&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;mikbaird on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mikebaird/2087879492/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1836&#34; title=&#34;clearingthewave&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/clearingthewave-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a point in every challenging experience where you go from questioning whether you&#39;ve got what it takes to survive and to feeling secure that things will be alright. You&#39;ve been staring up at an impending wave, not sure you&#39;ll get to the other side, but now you&#39;re on top, and you can see the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me living in Korea, I passed that point a few days ago. Nothing really has changed around me, but something inside me clicked. Finding my balance point is less of a daily struggle, I&#39;m starting to groove my daily paths and activities and get a sense for my surroundings. A and I have slowly transformed our apartment into a living space that reflects the kind of lives we want to live, so we are no longer fitting ourselves into someone else&#39;s living space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like I can see further and, while I may not feel that I&#39;ve accomplished that state of security just yet, I know it is attainable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn to Love Pain</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/learn-to-love-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/learn-to-love-pain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1593&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Nathan Phillips on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/npphoto/4383990220/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1593&#34; title=&#34;pain&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/pain-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you could get past pain and discomfort by  accepting it and relaxing into it? I don’t mean that the pain goes away,  but rather that you become okay with it. You still feel it, but it  doesn’t bother you. You can get on with whatever it is you’re doing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
