<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self-respect on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/self-respect/</link>
    <description>Recent content in self-respect on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/self-respect/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Valuing Your Own Happiness Earns You More Respect</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-valuing-your-own-happiness-earns-you-more-respect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-valuing-your-own-happiness-earns-you-more-respect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;There is one thing that will destroy a person faster than anything else: inauthenticity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being devoted to a life that you do not have, instead of being present and engaged in the one that you do have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constantly putting off, day after day, the things you love.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never disagreeing for fear of offending.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing what you think you should. Being a ‘nice guy’ or a ‘good girl’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Living up to others expectations of you, instead of living up to your own standards for yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;The reason being inauthentic is so self-destructive is because it sends the message to yourself that your beliefs and principles aren&#39;t worth expressing, and therefore you aren&#39;t valuable or worth listening to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By presenting ourselves in a way that matches our values, however, we are telling ourselves and others that we think we are worthwhile.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;So, by simply doing the things we enjoy, saying the things we hold as true, and acting or presenting ourselves in the ways that reflect who we are, we can build our confidence and sense of purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret of Authentic Confidence</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-secret-of-authentic-confidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-secret-of-authentic-confidence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“When people do not respect us we are sharply offended; yet deep down in his private heart no man much respects himself.” -Mark Twain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life&#39;s eternal question: Do you gain self-respect when your worth is proven in the world, or do you prove your worth by cultivating honest self-respect? And can you fake it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve noticed a harmful trend in personal development literature, in every field from entrepreneurship to dating, recommending over-the-top confidence, arrogance, and sometimes outright lying. In an attempt to get shy quiet types like me to actually sell ourselves, these gurus assure us that pushy sales tactics are a perfectly legitimate way to interact with people. We need to get over our sqeamishness and man-up, whether it&#39;s bulldozing a client to close a deal or asserting dominance to &#39;pick up&#39; a date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I disagree. I think that kind of arrogance is symptomatic of people who lack real confidence and so have to rely on a facade of bravado.&lt;/strong&gt; There is certainly value in rehearsal, routines, and templates, but these should serve as a framework to human interaction, not the basis of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Built-in BS Detector&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t think anyone can tell the difference? The human brain is really good at making judgement about other people based on subtle body language clues that give away a person&#39;s true character. For example, after watching a 30 second silent clip of a teacher interacting with a student, research subjects were able to predict how well the teacher would do on their evaluation at the end of the semester. Similar results were found with political candidates (2 seconds of exposure) and doctors facing malpractice suits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is, we&#39;re really good at telling when people are inauthentic. (Whether we give credence to what we detect and actually act on our instinct is a matter of &lt;a title=&#34;Listen to Your Intuition: It Could Save Your Life&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/listen-to-your-intuition-it-could-save-your-life/&#34;&gt;trusting your intuition&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fake It &#39;til You Make It&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I&#39;ve also noticed that people tend to assume you have an accurate idea of your own value. That is, if you act like you&#39;re &#34;kind of a big deal,&#34; they&#39;ll treat you that way unless circumstances prove otherwise (they may still challenge or test you to check if you&#39;re bluffing, so don&#39;t actually lie). &lt;strong&gt;If you act like you&#39;re not capable or worthy of respect and responsibility, others will treat you accordingly, even if you&#39;re actual accomplishments suggest otherwise&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
