<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nature deficit disorder on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/nature-deficit-disorder/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nature deficit disorder on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/nature-deficit-disorder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5 Stories of A Little Boy in Nature</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/5-stories-of-a-little-boy-in-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/5-stories-of-a-little-boy-in-nature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSC_1618.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter  wp-image-2874&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_1618&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/DSC_1618-1024x685.jpg&#34; width=&#34;574&#34; height=&#34;383&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up this morning and sat on the edge of my futon to meditate, A&#39;s breathing setting the backdrop for my own deeper, regulated breath. I had finally managed to wake up early enough that the apartment was silent; there were no dogs scrabbling around in the kitchen, and our roommate was still asleep as well. I was determined to make the most of this time when it would be easier to focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After sitting, I picked up a book I&#39;d been intending to start for months, &lt;i&gt;Last Child in the Woods.&lt;/i&gt; I read a few pages into the first chapter, remembering stories my dad used to tell about exploring the forest just outside town, hunting squirrels with a rifle. The book is about the epidemic of what the author calls, &#34;nature deficit disorder,&#34; a condition arising from a severe and notable lack of interaction with the natural world in children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to think about my own experiences with nature and came up with very little. I had hated leaving my precious computer games and Nintendo as a child, but when I really thought about it, I did spend quite a lot of time outdoors. Some of my strongest memories were formed in the natural world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
