<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>motivation on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/motivation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in motivation on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Take On Big Projects Without Choking</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-swallow-big-goals-without-choking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-swallow-big-goals-without-choking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3930&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/smallfishbiggoal-e1423078046392.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;smallfishbiggoal&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;262&#34; /&gt;I woke up this morning and looked out on a winter wonderland. Snow had been coming down all night, and it was falling in tiny biting crystals that stuck to everything. Very pretty, very cold, and very wet. The sidewalks were covered in snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;I guess I&#39;m not going for my morning run,&#34; I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I stopped myself and asked a different question: &#34;&lt;em&gt;Can&lt;/em&gt; I go for my morning run, in shorts and a shirt as usual?&#34; I&#39;d run in cold weather before, but not in actual falling snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I honestly didn&#39;t know the answer to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided not to make assumptions about my limitations and just give it a shot. Maybe it wouldn&#39;t be so bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can I do This?: A Question to Improve Performance on Everything</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/can-i-do-this-a-question-to-improve-performance-on-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/can-i-do-this-a-question-to-improve-performance-on-everything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3855&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/question-e1418143667521.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;question&#34; width=&#34;761&#34; height=&#34;566&#34; /&gt;Perhaps you&#39;ve heard the old advice that it&#39;s important to psych yourself up before a big test or meeting. Remind yourself how awesome you are! Tell yourself, &#34;I can do this! I&#39;m a rockstar!&#34; Maybe you&#39;ve even done this, despite all feelings to the contrary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve ever been in an airplane during extreme turbulence, you don&#39;t want to overhear your pilot insisting, &#34;I can do this! Yeah!&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they are talking at all, you want to hear specific actions that they will be taking to make things better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a reason for this. Our minds actually interpret insistent statements like these as a sign that there is something really wrong. After all, if you were confident, you wouldn&#39;t even need to bother with the motivation at all, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it turns out there&#39;s a better way to motivate yourself, one that feels less like a desperate plea to convince yourself of something you just don&#39;t believe, and that actually helps you do better, rather than simply feel better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask the simple question, &#34;Can I do this?&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Avoid Pursuing Our Dreams, and 3 Strategies to Get Motivated</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-we-avoid-pursuing-our-dreams-and-3-strategies-to-get-motivated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-we-avoid-pursuing-our-dreams-and-3-strategies-to-get-motivated/</guid>
      <description>Nothing ventured, nothing gained. - Anon
 I marvel at how easy it is for me to do everything except the thing that I dream about: writing a novel. I can blog all day, train, teach fitness and self-defense, promote and market and teach myself Javascript. I make plans and schedules to make these things happen. But for some reason, I have a lot of trouble bringing the same discipline to bear on writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give Yourself a Mission</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/give-yourself-a-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/give-yourself-a-mission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1654&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;The U.S. Army on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/soldiersmediacenter/3729394795/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1654&#34; title=&#34;mission&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/mission-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say that you do not recognize before you and around you  any but those office-holders whole commissions have been signed by a  minister or a king; and that the men whom God has put above these  office-holders, ministers, and kings, by giving them a mission to follow  out instead of a post to fill—I say that they escape your narrow,  limited field of observation. - The Count of Monte Cristo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the usual question we ask kids—“What do you want  to be when you grow up?”—is the wrong sort of question. Instead, we  should be asking them, “What do you want to do?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Count of Monte Cristo points out in the above  quotation, there are two kinds of people in the world: those who fill  posts and those who pursue missions. The two are not always mutually  exclusive, but they are usually very separate ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To me, the difference seems to be that a post is limiting while a mission is empowering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Process of Living</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-process-of-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-process-of-living/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_974&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;Source: mdezemery on flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mdezemery/311283302/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-974&#34; title=&#34;walking&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/walking-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;The journey is what brings us happiness not the destination.&#34; -&lt;em&gt;Dan Millman, The Peaceful Warrior&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the overriding themes that I refer to a lot is the idea that many important endeavors are ongoing. There is no end goal in mind, and having an end goal can often derail our efforts to improve. Instead, simply going through your routine, growing slowly and naturally, will get you where you want to go with less frustration and less pain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
