<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>warrior on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/warrior/</link>
    <description>Recent content in warrior on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/warrior/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Warrior Mindset Part 3: The Warrior’s Obligation</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-warrior-mindset-part-3-the-warriors-obligation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-warrior-mindset-part-3-the-warriors-obligation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2756&#34; alt=&#34;Swords into Plowshares&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/2981939103_1cbae339fb.jpg&#34; width=&#34;407&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#34;They shall beat their swords into plowshares and their spears into pruning hooks. Nation will not take up sword against nation, nor will they train for war anymore.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;
-Isaiah 2:4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post from Shawn Rhodes, founder of Shoshin Consulting. After growing up in the mountains training in martial arts and eastern philosophy, he followed his own warrior’s calling and joined the U.S. Marines. There, he accompanied infantry Marines through two tours in Iraq, documenting their trials and victories for international news outlets like CNN and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;rhodessmaller&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/rhodessmaller-e1358734605767-150x150.jpg&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;TIME. While living and fighting alongside this tribe of modern-day warriors, he discovered the link between the warrior’s path and mastery in life. He returned to the U.S. with the passion to share a vision of what humans are capable of when they embrace their own inner warrior and return to a mindset where all paths are possible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is the third in a three-part series on The Warrior&#39;s Path. Each installment will explore the evolution of the warrior mindset. Rooted in ancient methods warriors followed for thousands of years, adopting this mindset can help anyone to regain balance, direction, and control of their health, success, and life.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/part-i-of-the-warrior-mindset-turn-problems-into-challenges/&#34;&gt;the first part&lt;/a&gt; of this series, I showed readers how past and present-day warriors learn to shift their mindsets, allowing them to transform the problems they face into challenges of responsibility for the quality of their lives. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-warrior-mindset-part-2-transform-challenges-into-opportunities/&#34;&gt;part two&lt;/a&gt;, readers stepped into the mindset of a mature and experienced warrior, a person who is confident in their abilities and no longer feels the need to prove themselves. As a result of this mindset, they see experiences in their lives as opportunities for growth as warriors and human beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the next stage in a warrior’s development?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer this, it would be helpful to examine the roles that warriors throughout history have played when they - as a culture - existed in peacetime. It makes sense that skillful warriors would eventually work themselves out of a job by either death or victory. However, the warrior tradition in human cultures has grown to allow for periods of peace. In fact, some of the most skilled warrior societies were based on achieving internal and external peace. Japanese culture, for instance, gave rise to the renowned Samurai.  The word for ‘warrior’ - &lt;i&gt;bushi  &lt;/i&gt;(武士) &lt;i&gt;– &lt;/i&gt;is comprised of symbols for ‘a spear being removed or taken away.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are very few warriors who experienced and fought in prolonged combat who would choose that lifestyle for themselves and their families. It is a paradox that to achieve peace one must confront war (internally, externally, or both), but it is true. &lt;b&gt;A warriors’ ultimate objective is to bring peace to themselves and their world&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a warrior finds a place of peace, their real challenge begins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Warrior is Not a Fighter</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-warrior-is-not-a-fighter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-warrior-is-not-a-fighter/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&#34;attachment_2347&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;] A classic depiction of a Buddhist warrior, often as guardians in temples to keep away demons[/caption]
“When I was in the army, I was a soldier. I was a puppet doing whatever anybody told me to do, even if it meant going against what my heart told me was right. I didn’t know nothing about being a warrior until I hit the streets and marched alongside my brothers for something I really believed in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide to Warrior Spirit</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/guide-to-warrior-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/guide-to-warrior-spirit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You have probably noticed all the changes that have taken place recently around here. I just want to make sure everyone knows how things will be run from now on. The main changes have been the new subscription services and the posting schedule, as well as the focus of the posts. Here&#39;s a breakdown of what&#39;s new and what&#39;s to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warrior Profile: Comparing Batman and Spiderman</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/warrior-profile-comparing-batman-and-spiderman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/warrior-profile-comparing-batman-and-spiderman/</guid>
      <description>I talk a lot about Batman as an inspiration for training and following ideals, so just for fun, I thought I&#39;d write a post on how exactly the Path of the Warrior can be discerned from his life. To make things more interesting, I will be comparing him to another popular superhero: Spiderman. I picked these two because a) they are very nearly opposites without one being a villain, and b) there were recently made several movies about each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Separating the (Young) Men from the Boys</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/separating-the-young-men-from-the-boys/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/separating-the-young-men-from-the-boys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/youngman.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-430&#34; title=&#34;youngman&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/youngman.jpg?w=207&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;207&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Growing up, my conception of what kind of man I would become was always very different from that of my peers. When I was in elementary school, I was emulating my idea of what responsible adults acted like, rather than trying to grow up to be like the high school kids. I didn&#39;t look forward to high school and college as times to party and sleep around, but instead as opportunities to start developing the skills and qualities I wanted to use as the foundation of my life as a responsible, formidable man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friends thought I was weird, and I thought I had made a huge mistake. I still wonder if I wouldn&#39;t have been better off just going with the flow and enjoying myself, instead of trying so hard to grow up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons I&#39;ve Learned</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-ive-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-ive-learned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/lesson.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-419&#34; title=&#34;lesson&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/lesson.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sometimes the lessons you learn are harsh, and sometimes they are just surprising, but there is no point in denying reality. So here are a few partially inconvenient truths I&#39;ve managed to internalize over the past few years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traits of a Warrior: Service</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout history, Warriors have been the guardians of their societies. They do not train and fight for the sake of it, or for senseless violence. Historical warriors have learned the arts of war in order to better protect their people and families, or to extend their reach of their chosen sovereign. Tribal warriors were the ones who put their lives on the line to defend their families. Knights and Samurai were the ones willing to die for their lords&#39; agenda.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
