<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life changes on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/life-changes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life changes on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/life-changes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Good Bye</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/good-bye/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/good-bye/</guid>
      <description>Warrior Spirit has been a wonderful adventure, but I&#39;m sad to say I have decided to scale it back considerably.
I haven&#39;t really been able to focus it and lately, it has felt more of an obligation and a burden than something I get excited for. Also, my life is undergoing massive changes at the moment, and I feel that Warrior Spirit, as something that was started right after college, is making it difficult for me to let go of my old ways in order to grow, largely because I have several hundred eyes on me as I&#39;m shifting things around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Paleo Journey</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-paleo-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-paleo-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/paleo.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-414&#34; title=&#34;paleo&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/paleo.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;My gym&#39;s 30 Day Paleo Challenge has come to an end, though I know many of us will continue to stick to the diet, having seen a lot of progress in the last month. A number of my fellow CrossFitters didn&#39;t make it all the way though. The same attitude that gets them through grueling workouts is now making them very frustrated with themselves and their perceived inability to stick to a simple diet plan. They can&#39;t understand why a slice of toast is more difficult to overcome than a 250lb barbell.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
