<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>goals on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/goals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in goals on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/goals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Take On Big Projects Without Choking</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-swallow-big-goals-without-choking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-swallow-big-goals-without-choking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3930&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/smallfishbiggoal-e1423078046392.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;smallfishbiggoal&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;262&#34; /&gt;I woke up this morning and looked out on a winter wonderland. Snow had been coming down all night, and it was falling in tiny biting crystals that stuck to everything. Very pretty, very cold, and very wet. The sidewalks were covered in snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;I guess I&#39;m not going for my morning run,&#34; I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I stopped myself and asked a different question: &#34;&lt;em&gt;Can&lt;/em&gt; I go for my morning run, in shorts and a shirt as usual?&#34; I&#39;d run in cold weather before, but not in actual falling snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I honestly didn&#39;t know the answer to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided not to make assumptions about my limitations and just give it a shot. Maybe it wouldn&#39;t be so bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2015 Strategy Part 3: Specific, Measurable, Actions</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-3-specific-measurable-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-3-specific-measurable-actions/</guid>
      <description>Alright! It&#39;s the end of the second week in January and we&#39;re finally done with all the ways to plan out an epic 2015. Part 1 focused on the big picture strategy. Part 2 focused on the foundational habits that need to happen to provide the time, energy, and financial resources to make it happen. Part 3 will focus on the specific actions to take.
For the underlying theory, go here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategies for Success in 2015</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/strategies-for-success-in-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/strategies-for-success-in-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3869&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/chess-e1419979014150.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chess&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;406&#34; /&gt;I don&#39;t like resolutions. &lt;a title=&#34;Forget the Resolution! Set a Challenge!&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/forget-the-resolution-set-a-challenge/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Remember 2013&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with resolutions is that they simply set a goal. They don&#39;t provide a way to actually accomplish that goal, and often, they don&#39;t even determine if the goal is worth pursuing in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s no wonder so many people set resolutions on January 1st only to see them fall apart in a month. &lt;strong&gt;Most resolutions are chosen on a whim, or are the result of compounding pain, not compelling vision.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not that resolutions themselves are bad, it&#39;s that they are missing the essentials of good growth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A clear mission/purpose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solid strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actionable goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key aspects of the Warrior Spirit is being dedicated to a cause or a mission. Having that foundation is what gives you the ability to muster superhuman determination in whatever you choose to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But...you can&#39;t know what goals matter unless you have a clear idea of your mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the first step in creating a strategy for 2015 is to refocus on your mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did You Forget Why You Came This Way?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/did-you-forget-why-you-came-this-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/did-you-forget-why-you-came-this-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1862&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;David Spinks on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/davidspinks/4453498888/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1862&#34; title=&#34;Above the Clouds&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/4453498888_f576a9afd5-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyday, I wake up earlier than I want to, and work longer than I want do, at a job that wasn’t my idea, creating something that was never on my radar for things I want to accomplish in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, why do I do it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presumably to get paid so that I can live, but walking through the snow yesterday to the school where I work, I couldn’t help but wonder what the point of making enough money to live was. What would I do with the living that I earned? Just make more living, more money, so that I could go on buying food and renting a roof over my head?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I felt the need to rise above the clouds of my day-to-day for a little bit, to get a wider perspective on my life and why I do what I do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traits of a Warrior: Persistence</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-persistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/penguin.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-489&#34; title=&#34;penguin&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/penguin.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;222&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, the workout at my gym was to determine at what weight you could do 10 non-stop power cleans (move a barbell from floor to shoulder in one motion). At 165lbs, my form began to slip and I dragged the knurled bar up my shins, several times, leaving my legs bloody and stinging. I failed the set, only getting 9. Pretty upset with myself, I went to the bathroom to clean up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was taping up my leg, I was thinking about calling it a day. But looking at my leg, I realized there wasn&#39;t any actual damage. All I&#39;d done was scrape some skin, and while it stung, it had no impact on my muscles&#39; ability to perform. I covered the wound in tape to protect it, and got back on the pad, and did the full set as if nothing had happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of times in our lives when we suffer dramatic and painful failures. Our usual response is to throw in the towel, grudgingly accept that we did our best, and nurse our wounded egos. But when we look back, it is clear that our egos were the only things that were really injured by our setback. Our ability to complete the task at hand has not been diminished in any way, we simply have decided, arbitrarily, that we have failed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
