<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>unsticking on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/unsticking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in unsticking on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/unsticking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Face Your Inner Demons to Get Unstuck</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/inner-demons-unstuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/inner-demons-unstuck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Yesterday, I brought up the reality that we all have &lt;a title=&#34;The Hard Questions&#34; href=&#34;http://wp.me/p15g8X-Po&#34;&gt;troubling questions&lt;/a&gt; we&#39;d rather not deal with in our lives, demons that give us excuses to be complacent or hold ourselves back. To answer them is to face our own &lt;a title=&#34;Insecurity, the Root of All Evil&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/insecurity-the-root-of-all-evil/&#34;&gt;insecurities&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title=&#34;6 Ways Accepting Your Weaknesses Can Empower You&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/6-ways-accepting-your-weaknesses-can-empower-you/&#34;&gt;weaknesses&lt;/a&gt;. Today, I&#39;m going to dissect those demons so we can vanquish them and pursue our heroic destiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Many of these hard questions involve questioning the investment. Some examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&#34;Am I really happy in this relationship?&#34; -- If the answer is no, it would mean ending a long-term emotional, time, and material investment. If we know the answer will be &#39;no,&#39; we may avoid asking the question at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&#34;Why do I stay at a job I hate?&#34; -- The answer to this question often reveals perceived character flaws, things we&#39;d rather not believe about ourselves. Maybe we believe we aren&#39;t qualified for anything better, or we think quitting would make us look bad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;People are reluctant to break up long-term relationships because they’ve already invested so much in them, or they are afraid to quit a job because they worked so hard to get it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;A Choose-Your-Own-Reality Adventure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Why can&#39;t we just see an obvious answer, internalize it, and act on it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;The best explanation comes from a psychological theory called cognitive dissonance, which just sounds uncomfortable. It posits that humans have a natural inclination to seek consistency in our lives and actions. If we detect an inconsistency, we feel cognitive stress, which can manifest in a variety of ways from general anxiety up to psychosomatic disorders. Naturally, we will work to eliminate it, even if that means changing our beliefs (which is what the demons of mediocrity want). If we are successful, we can avoid the stress, but some things cannot be hidden, so even if we refuse to acknowledge them consciously, we still know there is an inconsistency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;The classic illustration of this is Aesop&#39;s fable, &#34;The Fox and the Grapes&#34;:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
