<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>posture on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/posture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in posture on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/posture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Keeping it Together; The Importance of Good Life Posture</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/keeping-it-together-the-importance-of-good-life-posture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/keeping-it-together-the-importance-of-good-life-posture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cell sits dark and dank, but tidy, waiting patiently for its occupant to return. With a clang, the door slams open and two burly guards throw a scarecrow of a man onto the floor, fresh out of torture. They stand at the door a moment, sniggering while he picks himself up and hobbles to the small washbasin, where he carefully starts to clean the blood off his face.&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/7304451284_aa7892d4a9.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2521&#34; title=&#34;Good Posture&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/7304451284_aa7892d4a9-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;Why does he waste his time?&#34; one guard asks the other. &#34;They&#39;ll just mess him up again in a few hours.&#34; The other guard just laughs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prisoner ignores them. When they leave, he removes his torn prison uniform, folds it carefully and sets it at the foot of his bed. Then, he tends to his wounds. All he wants is to throw himself onto his bed, curl up and blank out everything, but he makes the effort to respect himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slowly, he feels his sanity returning as he goes through the familiar motions. He feels his sense of value returning and he breathes deeply, enjoying the simple pleasure of moving his muscles and tending to his needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He does this every day, and has for the last eight years of torture. Fastidiously looking after his health and the tidiness of his environment, despite what to any other would justify letting go, he has held on to his sanity. By going through the motions of cleanliness, he is telling his mind that his life has not fallen apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And for eight years, no torture has broken him, because he lets nothing that has happened be enough of an emergency to disrupt his routine, and thus, his integrity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
