<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2015 on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/2015/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2015 on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/2015/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My 2015 Strategy Part 1: Dreams and Aspirations</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-1-dreams-and-aspirations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-1-dreams-and-aspirations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3875&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/newyear-e1420164792163.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;newyear&#34; width=&#34;698&#34; height=&#34;280&#34; /&gt;At the end of 2014, I sat down and wrote down all the things I would do if time and money were no issue. It&#39;s a really helpful exercise in figuring out what your mission in life is and where you find fulfillment, one I&#39;ll share in the Exercise section in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I thought, &#34;Okay, so I&#39;ll have a list of things that I can start thinking about doing, SOMEDAY.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Mission&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it turned out that most of the things I wanted to do didn&#39;t require time or money at all. Here&#39;s what I ended up writing, abridged:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;I would write a genre-bending science-fiction novel....I would travel to Tibet, hike the Himalayas, have tea with the Dalai Lama, and encounter a snow leopard in the wild...I would become a valuable resource for all of my friends, providing support, resources, and strategy to help them achieve their goals and dreams...I would travel back to Korea to study with my Krav Maga teacher for an extended sabbatical, and also go to Japan to study with a living ninjutsu master....I would read all the classics...I would find a way to see my friends face-to-face, or at least have more phone conversations, especially with the ones who have stuck with my for years....I would spend more time in nature, camping more than once a year....I would rekindle my love of gaming, playing more RPGs, computer strategy games, and card games with friends....I would get back into flying regularly....Start a business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I distilled those dreams down into the following list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a novel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See Tibet, meet the Dalai Lama, and see a snow leopard in the wild&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Become a martial arts master -- Krav Maga, Kenpo, Ninjutsu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend more face-to-face time with friends and become a valuable support to them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play more games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend more time in nature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start a business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of these, the one that resonated the most and seemed the most central to my idea of success and fulfillment was being there for my friends and supporting people. So that is my mission: &lt;strong&gt;to help the people in my life achieve their dreams by showing them how to be heroic in their own lives and communities.&lt;/strong&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
