<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>military on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/military/</link>
    <description>Recent content in military on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/military/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Giving Up On My Dream of Being a Soldier</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/giving-up-on-my-dream-of-being-a-soldier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/giving-up-on-my-dream-of-being-a-soldier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1760&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;The U.S. Army on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/soldiersmediacenter/478415299/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1760&#34; title=&#34;soldier&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/soldier-300x186.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;186&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always had an interest in joining the military. I wanted to be a jet fighter pilot, or a special forces operative. For the first time in my life, I have no reason to be afraid of the physical demands of the job; I routinely best soldiers in fitness competitions, and I could pass the special forces entrance exams. I’m confident enough in myself to withstand the rigors of training, and I feel more certain than ever that I could benefit from the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I have had to let go of that dream as I’ve come to understand the realities of what a soldier does. In order to live out my dream, I would have to compromise on a lot of things that are really important to me. This isn’t because of the nature of the military generally, but rather the way the system is set up currently. I could get behind fighting against Hitler in World War II, but I have never been very good at investing myself in other peoples’ agendas if I don’t believe in them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
