<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>students on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/students/</link>
    <description>Recent content in students on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/students/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How To Best Use Your Teacher</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-best-use-your-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-best-use-your-teacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1400&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;286&#34; caption=&#34;velvettangerine on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/velvettangerine/3922005142/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1400&#34; title=&#34;teacher&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/teacher-286x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;286&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re trying to learn something or achieve a skill, a teacher can be a big help, since they have already done what you want to do. But there are some pitfalls to having a teacher, especially if you try to put all the responsibility for your progress on their shoulders. The best way to use a teacher is as a resource for your own learning, not as the basis or sole motivation for your goals.&lt;em&gt; (if you&#39;re short on time, you can skip to the end of the article for a summary, a policy I&#39;ll be using more regularly)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a trainer, I work with a lot of people who want to get in great shape, but don&#39;t really want to put in the effort. Sure, they do the exercises I recommend when they show up, and they push themselves pretty hard. But then I won&#39;t see them for weeks. They have lessons maybe once a month, very intermittently, and as a result, they don&#39;t move towards their goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have trainees who see me about that often, but who do make progress. The difference is in the way they view our relationship. To the first group, I am responsible for their fitness progress. &lt;strong&gt;To the second group, I am merely a resource for them as they make their own journey towards fitness&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
