<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>control on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/control/</link>
    <description>Recent content in control on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/control/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Myth of Control in (Paleo) Health</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-myth-of-control-in-paleo-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-myth-of-control-in-paleo-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“The closest to being in control we will ever be is in that moment that we realize we&#39;re not.” - Brian Kessler&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/?attachment_id=2611&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2611&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-2611&#34; alt=&#34;LettingGo&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/LettingGo.jpg&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Last year, my&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/in-memory-of-auntie-phyllis/&#34;&gt; Aunt Phyllis&lt;/a&gt; succumbed to leukemia. I have often wondered if a change in diet could have improved her quality of life, given her more time, or even reversed the disease, based on anecdotes from  the Paleo community. Uncertainty kept me silent. Would it have made things better, or just given her more to worry about? Would I be trivializing her disease or the advice of her doctors? Would it mean I was &lt;i&gt;blaming&lt;/i&gt; her for the leukemia or its progression, by attributing the disease to lifestyle choices? Would it have made her feel ashamed that she had cancer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many, the suggestion that we can directly impact our health, even influencing such big-name diseases as cancer, diabetes, alzhiemer’s, and MS, is unwelcome. &lt;b&gt;It implies that our suffering is our fault, and can lead to a sense of guilt or shame.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if health is a critical factor in our ability to positively impact the world, it is not the final determinant of a person’s worth. Better to judge a person by what they have contributed to the lives of others and how they have made the world a better place. This may seem obvious, but in practice, many of us forget it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, someone else close to me has been diagnosed with a potentially life-threatening condition. Given my knowledge and experience, I&#39;m not sure how to help, or even if I should help at all. How we live if up to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
