<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>excellence on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/excellence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in excellence on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/excellence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Warrior Spirit Evolves</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/warrior-spirit-evolves/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/warrior-spirit-evolves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay...I&#39;ve really got it this time. Seriously. &lt;strong&gt;I now know what this blog is about&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, I&#39;ve said that a lot before, but this time it&#39;s real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check it out. See that snazzy new subtitle. This blog isn&#39;t about me anymore (well, I guess it will always kind of be about me). It&#39;s about &lt;em&gt;Us&lt;/em&gt;, trying to make ourselves the best we can be, so that we can be the most awesome, helpful, revolutionary, world-changing people we can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Shouldn&#39;t Always Do Your Best</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-you-shouldnt-always-do-your-best/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-you-shouldnt-always-do-your-best/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1342&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Alex E. Proimos&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/proimos/4199675334/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1342&#34; title=&#34;Head in Hands&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/failure-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only the mediocre are always at their best - Jean Giradoux&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My gymnastics coach recently revealed to me that Olympic gymnasts are only able to perform their routines at the time they compete. Most of the time, they use spotters, and they periodize their training so that they peak when they compete. Many of them can&#39;t even perform some of their hardest skills on an everyday basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this isn&#39;t especially unique in the world of elite athletes, it does reveal an interesting aspect of excellence: &lt;strong&gt;when you are performing at such a high level, you cannot always be at your best&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Warrior Spirit?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/what-is-warrior-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/what-is-warrior-spirit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1215&#34; title=&#34;Warrior Spirit&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/TShirtBack-300x240.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The warrior stands defiant, spear in hand, looking over a vast plain. Below him is a world full of challenge and adversity, dangerous enemies and tempting shortcuts. Beyond is a great mountain range, full of promise certainly, but hiding even greater challenges. On the other side...who knows? Hope, transcendence, enlightenment. Or perhaps darker, more sinister rewards hide behind those peaks. All the Warrior knows is that he has decided to scale them, carve a path through the plains and over the mountains, leading the way for others who seek a better life on the other side, guiding them and defending the tribe from the dangers ahead. He knows he may not survive, but he has prepared well and is among the greatest, most capable leaders of his tribe. He is confident and eager to begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrity: There is more to Life than Winning...There&#39;s being Awesome!</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-there-is-more-to-life-than-winning-theres-being-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-there-is-more-to-life-than-winning-theres-being-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/handstand.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-493&#34; title=&#34;handstand&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/handstand.jpg?w=199&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Since the CrossFit sectionals I&#39;ve been feeling considerably less motivated about my training. You&#39;d think that making it to regionals would give me a message that I have some potential, and that I should work hard to realize it. Instead, I feel oppressed by the prospect of competing again. All my training is geared towards this one event, an event that has a very narrow definition of success (even by the standards of CrossFit), and in which I will undoubtedly be one of the smallest, puniest, guys there. Maybe I&#39;m over-dramatizing here, but I definitely feel like an underdog - I&#39;m young, relatively weak (most guys at these things can deadlift 400+ lbs, I&#39;m around 315lb on a good day), and pretty inexperienced. If it&#39;s all about who can move the most weight, I&#39;m screwed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
