<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rurouni kenshin on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/rurouni-kenshin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rurouni kenshin on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/rurouni-kenshin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Smiling Swordsman</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-smiling-swordsman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-smiling-swordsman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/rurouni-kenshin-anime-184474-e1371668311238.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3029&#34; alt=&#34;rurouni-kenshin-anime-184474&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/rurouni-kenshin-anime-184474-e1371668311238.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We once fought together for an ideal with our swords. It wasn&#39;t for power or for glory, but to create a peaceful world where people could live without fear. And, if you should forget about that, then what did we fight the revolution for? &lt;em&gt;- Himura Kenshin, &lt;/em&gt;Rurouni Kenshin Anime Series&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My girlfriend recently introduced me to an anime series called Rurouni Kenshin, about a young man name Himura Kenshin who was an assassin during the Meiji Restoration, a massive revolution in 19th century Japan. The Meiji Restoration&#39;s greatest effect was the transference of political power from the militaristic, samurai-controlled Tokagawa Shogunate, which had ruled for 200 years, back to the emperor and his ministers. It also marked the start of modernization, both technologically and socially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(I want to take a moment to express how lucky and grateful I am to have a girlfriend who insists I watch anime series).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenshin was renown as the greatest assassin during the revolution, but the show is actually about him trying to renounce his bloody past and help Japan solidify its new peace. In one episode, his friend points out that Kenshin, of all people, feels the most anger towards the new government because he fought so hard to bring it into existence, only to find it just as exploitative and full of corruption. However, unlike many other characters in the series, Kenshin doesn&#39;t see this as justification for continued strife and fighting. Even with the corruption of the new government, he would rather do what he can to ease the lives of everyday people than support another bloody revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He is able to look past his personal feelings and the short-sighted agendas of those he deals with to see the effects on the people of Japan. There is sometimes an air of resignation about him--he must accept the lesser of two evils to preserve peace--but he also carries a lot of hope and faith in the innate goodness of humanity.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenshin&#39;s character is very interesting for a number of reasons, but the thing that inspires me the most is how he &lt;strong&gt;tries to enjoy the little moments of every day&lt;/strong&gt;. He is usually seen smiling, playing with children, making silly jokes, and generally enjoying life. When a villain shows up with the intention of taking advantage of the weak or causing mayhem, Kenshin puts them in their place very quickly, but for the most part, he tries to appreciate his new life and friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenshin epitomizes the Warrior Spirit, combining a deep and ruthless concern for the well-being of others with a determination to experience life as joyful.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the series, there are many characters who respond to the results of revolution much differently, stubbornly fixating on something that upsets them. They may have good intentions, but more often than not, they end up as villains. &lt;strong&gt;Their anger and frustration drive them to acts of violence that hurt others or threaten a return to a state of war.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;We Create a World to be Bitter In&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sometimes worry about crossing that line. I see a lot to be upset about in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
