<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>empowerment on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/empowerment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in empowerment on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/empowerment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Empower Yourself Through Humility</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/empower-yourself-through-humility/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/empower-yourself-through-humility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/16112_700950337914_589075632_n-e1360535516995.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2802&#34; alt=&#34;Bowing Before the Buddha&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/16112_700950337914_589075632_n-e1360535516995.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;545&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humility reminds us that we are human. It reminds us not to overestimate our abilities, not to get sloppy and lazy, to always be present and give our best effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humility reminds us that the big tasks, the ones that matter, really are difficult, even for such amazing warriors as ourselves. &lt;strong&gt;Remembering this, we will remain focused, taking the task seriously and bringing to it the attention it deserves.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humility says, &#34;I could mess this up, so I will make sure I don&#39;t.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only the fool forgoes humility for hubris. If he is talented, he will get far, but eventually, the task at hand will be bigger than he can handle casually. Eventually, it will require an acceptance of the need for help, either from other people or deeper wells of energy and focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&#39;ve adopted the habit of bowing upon waking and just before bed. Bowing is an interesting form of devotion because it is an expression of humility. You are honoring whatever you bow to by being humble before it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, that suggests an acknowledgement of how much we rely on certain things and how important mindfulness is. I recite certain gratitudes when I bow. For example, I give thanks for the opportunity to rest and recover at night, and then I bow. This expresses the acknowledgement that I don&#39;t necessarily have the right to peaceful rest -- many people don&#39;t get it. I am thankful for it, but also humbled by it, since I depend on it to function.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
