<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>acceptance on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/acceptance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in acceptance on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/acceptance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>6 Ways Accepting Your Weaknesses Can Empower You</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/6-ways-accepting-your-weaknesses-can-empower-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/6-ways-accepting-your-weaknesses-can-empower-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/weakness.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3173&#34; alt=&#34;weakness&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/weakness-300x153.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;153&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;One of the quirks of having subjective conscious experience (aka, self-awareness) is that we have a very different perspective on ourselves than we do on other people. For example, &lt;a title=&#34;Attribution Bias&#34; href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attribution_bias&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;attribution bias&lt;/a&gt; tells us that we tend to assume other peoples&#39; actions are the result of their character more than their circumstances, while we openly acknowledge that we are affected by circumstances when it suits us. For example, if we see someone else lie to avoid a fine, we would tend to judge them as generally dishonest. If we do the same thing, we would cite our tight finances and tell ourselves that normally we&#39;re honest, law-abiding citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;However, this can create some interesting conflicts as well. We may assume we&#39;re stronger or more reliable than we really are, or that we will be happy in a situation that won&#39;t really make us happy. Maybe the idea of living in New York excites you, but you know that you hate cars and crowds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basically, we don’t like to admit that we are as flawed as other people, but if we are to be honest about who we are, if we are to live with integrity, we have to have an accurate view of ourselves, flaws and all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Struggling and Suddenly Everything Clicks</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/stop-struggling-and-suddenly-everything-clicks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/stop-struggling-and-suddenly-everything-clicks/</guid>
      <description>A strange thing happened recently. My life went from being hectic, disorganized, and frustrating to suddenly clear and productive. This happened without any warning, and without any real discernible change in my circumstances. In the same way that you feel a lot lighter and calmer when you realize you&#39;ve been restricting your breathing and start taking deep breaths, something in my mindset that was cramped and tight simply relaxed.
This has had a number of interesting effects:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
