<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>obstacles on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/obstacles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in obstacles on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/obstacles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When Life Gets in the Way, What do You Do?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/when-life-gets-in-the-way-what-do-you-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/when-life-gets-in-the-way-what-do-you-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/bigrock.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3150&#34; alt=&#34;bigrock&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/bigrock-300x225.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Om Gam Ganapataye Namaha -Mantra to Ganesh, Remover of Obstacles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s the day before, and you&#39;ve committed to turning over a new leaf. Exercise, productivity, healthy eating, and overflowing compassion, starting tomorrow morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But to fit it in, you&#39;ll need to get up a bit earlier than usual. No problem, as going to bed early is part of your plan too. Off to bed at 9pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then your neighbor&#39;s dog gets loose in the middle of the night and her barking keeps you up for an hour. You wake up groggy when your alarm goes off at 6am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life Gets in the Way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, fueled by the passion of the untried, you make it out for your morning run. It&#39;s rough getting started, but once you hit your stride, your pace blows off the early morning cobwebs, and you return home invigorated and encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At work, you dive right in to your to-do&#39;s, rather than checking your e-mail, chatting with your coworkers, and adjusting your seat as usual. By 11am, you&#39;re on track to finish your required work so that you can work on that special project of your own that will get you ahead in the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, Mr. Garfield comes by with a request that you attend an &#34;emergency meeting&#34; right after lunch. Checking your schedule, you figure you can handle the slight delay and still stay on track if you eat at your desk. But, while you&#39;re doing that, Sarah comes by and says that she&#39;s going out of town tomorrow so she&#39;d like to discuss that important project with you over lunch. There goes your lunch break.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
