<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>travel on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in travel on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Back from Kyoto, and Pictures</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/back-from-kyoto-and-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/back-from-kyoto-and-pictures/</guid>
      <description>A and I are back from Kyoto after a day full of travel, so today&#39;s post will be going up tomorrow. To tide you over until then, here are some of A&#39;s gorgeous pictures. Enjoy!
[gallery link=&#34;file&#34;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cost of Living</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-cost-of-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-cost-of-living/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2134&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/DSC_6310.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-2134&#34; title=&#34;Small Hostel&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/DSC_6310-200x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The cramped but lovely hostel we stayed at in Kyoto[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a short post, because I&#39;m in Kyoto and don&#39;t want to be spending too much time on my computer, but something I&#39;ve experienced in Japan has got me to thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything here is very small&lt;/strong&gt;: the houses, the cars, the trains, the towels. There is a mentality that we should not use more than we need. That applies to space, food, money and resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Japan is not a developing country. It is fairly affluent. It &lt;em&gt;is &lt;/em&gt;expensive to live here, but that hasn&#39;t always been the case, and many of the small buildings are much older than Japan&#39;s current situation. It wouldn&#39;t be beyond the Japanese to have SUVs lining the streets, towering apartment complexes with massive floorplans, and showers with hot water that didn&#39;t need to be prepared ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I know Japan has a lot of problems, and the Japanese do some pretty atrocious things (like massacre dolphins), but I&#39;m going to go out on a limb and suggest that you can have respect for resources without unreasonable hatred of cetaceans. The two are not necessarily linked to each other.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, I&#39;m comparing Japan to America, where everyone aspires to a half-acre lot with a 40,000 sq. ft. pre-fab house sitting atop a hill, with an SUV or two in the driveway. &lt;strong&gt;Towels are big, meals are big, and everything is cheap, so it doesn&#39;t matter if you waste it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nothing is cheap here in Japan, and that is a strong reminder to use things wisely and only buy what you need&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nine Days in Portugal for $1525</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/nine-days-in-portugal-for-1525/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/nine-days-in-portugal-for-1525/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/porto.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1662&#34; title=&#34;porto&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/porto-300x200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;My girlfriend and I just returned from a nine day trip to  Portugal, in which we stayed at the Sheraton Lisboa, a number of  hostels, toured Lisbon and Porto for two days each, and spent two days  at the fishing village of Peniche. We ate really, really well (a little  too well actually), usually at restaurants with a few home-cooked meals.  We took trams and buses and trains all over the place, and spent a day  exploring an island off the coast. We also spent a day in Barcelona,  Spain, on our way to Portugal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And we did is all for $1525 per person&lt;/strong&gt;. Considering  how poorly we managed our money, I think that is a pretty good deal,  and it includes all incidentals. The cost of airfare getting to Portugal  and back was only $725 per person, and accommodation was less than $200  per person for the whole trip. If you cooked more of your own meals at  hostels, or weren’t so ditzy about navigating public transportation,  your incidentals would have been lower than ours (about $600).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering that I am only occasionally employed, it seems that if we can make this happen, anyone should be able to do it too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this seems ridiculously affordable, I thought I’d share how we did it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Should Blow it All to Travel</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-you-should-blow-it-all-to-travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-you-should-blow-it-all-to-travel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_743&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: DragonWoman on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/dragonwoman/31029572/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-743 &#34; title=&#34;china&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/china.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We know that travel is essential to a complete education. Traveling abroad teaches understanding of other people, cultures and communities, and these types of experiences offer young people a greater ability to be successful in today&#39;s global society. &lt;em&gt;- Michael Palmer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An old friend from my days interning at Forbes gave me some interesting advice today. As a well-established manager, she would have been able to make a very good argument for starting to seriously look at a career, putting down professional roots, building up my financial profile and really setting myself up for the long, steady path to independence and security. Instead, she pretty much recommended I risk it all and travel, try to work in some other countries, because, after all at my age and in this economic climate, there isn&#39;t much to lose. &lt;strong&gt;Take the big risks while you&#39;re young&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midwest Trip Wrap-Up</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/midwest-trip-wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/midwest-trip-wrap-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_622&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Graffiti Graveyard, Duluth, MN&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/06/100_0535.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-622&#34; title=&#34;100_0535&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/100_0535.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apologies for the delay. Upon arriving home I discovered my home in the midst of packing to move and have thus been distracted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Logistics from Hell&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon leaving Wisconsin, I made my way, via bus, to the Twin Cities of Minneapolis-St. Paul. Even though I&#39;m not from the state, whenever anyone refers to &#39;the cities&#39; it is this metropolis I immediately think of, even when I&#39;m elsewhere. The bus ride was uneventful, except for the fact that I missed my first bus and then had to negotiate my way on to the next bus out. 5-minutes of lateness cost me $80 in new bus far and a taxi ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More logistical problems at the MSP airport prevented me from renting a car from my originally planned company. I thought I&#39;d be stuck completely but they recommended me to another company, which actually ended up costing me less. So it worked out in the end, I made it out of the cities and got on the long, beautiful, pine-wrapped highway of Minnesota, en route to the Northwoods and the lake country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson&lt;/strong&gt;: This was exactly the fear that had kept me from travelling in the first place. I dealt with it and got to the places I wanted to go. So I learned that I am smart enough and resourceful enough to manage if things go astray. Still, the reliance on my own cash was a little unsettling. What if I ran out of money? I have long ago stopped carrying Daddy&#39;s Credit Card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Memory Lane on I-35&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drive up to camp was relaxing. I&#39;d been on the road all day anyway, but it was nice to drive my own (rented) car. I got up to camp around 11:30, feeling completely at home like always. I managed to find some people who knew me sharing a fire in the sailing house and sat with them for an hour, hanging out like we&#39;d been seeing each other all year. There was very little catch up talk and a lot of comfortable silence and random tangents. I slept in a cabin, all alone, which I should know by now is a bad idea. No matter how old I get, the intermediate cabins freak me out with all the windows open and their big, empty wooden rooms. I spent many a summer night as a kid bawling my eyes out in terror in those cabins, and old memories like that never really fade completely. While not afraid per se, I was unconsciously tense all night and didn&#39;t actually manage to fall asleep until the sun came up, lulled by the haunting call of the loon and the wind in the pines.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
