<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>whining on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/whining/</link>
    <description>Recent content in whining on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/whining/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quit Your Whining</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/quit-your-whining/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/quit-your-whining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1951&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; caption=&#34;kaibara87 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kaibara/3496249511/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1951&#34; title=&#34;Whiny Cat&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3496249511_2d194b807f.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your intention everyday just to survive? Is your intention everyday just to make it through the world, because your interpretation is &#39;the world is so hard, so stressful, so chaotic, I hope I can just get through this day&#39;? Because if that&#39;s where you&#39;re at, that identity for you is small. - Brendon Burchard&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to whine...a lot. Practically every word out of my mouth was a complaint of some kind. I was either talking about my frustration over my homework load, kvetching over the constant barrage of e-mails, or just going on about random aches and pains and fatigue. The only information I had to share with anyone was about how something was bothering me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hardly conscious of my behavior; whining just seemed to be the natural thing to say, and after all, it seemed to me that most conversations were based around complaining. People would get together after work to basically whine about the difficult week. Guys would bond over complaining about their girlfriends, and women would commiserate over the poor quality of men in their lives. Most of the student conversations I heard were about academic frustration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I was not pleasant to be around, and my family made this very clear to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t want to be that guy nobody invites to parties (I was already that guy, and knew it wasn&#39;t fun). I didn&#39;t want to be the guy nobody could rely on who couldn&#39;t handle his own life. So I resolved to change what I thought was a seemingly simple habit of conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no idea how deep it went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rule I instituted was: if what I am about to say is something negative and simply expresses how I feel bad about something, with no suggestion of actually fixing the problem, I will keep my mouth shut.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With only moderate self-control, I did very well at this. It was merely a matter of keeping my lips sealed. Sometimes I found I had nothing to contribute to conversations, but at least I wasn&#39;t bringing people down anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I made a horrifying discovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quit Your Belly Achin&#39;</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/quit-your-belly-achin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/quit-your-belly-achin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1573&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;mdanys on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mindaugasdanys/3766009204/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1573&#34; title=&#34;Angry Child&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3766009204_8721a00dde-300x252.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;252&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;There are a thousand reasons for failure, but not a single excuse.&#34; - a cool t-shirt&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you make a mistake even worse? You whine and complain about it and make lots of excuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little while ago, I performed a CrossFit workout in which I wasn&#39;t too happy with my performance. It was a surprisingly difficult one, involving a lot of burpees, followed by a lot of overhead squats, followed by muscle ups. I&#39;m very good at the first and the last movement, and apparently not so hot at the second. But I was so keen on getting to my strength - the muscle ups - that when I finally did, I lost all my focus and went crazy. The result was that I got just a single muscle up in two minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the buzzer went off, I let out an angry yell, uttering a curse I never use in my daily life. It just sort of slipped out, and I was immediately ashamed of myself. Not because I had cursed - lots of people do that - but that I had gotten so angry that I did something so out of character.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
