<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>teaching on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in teaching on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why My Favorite Students are the Most Difficult</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-my-favorite-students-are-the-most-difficult/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-my-favorite-students-are-the-most-difficult/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/brickwall.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1875&#34; title=&#34;brickwall&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/brickwall-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“When we long for life without difficulties, remind us that oaks grow strong in contrary winds and diamonds are made under pressure” - Peter Marshall&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an English teacher, I deal with kids of all ability levels. There are the star students who do all the homework, even the assignments you don’t really expect anyone to do, answer all the questions perfectly, and are polite, engaged and generally perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there are the students who fall asleep in class, which is a good day because when they are awake they are disruptive, harassing other students, yelling for no apparent reason, and making the classroom a living hell. Trying to teach them is like talking to a brick wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guess which students I appreciate more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bad ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not at first. The first few weeks working as a teacher, I loathed dealing with them. I wanted to just ignore their failing grades and total lack of understanding, but the little voice in my head said that, as the teacher, I should go over and help, even if it wouldn’t make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it did make a difference. In fact, it made a big difference. The kids improved (slightly) but their attitudes improved a lot. They tried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More importantly, I improved as a teacher&lt;/strong&gt;. I started to get a sense of what worked and what didn’t. If I could learn to motivate the worst students, I would be that much better at motivating everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And honestly, I could teach the best students with my eyes closed (actually, they can teach themselves). Unfortunately, as teachers it is so tempting to give all our attention to the good students, since they clearly appreciate and value us. But now, with my new perspective on the frustrating kids, I actually enjoy working with them. When I bring that kind of energy to the interaction, it makes it more pleasant for everyone, and then they start to make an effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Appreciation</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/teacher-appreciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/teacher-appreciation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1247&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Abhijit Tembhekar on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/abhijittembhekar/3345977842/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1247&#34; title=&#34;apple&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/apple-300x201.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wax on, wax off. - Mr. Miyagi, the Karate Kid (1984)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warriors are always seeking to grow and learn new things, so it makes sense that we&#39;d have a lot of teachers in our life. As the year comes to a close and I contemplate my card list, I&#39;m realizing that most of the people on it are my teachers and mentors. In the past two years, I&#39;ve acquired an unusually large number of teachers, of exceptionally good quality, and I realize that all the growth and knowledge I&#39;ve acquired is largely thanks to their efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love Working with Kids</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-i-love-working-with-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-i-love-working-with-kids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1001&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;are you my rik? on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/areyoumyrik/308908809/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1001&#34; title=&#34;kids&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/kids-300x228.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;228&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I really need to know about how to live and what to do and how to be I learned in kindergarten. Wisdom was not at the top of the graduate school mountain, but there in the sand pile at school. &lt;em&gt;- Robert Fulghum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children give you a lot of perspective on life. They are impossible to keep in order, except when you do seemingly trivial and silly things. They seem very rude and uncouth most of the time, but the best way to get them to do what you want is simply to ask nicely. They remind you what&#39;s important in life, and the importance of friends, food, and enough rest. They also teach you how to appreciate the little things in life, like the wonder of floating on a surfboard in the sun (something I find endlessly tedious) and how stupid things can be really, legitimately funny.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
