<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>play on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/play/</link>
    <description>Recent content in play on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/play/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fight: Learn Confidence through Combative Play</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/fight-learn-confidence-through-combative-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/fight-learn-confidence-through-combative-play/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I’ve been experimenting with a new approach to fitness and movement, inspired by a teacher I greatly respect: &lt;a title=&#34;Evolve Move Play&#34; href=&#34;http://www.evolvemoveplay.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rafe Kelley of &lt;em&gt;Evolve Move Play&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;His philosophy is that humans evolved movement rehearsal (aka, play) to learn and refine the skills we needed to survive. Some of these were simply moving about the environment, but for men especially, the ultimate goal was hunting or fighting other humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Removing this context from training robs it of some of its most valuable aspects. Competition encourages growth, whether that is with a training partner or an opponent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 1.17em; line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;Respecting Your Opponent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;As a kid, I was unstoppable in contests where there were no losers: straight A&#39;s and every academic award I qualified for. But on a sports field, I preferred playing defense to scoring goals. My contribution to winning was keeping my side from losing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;When I started &lt;a title=&#34;Returning to the Dojo: The Importance of Martial Arts&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;martial arts&lt;/a&gt;, it was exciting but also uncomfortable because I had to become more assertive. After getting beaten a few times, I learned to &lt;a title=&#34;Learn to Stand Alone&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/learn-to-stand-alone/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;stand my ground&lt;/a&gt;. I didn&#39;t get violent, but I stopped inviting others to walk all over me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Play is the perfect place to teach people how to safely assert themselves without hurting others, both physically and emotionally, so that when it becomes important in life, they don’t go overboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spreading the Natural Movement Gospel</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/spreading-the-natural-movement-gospel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/spreading-the-natural-movement-gospel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2744&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/307846_683428511794_1406122075_n1-e1358867196564.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2744&#34; alt=&#34;Monkeybars in Japan are 3D&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/307846_683428511794_1406122075_n1-e1358867196564.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;335&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Monkeybars in Japan are 3D[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is shared with my &lt;a title=&#34;Warrior Spirit Movement&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/move&#34;&gt;movement training website&lt;/a&gt;. Head over there if you&#39;re curious about learning to move with power and grace.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I &lt;a title=&#34;I’m Moving to Boulder&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/im-moving-to-boulder/&#34;&gt;live in Boulder&lt;/a&gt;, I have the great opportunity to &lt;a title=&#34;The Communion of Play; A Day of Natural Movement on the River&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-communion-of-play-a-day-of-natural-movement-on-the-river/&#34;&gt;share my love of natural, playful, useful movement&lt;/a&gt; with the great community of the University of Colorado at Boulder. With its thriving athletics community and the fact that it is the heart of &lt;a title=&#34;The Greenwashing of Exercise&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-greenwashing-of-exercise/&#34;&gt;outdoor- and wellness-obsessed&lt;/a&gt; Boulder, CU is the perfect place to introduce young athletes to the concept that exercise doesn&#39;t have to be a chore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first, I have to prove my skills to the head of the fitness department, and while&lt;strong&gt; I do this stuff because I want to &lt;a title=&#34;Move and Be Free&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/move-and-be-free/&#34;&gt;flow like a wild animal ninja through the woods&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; I knew I&#39;d have to tone it down a bit to avoid alienating her. On Tuesday, I had my interview. Here is how it went:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived early to make sure I had time to orient myself to the facilities. The head of the department had structured the interview as a &#39;Snapshot&#39; training session; I would be training one of CU&#39;s established trainers, who would be acting as a naive client. We met outside the locker room, I got changed, and we headed up to the massive weight and cardio room that serves the CU student population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I walked by rows and rows of weight machines and treadmills, I began to doubt myself. It was clear that the status quo was well-entrenched here. I didn&#39;t want to estrange my &#39;client&#39;, who, as a trainer herself, would probably have some very strong opinions about what was legitimate and what was &lt;a title=&#34;Are You as Fit as Your Dog? 5 Ways to Play Fetch&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/are-you-as-fit-as-your-dog-5-ways-to-play-fetch/&#34;&gt;ridiculous&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had two choices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;Follow the program I had drafted, which was a standard weight loss/strength/&#39;firming up&#39; sequence, with some MovNat thrown into the warmup, OR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;Really emphasize the natural movement and blow her mind, hoping that she would get it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose the latter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Greenwashing of Exercise</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-greenwashing-of-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-greenwashing-of-exercise/</guid>
      <description>This post is cross-published on my coaching blog, Warrior Spirit Movement.
Most mornings, I head out into the mountains, not to hike, but to ramble. I go where my heart leads me, over rocks, up trees, through fields. And when I am on the trail, I move over it in my own way, hopping from rock to rock or crawling along past wary hikers and excited dogs. Moving in these ways has me sprinting, swinging, scrambling, leaping, reaching, and everything but “Hiking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Moving Well Can Make You Confident and Popular</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/two-reasons-play-is-a-big-deal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/two-reasons-play-is-a-big-deal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2744&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;]&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2744&#34; alt=&#34;Monkeybars in Japan are 3D&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/307846_683428511794_1406122075_n1-e1358867196564.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;335&#34; /&gt; Monkeybars in Japan are 3D[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I was doing some research for an article I&#39;m writing on play as exercise, and I needed a photograph of a playground. Of course, that meant I had to test out the playground, which got me thinking on &lt;a title=&#34;Fitness is Play&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/fitness-is-play/&#34;&gt;how central the playground was in my daily life when I was a kid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Movement as a Rite of Passage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The American School of Dubai, where I went to elementary school, had a pretty awesome playground. The front consisted of three corridors of hanging traverse: there was a line of monkey bars flanked on both sides by lines of hanging rings. The rings on the left were short and closely spaced, while those on the right had much larger spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember &lt;a title=&#34;Your Mountain is Waiting. Do You Dare Conquer it?&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/your-mountain-is-waiting-do-you-dare-conquer-it/&#34;&gt;aspiring&lt;/a&gt; to complete the full set on the right side, like all the big kids. Every day, before school, at recess, and after school, I would practice swinging from the rings. Some days I would just do the short rings, to build confidence, but I usually gave the long rings a shot. I would patiently wait my turn in line with the big kids, enduring sneers and ridicule (I don&#39;t honestly remember), until I came to the front of the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart would catch. After waiting in line for agonizing minutes, would I now waste all of that by falling to the sand in &lt;a title=&#34;But What if You Fail?&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/but-what-if-you-fail/&#34;&gt;failure&lt;/a&gt; after one measly swing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You as Fit as Your Dog? 5 Ways to Play Fetch</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/are-you-as-fit-as-your-dog-5-ways-to-play-fetch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/are-you-as-fit-as-your-dog-5-ways-to-play-fetch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/?attachment_id=2707&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2707&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2707&#34; alt=&#34;Hard at Play&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3244259451_0120de8a9d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We&#39;ve had a series of intense posts lately, and there are more in the schedule (see below for more on that...and a funny video of me falling in the mud), so here&#39;s a much more lighthearted one.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m a strong advocate of spontaneous, playful movement as the best way to get exercise. That&#39;s why I love &lt;a title=&#34;Freeing the Zoo Humans: Why I Want to Become a MovNat Instructor&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/movnat-instructor/&#34;&gt;MovNat&#39;s philosophy&lt;/a&gt;. I feel that play is more engaging, gets your mind off the strain of exercising (so you&#39;ll do more), and &lt;a title=&#34;The Communion of Play; A Day of Natural Movement on the River&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-communion-of-play-a-day-of-natural-movement-on-the-river/&#34;&gt;can be shared as social activity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I&#39;ve been undergoing a self-imposed training program for my &lt;a title=&#34;How to Make a Dream Come True&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/how-to-make-a-dream-come-true/&#34;&gt;MovNat Trainer Certification&lt;/a&gt;, which has been lonely in the cold winter of New England. This past weekend, I finally got my girlfriend (who will now be referred to as Rocketpack instead of the mysterious, A) to come out with me. Seizing on this opportunity for social play, I came up with a game to make my sprint-esque workout more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We played a timeless classic, enjoyed not just by humans, but by our furry friends as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yup, we played fetch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Communion of Play; A Day of Natural Movement on the River</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-communion-of-play-a-day-of-natural-movement-on-the-river/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-communion-of-play-a-day-of-natural-movement-on-the-river/</guid>
      <description>Last month, I spent a day enjoying a river park that runs past my home in Korea. While the exercise itself was freeing, what really struck me was how simply being playful and exercising like this seemed to connect with other people, even those I couldn&#39;t communicate with. The natural, playful movement intrigued people, brought them joy, even inspired some of them to try it themselves. It was as if seeing an &#39;adult&#39; playing let them believe it was okay for them to engage with their own bodies in ways they normally left to their kids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitness is Play</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/fitness-is-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/fitness-is-play/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/6885273501_9df2a14fb4.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2176&#34; title=&#34;On the Swings&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/6885273501_9df2a14fb4-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In our modern world, all fitness regimens are accessory and optional.  It is up to each and every individual to decide if they want to exercise or not, and how.  Even walking has already become an option.  But like it or not, &lt;strong&gt;moving naturally still is, and always will be a biological necessity&lt;/strong&gt;. - Erwan Le Corre&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do kids do to play?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They move&lt;/strong&gt;. They climb, scramble, swing, slide, crawl, roll, and jump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Movement is FUN, plain and simple&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are sports enjoyable? Because they involve movement. &lt;strong&gt;For whatever reason, humans (all animals actually) seem to &lt;a title=&#34;Move and Be Free&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/move-and-be-free/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;enjoy movement&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
