<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>employment on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/employment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in employment on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/employment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned About Landing a Job in Boulder</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-learned-about-landing-a-job-in-boulder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-learned-about-landing-a-job-in-boulder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2868&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;332&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/4273787940_2c1c65f67a.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2868&#34; alt=&#34;A job to let me land safely...can you tell I had trouble with the image for this post?&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/4273787940_2c1c65f67a.jpg&#34; width=&#34;332&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A job to let me land safely...can you tell I had trouble with the image for this post?[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m happy to announce that I have finally landed a job in Boulder, which means that I can stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you know, &lt;a title=&#34;Live What You Preach: Maintaining Faith in my Move to Boulder&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/live-what-you-preach-maintaining-faith-in-my-move-to-boulder/&#34;&gt;keeping upbeat&lt;/a&gt; in the face of difficult prospects has been hard. Especially going into March, which would have been the limit of my savings, I was worried I was going to hit a wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luckily, just as I reached the end of my financial rope, a job came through&lt;/strong&gt;. Funny how that works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, now I have the issue of having too many things to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the usual workaday job at the grocery store, I was also given my first tutoring assignment, and landed my first paid freelance magazine article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Freeing the Zoo Humans: Why I Want to Become a MovNat Instructor&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/movnat-instructor/&#34;&gt;Coaching MovNat&lt;/a&gt; is still my preferred form of employment, but that hasn&#39;t resulted in any paying arrangements. However, I&#39;m still giving it as much attention as I can spare, going around to gyms and studios offering to run workshops and introduce myself to as wide an audience as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My guess is that I will use the consistent job to get established while developing more lucrative opportunities that allow me to work on my own time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This period of my life is certainly one of the most challenging and uncomfortable, but I can tell it is also fostering a lot of growth. It&#39;s the kind of uncomfortable experience that you know is good for you, even if you&#39;d rather not have to go through it. Sort of like exercise (which I guess I&#39;m fairly good at).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few short lessons I&#39;ve learned:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guilt by Association; Chained to the Wrong Job</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/guilt-by-association-chained-to-the-wrong-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/guilt-by-association-chained-to-the-wrong-job/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#34;There Is A Voice Inside Of You&lt;br /&gt;
That Whispers All Day Long,&lt;br /&gt;
&#34;I Feel That This Is Right For Me,&lt;br /&gt;
I Know That This Is Wrong.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;
No Teacher, Preacher, Parent, Friend&lt;br /&gt;
Or Wise Man Can Decide&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s Right For You- Just Listen To&lt;br /&gt;
The Voice That Speaks Inside.&#34; - Shel Silverstein&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/7550109580_08554ef572.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2454&#34; title=&#34;Chained to your job&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/7550109580_08554ef572-247x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;247&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, my employer did something that got me really angry. I&#39;m not going to go into details, because even though she doesn&#39;t read English and I wouldn&#39;t mind that much if I got fired at this point, it would still be kind of underhanded to do it publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;However, today&#39;s events did teach me a very important lesson about integrity: When I work for someone, a group, or a company, I need to make sure their values are in line with my own, otherwise I risk putting my efforts and energy into causes that I either don&#39;t care about, or that I am totally opposed to.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you work for an organization, your efforts are directed towards achieving that organization&#39;s ends. Sometimes, this is great. With the multiplier effect of a dedicated community, your small contribution can have much larger effects than it otherwise would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if you don&#39;t agree with what your organization is doing, then your energy is applied to something you would otherwise oppose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is why &lt;a title=&#34;The 3 Things You Need for a Complete Life (my mother agrees)&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/3-things-complete-life/&#34;&gt;Awareness &lt;/a&gt;is extremely important in ensuring that you live the life you want. If you don&#39;t pay attention to the implications of your actions, then you end up being taken for a ride.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
