<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>movnat on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/movnat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in movnat on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/movnat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Judge the Newbs</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dont-judge-the-newbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dont-judge-the-newbs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/5770042200_bc1b1f00c3.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3160&#34; alt=&#34;5770042200_bc1b1f00c3&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5770042200_bc1b1f00c3-300x160.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;It saddens me when I see people who have accomplished something judging others who are trying to do the same thing. I see this a lot among trainers, particularly those in unorthodox fitness methods like CrossFit and MovNat. We like to remind other people what they are doing wrong, how they are ignorant, unskilled, or lazy, too focused on strength/flexibility/skill and neglecting our pet trait, how they are clearly too wimpy to do &#39;real&#39; exercise, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is only natural. We&#39;ve put a lot of effort into unlocking the secretes of superpowers, so we want to enjoy the status that gives us. I did it all the time, until I remembered how incompetent I was when I started. &lt;/strong&gt;But it doesn&#39;t actually help anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;For example, I was working out with some friends the other day while another gym-goer was loudly, clumsily, doing his own workout. My buddies noticed and snickered, whispering among themselves how what he was doing was both dangerous and inappropriate for his apparent level of fitness.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wasn&#39;t the first time this particular group of friends had indulged in this kind of behavior, so I spoke up. &lt;strong&gt;First, I reminded them that the fact that he was out there at all, clearly pushing his limits and trying something new and challenging, was a good thing. Second, every single one of us in that group had gone through a similar phase when we did things that we realized were stupid in retrospect&lt;/strong&gt;. I tried a lot of weird things, some stupid and some legitimate but misplaced in my training:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Unexpected Benefits of Natural Movement</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/3-unexpected-benefits-of-natural-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/3-unexpected-benefits-of-natural-movement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/threedeer.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3046&#34; alt=&#34;threedeer&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/threedeer.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started training with natural movements, as opposed to the contrived, isolated, and repetitive movements that used to make up the bulk of my training program, I was mainly interested in the obvious benefits: catlike reflexes, amazing strength, awe-inspiring toughness, and ninja skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly, I was focused on the physical benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I discovered after training this way for a while that it was changing me in other ways, too. I started to relate to my body differently than I had before, even during my years training CrossFit. Instead of feeling constantly inadequate, always being a step behind where I needed to be, I started to feel capable where I was right now, even as I trained to continue improving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve written extensively on the &lt;a title=&#34;Move and Be Free&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/move-and-be-free/&#34;&gt;physical&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title=&#34;How Moving Well Can Make You Confident and Popular&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/two-reasons-play-is-a-big-deal/&#34;&gt;mental&lt;/a&gt; benefits of natural movement, and plenty of other people have as well, so I just wanted to share some of the less obvious benefits I&#39;ve found from my training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the Barefootsteps of Erwan Le Corre</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/in-the-barefootsteps-of-erwan-le-corre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/in-the-barefootsteps-of-erwan-le-corre/</guid>
      <description>Boulder&#39;s magic strikes again.
I was out for a barefoot run last week and decided to explore a new trail. I was getting the usual stares, when one woman held my gaze. I smiled politely, and she did too, but she didn&#39;t just turn back to her hike. Instead, she yelled, &#34;Another barefooter like me!&#34; I saw shoes, but when I stopped, I realized they were light moccasins. We walked a while together until we reached a side trail where she removed her shoes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Superhuman Heritage</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/your-superhuman-heritage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/your-superhuman-heritage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/moonandstars.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3014 alignright&#34; alt=&#34;moonandstars&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/moonandstars.jpg&#34; width=&#34;342&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Shoot for the stars and hit the moon. - Anon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all dream of becoming something more than we are, of surpassing the everyday. We have an urge to outgrow ourselves: be more healthy, more wealthy, more confident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, we act on that, and sometimes we don&#39;t, but it&#39;s always there, tickling at the back of our minds. &#34;How wonderful it would be to transcend my limitations?&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, one of the most chafing limitations has always been where I can go and what my body is capable of. Whenever I watch movies or even cartoons about exceptional warriors, martial artists, and heroes, I am always surprised by how I feel seeing those fancy moves. &lt;strong&gt;It&#39;s not awe so much as jealousy, a sense that, not only do I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to be able to do that, I believe that I &lt;em&gt;should &lt;/em&gt;be able to&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, obviously I have to keep in mind that most of these shows and stories are fiction, and most of the moves are performed by stunt doubles with the aid of special effects. But there are exceptional humans out there who are not always Olympic or world champion level: club gymnasts, strongmen and women, marathoners and ultra-runners, powerlifters, traceurs, rocks climbers, dancers, athletes, Shaolin monks, stuntmen. Anyone from any walk of life can become accomplished in any of these feats that transcend what we consider normal for a human being. They may not break any world records, but a 2x bodyweight deadlift is a significant achievement, and puts you in the top range of (modern, industrialized) humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But maybe it&#39;s not about becoming something more than what we are. Maybe it&#39;s about expressing what we already have within us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous but Safe</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dangerous-but-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dangerous-but-safe/</guid>
      <description>Utah&#39;s Canyonlands National Park contains some of the most beautiful and harsh landscape in the world, so when I had the chance to bike and camp through it last month, I was excited to explore the terrain away from the campsite. That first evening, I headed up a rocky slope within sight of camp to really experience the landscape up close.
When I got back, it turned out I had upset one of the people I was traveling with, who saw my actions as foolishly dangerous, citing the possibility of me slipping or a tumbling rock causing me to fall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practicing Courage Through Movement</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/practicing-courage-throught-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/practicing-courage-throught-movement/</guid>
      <description>Do one thing everyday that scares you. - Eleanor Roosevelt
 After practicing movement and martial arts for so long, I sometimes lose track of the reasons I started in the first place. Lately, I&#39;ve been on a bit of a hiatus, but I was able to get some training time in last weekend. The combination of time off plus the intensity of training reminded me of why I do this in the first place, and, more importantly, why I want to do this every single day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spreading the Natural Movement Gospel</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/spreading-the-natural-movement-gospel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/spreading-the-natural-movement-gospel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2744&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/307846_683428511794_1406122075_n1-e1358867196564.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2744&#34; alt=&#34;Monkeybars in Japan are 3D&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/307846_683428511794_1406122075_n1-e1358867196564.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;335&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Monkeybars in Japan are 3D[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is shared with my &lt;a title=&#34;Warrior Spirit Movement&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/move&#34;&gt;movement training website&lt;/a&gt;. Head over there if you&#39;re curious about learning to move with power and grace.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I &lt;a title=&#34;I’m Moving to Boulder&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/im-moving-to-boulder/&#34;&gt;live in Boulder&lt;/a&gt;, I have the great opportunity to &lt;a title=&#34;The Communion of Play; A Day of Natural Movement on the River&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-communion-of-play-a-day-of-natural-movement-on-the-river/&#34;&gt;share my love of natural, playful, useful movement&lt;/a&gt; with the great community of the University of Colorado at Boulder. With its thriving athletics community and the fact that it is the heart of &lt;a title=&#34;The Greenwashing of Exercise&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-greenwashing-of-exercise/&#34;&gt;outdoor- and wellness-obsessed&lt;/a&gt; Boulder, CU is the perfect place to introduce young athletes to the concept that exercise doesn&#39;t have to be a chore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first, I have to prove my skills to the head of the fitness department, and while&lt;strong&gt; I do this stuff because I want to &lt;a title=&#34;Move and Be Free&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/move-and-be-free/&#34;&gt;flow like a wild animal ninja through the woods&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; I knew I&#39;d have to tone it down a bit to avoid alienating her. On Tuesday, I had my interview. Here is how it went:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived early to make sure I had time to orient myself to the facilities. The head of the department had structured the interview as a &#39;Snapshot&#39; training session; I would be training one of CU&#39;s established trainers, who would be acting as a naive client. We met outside the locker room, I got changed, and we headed up to the massive weight and cardio room that serves the CU student population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I walked by rows and rows of weight machines and treadmills, I began to doubt myself. It was clear that the status quo was well-entrenched here. I didn&#39;t want to estrange my &#39;client&#39;, who, as a trainer herself, would probably have some very strong opinions about what was legitimate and what was &lt;a title=&#34;Are You as Fit as Your Dog? 5 Ways to Play Fetch&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/are-you-as-fit-as-your-dog-5-ways-to-play-fetch/&#34;&gt;ridiculous&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had two choices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;Follow the program I had drafted, which was a standard weight loss/strength/&#39;firming up&#39; sequence, with some MovNat thrown into the warmup, OR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;Really emphasize the natural movement and blow her mind, hoping that she would get it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose the latter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MovNat Guest Post: Accept Frailty to Grow Strong</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/movnat-guest-post-accept-frailty-to-grow-strong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/movnat-guest-post-accept-frailty-to-grow-strong/</guid>
      <description>I was recently featured on the MovNat blog, talking about how much of a pansy I am (sort of). I thought I&#39;d just share that article for today.
One thing they never tell you about barefoot running is how painful it can be. When you step out on a trail for your first totally unshod trek, eager to run wild and free though the forest, you are suddenly struck with an unexpected problem: tiny pebbles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Greenwashing of Exercise</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-greenwashing-of-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-greenwashing-of-exercise/</guid>
      <description>This post is cross-published on my coaching blog, Warrior Spirit Movement.
Most mornings, I head out into the mountains, not to hike, but to ramble. I go where my heart leads me, over rocks, up trees, through fields. And when I am on the trail, I move over it in my own way, hopping from rock to rock or crawling along past wary hikers and excited dogs. Moving in these ways has me sprinting, swinging, scrambling, leaping, reaching, and everything but “Hiking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 80/20 Principle in Training</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-8020-principle-in-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-8020-principle-in-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2889&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;576&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/16761_702845749494_1943566062_n-1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-2889 &#34; alt=&#34;Dunebashing: 80% Play, 20% Sweat&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/16761_702845749494_1943566062_n-1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;576&#34; height=&#34;386&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Dunebashing: 80% Play, 20% Sweat[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;This was a concept that I had trouble understanding from my MovNat trainer certification. I have read &lt;a title=&#34;Book Review: The 80/20 Principle&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/book-review-the-8020-principle/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The 80/20 Principle by Richard Koch&lt;/a&gt;, so it was more an issue of understanding how to apply it to physical adaptation than a failure to grasp the concept. This article is what I came up with.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The few things that work fantastically well should be identified, cultivated, nurtured, and multiplied. - Richard Koch, &lt;em&gt;The 80/20 Principle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;80% of our results comes from 20% of our efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the 80/20 rule in a nutshell. It means that only 20% of our effort is responsible for most of our results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20% of our clients supply 80% of our income&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20% of our work time is when we get 80% of our assignments done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We watch 20% of our movie collection 80% of the time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, that last one may not be totally accurate. Perhaps, if you&#39;re me, it&#39;s more like you watch 10% of your movie collection 90% of the time, but the point is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The majority of our results come from a surprisingly small minority of our efforts or resources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is good news, because it means we can cut out 80% of the busy work and dedicate more of our time to the 20% that actually makes a difference. Or we can retain 80% of our current results and spend much less time on achieving them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In training, that means we should focus on the exercises that make the most difference to our health and ability&lt;/strong&gt;. These would be exercises that trigger a powerful, full-body adaptation response. Heavy strength training would be preferable to isolation biceps curls, for example (sorry biceps curls, I know everyone picks on you).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing in the Woods, Mountain Lions, and Braised Chicken</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/playing-in-the-woods-mountain-lions-and-braised-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/playing-in-the-woods-mountain-lions-and-braised-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Training for my MovNat certs has been exhilarating in a lot of ways. Unfortunately, it means I have been totally swamped between preparing for them, preparing for the workshops I&#39;m leading in Boulder later this week, and actual training, which means this is the only blog post for today. Sorry. I&#39;ll try to get something more substantial up on Wednesday.
Just some highlights of what I&#39;ve been up to:
 We spent the entire day outdoors, exploring parks and trails and looking or movement opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empower Yourself Through Humility</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/empower-yourself-through-humility/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/empower-yourself-through-humility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/16112_700950337914_589075632_n-e1360535516995.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2802&#34; alt=&#34;Bowing Before the Buddha&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/16112_700950337914_589075632_n-e1360535516995.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;545&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humility reminds us that we are human. It reminds us not to overestimate our abilities, not to get sloppy and lazy, to always be present and give our best effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humility reminds us that the big tasks, the ones that matter, really are difficult, even for such amazing warriors as ourselves. &lt;strong&gt;Remembering this, we will remain focused, taking the task seriously and bringing to it the attention it deserves.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humility says, &#34;I could mess this up, so I will make sure I don&#39;t.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only the fool forgoes humility for hubris. If he is talented, he will get far, but eventually, the task at hand will be bigger than he can handle casually. Eventually, it will require an acceptance of the need for help, either from other people or deeper wells of energy and focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&#39;ve adopted the habit of bowing upon waking and just before bed. Bowing is an interesting form of devotion because it is an expression of humility. You are honoring whatever you bow to by being humble before it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, that suggests an acknowledgement of how much we rely on certain things and how important mindfulness is. I recite certain gratitudes when I bow. For example, I give thanks for the opportunity to rest and recover at night, and then I bow. This expresses the acknowledgement that I don&#39;t necessarily have the right to peaceful rest -- many people don&#39;t get it. I am thankful for it, but also humbled by it, since I depend on it to function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Moving Well Can Make You Confident and Popular</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/two-reasons-play-is-a-big-deal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/two-reasons-play-is-a-big-deal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2744&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;]&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2744&#34; alt=&#34;Monkeybars in Japan are 3D&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/307846_683428511794_1406122075_n1-e1358867196564.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;335&#34; /&gt; Monkeybars in Japan are 3D[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I was doing some research for an article I&#39;m writing on play as exercise, and I needed a photograph of a playground. Of course, that meant I had to test out the playground, which got me thinking on &lt;a title=&#34;Fitness is Play&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/fitness-is-play/&#34;&gt;how central the playground was in my daily life when I was a kid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Movement as a Rite of Passage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The American School of Dubai, where I went to elementary school, had a pretty awesome playground. The front consisted of three corridors of hanging traverse: there was a line of monkey bars flanked on both sides by lines of hanging rings. The rings on the left were short and closely spaced, while those on the right had much larger spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember &lt;a title=&#34;Your Mountain is Waiting. Do You Dare Conquer it?&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/your-mountain-is-waiting-do-you-dare-conquer-it/&#34;&gt;aspiring&lt;/a&gt; to complete the full set on the right side, like all the big kids. Every day, before school, at recess, and after school, I would practice swinging from the rings. Some days I would just do the short rings, to build confidence, but I usually gave the long rings a shot. I would patiently wait my turn in line with the big kids, enduring sneers and ridicule (I don&#39;t honestly remember), until I came to the front of the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart would catch. After waiting in line for agonizing minutes, would I now waste all of that by falling to the sand in &lt;a title=&#34;But What if You Fail?&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/but-what-if-you-fail/&#34;&gt;failure&lt;/a&gt; after one measly swing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You as Fit as Your Dog? 5 Ways to Play Fetch</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/are-you-as-fit-as-your-dog-5-ways-to-play-fetch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/are-you-as-fit-as-your-dog-5-ways-to-play-fetch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/?attachment_id=2707&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2707&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2707&#34; alt=&#34;Hard at Play&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3244259451_0120de8a9d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We&#39;ve had a series of intense posts lately, and there are more in the schedule (see below for more on that...and a funny video of me falling in the mud), so here&#39;s a much more lighthearted one.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m a strong advocate of spontaneous, playful movement as the best way to get exercise. That&#39;s why I love &lt;a title=&#34;Freeing the Zoo Humans: Why I Want to Become a MovNat Instructor&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/movnat-instructor/&#34;&gt;MovNat&#39;s philosophy&lt;/a&gt;. I feel that play is more engaging, gets your mind off the strain of exercising (so you&#39;ll do more), and &lt;a title=&#34;The Communion of Play; A Day of Natural Movement on the River&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-communion-of-play-a-day-of-natural-movement-on-the-river/&#34;&gt;can be shared as social activity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I&#39;ve been undergoing a self-imposed training program for my &lt;a title=&#34;How to Make a Dream Come True&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/how-to-make-a-dream-come-true/&#34;&gt;MovNat Trainer Certification&lt;/a&gt;, which has been lonely in the cold winter of New England. This past weekend, I finally got my girlfriend (who will now be referred to as Rocketpack instead of the mysterious, A) to come out with me. Seizing on this opportunity for social play, I came up with a game to make my sprint-esque workout more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We played a timeless classic, enjoyed not just by humans, but by our furry friends as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yup, we played fetch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make a Dream Come True</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-make-a-dream-come-true/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-make-a-dream-come-true/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/?attachment_id=2693&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2693&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter  wp-image-2693&#34; alt=&#34;Achieving Goals Feels Good&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/66728_700953401774_1869754869_n1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;592&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn&#39;t very often that we get to cross out a big goal in our lives, but that is exactly what I did at the end of November. I&#39;d been dreaming of &lt;a title=&#34;Freeing the Zoo Humans: Why I Want to Become a MovNat Instructor&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/movnat-instructor/&#34;&gt;becoming a MovNat trainer&lt;/a&gt; since I heard about the method in 2009. Around April of last year, when MovNat announced they were offering trainer certifications, I finally decided to make this dream a reality. I couldn&#39;t afford the certification with what I was making as an ESL teacher; I would have to raise the money by &lt;a title=&#34;Lessons Learned on Finishing My First Book&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/lessons-learned-on-finishing-my-first-book/&#34;&gt;writing and promoting&lt;/a&gt; an eBook, which I published in September of 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By November of 2012, I had raised enough from donations for the eBook (as well as a few t-shirt sales) to sign up for my MovNat trainer certification in March 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a long road to get there, but the most valuable thing I got out of the whole experience won&#39;t be the MCT certification itself. &lt;strong&gt;Instead, it is the confidence that I can affect my life without permission from anyone else&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Communion of Play; A Day of Natural Movement on the River</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-communion-of-play-a-day-of-natural-movement-on-the-river/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-communion-of-play-a-day-of-natural-movement-on-the-river/</guid>
      <description>Last month, I spent a day enjoying a river park that runs past my home in Korea. While the exercise itself was freeing, what really struck me was how simply being playful and exercising like this seemed to connect with other people, even those I couldn&#39;t communicate with. The natural, playful movement intrigued people, brought them joy, even inspired some of them to try it themselves. It was as if seeing an &#39;adult&#39; playing let them believe it was okay for them to engage with their own bodies in ways they normally left to their kids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitness is Play</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/fitness-is-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/fitness-is-play/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/6885273501_9df2a14fb4.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2176&#34; title=&#34;On the Swings&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/6885273501_9df2a14fb4-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In our modern world, all fitness regimens are accessory and optional.  It is up to each and every individual to decide if they want to exercise or not, and how.  Even walking has already become an option.  But like it or not, &lt;strong&gt;moving naturally still is, and always will be a biological necessity&lt;/strong&gt;. - Erwan Le Corre&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do kids do to play?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They move&lt;/strong&gt;. They climb, scramble, swing, slide, crawl, roll, and jump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Movement is FUN, plain and simple&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are sports enjoyable? Because they involve movement. &lt;strong&gt;For whatever reason, humans (all animals actually) seem to &lt;a title=&#34;Move and Be Free&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/move-and-be-free/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;enjoy movement&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freeing the Zoo Humans: Why I Want to Become a MovNat Instructor</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/movnat-instructor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/movnat-instructor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/cagedworld.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2117&#34; title=&#34;cagedworld&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/cagedworld-283x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;283&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“Learning is all about freedom. The more you know, the more options you have. Knowledge is both liberating and empowering.” ~Erwan Le Corre&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time I read &lt;a title=&#34;MovNat Men&#39;s Health Article&#34; href=&#34;http://www.menshealth.com/fitness/fitness-survive-wild&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chris McDougall&#39;s article on MovNat in Men&#39;s Health&lt;/a&gt; back in 2009, I couldn&#39;t stop staring at the computer screen, rolling over what it meant in my mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Somewhere, in the forests of Brazil, &lt;a title=&#34;Erwan Le Corre MovNat Sampler&#34; href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m61t3ObnSP0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;there was a man living in harmony with nature&lt;/a&gt;, climbing trees, vaulting over rocks, carrying logs, jumping from boulder to boulder, teaching people to grow past the limits of their sad, domesticated bodies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever seen something and immediately felt, &#34;I have &lt;em&gt;got&lt;/em&gt; to do that. If there is one thing I must do in my life, this...is...it!&#34;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t just want to go do one workshop and be done with it. I wanted to live it. I wanted to be that wild and free. I wanted to get so good, I&#39;d give Le Corre, the founder, a run for his money. I wanted to spread the word, show people that being healthy &lt;a title=&#34;Fitness is Not Health&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/fitness-is-not-health/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;doesn&#39;t mean hours on a treadmill&lt;/a&gt; or tedious, repetitive movement. It can--it should--mean &lt;a title=&#34;Move and Be Free&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/move-and-be-free/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;vibrant, moving, freedom&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the article provided more information on the history of Methode Naturelle, the precursor to MovNat, than information on MovNat itself. MovNat at the time was small and not well-known. I was in college, broke, beat down by my studies at one of the most masochistic universities in the country, and &lt;strong&gt;very, very far away from running wild and free in the forests of Brazil&lt;/strong&gt;. I was at a dead end, but the seed had been planted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitness is Not Health</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/fitness-is-not-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/fitness-is-not-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2008&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/tomsaint/3752937440/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-2008 &#34; title=&#34;Tired Runners&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3752937440_4641fa806d.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Rennett Stowe on Flickr[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In writing my fitness book and thinking about how I want to explain my views to others, I&#39;ve realized that I was never really comfortable with fitness as we normally conceive it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitness is a confusing term these days. It has become so confusing, in fact, that you can have Fitness without Health. You can be very good at the Fitness thing, exercising religiously, following the right diet, wearing the right $70 Yoga pants, and be completely miserable. Originally meant to be a means to promote our holistic health, Fitness has taken on a life of its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To define Fitness, I want put aside dictionary definitions and focus on what most people mean when they talk about Fitness. I&#39;m concerned with ideas and conceptions, not academic or scientific definitions that have little to do with how people interact with the term in their real lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most, fitness is synonymous with athletic performance: the better your fitness, the better athlete you are. It is also synonymous with health: the better your fitness, the healthier you are. So, the assumption is that athletes are healthy, meaning their bodies express the full range of human function, painlessly, and for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Unhealthy Athlete&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we know that not all great athletes are healthy. The standards of a sport do not always require holistic human health to perform well (think golf), and sometimes the requirements of excellence in a sport actually favor adaptations that cause health problems. When an elite runner dies of heart failure, what do we make of it? How do we reconcile the awe-inspiring performance of gymnasts with the spine and shoulder problems that come with the intensive practice?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Understanding of Fitness and the Human Body</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-new-understanding-of-fitness-and-the-human-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-new-understanding-of-fitness-and-the-human-body/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/245952551_797503484e.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright  wp-image-1995&#34; title=&#34;Bodies in Motion&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/245952551_797503484e.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;360&#34; height=&#34;270&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Many people treat their bodies as if they were rented from Hertz--something they are using to get around in but nothing they genuinely care about understanding. - Chungliang Al Huang&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until recently, it was thought that a human being could be perfectly healthy eating only parts of food, as long as they were in sufficient quantities and ratios. The nutrient model of diet claimed that we simply needed sufficient protein, carbohydrates, and fats, plus vitamins, in order to be healthy. Foods were broken down, proteins, vitamins, and minerals extracted, removed, concentrated, and added back in sufficient quantities. We had mastered the science of nutrition and were entering a golden age of health and convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much for that...the nutrient model has been discredited lately, as it became more and more obvious that the benefits of whole foods, eaten fresh and close to the source, simply could not be copied by even the most carefully scientifically balanced meals. Sometimes this was because of the limits of our technology, but just as often, there were factors we hadn&#39;t even identified that seemed to make the difference between health-promoting and obesity-inducing food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitness and exercise is where nutrition was a few years ago. We are only now starting to pull out of the mistaken belief that movement-related health can be broken down into its constituent parts and fed in concentrations to promote certain kinds of growth. Happily, we have mostly discarded the notion that the body can respond to training muscles in isolation on weight machines. Unfortunately, we still pull movement apart into elements like strength, speed, power, agility, coordination, balance, and flexibility, just as we used to think of food only in terms of its proteins, carbohydrates, fats, vitamins, and minerals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move and Be Free</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/move-and-be-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/move-and-be-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1974&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/amagill/4614314729/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-1974 &#34; title=&#34;movement&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/movement.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; AMagill on Flickr[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&#39;t freedom to move the most fundamental freedom there is? - Erwan Le Corre, founder MovNat&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine that walking tires you out quickly. You cannot walk more than five minutes before desperately needing a rest. Add to that the fact that you are too weak to carry a day&#39;s worth of food more than five minutes. Let&#39;s say you&#39;re also too inflexible to sit comfortably on the ground for very long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now try to imagine all the places you cannot go: anywhere without cars, regular and cheap food, or chairs. You are strongly dependent on the presence and goodwill of other people for things as simple as your comfort. Because of your inability to move your body and endure hardship, you have fewer options for where you can go and the things you can do. You literally could not go more than five minutes without needing someone or something to help you. If you get stuck or behind schedule, you&#39;re screwed because you cannot run to catch a bus, much less a few miles to the nearest gas station if your car breaks down out of cell phone range on an urgent errand. You are dependent, in a very visceral sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movement Naturale</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/movement-naturale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/movement-naturale/</guid>
      <description>A break from the usual thought-provoking stuff to share something I&#39;m getting really passionate about: Movement Naturale! This was the original functional fitness program developed by the French before WWI. I read about it years ago, and it was what initially sparked my interest in other functional fitness programs like CrossFit. Partly because it was so intense, I didn&#39;t really entertain the notion of getting into it right off the bat, but now that I&#39;ve developed a good base from CrossFit and have started trail running, I&#39;m probably going to start incorporating some of it into my fitness program.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
