<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>exercise on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/exercise/</link>
    <description>Recent content in exercise on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/exercise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Be Gentle, Be Powerful</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/be-gentle-be-powerful/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/be-gentle-be-powerful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1884&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Espara on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/esparta/2214658212/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1884&#34; title=&#34;Sleeping Tiger&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/2214658212_9d9183226f-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I have never taken any exercise except sleeping and resting.” - Mark Twain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intensity in exercise is good. Most of us aren’t getting enough of it. Instead we settle for lifting weights we can handle comfortably and running at speeds that just break a sweat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then there are those of us who do nothing but high intensity exercise. We’re CrossFitters and Traceurs, MMA fighters and sprinters. We only have one speed, and that’s insane! We are not know for our gentleness, with others or ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to be one of those. Until I got injured, which happened a lot actually. When you’re body is constantly working near its limits, there is not much time for healing or recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My most recent injury was a pulled muscle in my hip that immobilized my lower back. I couldn’t even bend over to tie my shoes. I had zero flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of options and fed up with being in pain all the time, I started practicing yoga to regain my flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started it only as a therapeutic form of exercise, but I noticed that I felt much better on days I started with some yoga than those without. Clearly yoga was addressing some aspect of my physical training I’d been neglecting with all the CrossFit and gymnastics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intense stretching didn&#39;t help at all. The painful deep tissue massage didn&#39;t help, either. But slow, comfortable, gentle yoga slowly untied my back and improved my flexibility in other areas as well. When I finally started being gentle and kind to my body, it stopped punishing me with pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Truth About My Training and Diet</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-truth-about-my-training-and-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-truth-about-my-training-and-diet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1699&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;I&amp;#39;d rather be able to do this than have a fast Fran time. Source: Raphael Goetter on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/goetter/2567497624/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1699&#34; title=&#34;ironcross&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/ironcross-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a CrossFit trainer, I sometimes feel like I&#39;m not allowed to use, much less espouse, alternative forms of physical training or diet. But since I&#39;ve been caught so many times doing very un-CrossFit-like things, and a lot of people ask me what my training program is, or what my diet is, I thought I&#39;d come clean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intensity vs. Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/intensity-vs-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/intensity-vs-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1640&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Daisyree Bakker on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/27875041@N02/4425848358/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1640&#34; title=&#34;bear&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/bear-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d rather train to outrun a bear than to fight one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am more likely to actually attain my goal of outrunning a  bear, and will be able to apply that skill in a variety of  environments. If there are trees, I can climb them. If there is water, I  can swim. Climbing cliffs and rocks is another option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If, however, I simply train to be massively strong in  hopes of eventually overpowering the bear, I am starting at a distinct  disadvantage. Additionally, if I do face the bear in a fight, even if I  win (which is extremely unlikely), I am much more likely to get injured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Need for Inspiration in Fitness</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-need-for-inspiration-in-fitness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-need-for-inspiration-in-fitness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1578&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Zach Dischner on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/zachd1_618/4760723894/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1578&#34; title=&#34;mountainclimbing&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/mountainclimbing-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was going on a rant about all the problems with the fitness industry the other day, as I often do, and one of the few things I said of value was that fitness isn’t about the body, at least not ultimately. It is about the spirit. We mainly want to have healthy bodies so that we can enjoy life, feel confident and strong, experience lots of cool adventures, and play with our grandkids. Most people don’t want to lose weight just for the sake of losing weight, but because they believe it will make them happier. After all, isn’t that why we do everything – in order to be happy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forays in Barefoot Running</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/forays-in-barefoot-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/forays-in-barefoot-running/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1570&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;chumley80 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/29937348@N05/5247371406/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1570&#34; title=&#34;Runners Feet&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5247371406_ffb0cc0563-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve started barefoot running. Not just going out to the mail in my bare feet. Not jogging in light shoes. Full on, running down the road with no shoes on, barefoot running. So far my maximum distance is about 3/4 mile, and I&#39;m taking it slowly, but it is addictive, and holding back is the hardest part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned as a Trainer and Athlete</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-learned-as-a-trainer-and-athlete/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-learned-as-a-trainer-and-athlete/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;cliff1066 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/20110403-133920.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/20110403-133920.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20110403-133920.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been a personal trainer now for about two years, and I&#39;ve been actively training myself for about three. It has been quite a journey, and I&#39;ve come a long way. When I started, I could only dream of doing a pull up. Now it is my strongest movement. Handstands were so far beyond my abilities as to be pure fantasy, and now I spend a lot of time inverted. I&#39;ve travelled a long road in a short amount of time, and I&#39;ve learned a few lessons along the way that I thought I would share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Warrior Spirit</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-warrior-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-warrior-spirit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Hello World&#34;]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/20110331-213409.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/20110331-213409.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20110331-213409.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d like to inject a little more of me into my posts. After all, this blog was started by me as a sort of online journal. I was reluctant to assume that all my readers found my life all that interesting, but I thought I&#39;d just write about it. I am a storyteller, after all, not just an essayist. Since the story I know best is my own, I wanted to tell that story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the way, I got swept up by all these other great blogs that also tell stories, but which also provide lots of useful information besides. Somehow, the information stuck out more than the stories, and I focused on that. As a result, I feel that Warrior Spirit has kind of drifted from being personal to trying too hard to be useful. The result I think has been less connection with my readers. The blog has grown and grown, and for that I&#39;m thankful, but I feel a little like I&#39;ve sold out (except without the monetary rewards).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&#39;m going to try to tell more of my stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Until You Break</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/go-until-you-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/go-until-you-break/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;willem! on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/20110326-085423.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/20110326-085423.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20110326-085423.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a tendency in difficult times to stop before the end of our rope. Things start to get too hard and the voice in our head says, &#34;We are almost finished. We&#39;d better stop before we actually fail.&#34; And so we stop to rest, even though there was no concrete evidence of our immiment failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Best Use Your Teacher</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-best-use-your-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-best-use-your-teacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1400&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;286&#34; caption=&#34;velvettangerine on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/velvettangerine/3922005142/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1400&#34; title=&#34;teacher&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/teacher-286x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;286&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re trying to learn something or achieve a skill, a teacher can be a big help, since they have already done what you want to do. But there are some pitfalls to having a teacher, especially if you try to put all the responsibility for your progress on their shoulders. The best way to use a teacher is as a resource for your own learning, not as the basis or sole motivation for your goals.&lt;em&gt; (if you&#39;re short on time, you can skip to the end of the article for a summary, a policy I&#39;ll be using more regularly)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a trainer, I work with a lot of people who want to get in great shape, but don&#39;t really want to put in the effort. Sure, they do the exercises I recommend when they show up, and they push themselves pretty hard. But then I won&#39;t see them for weeks. They have lessons maybe once a month, very intermittently, and as a result, they don&#39;t move towards their goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have trainees who see me about that often, but who do make progress. The difference is in the way they view our relationship. To the first group, I am responsible for their fitness progress. &lt;strong&gt;To the second group, I am merely a resource for them as they make their own journey towards fitness&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Respect Your Rest; Respect Your Work</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/respect-your-rest-respect-your-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/respect-your-rest-respect-your-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1354&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;John Pavelka on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/28705377@N04/4355106020/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1354&#34; title=&#34;Sunbathing&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/rest-300x229.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;229&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I&#39;ve been able to commit myself to a more minimalist approach to training. As an multi-sport athlete, I&#39;ve always found it difficult to focus my training on one or two things. Instead, I&#39;ve found myself always jumping around, never giving enough time to any particular method to make much headway. Alternatively, I&#39;ve toyed with trying to do everything all the time, and quickly burned myself out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, by limiting the time I can train, I am finding myself more motivated to give a good effort in the less time that I do train. &lt;strong&gt;When there is less to do, and less time to do it in, you will push yourself to make the most of what time you do have&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remember to Value Your Strengths</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/remember-to-value-your-strengths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/remember-to-value-your-strengths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1328&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;RightIndex on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/leomei/2652108834/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1328&#34; title=&#34;muscle&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/muscle-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an exercise program, CrossFit demands that its participants expose themselves to a wide variety of different challenges; you learn very quickly what you&#39;re good at and what you&#39;re not. Often, one weakness can derail an entire workout as you struggle to make up the slack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Odd Duck: My Stranger Health Habits</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/an-odd-duck-my-stranger-health-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/an-odd-duck-my-stranger-health-habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1288&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Bobby MacInnes on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/lonetown/1087101701/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1288&#34; title=&#34;odd duck&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/odd-duck-300x200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the name of health, I engage in some practices that others find pretty weird. I actually don&#39;t find them that odd, and they aren&#39;t really inconvenient to me. I actually really enjoy them. But since they aren&#39;t mainstream, they garner some odd looks. I thought I&#39;d list some of them for your entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Health Revolution</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-health-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-health-revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1285&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;eva101 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/evapro/425230963/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1285&#34; title=&#34;protest&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/protest-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A little rebellion now and then... is a medicine necessary for the sound health of government.”- Thomas Jefferson&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently stumbled upon an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/dr-mark-hyman/healthy-living-join-the-health-_b_799191.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;article &lt;/a&gt;claiming that being healthy is a revolutionary act, a difficult process that necessitates you make choices that put you in opposition to the mainstream and the social norm. To be healthy requires you be willing to ostracise yourself in the name of your own well-being because the sad truth is that our society has made poor health the trend and the norm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Instant Under the Bar</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/an-instant-under-the-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/an-instant-under-the-bar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1274&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Marc-Andre Casavant on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/casavant/4415188448/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1274&#34; title=&#34;olylift&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/olylift-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, over the course of something like two hours and 15-20 failed attempts, I managed to snatch 165 lbs, which is significant because that is my bodyweight (a snatch is an Olympic weightlifting movement in which you take a bar from the ground to overhead in one motion). I had set a bodyweight snatch as a goal almost a year ago, and had gotten to 160 lbs long before, but that elusive 5 lbs seemed impossible. Yesterday, I decided I would nail it, and in the end, it was mostly this determination that made the difference, rather than any actual performance improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patience</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/patience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1226&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;WasabiDoobie on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wasabidoobie/2448490111/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1226&#34; title=&#34;patience&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/patience-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Genius is only a greater aptitude for patience.” - George-Louis Leclerc de Buffon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have had a lot of waiting to do as my plans start to gain momentum. There are long periods during which nothing seems to bear any fruit. Farm to Table went silent for a long time, with almost no new comments or community engagement, leading me to get very discouraged. I was lacking motivation in my workouts and didn&#39;t really feel like I was making any progress. My blog seemed to be wallowing in obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, all of sudden things started to move very quickly, and I realized that it was the quiet times when things were starting to move towards a tipping point. I am getting a lot of people reaching out to connect over Farm to Table, there is a new energy in my training, and I am making all sorts of friends while reconnecting with old ones. It&#39;s almost more than I can handle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Process of Living</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-process-of-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-process-of-living/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_974&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;Source: mdezemery on flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mdezemery/311283302/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-974&#34; title=&#34;walking&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/walking-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;The journey is what brings us happiness not the destination.&#34; -&lt;em&gt;Dan Millman, The Peaceful Warrior&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the overriding themes that I refer to a lot is the idea that many important endeavors are ongoing. There is no end goal in mind, and having an end goal can often derail our efforts to improve. Instead, simply going through your routine, growing slowly and naturally, will get you where you want to go with less frustration and less pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unconventional Fitness Truths</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/unconventional-fitness-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/unconventional-fitness-truths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_883&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Source: JcOlivera.com on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/unconventional.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-883&#34; title=&#34;Guy exercising outdoor in Venice Beach&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/unconventional-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A bear, however hard he tries, grows tubby without exercise.” -Winnie the Pooh&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I began CrossFit two years ago, I&#39;ve learned some things about fitness that seem very counterintuitive. When I started training other people, one of my biggest challenges had been convincing people that what they&#39;ve always thought about fitness is wrong. Here are some common misconceptions that I&#39;ve discovered to be false, along with some strange truths that you wouldn&#39;t suspect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ll Never Be Good Enough...Until You Are</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youll-never-be-good-enough-until-you-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youll-never-be-good-enough-until-you-are/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/05/barbell.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-574&#34; title=&#34;barbell&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/barbell.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;221&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an athlete, one of the most common de-motivators I deal with is the assertion, made either by myself or well-meaning friends trying to help me deal with frustration at limited progress, that professional and Olympic athletes (those I aspire to be like) are genetic abnormalities. Thus, I should not expect myself to perform at their level, and should not hold myself to similar expectations of progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, I have agreed with this statement. After all, I&#39;m just a genetically average human, right? Even with all the determination in the world (and I have plenty of that) I just don&#39;t have the right bone length, muscle fiber ratios, metabolic eccentricities, to make it to the big leagues. So I shouldn&#39;t even try, and certainly not become frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I realized I have no idea what my genetic make-up is. For all I know, I am an Olympic sprinter who just needs the right training to unleash his genetic potential. People tell me I&#39;m too tall to be a gymnast, too lanky to be a good lifter, but there have been unlikely champions in every sport imaginable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with Injury</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/dealing-with-injury/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/dealing-with-injury/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_557&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;It would be easier if they could put a cone on me to keep me from exercising when I&amp;#39;m injured&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/05/cat.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-557&#34; title=&#34;cat&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/cat.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;268&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have times in our lives when we find ourselves unable to do the things we love, often because we did too much of the things we love. Whether it&#39;s cutting back on delicious pies because we had too many in one sitting last winter or cutting back our training load because we hurt ourselves, we get ourselves into situations that we regret, doing something we knew we shouldn&#39;t have done at the time, but did anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the Aftermath of Wino</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/in-the-aftermath-of-wino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/in-the-aftermath-of-wino/</guid>
      <description>Five rounds for time:
 21 thrusters @ 75lb 21 double unders</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Point of the Clock</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-point-of-the-clock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-point-of-the-clock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/clock.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-462&#34; title=&#34;clock&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/clock.jpg?w=199&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, after our workout, Kristi, my coach, Nick, a fellow CrossFitter, and myself stuck around to discuss the upcoming sectionals.  Somewhere in the discussion, the topic of different gyms&#39; methodologies came up. The other Stamford-based CrossFit gym, Hybrid Fitness, believes that extreme strength is pretty much the fundamental requirement for a good athelete. As such, they utilize a lot of strongman programming and training. We do not, and generally we aren&#39;t as strong on average. Does that mean we are worse than them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epic Fail</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/epic-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/epic-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/failure.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-438&#34; title=&#34;failure&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/failure.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, I failed epically. The workout for today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many rounds as possible, in 10 minutes, of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 deadlifts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 hang cleans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 front squats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 push jerks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All with 95 lbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, it&#39;s a ton of work, and much of it involving very technical movements. I was aiming to complete 7 rounds (so 49 of everything) because the previous record was 6 and change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I completed 6 rounds with about a minute and a half left. I was already dying. My vision was blurry and my legs felt like jelly, but I pushed through the sets. I got to the push jerks with 30 seconds left and without taking any rest, started into them. As the clock ticked to 0 seconds, I became distanced from my body, aware of but not feeling the burning in every muscle (a sensation that I had never experienced before), until the very last rep.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
