<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self-discipline on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/self-discipline/</link>
    <description>Recent content in self-discipline on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/self-discipline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Willpower</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-willpower/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-willpower/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/willpowerbook.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-1796&#34; title=&#34;willpowerbook&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/willpowerbook.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;144&#34; height=&#34;220&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Life is full of paradox. Eating fat doesn’t make you fat. Running in shoes can be bad for your feet. Giving yourself free reign to express your every desire and emotion can mire your personal growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last one will require some explanation, especially since there is a lot of talk here on Warrior Spirit about the importance of listening to your heart and following your dreams, no matter what comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve just finished a book summarizing the psychological research on the topic of willpower and self-control. The book, &lt;em&gt;Willpower, &lt;/em&gt;by psychologists Roy F. Baumeister and John Tierney, is rife with examples of how the failure to set and follow limitations leads to a breakdown of character. It is mainly a survey of the research, but what makes it readable is the authors’ sincere interest in helping the reader, and the interviews with such characters as endurance artist David Blaine (who spent 63 hours encased in a block of ice in Times Square) and Amanda Palmer (known for her tabloid-friendly outbursts). The authors also draw examples on how willpower can be utilized from Ophrah, Eric Clapton and Henry Morton Stanley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happiness is a Choice</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/happiness-is-a-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/happiness-is-a-choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1199&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Jayel Aheram&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/aheram/2228606820/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1199&#34; title=&#34;smile&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/smile-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most People are about as happy as they make up their minds to be &lt;em&gt;- Abraham Lincoln&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/book-review-the-8020-principle/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The 80/20 Principle, &lt;/a&gt;I was struck by how many useful strategies are presented for increasing one&#39;s happiness. Having spent most of my young adult life pursuing happiness and learning what behaviors and life situations lead to happiness, I was not struck so much by the idea that you can cultivate happiness as by the new approaches to the old problem. I had always taken it for granted that I could be more or less happy, and that was in my control. So it came as a bit of a shock for me when the author spent the larger portion of the section on happiness trying to convince his readers that they happiness was something they could actually control. He cited all sorts of studies and authors showing that people have a say in their happiness level, that we are not simply at the mercy of circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Process of Living</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-process-of-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-process-of-living/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_974&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;Source: mdezemery on flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mdezemery/311283302/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-974&#34; title=&#34;walking&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/walking-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;The journey is what brings us happiness not the destination.&#34; -&lt;em&gt;Dan Millman, The Peaceful Warrior&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the overriding themes that I refer to a lot is the idea that many important endeavors are ongoing. There is no end goal in mind, and having an end goal can often derail our efforts to improve. Instead, simply going through your routine, growing slowly and naturally, will get you where you want to go with less frustration and less pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Beat Procrastination</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-beat-procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-beat-procrastination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_789&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Source: CraigGrocott on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/craigweb/2887922337/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-789&#34; title=&#34;procrastination&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/procrastination-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Do it now! can affect every phase of your life. It can help you do the things you should do but don&#39;t feel like doing. It can keep you from procrastinating when an unpleasant duty faces you. But it can also help you do those things that you want to do. It helps you seize those precious moments that, if lost, may never be retrieved.” - &lt;em&gt;Napoleon Hill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading my blog today, but I have to ask, is there something more important you have to do that you are putting off by checking in? (Or perhaps reading my blog is the most important thing you have to do today, in which case I&#39;m flattered :)). &lt;strong&gt;Procrastination, the sacred art of putting things off to the last minute, is one of the biggest productivity killers in our lives, and also one of the biggest sources of stress and anxiety&lt;/strong&gt;. It is a learned habit, one that can really mess with your sense of well-being and mental health. It cuts into all aspects of our lives, from reading, to shopping, to paying bills, to exercising. So why do we procrastinate, and how can we eliminate this habit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returning to the Dojo: The Importance of Martial Arts</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_713&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; caption=&#34;Source: Pieter Baert on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pietel/15322162/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-713&#34; title=&#34;karate&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/karate2.jpg?w=201&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was a child I have had this instinctive urge for expansion and growth. To me, the function and duty of a quality human being is the sincere and honest development of one&#39;s potential. - Bruce Lee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I attended my first class of American Kenpo Karate in over five years. My old teacher told me in an e-mail to bring my old Gi, which I had kept, anticipating an eventual return to the art. When I went to dig it out from a trunk under my bed, I found my old belts, one soft, well-worn, and white, and the other stiff and bright, un-faded yellow. I grabbed the white belt and headed to class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I stepped into the dance studio where the class was being held, my old instructor, taller and leaner than I remembered, looked at me without recognition. It &lt;em&gt;had &lt;/em&gt;been a long time. He was shocked at the growth he saw in me and had trouble connecting the old Khaled with the one who stood before him. And then he looked down and saw I was wearing my old white belt and asked, &#34;Where&#39;s your belt?&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom Through Discipline</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/freedom-through-discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/freedom-through-discipline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_695&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;Source: Laniee75 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/laniee75/4213598676/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-695&#34; title=&#34;OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/discipline.jpg?w=225&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Seek freedom and become captive of your desires. Seek discipline and find your liberty.” - Frank Herbert&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to follow a very strict diet, and was religious about exercising. Rain or shine, groggy or energetic, sugar cravings or not, I followed my program. Ultimately, it turned out my particular program was a little intense and led to some problems, and so I have lately abandoned it for a more intuitive approach, meaning I do things when I feel like it, meaning I often don&#39;t do what I&#39;m supposed to do. At first, this felt liberating, but I&#39;ve begun to realize that I have given up something very important by letting go of my confining routines: my freedom.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
