<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>potential on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/potential/</link>
    <description>Recent content in potential on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/potential/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Your Superhuman Heritage</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/your-superhuman-heritage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/your-superhuman-heritage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/moonandstars.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3014 alignright&#34; alt=&#34;moonandstars&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/moonandstars.jpg&#34; width=&#34;342&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Shoot for the stars and hit the moon. - Anon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all dream of becoming something more than we are, of surpassing the everyday. We have an urge to outgrow ourselves: be more healthy, more wealthy, more confident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, we act on that, and sometimes we don&#39;t, but it&#39;s always there, tickling at the back of our minds. &#34;How wonderful it would be to transcend my limitations?&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, one of the most chafing limitations has always been where I can go and what my body is capable of. Whenever I watch movies or even cartoons about exceptional warriors, martial artists, and heroes, I am always surprised by how I feel seeing those fancy moves. &lt;strong&gt;It&#39;s not awe so much as jealousy, a sense that, not only do I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to be able to do that, I believe that I &lt;em&gt;should &lt;/em&gt;be able to&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, obviously I have to keep in mind that most of these shows and stories are fiction, and most of the moves are performed by stunt doubles with the aid of special effects. But there are exceptional humans out there who are not always Olympic or world champion level: club gymnasts, strongmen and women, marathoners and ultra-runners, powerlifters, traceurs, rocks climbers, dancers, athletes, Shaolin monks, stuntmen. Anyone from any walk of life can become accomplished in any of these feats that transcend what we consider normal for a human being. They may not break any world records, but a 2x bodyweight deadlift is a significant achievement, and puts you in the top range of (modern, industrialized) humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But maybe it&#39;s not about becoming something more than what we are. Maybe it&#39;s about expressing what we already have within us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Warrior Spirit?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/what-is-warrior-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/what-is-warrior-spirit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1215&#34; title=&#34;Warrior Spirit&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/TShirtBack-300x240.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The warrior stands defiant, spear in hand, looking over a vast plain. Below him is a world full of challenge and adversity, dangerous enemies and tempting shortcuts. Beyond is a great mountain range, full of promise certainly, but hiding even greater challenges. On the other side...who knows? Hope, transcendence, enlightenment. Or perhaps darker, more sinister rewards hide behind those peaks. All the Warrior knows is that he has decided to scale them, carve a path through the plains and over the mountains, leading the way for others who seek a better life on the other side, guiding them and defending the tribe from the dangers ahead. He knows he may not survive, but he has prepared well and is among the greatest, most capable leaders of his tribe. He is confident and eager to begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
