<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>weightlifting on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/weightlifting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in weightlifting on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/weightlifting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Instant Under the Bar</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/an-instant-under-the-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/an-instant-under-the-bar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1274&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Marc-Andre Casavant on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/casavant/4415188448/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1274&#34; title=&#34;olylift&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/olylift-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, over the course of something like two hours and 15-20 failed attempts, I managed to snatch 165 lbs, which is significant because that is my bodyweight (a snatch is an Olympic weightlifting movement in which you take a bar from the ground to overhead in one motion). I had set a bodyweight snatch as a goal almost a year ago, and had gotten to 160 lbs long before, but that elusive 5 lbs seemed impossible. Yesterday, I decided I would nail it, and in the end, it was mostly this determination that made the difference, rather than any actual performance improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If Failure is Not An Option, You Won&#39;t Fail</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/if-failure-is-not-an-option-you-wont-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/if-failure-is-not-an-option-you-wont-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1030&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;wolfsavard on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wolfsavard/4716421032/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1030&#34; title=&#34;nets&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/nets-300x200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;Do or do not. There is no try.&#34; - &lt;em&gt;Yoda,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Return of the Jedi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently learned a back handspring, and a front flip, among some other more complex gymnastics moves. Every time I want to try one without my coach to spot me, he considers whether I&#39;m ready, nods and says, &#34;Alright, give it a shot. The chance of seriously injuring yourself is probably less than 60/40.&#34; He is joking, sort of, but it is true that many of the stunts I attempt are actually quite dangerous. And that is why I don&#39;t mess up. &lt;strong&gt;Without safety nets, I can&#39;t afford to fail.&lt;/strong&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unconventional Fitness Truths</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/unconventional-fitness-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/unconventional-fitness-truths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_883&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Source: JcOlivera.com on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/unconventional.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-883&#34; title=&#34;Guy exercising outdoor in Venice Beach&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/unconventional-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A bear, however hard he tries, grows tubby without exercise.” -Winnie the Pooh&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I began CrossFit two years ago, I&#39;ve learned some things about fitness that seem very counterintuitive. When I started training other people, one of my biggest challenges had been convincing people that what they&#39;ve always thought about fitness is wrong. Here are some common misconceptions that I&#39;ve discovered to be false, along with some strange truths that you wouldn&#39;t suspect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Brain is Making You Weak</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/your-brain-is-making-you-weak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/your-brain-is-making-you-weak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/06/brain.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-611&#34; title=&#34;brain&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/brain.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;There&#39;s a lot in the fitness community on how diet and exercise impact fitness and strength, and even a fair amount on sleep. Less discussed is the impact of mental state and the way the nervous system can interact with muscles to have a huge impact on athletic performance and strength. Since I&#39;ve been reading some alternative theories lately, I thought I&#39;d share some things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nervous Inhibition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s an interesting fact: by default, the nervous system limits muscle tension to 30% of what the associated tendons can bear. So if you can only lift 100lbs, it&#39;s not because your muscles are weak, it&#39;s because your brain is holding you back to protect the tendons. Probably the biggest factor limiting how strong we are is our own nervous system keeping our muscles down to protect us. Another related phenomenon is that the brain will inhibit agonist (primary mover) muscles if it perceives the antagonist is weak, in order to protect the joint. For example, your bicep will be inhibited if your triceps is weak because the brain will worry that, should things get out of hand, the triceps won&#39;t be able to counteract the bicep force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the Aftermath of Wino</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/in-the-aftermath-of-wino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/in-the-aftermath-of-wino/</guid>
      <description>Five rounds for time:
 21 thrusters @ 75lb 21 double unders</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrity: There is more to Life than Winning...There&#39;s being Awesome!</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-there-is-more-to-life-than-winning-theres-being-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-there-is-more-to-life-than-winning-theres-being-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/handstand.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-493&#34; title=&#34;handstand&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/handstand.jpg?w=199&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Since the CrossFit sectionals I&#39;ve been feeling considerably less motivated about my training. You&#39;d think that making it to regionals would give me a message that I have some potential, and that I should work hard to realize it. Instead, I feel oppressed by the prospect of competing again. All my training is geared towards this one event, an event that has a very narrow definition of success (even by the standards of CrossFit), and in which I will undoubtedly be one of the smallest, puniest, guys there. Maybe I&#39;m over-dramatizing here, but I definitely feel like an underdog - I&#39;m young, relatively weak (most guys at these things can deadlift 400+ lbs, I&#39;m around 315lb on a good day), and pretty inexperienced. If it&#39;s all about who can move the most weight, I&#39;m screwed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
