<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>integrity on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/integrity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in integrity on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/integrity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Success, 14 Truths</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/success-14-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/success-14-truths/</guid>
      <description>The Basics Stay Healthy: Respect your body. It is your most vital tool. Eat well. Stay active. Sleep.
Respect Yourself: Dress well. Stay clean. Give yourself a clean place to live.
Love Yourself: You must, must, must be your own biggest supporter. Treat yourself with the same compassion you would offer your children. Commit to yourself. Commit to doing what it takes to make yourself happy and successful.
Be Kind: To yourself, to others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Difference Between Nice Guys and Good Men</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-difference-between-nice-guys-and-good-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-difference-between-nice-guys-and-good-men/</guid>
      <description>As long as you truly respect the other person, you can say whatever you want without hurting them. - A friend
 It&#39;s not a compliment, being called a nice guy. &#34;Nice guys finish last&#34; means that being nice is giving up ambition and assertiveness.
Or maybe you&#39;ve heard, &#34;No more Mr. Nice Guy,&#34; meaning, &#34;I&#39;m done holding back my true abilities,&#34; or, &#34;Now I&#39;m going to say what I mean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Trade Happiness to Live &#39;Right?&#39;: Claim Your Light</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/do-you-trade-happiness-to-live-right-claim-your-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/do-you-trade-happiness-to-live-right-claim-your-light/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Our deepest fear is not that we are inadequate. Our deepest fear is that we are powerful beyond measure. It is our light, not our darkness that most frightens us. We ask ourselves, Who am I to be brilliant, gorgeous, talented, and fabulous? Actually, who are you &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; to be? You are a child of God. Your playing small does not serve the world. There is nothing enlightened about shrinking so that other people will not feel insecure around you. We are all meant to shine, as children do. We were born to make manifest the glory of God that is within us. It is not just in some of us; it is in everyone and as we let our own light shine, we unconsciously give others permission to do the same. As we are liberated from our own fear, our presence automatically liberates others. - Marianne Williamson&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I moved to Boulder was the belief that it would be a good place to live car-free, to find affordable and plentiful local food, to swear off modern, wasteful comforts (like shoes), and to pursue minimalism by selling my iPad and other non-essentials. Basically, to live the way I believed was Right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turned out to be much harder that I thought. I never found the spiritual and emotional fulfillment promised. Instead, I was limited in my activities because I could only go so far without a car, I was always hungry because of my insistence on absurdly high food quality, and I was dirty and ratty because my clothes were so worn out and overused. I was a burden to my friends, always leaning on them to drive me places I couldn&#39;t bike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I was doing the right thing, and that if I held on long enough, things would start to work out (if you&#39;ve read my book, you know I did this with eating Paleo, and CrossFit). When they never did, I got really frustrated and started to feel bitterness and resentment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up cleaving so strongly to the way I believed I &#39;should&#39; be that I completely lost sight of what actually made me happy and ended up undermining my self-esteem and sanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I knew a lot of people who weren&#39;t terribly worried about doing things right. They simply went after the things that made them feel good, made them happy, or seemed interesting. Their standard was, &#34;Does this make me happy?&#34; and not, &#34;Is this the right way?&#34; I put so much effort into figuring out the right way and following it, but I was lost and floundering. &lt;strong&gt;It didn&#39;t seem fair that others could be so seemingly lax in their morals but have the peace-of-mind and sense of purpose that I lacked.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of those people who was living the dream while happily skipping through life in time with her own drummer, was my little sister.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pursue Your Bliss with Integrity</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/pursue-your-bliss-with-integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/pursue-your-bliss-with-integrity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is it that makes it so hard for us to pursue our dreams? Why is it so frustrating to pull together all the elements of our lives in order to move in the direction we so fervently want to go?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Follow Your Bliss - Joseph Campbell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Campbell compared the internal psychological journey of our lives with classic myths that have accompanied humans throughout history: from Genesis to Robin Hood, Coyote to Quetzalcoatl, &lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, the stories that move us all share common themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campbell believed that these themes were reflections of the stages of human development: if we have the &lt;a title=&#34;5 Ways to Boost Your Courage Right Now!&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/5-ways-to-boost-your-courage-right-now/&#34;&gt;courage&lt;/a&gt; to face up to our psychic dragons and to descend into the dark caves and underworlds of our fears and insecurities, we can face the challenges that allow us to become true heroes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we lack that courage, then we stagnate, never living up to our potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;This begs the question of what directs our growth. Campbell&#39;s answer would be that it is our dreams, aspirations, and passions, the thing that we were put on this earth to do, that drive us. Follow your bliss unerringly and with commitment, and you will surely become the hero of your myth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the myths, the greatest treasures are kept in the darkest caves, guarded by the most fearsome monsters. &lt;strong&gt;Likewise, attaining our bliss requires us to &lt;a title=&#34;Insecurity, the Root of All Evil&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/insecurity-the-root-of-all-evil/&#34;&gt;face our most ingrained fears&lt;/a&gt; and negative habits&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Moment of Your Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-most-important-moment-of-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-most-important-moment-of-your-life/</guid>
      <description>“Excellence is never an accident. It is always the result of high intention, sincere effort, and intelligent execution; it represents the wise choice of many alternatives - choice, not chance, determines your destiny.” - Aristotle
 Every moment of every day is full of choices. Some choices are trivial and some have life-altering consequences.
 Laugh or get angry Eat healthy or eat conveniently Read or watch TV Walk or run Play or work Love or hate Marriage or dating Create or consume College or work Write or don&#39;t  There are No Turning Points I often catch myself thinking that I need some big event to &#39;turn over a new leaf&#39; or otherwise start living the life I want/being the person I want to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Priorities: Matching Reality to Your Values</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/priorities-matching-reality-to-your-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/priorities-matching-reality-to-your-values/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/213085702_8d5e812d9d.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2958&#34; alt=&#34;New Changed Priorities Ahead&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/213085702_8d5e812d9d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Upon returning from my trip to Utah, I&#39;ve found myself caught in a whirlwind of activity, trying to catch up with all sorts of projects. This hasn&#39;t given me time to act on the important things that are normally part of my routine, nor the amazing insights I gained in the desert of the Canyonlands. That&#39;s one reason this post is late. It is a pattern I&#39;ve noticed in myself before, when I lived in Korea and was trying to establish a match between the life and wanted and the life I ended up living.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every now and then, it&#39;s good to take stock of how closely the life you&#39;re actually living matches the life you want to be living. Are the things that are important to you getting their due, or are they just sitting on the back burner, day after day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I find that stress tends to lead me to give up on my routines and plans with the excuse of surviving or making do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s like that saying about putting your head down and plowing through. You don&#39;t know (or don&#39;t want to know) where you&#39;re going, you just need to get through whatever&#39;s in front you, as fast as possible, without regard to finesse or tact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But the problem with doing that is that sometimes you move forward only to look up to find yourself somewhere you didn&#39;t mean to go&lt;/strong&gt;. Then you&#39;ve got to go back or find another way. You&#39;ve wasted effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or worse, because you haven&#39;t taken the time to plot your course, you end up barreling into another crisis situation, and the only way to deal with that is to do the same thing that got you there in the first place. Then, you become a slave to events, moving in the direction set by each crisis. At first, you are just telling yourself, &#34;I just need to get through this week, then everything will be back on track.&#34; But when that week passes, you haven&#39;t taken the time to set your course, and it becomes another week or &#39;getting through,&#39; then another, then another, until you find yourself lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guilt by Association; Chained to the Wrong Job</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/guilt-by-association-chained-to-the-wrong-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/guilt-by-association-chained-to-the-wrong-job/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#34;There Is A Voice Inside Of You&lt;br /&gt;
That Whispers All Day Long,&lt;br /&gt;
&#34;I Feel That This Is Right For Me,&lt;br /&gt;
I Know That This Is Wrong.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;
No Teacher, Preacher, Parent, Friend&lt;br /&gt;
Or Wise Man Can Decide&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s Right For You- Just Listen To&lt;br /&gt;
The Voice That Speaks Inside.&#34; - Shel Silverstein&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/7550109580_08554ef572.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2454&#34; title=&#34;Chained to your job&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/7550109580_08554ef572-247x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;247&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, my employer did something that got me really angry. I&#39;m not going to go into details, because even though she doesn&#39;t read English and I wouldn&#39;t mind that much if I got fired at this point, it would still be kind of underhanded to do it publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;However, today&#39;s events did teach me a very important lesson about integrity: When I work for someone, a group, or a company, I need to make sure their values are in line with my own, otherwise I risk putting my efforts and energy into causes that I either don&#39;t care about, or that I am totally opposed to.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you work for an organization, your efforts are directed towards achieving that organization&#39;s ends. Sometimes, this is great. With the multiplier effect of a dedicated community, your small contribution can have much larger effects than it otherwise would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if you don&#39;t agree with what your organization is doing, then your energy is applied to something you would otherwise oppose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is why &lt;a title=&#34;The 3 Things You Need for a Complete Life (my mother agrees)&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/3-things-complete-life/&#34;&gt;Awareness &lt;/a&gt;is extremely important in ensuring that you live the life you want. If you don&#39;t pay attention to the implications of your actions, then you end up being taken for a ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrity in Action: Why I&#39;m Not Charging for My Book</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-in-action-why-im-not-charging-for-my-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-in-action-why-im-not-charging-for-my-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2427&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2075441844_b3a8ed26a0.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-2427&#34; title=&#34;Steadfast Rocks&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/2075441844_b3a8ed26a0-300x201.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Sometimes you aren&#39;t supposed to go with the flow[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important principles may and must be inflexible. -Abraham Lincoln&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to explain why I decided to go back to giving away my book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Warrior Spirit Principles of Holistic Health&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/store/warrior-spirit-principles-of-holistic-health/&#34;&gt;The Warrior Spirit Principles of Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, for free or a donation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As some of you know, I had been reading Simon Sinek&#39;s book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;The Golden Circle&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-golden-circle/&#34;&gt;Start with Why&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;which explains that leaders inspire because they lead with WHY they do things, as opposed to WHAT they do. Even if they do ineffective things, they are driven by a purpose, and that comes across in all their actions. They maintain integrity, behaving in accordance with their principles, rather than convenience. The result is that we follow them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of great leaders in history. Not everything they did was the best course of action for every situation, but they were always people of integrity, so we forgave them, believed they had the right purpose, and gave them our loyalty anyway. One of my personal role models, Franklin D. Roosevelt, led the United States through a morally complicated war. There were certainly a great number of poor decisions made by him and his administration, but he had a clear purpose, and everything he did was somehow connected to that purpose. So, for the most part, he had the country&#39;s loyalty and he is remembered as a great leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Well, after I finished my book, I realized that charging $10 for it did not mesh with WHY I&#39;d written the book in the first place.&lt;/strong&gt; I wrote it because I believe that everyone should &lt;a title=&#34;A New Understanding of Fitness and the Human Body&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/a-new-understanding-of-fitness-and-the-human-body/&#34;&gt;know as much as possible &lt;/a&gt;about their health and be fully empowered to &lt;a title=&#34;Move and Be Free&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/move-and-be-free/&#34;&gt;cultivate their bodies&lt;/a&gt;. I also firmly believe that this is a natural right of being human. It&#39;s not something that should be withheld or taken advantage of. I wrote the book to &lt;strong&gt;share&lt;/strong&gt; what I know with my friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I finished &lt;em&gt;Start with Why, &lt;/em&gt;I applied the ideas to my own projects, and it became clear that if my purpose was free and open sharing of my experiences, I couldn&#39;t justify charging money for it. Even if my book was worth money by societal standard, that&#39;s not why I wrote it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, why did I decide to sell it in the first place?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Left Paleo Behind, and Why I&#39;m Returning</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-i-left-paleo-behind-and-why-im-returning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-i-left-paleo-behind-and-why-im-returning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/3234878244_e7e5dbef88.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2338&#34; title=&#34;Walking Away&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3234878244_e7e5dbef88-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;They are asking us to pay more for less shoe, calling it a &#39;barefoot&#39; shoe, and we are happily handing over the money! -- Bryant Rolfe, to me, on a trail run with our new $100 Merrell Trailgloves&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got into Paleo, I came through Mark Sisson&#39;s Primal Blueprint. The MDA community was never exclusively about diet, but focused on a &lt;em&gt;lifestyle&lt;/em&gt; of health, vitality, and playfulness. Sure it was a bit tongue-in-cheek and insular, but it was a community with plenty of room for whatever your views might be. There were the hardcore, live-in-the-woods-naked eco-warriors, and there were those who simply wanted to sneak their Vibrams into their cubicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, I thought I ought to grow up and go Paleo. Primal seemed like a softer version of the real deal. I attended a Whole9 workshop at my CrossFit box. It didn&#39;t entirely mesh with what I knew about nutrition at the time from my study of Weston A. Price principles and the Primal Blueprint, but I signed on (since then, our beliefs about nutrition have come closer together). As my whole box went into it together, I was swept into the world of Paleo eating and CrossFit exercise, &lt;a title=&#34;Fitness is Not Health&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/fitness-is-not-health/&#34;&gt;two movements totally divorced from a holistic view on life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&#39;m sure the blame lies in how I implemented things, not in the methods themselves, but the way I saw the methods being presented, it didn&#39;t seem like there was much leeway. The segment of the community I was in, which I took to represent all of it, was decidedly narrow-minded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrity of Movement, and My First RKC Class</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-of-movement-and-my-first-rkc-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-of-movement-and-my-first-rkc-class/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/7400969208_010890b9c21.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright  wp-image-2231&#34; title=&#34;Cheetah Run&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/7400969208_010890b9c21.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“Like a graceful vase, a cat, even when motionless, seems to flow.” - George F. Will&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always espoused the importance of &lt;a title=&#34;Move and Be Free&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/move-and-be-free/&#34;&gt;good quality movement&lt;/a&gt;, but it wasn&#39;t until I attended my first RKC Kettlebell class that I got to experience how Integrity of Movement can be taught and conveyed through a comprehensive program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RKC class, which stands for Russian Kettlebell Certification, was taught completely in Korean (because I live in Korea right now), but that wasn&#39;t a huge problem because the coaches were so well-versed in observing and correcting body-mechanics. They had a huge arsenal of tactile cues and could spot an anterior-tilted pelvis across the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 90-minute class focused on just one movement: the kettlebell swing. For those who have done it, it seems like a fairly simple movement: just swing the kettlebell, using your hips, and keep your back straight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&#39;d been teaching kettlebell swings the way I was taught at my CrossFit Level 1 cert for two years. I&#39;ve been doing them regularly for about four years. I had seen all sorts of variations, and I thought I had it down. I was very, very wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heroes are Rare</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/heroes-are-rare/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/heroes-are-rare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/3468969774_2e1327b481.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2123&#34; title=&#34;Ancient Hero&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3468969774_2e1327b481-e1343308708728.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“A hero is someone who has given his or her life to something bigger than oneself.” -Joseph Campbell&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heroes are rare. That&#39;s why we tell legends about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heroes do the things nobody else can do, the things nobody else has the courage or the will to do. Heroes do the hard things.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without heroes, society sits on auto-pilot because we are kept &lt;a title=&#34;The 3 Things You Need for a Complete Life (my mother agrees)&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/3-things-complete-life/&#34;&gt;unaware&lt;/a&gt;. Nobody fights to see the truth. And when the truth surfaces anyway--the problems society can no longer hide--there is nobody with the intention or the &lt;a title=&#34;The Compete Human Being&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-compete-human-being/&#34;&gt;integrity &lt;/a&gt;to stand up, do the work, and change it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; heroes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could be a hero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;But heroes are rare for a reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m No Expert...And I Don&#39;t Want to Be</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/im-no-expert-and-i-dont-want-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/im-no-expert-and-i-dont-want-to-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1626&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;kevinpoh on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kevinpoh/3650866967/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1626&#34; title=&#34;Tai Chi Master&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/master-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started this blog, I had no aspirations to do  anything more than share my thoughts about life and the world. I figured some of the things I was going through might be  interesting to others, mainly my family. I didn’t really set out to tell  anyone how to live their life or even provide advice. I was just  sharing my experience of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This differs markedly from how blogs are getting used these days as a platform to establish the author as an expert with no other credentials besides the blog itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can I Preach It, if I Don&#39;t Live It?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/can-i-preach-it-if-i-dont-live-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/can-i-preach-it-if-i-dont-live-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1606&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;226&#34; caption=&#34;Mike Cattell on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mikecattell/4411829834/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1606&#34; title=&#34;pews&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/pews-226x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;226&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be too easy to be perfect all the time. It is  far more difficult to accept that you’re not perfect but to believe  that you have worthwhile things to say despite that, and to say those  things with conviction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the last two weeks, I’d been in a bit of a rut.  Things that used to excite me didn’t appeal to me anymore. Exercise,  gymnastics, trail running, and even writing all seemed tedious and  boring. All I wanted to do all day was go home and sleep, and when I got  home, I didn’t want to sleep. I was just generally out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also seemed to be messing up everything good in my life.  Professionally, I’d given up a lot of hours training to work on my  writing, with the result that I was pretty broke. My  iPad-as-laptop-replacement experiment was a failure, so I had to buy a  new laptop. My relationship with my girlfriend was in a rough patch,  which just makes everything else seems hellish. I wasn’t sleeping well,  and all I wanted to eat was peanut butter and jelly sandwiches, which  was a problem because I don’t keep jelly at my house and most bread  gives me indigestion. My room was a mess, and I was out of clean  underwear and floss (surprisingly discouraging, actually).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to say that things have improved, though I still  need to invest in some floss, but I wanted to talk a little bit about  the weirdness of being an inspirational writer and not always feeling  inspired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quit Your Belly Achin&#39;</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/quit-your-belly-achin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/quit-your-belly-achin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1573&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;mdanys on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mindaugasdanys/3766009204/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1573&#34; title=&#34;Angry Child&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3766009204_8721a00dde-300x252.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;252&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;There are a thousand reasons for failure, but not a single excuse.&#34; - a cool t-shirt&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you make a mistake even worse? You whine and complain about it and make lots of excuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little while ago, I performed a CrossFit workout in which I wasn&#39;t too happy with my performance. It was a surprisingly difficult one, involving a lot of burpees, followed by a lot of overhead squats, followed by muscle ups. I&#39;m very good at the first and the last movement, and apparently not so hot at the second. But I was so keen on getting to my strength - the muscle ups - that when I finally did, I lost all my focus and went crazy. The result was that I got just a single muscle up in two minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the buzzer went off, I let out an angry yell, uttering a curse I never use in my daily life. It just sort of slipped out, and I was immediately ashamed of myself. Not because I had cursed - lots of people do that - but that I had gotten so angry that I did something so out of character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If You Want to Be Liked, Don&#39;t Try</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/if-you-want-to-be-liked-dont-try/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/if-you-want-to-be-liked-dont-try/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1043&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;moose.boy on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alces/47422069/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1043&#34; title=&#34;Jackass&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/Jackass-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You follow what you feel inside&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s intuitive, you don&#39;t have to try&lt;br /&gt;
It comes naturally, mmmm it comes naturally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it takes my breath away&lt;br /&gt;
What you do, so naturally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are the thunder and I am the lightening&lt;br /&gt;
And I love the way you know who you are&lt;br /&gt;
And to me it&#39;s exciting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;- Selena Gomez, &#34;Naturally&#34;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine in the services industry is finding the customer relation aspect to be somewhat taxing. No matter how hard she works, there always seems to be some customer who decides to complain anyway. Even when she is doing everything right, someone finds something to criticize. As a very driven individual who always expects the best from herself, she has been trying very hard to rise to the challenges posed and improve her performance, but this doesn&#39;t seem to be helping. Customers still sometimes complain or whine or antagonize her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Integrity: The Complete Human</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-meaning-of-integrity-the-complete-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-meaning-of-integrity-the-complete-human/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_767&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;Source: poeticaldistractions on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/visualpoeticaldistractions/3481595328/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-767&#34; title=&#34;david&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/david-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“The truth of the matter is that you always know the right thing to do. The hard part is doing it.” - General Norman Schwarzkopf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is largely about the development of character. The most important quality of character is integrity, because without it, character has no meaning. So what is integrity, anyway? The word is vaguely defined in most discussions, and looking back over my posts, I realize I have never actually clarified what it is I am talking about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returning to the Dojo: The Importance of Martial Arts</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_713&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; caption=&#34;Source: Pieter Baert on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pietel/15322162/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-713&#34; title=&#34;karate&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/karate2.jpg?w=201&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was a child I have had this instinctive urge for expansion and growth. To me, the function and duty of a quality human being is the sincere and honest development of one&#39;s potential. - Bruce Lee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I attended my first class of American Kenpo Karate in over five years. My old teacher told me in an e-mail to bring my old Gi, which I had kept, anticipating an eventual return to the art. When I went to dig it out from a trunk under my bed, I found my old belts, one soft, well-worn, and white, and the other stiff and bright, un-faded yellow. I grabbed the white belt and headed to class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I stepped into the dance studio where the class was being held, my old instructor, taller and leaner than I remembered, looked at me without recognition. It &lt;em&gt;had &lt;/em&gt;been a long time. He was shocked at the growth he saw in me and had trouble connecting the old Khaled with the one who stood before him. And then he looked down and saw I was wearing my old white belt and asked, &#34;Where&#39;s your belt?&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrity: There is more to Life than Winning...There&#39;s being Awesome!</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-there-is-more-to-life-than-winning-theres-being-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-there-is-more-to-life-than-winning-theres-being-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/handstand.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-493&#34; title=&#34;handstand&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/handstand.jpg?w=199&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Since the CrossFit sectionals I&#39;ve been feeling considerably less motivated about my training. You&#39;d think that making it to regionals would give me a message that I have some potential, and that I should work hard to realize it. Instead, I feel oppressed by the prospect of competing again. All my training is geared towards this one event, an event that has a very narrow definition of success (even by the standards of CrossFit), and in which I will undoubtedly be one of the smallest, puniest, guys there. Maybe I&#39;m over-dramatizing here, but I definitely feel like an underdog - I&#39;m young, relatively weak (most guys at these things can deadlift 400+ lbs, I&#39;m around 315lb on a good day), and pretty inexperienced. If it&#39;s all about who can move the most weight, I&#39;m screwed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ties That Bind</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-ties-that-bind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-ties-that-bind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/web.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-424&#34; title=&#34;web&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/web.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;224&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my path down alternative fitness and nutrition and spirituality, I&#39;m discovering that members of my various communities all seem to agree on certain things. Most CrossFitters tend to agree that we should move as our bodies were meant to, and often think in terms of evolutionary biology and anatomy. This parallels a similar trend in the local and traditional food community to look back to how our ancestors ate to determine the best way to eat now. In fact, the CrossFitters also extend this mentality to nutrition, and I&#39;m sure many traditional foodies would as well if fitness were as central to their lives as nutrition is to a CrossFitter&#39;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellectual Honesty</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/intellectual-honesty/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/intellectual-honesty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since starting this blog, I have constantly run into the problem of how honest to be with my readers. My parents are constantly asking me to tone down certain things, to refrain from sharing personal details of my life I think are important to understanding my thought process. I don&#39;t really know where to draw the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a conversation the other day with a friend who works in advertising. She is very supportive of my blogging, and every time I come up with an interesting idea, she encourages me to blog it, to share it with the world. My latest idea was somewhat risque, to put it lightly, but she said that was precisely the point. By being open and honeset about the truth of my life, I would be able to achieve a degree of integrity in my intellectual and emotional life that had eluded me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
