<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>training on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/training/</link>
    <description>Recent content in training on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/training/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spreading the Natural Movement Gospel</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/spreading-the-natural-movement-gospel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/spreading-the-natural-movement-gospel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2744&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/307846_683428511794_1406122075_n1-e1358867196564.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2744&#34; alt=&#34;Monkeybars in Japan are 3D&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/307846_683428511794_1406122075_n1-e1358867196564.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;335&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Monkeybars in Japan are 3D[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is shared with my &lt;a title=&#34;Warrior Spirit Movement&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/move&#34;&gt;movement training website&lt;/a&gt;. Head over there if you&#39;re curious about learning to move with power and grace.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I &lt;a title=&#34;I’m Moving to Boulder&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/im-moving-to-boulder/&#34;&gt;live in Boulder&lt;/a&gt;, I have the great opportunity to &lt;a title=&#34;The Communion of Play; A Day of Natural Movement on the River&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-communion-of-play-a-day-of-natural-movement-on-the-river/&#34;&gt;share my love of natural, playful, useful movement&lt;/a&gt; with the great community of the University of Colorado at Boulder. With its thriving athletics community and the fact that it is the heart of &lt;a title=&#34;The Greenwashing of Exercise&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-greenwashing-of-exercise/&#34;&gt;outdoor- and wellness-obsessed&lt;/a&gt; Boulder, CU is the perfect place to introduce young athletes to the concept that exercise doesn&#39;t have to be a chore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first, I have to prove my skills to the head of the fitness department, and while&lt;strong&gt; I do this stuff because I want to &lt;a title=&#34;Move and Be Free&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/move-and-be-free/&#34;&gt;flow like a wild animal ninja through the woods&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; I knew I&#39;d have to tone it down a bit to avoid alienating her. On Tuesday, I had my interview. Here is how it went:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived early to make sure I had time to orient myself to the facilities. The head of the department had structured the interview as a &#39;Snapshot&#39; training session; I would be training one of CU&#39;s established trainers, who would be acting as a naive client. We met outside the locker room, I got changed, and we headed up to the massive weight and cardio room that serves the CU student population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I walked by rows and rows of weight machines and treadmills, I began to doubt myself. It was clear that the status quo was well-entrenched here. I didn&#39;t want to estrange my &#39;client&#39;, who, as a trainer herself, would probably have some very strong opinions about what was legitimate and what was &lt;a title=&#34;Are You as Fit as Your Dog? 5 Ways to Play Fetch&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/are-you-as-fit-as-your-dog-5-ways-to-play-fetch/&#34;&gt;ridiculous&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had two choices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;Follow the program I had drafted, which was a standard weight loss/strength/&#39;firming up&#39; sequence, with some MovNat thrown into the warmup, OR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;Really emphasize the natural movement and blow her mind, hoping that she would get it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose the latter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ve Got to Be A Little Crazy</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/youve-got-to-be-a-little-crazy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/youve-got-to-be-a-little-crazy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve often wondered how great things get accomplished in this world. It&#39;s so hard to get past the day-to-day of basic social niceties, the need to make a living, following current fashion trends, and doing what&#39;s expected of you. How does anyone have time to do anything else? Where do you find the time to redefine a field when most modern fields require all your time just to stay current? How do you become all that you can be when being the bare minimum is a full time job?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intensity vs. Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/intensity-vs-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/intensity-vs-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1640&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Daisyree Bakker on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/27875041@N02/4425848358/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1640&#34; title=&#34;bear&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/bear-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d rather train to outrun a bear than to fight one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am more likely to actually attain my goal of outrunning a  bear, and will be able to apply that skill in a variety of  environments. If there are trees, I can climb them. If there is water, I  can swim. Climbing cliffs and rocks is another option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If, however, I simply train to be massively strong in  hopes of eventually overpowering the bear, I am starting at a distinct  disadvantage. Additionally, if I do face the bear in a fight, even if I  win (which is extremely unlikely), I am much more likely to get injured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned as a Trainer and Athlete</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/lessons-learned-as-a-trainer-and-athlete/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/lessons-learned-as-a-trainer-and-athlete/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;cliff1066 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/20110403-133920.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/20110403-133920.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20110403-133920.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been a personal trainer now for about two years, and I&#39;ve been actively training myself for about three. It has been quite a journey, and I&#39;ve come a long way. When I started, I could only dream of doing a pull up. Now it is my strongest movement. Handstands were so far beyond my abilities as to be pure fantasy, and now I spend a lot of time inverted. I&#39;ve travelled a long road in a short amount of time, and I&#39;ve learned a few lessons along the way that I thought I would share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Until You Break</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/go-until-you-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/go-until-you-break/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;willem! on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/20110326-085423.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/20110326-085423.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20110326-085423.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a tendency in difficult times to stop before the end of our rope. Things start to get too hard and the voice in our head says, &#34;We are almost finished. We&#39;d better stop before we actually fail.&#34; And so we stop to rest, even though there was no concrete evidence of our immiment failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Best Use Your Teacher</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-best-use-your-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-best-use-your-teacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1400&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;286&#34; caption=&#34;velvettangerine on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/velvettangerine/3922005142/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1400&#34; title=&#34;teacher&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/teacher-286x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;286&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re trying to learn something or achieve a skill, a teacher can be a big help, since they have already done what you want to do. But there are some pitfalls to having a teacher, especially if you try to put all the responsibility for your progress on their shoulders. The best way to use a teacher is as a resource for your own learning, not as the basis or sole motivation for your goals.&lt;em&gt; (if you&#39;re short on time, you can skip to the end of the article for a summary, a policy I&#39;ll be using more regularly)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a trainer, I work with a lot of people who want to get in great shape, but don&#39;t really want to put in the effort. Sure, they do the exercises I recommend when they show up, and they push themselves pretty hard. But then I won&#39;t see them for weeks. They have lessons maybe once a month, very intermittently, and as a result, they don&#39;t move towards their goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have trainees who see me about that often, but who do make progress. The difference is in the way they view our relationship. To the first group, I am responsible for their fitness progress. &lt;strong&gt;To the second group, I am merely a resource for them as they make their own journey towards fitness&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Respect Your Rest; Respect Your Work</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/respect-your-rest-respect-your-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/respect-your-rest-respect-your-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1354&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;John Pavelka on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/28705377@N04/4355106020/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1354&#34; title=&#34;Sunbathing&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/rest-300x229.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;229&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I&#39;ve been able to commit myself to a more minimalist approach to training. As an multi-sport athlete, I&#39;ve always found it difficult to focus my training on one or two things. Instead, I&#39;ve found myself always jumping around, never giving enough time to any particular method to make much headway. Alternatively, I&#39;ve toyed with trying to do everything all the time, and quickly burned myself out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, by limiting the time I can train, I am finding myself more motivated to give a good effort in the less time that I do train. &lt;strong&gt;When there is less to do, and less time to do it in, you will push yourself to make the most of what time you do have&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Shouldn&#39;t Always Do Your Best</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-you-shouldnt-always-do-your-best/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-you-shouldnt-always-do-your-best/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1342&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Alex E. Proimos&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/proimos/4199675334/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1342&#34; title=&#34;Head in Hands&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/failure-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only the mediocre are always at their best - Jean Giradoux&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My gymnastics coach recently revealed to me that Olympic gymnasts are only able to perform their routines at the time they compete. Most of the time, they use spotters, and they periodize their training so that they peak when they compete. Many of them can&#39;t even perform some of their hardest skills on an everyday basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this isn&#39;t especially unique in the world of elite athletes, it does reveal an interesting aspect of excellence: &lt;strong&gt;when you are performing at such a high level, you cannot always be at your best&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
