<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>intention on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/intention/</link>
    <description>Recent content in intention on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/intention/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Be Like a River: Live with Intention</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/be-like-a-river-live-with-intention/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/be-like-a-river-live-with-intention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/7628864666_fb943c9fcf.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2329&#34; title=&#34;River&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/7628864666_fb943c9fcf-300x224.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;224&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A river always flows to the ocean. You can divert it, but it will always find a way to continue its journey downhill.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only we were like rivers, and moving towards our goals in life was natural and inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The third part of Warrior Spirit is Intention: living with directed focus towards a vision of how you want your life, your self, or your world to be.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;The Meaning of Integrity: The Complete Human&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-meaning-of-integrity-the-complete-human/&#34;&gt;Integrity &lt;/a&gt;gives us the purpose. We have values and integrity ensures that those values actually matter to us and define who we are. Integrity allows us to live in accordance with our values, and to honestly care about the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;The 3 Things You Need for a Complete Life (my mother agrees)&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/3-things-complete-life/&#34;&gt;Awareness &lt;/a&gt;lets us see how our values play out in the world. It lets us understand the impact of our actions and our life. It is compassion for the world. Awareness is accepting what consequences we create, not hiding from the implications of our actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intention is the essential third point of the triangle that gives it direction. Intention is what allows us to take action on our values and to do something with what our awareness reveals. It is turning belief into action. It is turning dreams into reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Things You Need for a Complete Life (my mother agrees)</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/3-things-complete-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/3-things-complete-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/2259908021_e2ac9dd376.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2068&#34; title=&#34;Three Leaves&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/2259908021_e2ac9dd376-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;One of the most frustrating things about this blog is that I don&#39;t really know what I&#39;m writing about. It&#39;s my view on life, but it&#39;s been a real pain figuring out what the overarching theme on my life is. I mean, how do you tie together my interest in &lt;a title=&#34;Empty Your Cup: Accepting Ignorance to Learn&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/empty-your-cup-accepting-ignorance-to-learn/&#34;&gt;Buddhist spirituality&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title=&#34;A New Understanding of Fitness and the Human Body&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/a-new-understanding-of-fitness-and-the-human-body/&#34;&gt;evolutionary fitness&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title=&#34;Returning to the Dojo: The Importance of Martial Arts&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/&#34;&gt;martial arts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title=&#34;Book Review: The Omnivore’s Dilemma&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/book-review-the-onivores-dilemma/&#34;&gt;local food&lt;/a&gt;, environmentalism, &lt;a title=&#34;The Value of Failure&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-value-of-failure/&#34;&gt;positive psychology&lt;/a&gt;, and holistic personal health and growth? To me, all of those things are one and the same, but Google keyword searches don&#39;t generally group them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then I realized that this blog isn&#39;t really about &lt;em&gt;those &lt;/em&gt;things. It is about the approach to living that &lt;em&gt;led&lt;/em&gt; me to those things.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what are the keywords of my life? What about my approach to life led me to adopt evolutionary fitness instead of Fatbusters 2.0?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt; I Prefer the Term...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since reading &lt;em&gt;Shambhala: The Sacred Path of the Warrior&lt;/em&gt;, I&#39;ve spent some time thinking about the words I want to describe me and my lifestyle. I have already written a lot about Integrity, and I know that is a central part of who I want to be and what I believe characterizes the Warrior Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since all good things come in threes, I needed two more words. Naturally, I looked to the most annoying things about me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
