<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>feminism on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/feminism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in feminism on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/feminism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Feminine Mystique</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-the-feminine-mystique/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-the-feminine-mystique/</guid>
      <description>One of my biggest reading projects these past few months has been Betty Friedan’s The Feminine Mystique. I’ve always been interested in women’s psychology and feminism, so I was eager to deepen my understanding by reading this canonical work.
It’s a very, very long and very convoluted book (the nature of the problem seems to ensure this, since Second Sex was equally difficult), but here’s a quick overview.
The Mystique Friedan addresses the state of women during the 40s, 50s, and 60s, into the 70s, when many women gave up on pursuing an education and a career, denying all their aspirations but those related to raising a family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Don&#39;t Women Want to be Strong?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-dont-women-want-to-be-strong/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-dont-women-want-to-be-strong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“Go in peace my daughter. And remember that, in a world of ordinary mortals, you are a Wonder Woman.” Queen Hippolyte to Wonder Woman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2027&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;283&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/3896838102_1273912e8e.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-2027&#34; title=&#34;angie&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3896838102_1273912e8e-283x300.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;283&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/imagesbywestfall/3896838102/&#34;&gt;greg westfall on Flickr&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &#39;ideal&#39; woman is toned but not muscular, thin but not skinny (or is it the other way around?). She has curves, but no hips or butt. The &#39;ideal&#39; woman is also apparently defined solely by her body&#39;s appearance. &lt;strong&gt;The &#39;ideal&#39; woman is a biological contradiction&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what I have gathered as a guy, the world of exercise and fitness is a minefield for woman. It is promised as the path to a sexy, &lt;em&gt;thin&lt;/em&gt; body, but one misstep could lead a woman to functionally useful strength or worse, mannishness (which apparently means any visible muscle definition).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The phrase a &#39;strong woman&#39; brings to mind tenacity, persistence, mental toughness, but almost never physical strength. Why is that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My opinion is that standards of beauty should be a reflection of physical health: that which is considered beautiful ought to correlate to that which is healthy: a healthy human being, man or women, is a beautiful human being. Unfortunately, somewhere along the line, we associated feminine frailty with feminine beauty, to the detriment of women (and men) everywhere. The media has cemented this image, with even action heroines sporting builds that could never perform the stunts they execute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, my opinion doesn&#39;t matter all that much. If women want to conform to a standard of beauty that does not allow for health, that&#39;s their choice, and I know that for many women, attractiveness is a far, far more pressing concern than health. &lt;strong&gt;In fact, healthy behavior is pursued only as a means to acquire an attractive appearance.&lt;/strong&gt; This works to an extent because humans are hardwired to prefer the appearance of a healthy human over an unhealthy one. Biologically, attractiveness is an indicator of underlying health, so we seek out attractive mates because they are more likely to produce healthy offspring and survive the hardships of life. From an evolutionary perspective, attractiveness itself is not the desirable trait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We should be more concerned about health than about attractiveness&lt;/strong&gt;. Using diet and exercise in order to acquire a nice appearance begs the question of what happens when you no longer need or want to look attractive. Do you just start neglecting your health? After all, if health was only a means to look nice, it would only be pursued for the sake of appearance. There would be no concern about longevity, usefulness to others, or even respect for one&#39;s own body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human organism expresses its greatest health when it is functionally adept. When it can move well, it looks good. When it is well nourished, it looks good. That makes it attractive to others, as a side effect, as a flag telling others the organism is succeeding and flourishing. &lt;strong&gt;When you achieve vitality and vibrant health--when you flourish--you are beautiful&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
