<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>christmas on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/christmas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in christmas on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/christmas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Holiday Thanks You&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-holiday-thanks-yous/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-holiday-thanks-yous/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1856&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;jenny downing on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jenny-pics/3108467816/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1856&#34; title=&#34;holidaytrees&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/holidaytrees-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love this time of year. The cozy winter drinks, the warm crackling fires after a day in the cold, people bundled up but still extending warm greetings and presents. While it&#39;d be great to be this thoughtful all year, it is still nice to step out of our self-centered mindset, even if just for a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The holidays are a time when people take a moment to remember the important people in their lives. My usual holiday tradition has been to write handwritten cards to all the people who have made a difference in my life in the past year. It&#39;s sort of a massive thank you note for the intangible things that my friends have done for me throughout the year, whether that was just to be there and listen, to hang out and have fun, or give me much-needed help or advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, however, I got so caught up in my move to South Korea that I didn&#39;t get around to making all the cards. So, if you don&#39;t get something from me, please know that doesn&#39;t mean I forgot, just that life has been very busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I wanted to take this opportunity to say thank you to my community. This past year, I&#39;ve learned that so much of what makes us who we are is who makes up our community. We are, to a very large extent, the result of our friends, families, followers, and teachers. &lt;strong&gt;I want to acknowledge just how much of who I am is the result of the generous contributions of others who have seen something in me worth supporting&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
