<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>expense on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/expense/</link>
    <description>Recent content in expense on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/expense/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Much Do You Cost? How Much Do You Create?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-much-do-you-cost-how-much-do-you-create/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-much-do-you-cost-how-much-do-you-create/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/3544855402_ef3c3c980d.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2165&#34; title=&#34;Expensive Foundations&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3544855402_ef3c3c980d-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I am an expensive human being, for better or worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not expensive because I live lavishly. I am expensive because, in social and ecological terms, I cost a lot to produce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My education took place at a university, supported by a huge staff of underpaid workers who themselves would never have the chance to study in the classrooms they cleaned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My fitness training took place in expensive gyms where only very determined or very wealthy people could afford to train,  which were stocked with equipment shipped across the world from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My nutrition, on Paleo, was supported by the deaths of more animals than I care to count (with such a strong reliance on protein) and costly exotic fruits and vegetables (like coconut oil).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My writing takes place on a MacBook Air, one of the most expensive pen-and-paper substitutes in existence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a financial point of view, I don&#39;t spend too much. From a resource perspective, however, I consume a lot. &lt;strong&gt;Of all the 7+ billion humans on Earth, I am easily among the costliest for the planet to maintain&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
