<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>women on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/women/</link>
    <description>Recent content in women on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/women/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Don&#39;t Women Want to be Strong?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-dont-women-want-to-be-strong/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-dont-women-want-to-be-strong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“Go in peace my daughter. And remember that, in a world of ordinary mortals, you are a Wonder Woman.” Queen Hippolyte to Wonder Woman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2027&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;283&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/3896838102_1273912e8e.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-2027&#34; title=&#34;angie&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3896838102_1273912e8e-283x300.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;283&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/imagesbywestfall/3896838102/&#34;&gt;greg westfall on Flickr&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &#39;ideal&#39; woman is toned but not muscular, thin but not skinny (or is it the other way around?). She has curves, but no hips or butt. The &#39;ideal&#39; woman is also apparently defined solely by her body&#39;s appearance. &lt;strong&gt;The &#39;ideal&#39; woman is a biological contradiction&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what I have gathered as a guy, the world of exercise and fitness is a minefield for woman. It is promised as the path to a sexy, &lt;em&gt;thin&lt;/em&gt; body, but one misstep could lead a woman to functionally useful strength or worse, mannishness (which apparently means any visible muscle definition).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The phrase a &#39;strong woman&#39; brings to mind tenacity, persistence, mental toughness, but almost never physical strength. Why is that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My opinion is that standards of beauty should be a reflection of physical health: that which is considered beautiful ought to correlate to that which is healthy: a healthy human being, man or women, is a beautiful human being. Unfortunately, somewhere along the line, we associated feminine frailty with feminine beauty, to the detriment of women (and men) everywhere. The media has cemented this image, with even action heroines sporting builds that could never perform the stunts they execute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, my opinion doesn&#39;t matter all that much. If women want to conform to a standard of beauty that does not allow for health, that&#39;s their choice, and I know that for many women, attractiveness is a far, far more pressing concern than health. &lt;strong&gt;In fact, healthy behavior is pursued only as a means to acquire an attractive appearance.&lt;/strong&gt; This works to an extent because humans are hardwired to prefer the appearance of a healthy human over an unhealthy one. Biologically, attractiveness is an indicator of underlying health, so we seek out attractive mates because they are more likely to produce healthy offspring and survive the hardships of life. From an evolutionary perspective, attractiveness itself is not the desirable trait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We should be more concerned about health than about attractiveness&lt;/strong&gt;. Using diet and exercise in order to acquire a nice appearance begs the question of what happens when you no longer need or want to look attractive. Do you just start neglecting your health? After all, if health was only a means to look nice, it would only be pursued for the sake of appearance. There would be no concern about longevity, usefulness to others, or even respect for one&#39;s own body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human organism expresses its greatest health when it is functionally adept. When it can move well, it looks good. When it is well nourished, it looks good. That makes it attractive to others, as a side effect, as a flag telling others the organism is succeeding and flourishing. &lt;strong&gt;When you achieve vitality and vibrant health--when you flourish--you are beautiful&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a Guy Wants</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/what-a-guy-wants/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/what-a-guy-wants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1805&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Astragony on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/astragony/4841649944/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1805&#34; title=&#34;ModelinRome&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/ModelinRome-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women do not have it easy in our society. For example, they get &lt;a title=&#34;Miss Representation&#34; href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?v=2349117563337&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;objectified&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title=&#34;Why a Woman Can Never Win Against a Man&#34; href=&#34;http://www.care2.com/causes/why-a-woman-can-never-win-against-a-man.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;have their world records revoked&lt;/a&gt;, and are underrepresented in American government. Nobody thinks these things are okay (and if you do, you suck). Women also have to put up with an unrealistic and extremely narrow definition of beauty. Yet a lot of men see no reason to work to change they way they see women or deal with them. Would you boycott almost every show on TV? Would you date a girl you respected, even if she wasn’t stereotypically sexual? Would you turn down the svelte, leggy blonde for the intelligent, athletic brunette?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, for many men, the answer is no, even if they would prefer to meet the latter lady. The result is that a lot of women feel that they aren’t desirable unless they look a particular way. The problem doesn’t just affect women, however.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Game, and Dating Advice for Men</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-the-game-and-dating-advice-for-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-the-game-and-dating-advice-for-men/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&amp;lt;iframe src=&amp;quot;http://rcm.amazon.com/e/cm?lt1=_blank&amp;amp;bc1=000000&amp;amp;IS2=1&amp;amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;amp;fc1=000000&amp;amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;amp;t=warrspir-20&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;p=8&amp;amp;l=as1&amp;amp;m=amazon&amp;amp;f=ifr&amp;amp;md=10FE9736YVPPT7A0FBG2&amp;amp;asins=0060554738&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;width:120px;height:240px;&amp;quot; scrolling=&amp;quot;no&amp;quot; marginwidth=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; marginheight=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt; &#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-447&#34; title=&#34;The_game&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/the_game.jpg?w=192&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;192&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;With the recent popularity of Neil Strauss&#39;s book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&amp;lt;iframe src=&amp;quot;http://rcm.amazon.com/e/cm?lt1=_blank&amp;amp;bc1=000000&amp;amp;IS2=1&amp;amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;amp;fc1=000000&amp;amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;amp;t=warrspir-20&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;p=8&amp;amp;l=as1&amp;amp;m=amazon&amp;amp;f=ifr&amp;amp;md=10FE9736YVPPT7A0FBG2&amp;amp;asins=0060554738&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;width:120px;height:240px;&amp;quot; scrolling=&amp;quot;no&amp;quot; marginwidth=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; marginheight=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt; &#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Game&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; there has been a lot of backlash against what some call &#39;dating advice for men&#39; and others (usually women, to be fair) call &#39;coaching men to take advantage of and manipulate women.&#39; The book is subtitled, &lt;em&gt;Penetrating the Secret Society of Pickup Artists,&lt;/em&gt; and that pretty much sums up what it is about. The author undertook to learn the ways of pickup artists for a year, ended up becoming one of the greatest pickup artists in the world (according to an internal rating), developed his own system, and eventually stepped out. He then wrote a book about his experiences, triggering a massive outpouring of additional pickup methods, books, how-to&#39;s, workshops, dating coaching seminars, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
