<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>strength on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/strength/</link>
    <description>Recent content in strength on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/strength/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Vulnerability is Actually Strength</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-vulnerability-is-actually-strength/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-vulnerability-is-actually-strength/</guid>
      <description>Some books change our lives. Daring Greatly was that kind of book for me. In the midst of an internal crisis this summer, I came across this book by Brene Brown, renowned researcher and author on vulnerability, courage, worthiness, and shame.
One of Brown&#39;s key points is that, in order to do great things, we have to embrace vulnerability. That feeling of exposing yourself is scary, but it&#39;s necessary because only by really reaching outside our comfort zones, by risking real pain or loss, can we achieve something really worth striving for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mantra for Strength</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/mantra-for-strength/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/mantra-for-strength/</guid>
      <description>Dwell not upon thy weariness, thy strength shall be according to thy desire. - Arab Proverb
 
In high school, I decided to become a vegetarian. At first, I was terrified and overwhelmed by the prospect of never eating meat again, but I realized that I didn&#39;t have to make such a large commitment at all. All I needed to do was to commit to not eating meat for that particular day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Don&#39;t Women Want to be Strong?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-dont-women-want-to-be-strong/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-dont-women-want-to-be-strong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“Go in peace my daughter. And remember that, in a world of ordinary mortals, you are a Wonder Woman.” Queen Hippolyte to Wonder Woman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2027&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;283&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/3896838102_1273912e8e.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-2027&#34; title=&#34;angie&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3896838102_1273912e8e-283x300.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;283&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/imagesbywestfall/3896838102/&#34;&gt;greg westfall on Flickr&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &#39;ideal&#39; woman is toned but not muscular, thin but not skinny (or is it the other way around?). She has curves, but no hips or butt. The &#39;ideal&#39; woman is also apparently defined solely by her body&#39;s appearance. &lt;strong&gt;The &#39;ideal&#39; woman is a biological contradiction&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what I have gathered as a guy, the world of exercise and fitness is a minefield for woman. It is promised as the path to a sexy, &lt;em&gt;thin&lt;/em&gt; body, but one misstep could lead a woman to functionally useful strength or worse, mannishness (which apparently means any visible muscle definition).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The phrase a &#39;strong woman&#39; brings to mind tenacity, persistence, mental toughness, but almost never physical strength. Why is that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My opinion is that standards of beauty should be a reflection of physical health: that which is considered beautiful ought to correlate to that which is healthy: a healthy human being, man or women, is a beautiful human being. Unfortunately, somewhere along the line, we associated feminine frailty with feminine beauty, to the detriment of women (and men) everywhere. The media has cemented this image, with even action heroines sporting builds that could never perform the stunts they execute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, my opinion doesn&#39;t matter all that much. If women want to conform to a standard of beauty that does not allow for health, that&#39;s their choice, and I know that for many women, attractiveness is a far, far more pressing concern than health. &lt;strong&gt;In fact, healthy behavior is pursued only as a means to acquire an attractive appearance.&lt;/strong&gt; This works to an extent because humans are hardwired to prefer the appearance of a healthy human over an unhealthy one. Biologically, attractiveness is an indicator of underlying health, so we seek out attractive mates because they are more likely to produce healthy offspring and survive the hardships of life. From an evolutionary perspective, attractiveness itself is not the desirable trait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We should be more concerned about health than about attractiveness&lt;/strong&gt;. Using diet and exercise in order to acquire a nice appearance begs the question of what happens when you no longer need or want to look attractive. Do you just start neglecting your health? After all, if health was only a means to look nice, it would only be pursued for the sake of appearance. There would be no concern about longevity, usefulness to others, or even respect for one&#39;s own body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human organism expresses its greatest health when it is functionally adept. When it can move well, it looks good. When it is well nourished, it looks good. That makes it attractive to others, as a side effect, as a flag telling others the organism is succeeding and flourishing. &lt;strong&gt;When you achieve vitality and vibrant health--when you flourish--you are beautiful&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Weakness the Smart Way</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/overcoming-weakness-the-smart-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/overcoming-weakness-the-smart-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1528&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;fPat on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/fpat/3375999258/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1528&#34; title=&#34;tigers&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/tigers-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I undertook the fourth installment of the CrossFit Sectionals Open Workouts. It looked right up my alley, involving two movements I am very good at - burpees and muscle ups - and only one that I wasn&#39;t - heavy overhead squat (really, I&#39;m not good at much that is heavy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I was confident I would do well. All I had to do was suffer through the squats in order to get to one of my strengths. Unfortunately, I found the squats too much, and I didn&#39;t even manage to finish them before the timer buzzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I felt defeated. Even with the advantage of having my strengths, I was stopped by one thing that I&#39;m weak at.&lt;/strong&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Instant Under the Bar</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/an-instant-under-the-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/an-instant-under-the-bar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1274&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Marc-Andre Casavant on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/casavant/4415188448/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1274&#34; title=&#34;olylift&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/olylift-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, over the course of something like two hours and 15-20 failed attempts, I managed to snatch 165 lbs, which is significant because that is my bodyweight (a snatch is an Olympic weightlifting movement in which you take a bar from the ground to overhead in one motion). I had set a bodyweight snatch as a goal almost a year ago, and had gotten to 160 lbs long before, but that elusive 5 lbs seemed impossible. Yesterday, I decided I would nail it, and in the end, it was mostly this determination that made the difference, rather than any actual performance improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unconventional Fitness Truths</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/unconventional-fitness-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/unconventional-fitness-truths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_883&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Source: JcOlivera.com on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/unconventional.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-883&#34; title=&#34;Guy exercising outdoor in Venice Beach&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/unconventional-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A bear, however hard he tries, grows tubby without exercise.” -Winnie the Pooh&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I began CrossFit two years ago, I&#39;ve learned some things about fitness that seem very counterintuitive. When I started training other people, one of my biggest challenges had been convincing people that what they&#39;ve always thought about fitness is wrong. Here are some common misconceptions that I&#39;ve discovered to be false, along with some strange truths that you wouldn&#39;t suspect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Brain is Making You Weak</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/your-brain-is-making-you-weak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/your-brain-is-making-you-weak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/06/brain.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-611&#34; title=&#34;brain&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/brain.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;There&#39;s a lot in the fitness community on how diet and exercise impact fitness and strength, and even a fair amount on sleep. Less discussed is the impact of mental state and the way the nervous system can interact with muscles to have a huge impact on athletic performance and strength. Since I&#39;ve been reading some alternative theories lately, I thought I&#39;d share some things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nervous Inhibition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s an interesting fact: by default, the nervous system limits muscle tension to 30% of what the associated tendons can bear. So if you can only lift 100lbs, it&#39;s not because your muscles are weak, it&#39;s because your brain is holding you back to protect the tendons. Probably the biggest factor limiting how strong we are is our own nervous system keeping our muscles down to protect us. Another related phenomenon is that the brain will inhibit agonist (primary mover) muscles if it perceives the antagonist is weak, in order to protect the joint. For example, your bicep will be inhibited if your triceps is weak because the brain will worry that, should things get out of hand, the triceps won&#39;t be able to counteract the bicep force.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
