<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lifestyle design on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/lifestyle-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lifestyle design on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/lifestyle-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Lifestyle Design is Broken</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-lifestyle-design-is-broken/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-lifestyle-design-is-broken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the &lt;em&gt;4-Hour Body&lt;/em&gt; was first released, I was so excited to read about quick, easily applied shortcuts to &#39;improve&#39; my life and my body. How could I resist the promise of becoming superhuman?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when I tried to apply the habits, none of them stuck. It wasn&#39;t that they didn&#39;t work, but they were hacks, not part of a cohesive lifestyle, and hacks are not meant to be permanent or sustainable. The &lt;em&gt;4-Hour Body&lt;/em&gt; in particular reads like a recipe book: you pick your abilities, like building a character in Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was Lifehacking applied to people, and while the allure was irresistible, it felt hollow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Out of the Box!</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/get-out-of-the-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/get-out-of-the-box/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1793&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;sxld on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/sxld/6123441787/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1793&#34; title=&#34;inthebox&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/inthebox-300x198.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;198&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are people living very happily right now without a home. There are people enjoying life floating on a boat or migrating from place to place with all their belongings on the backs of steppe ponies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are happy, successful people without stable, secure, 9-5 jobs. There are happy, fulfilled people working in mailrooms, stockrooms, and vast libraries, with minimal human interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are folks who are do all their work at night, hardly ever see the light of day, and who are perfectly healthy and well adjusted. There are some people, who do bring value to their communities, who live without any money at all, relying on their own ingenuity and the charity of their friends to get by, or they live as part of a self-sustaining community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a slightly more radical note, there are people getting a really good education without going to school and who have their dream jobs without ever finishing college, despite what our parents told us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
