<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>love on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/love/</link>
    <description>Recent content in love on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/love/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Life and Love</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-art-of-life-and-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-art-of-life-and-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, I took the Landmark Forum. For those of you who don&#39;t know, Landmark is a personal development coaching workshop that has a reputation for being confrontational. I wasn&#39;t a fan of their coaching method, but I certainly did learn a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One concept that forms the core of the Landmark approach to life is that life is meaningless, and that this fact is itself meaningless (which is kind of a clever solution to the problem, though it becomes contradictory considering the intention behind making the statement).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve been on Warrior Spirit for a while, you know that I&#39;ve spent a lot of time working on the idea that life has no inherent meaning. The conclusion I came to, and that which Landmark offered, is that we create the meaning in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, that is a simplistic answer that fails to capture the true nature of being, a creative, artistic act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tender-hearted Warrior</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-tender-hearted-warrior/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-tender-hearted-warrior/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“Real fearlessness is the product of tenderness. It comes from letting the world tickle your heart, your raw and beautiful heart. You are willing to open up, without resistance or shyness, and face the world. You are willing to share your heart with others.” - Chogyam Trungpa&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chogyam Trungpa said one of the defining traits of the spiritual warrior is a raw, vulnerable heart open to both the beautiful and the tragic. The main character in Dan Millman&#39;s &lt;em&gt;The Way of the Peaceful Warrior &lt;/em&gt;also learns the importance of allowing himself to open up his heart to both love and grieve when a friend&#39;s house burns down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Warrior Spirit is not characterized by a stony heart and ultimate pragmatism. It includes--even requires--a sensitive heart that can be inspired to action to protect the wonderful things in the world and to oppose the evil ones.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Warrior Spirit has a heart so sensitive, &#34;even if a tiny little mosquito lands on it, you feel touched.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait! This seems like a liability for us who commit ourselves to taking on the big challenges in the world and our lives. How can we hope to stand up to the manipulations of those with no moral limitations if we are so affected by our own?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, &lt;strong&gt;the reason there is such suffering and fear in the world is because we hardened our hearts in order to survive the disappointments and hardships of the world&lt;/strong&gt;. By cutting those things out, we also lost our ability to truly appreciate beauty and wonder and we entered into a cycle of emotional defensiveness: we hide in our comfortable houses that keep out the world, we get to work in protective luxury cars that keep out the noise of the street, we isolate ourselves from the suffering of others so we can pretend it doesn&#39;t exist, but we also never understand it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;To understand everything is to forgive everything. - Buddha</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love is Like Having a Cat...and a Temporary Goodbye</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/love-is-like-having-a-cat-and-a-temporary-goodbye/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/love-is-like-having-a-cat-and-a-temporary-goodbye/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&#34;attachment_2504&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34;] Heeeeey! Heeeey! Play with meee![/caption]
One of the problems with being my age is that I forget how inexperienced I am and how much I have to learn about myself and life in general. I sometimes trick myself into thinking I can do anything and everything. I am wrong, but I still persist, sometimes to my detriment and that of others around me. Nowhere is that truth driven home more forcefully than in relationships and the delicate dance that is loving another person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Process of Living</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-process-of-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-process-of-living/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_974&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;Source: mdezemery on flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mdezemery/311283302/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-974&#34; title=&#34;walking&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/walking-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;The journey is what brings us happiness not the destination.&#34; -&lt;em&gt;Dan Millman, The Peaceful Warrior&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the overriding themes that I refer to a lot is the idea that many important endeavors are ongoing. There is no end goal in mind, and having an end goal can often derail our efforts to improve. Instead, simply going through your routine, growing slowly and naturally, will get you where you want to go with less frustration and less pain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
