<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>efficiency on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/efficiency/</link>
    <description>Recent content in efficiency on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/efficiency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Patience</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/patience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1226&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;WasabiDoobie on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wasabidoobie/2448490111/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1226&#34; title=&#34;patience&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/patience-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Genius is only a greater aptitude for patience.” - George-Louis Leclerc de Buffon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have had a lot of waiting to do as my plans start to gain momentum. There are long periods during which nothing seems to bear any fruit. Farm to Table went silent for a long time, with almost no new comments or community engagement, leading me to get very discouraged. I was lacking motivation in my workouts and didn&#39;t really feel like I was making any progress. My blog seemed to be wallowing in obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, all of sudden things started to move very quickly, and I realized that it was the quiet times when things were starting to move towards a tipping point. I am getting a lot of people reaching out to connect over Farm to Table, there is a new energy in my training, and I am making all sorts of friends while reconnecting with old ones. It&#39;s almost more than I can handle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Engine is Bigger than Yours: Efficiency vs. Effectiveness in CrossFit</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-engine-is-bigger-than-yours-efficiency-vs-effectiveness-in-crossfit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-engine-is-bigger-than-yours-efficiency-vs-effectiveness-in-crossfit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/060910_1718_myengineisb1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt;Generally, when presented with any given task, we seek out the most efficient way to complete that task. The less time it takes, the less effort involved, the better. Not so often do we ask ourselves whether we&#39;re doing the right task or not. Is what we are doing actually the most effective way to reach our goals, or is it just busy-work? A Honda is more efficient than a Ferrari, but a Ferrari will get your where you&#39;re going much, much faster, making it more effective if your goal is saving time in transit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
