<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gymnastics on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/gymnastics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gymnastics on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/gymnastics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Review of Gold Medal Bodies Floor 1 Training Program</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/review-of-gold-medal-bodies-floor-1-training-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/review-of-gold-medal-bodies-floor-1-training-program/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/Floor-One_small.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-2422&#34; title=&#34;Floor-One_small&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/Floor-One_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;351&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I have always been inspired by gymnasts, who seem to defy gravity. When I started strengthening my own body, the first methods I used were based on gymnastics bodyweight movements: handstand pushups, pistol squats, jumps, dives, rolls, and pullups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it was always difficult to program a good bodyweight routine, and I spent years making progress then stalling, revising my approach, moving forward, stalling, etc. Most resources assume that if you&#39;re going to use the same movements as gymnasts, you must train as intensely as gymnasts, regardless of your goals. The programs were either too demanding, required too much time, or were absurdly complicated. It was a frustrating process, and the simplicity of barbell training was very tempting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I found &lt;a title=&#34;Gold Medal Bodies&#34; href=&#34;http://www.goldmedalbodies.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gold Medal Bodies&lt;/a&gt;, I got really excited. They specifically addressed the fact that, while gymnasts take these training methods to extremes for their sport, the movements and programs themselves don&#39;t need to be so difficult for the average person. In fact, Gold Medal Bodies (GMB) emphasized that they don&#39;t provide gymnastic training but rather draw from gymnastics (as well as yoga and martial arts).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their attitude towards training also mirrored my own: useful, holistic, comprehensive, not self-destructive, and fun. They really stress &lt;a title=&#34;Integrity of Movement, and My First RKC Class&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/integrity-of-movement-and-my-first-rkc-class/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;integrity of movement &lt;/a&gt;and body control, and consolidating strength exercises into applicable skills. Generally, I think they are one of the best things to happen to training. I downloaded their free handstand tutorial and in 1 week found myself finally getting a solid handstand, after 3 years of shaky results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was determined to try out GMB&#39;s main training programs, and after mentioning it in my book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Warrior Spirit Principles of Holistic Health&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/store/warrior-spirit-principles-of-holistic-health/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Warrior Spirit Principles of Holistic Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, they offered me my choice of program, so here is the review after my first two weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Truth About My Training and Diet</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-truth-about-my-training-and-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-truth-about-my-training-and-diet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1699&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;I&amp;#39;d rather be able to do this than have a fast Fran time. Source: Raphael Goetter on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/goetter/2567497624/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1699&#34; title=&#34;ironcross&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/ironcross-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a CrossFit trainer, I sometimes feel like I&#39;m not allowed to use, much less espouse, alternative forms of physical training or diet. But since I&#39;ve been caught so many times doing very un-CrossFit-like things, and a lot of people ask me what my training program is, or what my diet is, I thought I&#39;d come clean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Shouldn&#39;t Always Do Your Best</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-you-shouldnt-always-do-your-best/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-you-shouldnt-always-do-your-best/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1342&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Alex E. Proimos&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/proimos/4199675334/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1342&#34; title=&#34;Head in Hands&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/failure-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only the mediocre are always at their best - Jean Giradoux&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My gymnastics coach recently revealed to me that Olympic gymnasts are only able to perform their routines at the time they compete. Most of the time, they use spotters, and they periodize their training so that they peak when they compete. Many of them can&#39;t even perform some of their hardest skills on an everyday basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this isn&#39;t especially unique in the world of elite athletes, it does reveal an interesting aspect of excellence: &lt;strong&gt;when you are performing at such a high level, you cannot always be at your best&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Appreciation</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/teacher-appreciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/teacher-appreciation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1247&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Abhijit Tembhekar on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/abhijittembhekar/3345977842/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1247&#34; title=&#34;apple&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/apple-300x201.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wax on, wax off. - Mr. Miyagi, the Karate Kid (1984)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warriors are always seeking to grow and learn new things, so it makes sense that we&#39;d have a lot of teachers in our life. As the year comes to a close and I contemplate my card list, I&#39;m realizing that most of the people on it are my teachers and mentors. In the past two years, I&#39;ve acquired an unusually large number of teachers, of exceptionally good quality, and I realize that all the growth and knowledge I&#39;ve acquired is largely thanks to their efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If Failure is Not An Option, You Won&#39;t Fail</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/if-failure-is-not-an-option-you-wont-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/if-failure-is-not-an-option-you-wont-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1030&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;wolfsavard on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wolfsavard/4716421032/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1030&#34; title=&#34;nets&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/nets-300x200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;Do or do not. There is no try.&#34; - &lt;em&gt;Yoda,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Return of the Jedi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently learned a back handspring, and a front flip, among some other more complex gymnastics moves. Every time I want to try one without my coach to spot me, he considers whether I&#39;m ready, nods and says, &#34;Alright, give it a shot. The chance of seriously injuring yourself is probably less than 60/40.&#34; He is joking, sort of, but it is true that many of the stunts I attempt are actually quite dangerous. And that is why I don&#39;t mess up. &lt;strong&gt;Without safety nets, I can&#39;t afford to fail.&lt;/strong&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unconventional Fitness Truths</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/unconventional-fitness-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/unconventional-fitness-truths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_883&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Source: JcOlivera.com on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/unconventional.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-883&#34; title=&#34;Guy exercising outdoor in Venice Beach&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/unconventional-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A bear, however hard he tries, grows tubby without exercise.” -Winnie the Pooh&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I began CrossFit two years ago, I&#39;ve learned some things about fitness that seem very counterintuitive. When I started training other people, one of my biggest challenges had been convincing people that what they&#39;ve always thought about fitness is wrong. Here are some common misconceptions that I&#39;ve discovered to be false, along with some strange truths that you wouldn&#39;t suspect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrity: There is more to Life than Winning...There&#39;s being Awesome!</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-there-is-more-to-life-than-winning-theres-being-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-there-is-more-to-life-than-winning-theres-being-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/handstand.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-493&#34; title=&#34;handstand&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/handstand.jpg?w=199&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Since the CrossFit sectionals I&#39;ve been feeling considerably less motivated about my training. You&#39;d think that making it to regionals would give me a message that I have some potential, and that I should work hard to realize it. Instead, I feel oppressed by the prospect of competing again. All my training is geared towards this one event, an event that has a very narrow definition of success (even by the standards of CrossFit), and in which I will undoubtedly be one of the smallest, puniest, guys there. Maybe I&#39;m over-dramatizing here, but I definitely feel like an underdog - I&#39;m young, relatively weak (most guys at these things can deadlift 400+ lbs, I&#39;m around 315lb on a good day), and pretty inexperienced. If it&#39;s all about who can move the most weight, I&#39;m screwed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
