<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blogging on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/blogging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blogging on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy of a WS Blog Post</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/anatomy-of-a-ws-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/anatomy-of-a-ws-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“Writing is an exploration. You start from nothing and learn as you go.” E.L. Doctorow&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/3397858623_ff8e4ce060.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-2445&#34; title=&#34;Anatomy of a Blogger&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3397858623_ff8e4ce060.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;322&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An old writing teacher once told me it&#39;s better to be wordy and get the point across than try to cater to short attention spans and leave everyone scratching their heads. I learned in high school that if you write an engaging story, people will read 20 page sci-fi action adventures, long for high school creative writing. If you make it appeal to their emotions, they will even enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same thing goes for blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a writer with a blog, I want to make sure every post I write is engaging and inspiring. Learning how to write in this medium has been a long and arduous process. I am still refining it, but in recent months, I&#39;ve had a bit of success reaching new readers, so I wanted to share my current working template of my blog posts. Not all of them match this, of course (this one doesn&#39;t), but it serves as a loose framework to aim for.  It largely depends on how much time I have and how much energy I have after chasing &lt;del&gt;psychotic&lt;/del&gt; energetic Korean children around all day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m No Expert...And I Don&#39;t Want to Be</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/im-no-expert-and-i-dont-want-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/im-no-expert-and-i-dont-want-to-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1626&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;kevinpoh on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kevinpoh/3650866967/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1626&#34; title=&#34;Tai Chi Master&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/master-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started this blog, I had no aspirations to do  anything more than share my thoughts about life and the world. I figured some of the things I was going through might be  interesting to others, mainly my family. I didn’t really set out to tell  anyone how to live their life or even provide advice. I was just  sharing my experience of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This differs markedly from how blogs are getting used these days as a platform to establish the author as an expert with no other credentials besides the blog itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patience</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/patience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1226&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;WasabiDoobie on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wasabidoobie/2448490111/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1226&#34; title=&#34;patience&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/patience-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Genius is only a greater aptitude for patience.” - George-Louis Leclerc de Buffon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have had a lot of waiting to do as my plans start to gain momentum. There are long periods during which nothing seems to bear any fruit. Farm to Table went silent for a long time, with almost no new comments or community engagement, leading me to get very discouraged. I was lacking motivation in my workouts and didn&#39;t really feel like I was making any progress. My blog seemed to be wallowing in obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, all of sudden things started to move very quickly, and I realized that it was the quiet times when things were starting to move towards a tipping point. I am getting a lot of people reaching out to connect over Farm to Table, there is a new energy in my training, and I am making all sorts of friends while reconnecting with old ones. It&#39;s almost more than I can handle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Writer&#39;s Struggles as a Blogger</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-writers-struggles-as-a-blogger/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-writers-struggles-as-a-blogger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1223&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;amanky on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/amanky/2219631791/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1223&#34; title=&#34;blogging&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/blogging-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;Blogging is not rocket science, it’s about being yourself, and putting what you have into it.&#34; -Unknown&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogging is both a wonderful and a frustrating experience for a writer. On the one hand, it gives you the opportunity to put your ideas out there with no publishing costs and the freedom to write whatever you want. On the other hand, it leaves all the publicity up to you. It&#39;s like a journal that people might actually care about and read, and it creates the possibility of a self-crafted audience. I&#39;ve come a long way as a blogger, but I still find that I have a lot to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide to Warrior Spirit</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/guide-to-warrior-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/guide-to-warrior-spirit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You have probably noticed all the changes that have taken place recently around here. I just want to make sure everyone knows how things will be run from now on. The main changes have been the new subscription services and the posting schedule, as well as the focus of the posts. Here&#39;s a breakdown of what&#39;s new and what&#39;s to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Find Time to Write</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-i-find-time-to-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-i-find-time-to-write/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/typewriter.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-516&#34; title=&#34;Old typewriter help&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/typewriter.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I know that lately, I haven&#39;t been posting as regularly as  I used to. I&#39;ve felt the consequences. My readership has declined, and I feel like my writing style has gotten a little stiff from lack of flexing. Writing has always been a hugely important part of my life. Not only is it an artistic means to express myself, it has always been associated with periods of balance in my life; when I&#39;m writing regularly, my mind and spirit are in order, and a lot of other things as well. When I can&#39;t find the time to write, things slowly come apart at the seams. I don&#39;t really know why this is. Perhaps writing is how I parse my jumbled thoughts into discrete, comprehensible units called words and sentences, which I can then manipulate and act on in my life. Without taking the time to do this, my thoughts and ideas just fill to the brim and overflow in a messy jumble of psychic disorder. Writing is a form of meditation, a kind of waking dreaming for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Stand Out</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learning-to-stand-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learning-to-stand-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Standing out&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/entrepreneur1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;412&#34; height=&#34;309&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have already talked about one aspect of the mindset associated with this post-college, recessionary jobhunt, that of having confidence in my employability. I wanted to share some recent developments in my strategies and the way I&#39;m approaching things now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
