<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tedium on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/tedium/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tedium on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/tedium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Other Side of the Register</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-other-side-of-the-register/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-other-side-of-the-register/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;True compassion is true understanding. - Attributed to the Buddha&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My worst nightmare is standing behind the checkout counter at the local supermarket. He has been working there every day for 17 years, 8-10 hours. He goes to bed knowing that, upon waking, all he has to look forward to is another day, another week, another month, another year of standing at the same counter, scanning other peoples&#39; stuff, much of it stuff he can&#39;t afford. It&#39;s not that he&#39;s come to enjoy the job, but he has become numb to the quiet panic that pervades every one of his days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m describing an archetype, not an actual person, the life I don&#39;t want to lead, but a life I know many people do live. It is a life I cannot comprehend and one I&#39;m terrified of finding myself in. Knowing others who live it makes me uneasy because of the assumptions I have about human potential. I don&#39;t know anyone who aspires to being a cashier, and the mindset that can be happy and accept it is one I simply don&#39;t understand.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
