<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>warrior spirit on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/warrior-spirit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in warrior spirit on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/warrior-spirit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A 10 Minute Exercise that Will Change Your Day</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-10-minute-exercise-that-will-change-your-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-10-minute-exercise-that-will-change-your-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3907&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/watch-e1421889550877.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;watch&#34; width=&#34;698&#34; height=&#34;210&#34; /&gt;Imagine what your life would be like and what you&#39;d accomplish if you started &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; day full of passion, purpose and drive. Not just a few days a month, or a few hours of each day, but every hour of every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re probably thinking that&#39;d be great, but it&#39;s not realistic. After all, moods and mindsets are fickle, and people are either born with drive or they&#39;re not, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found myself asking the same question recently, and I decided to see if I could find an answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all my research on high achieving individuals, from the ultra-wealthy to the ultra-accomplished, I noticed that the biggest difference was their mindset. They ask different kinds of questions and see the world in a different way than the majority of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For an example of this, check out &lt;a title=&#34;KhanAcademy Interviews Elon Musk&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vDwzmJpI4io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sal Khan&#39;s interview of Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It dawned on me that an essential technique for increasing people&#39;s capabilities was to find a way for them to consistently elevate their mindset. Each day spent in a state of openness to possibility compounds on the previous ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is, for most of us, our mindset is determined by our mood, which is often determined by the events of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed a way to make sure that every day started with an empowered mindset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2015 Strategy Part 2: The Logistics of Being Awesome</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-2-the-logistics-of-being-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-2-the-logistics-of-being-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3880&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/timeclock-e1420568994227.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;timeclock&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;245&#34; /&gt;Last week, I shared &lt;a title=&#34;My 2015 Strategy Part 1: Dreams and Aspirations&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/my-2015-strategy-part-1-dreams-and-aspirations/&#34;&gt;my overarching strategy for 2015&lt;/a&gt; and how I got there, with a simple, but very helpful exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, I was planning to talk about specific actions and the structures I&#39;m going to put into place to support my plans, but it became a longer article than I&#39;d expected. So, I&#39;m going to limit it to logistics now, and actions on Thursday, because dreams without action will stay that way, and action without logistics will fizzle out real fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Quick Definitions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize not everyone here is a military history buff (or UPS admirer), so you may not be entirely familiar with what logistics are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, logistics are the support systems that enable an army to do its job. This includes things like food, transportation systems, and even lifestyle. The best trained Navy SEAL is useless without the entire support system that puts him in the right place to start his mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your personal life, it is important to create a system to support you. This includes things like your habits, your environment, and your routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good logistics are just as essential as good strategy and good tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Logistics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with last week&#39;s post was that I didn&#39;t account for time, energy, or financial resources; I simply wrote down everything I want to do in the next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this week, I&#39;ll show you how to handle the rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wake Up: The Not-So-Secret Key to Happiness</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/wake-up-the-not-so-secret-key-to-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/wake-up-the-not-so-secret-key-to-happiness/</guid>
      <description>“People say that what we’re all seeking is a meaning for life. I don’t think that’s what we’re really seeking. I think that what we’re seeking is an experience of being alive, so that our life experiences on the purely physical plane will have resonances with our own innermost being and reality, so that we actually feel the rapture of being alive.”- Joseph Campbell
 We spend so much time worrying about the future or reliving the past that we rarely if ever experience the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock the Vast Knowledge in Your Ancient DNA</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/unlock-the-vast-knowledge-in-your-ancient-dna/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/unlock-the-vast-knowledge-in-your-ancient-dna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently discovered a secret store of untapped skill and agility that anyone can use. I was out running on a trail with no shoes on, struggling mightily not to stub my toes on all the rocks and stones. It was mentally exhausting. I&#39;d just finished a novel: &lt;em&gt;God Emperor of Dune.&lt;/em&gt; One of the main characters in this book has conscious access to all his ancestor&#39;s memories and experiences, encoded in his DNA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It occurred to me that &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; body also contains the DNA of all of my ancestors, millions of whom probably spent a lot of time running on rugged trails. In fact, encoded into my DNA and all that has arisen out of it are the instincts of tens of millions (maybe more) organisms, not all human, that spent their entire lives navigating wild, treacherous terrain. Along the way, there must have been some creation of an instinct that helped these creatures manage rocky trails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, no matter how my life had progressed, &lt;strong&gt;I could not deny that there was in fact some remnant of all that history within me, if only in the way my DNA was constructed&lt;/strong&gt;. The experience of my ancestors, all the way back to the first proto-life, had created the blueprint for my existence and the framework around which my brain and nervous system were built. It seemed reasonable to think that perhaps there were some useful instincts prebuilt into me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to try something. I stopped consciously thinking about where to put my feet. I let go of the need to control my body and leaned forward to pick up speed, forcing my reflexes to direct my actions in order to avoid injury. I trusted my feet and my body&#39;s intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You Too Stupid to Understand Your Health?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/are-you-too-stupid-to-understand-your-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/are-you-too-stupid-to-understand-your-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/paleomeal.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3055&#34; alt=&#34;paleomeal&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/paleomeal-300x200.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wild lettuce is nearly inedible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How strange that this food, touted as one of the healthiest icons of a simple, wholesome diet, is not a food humans regularly consumed prior to the advent of agriculture. Wild carrots are woody and fibrous; wild avocados had hardly enough meat to be worth eating; bananas were so full of seeds they would be inedible to modern people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently learned all this watching a video entitled, &#34;&lt;a title=&#34;Debunking the Paleo Diet&#34; href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BMOjVYgYaG8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Debunking the Paleo Myth&lt;/a&gt;&#34; (as usual, I&#39;m way behind the curve). I knew that much of Paleo was based on romantic  but unrealistic notions of Paleolithic cavemen and women living in an edenic utopia chasing mammoth for exercise and eating garden salads, but I had no idea how far off we were.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Priorities: Matching Reality to Your Values</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/priorities-matching-reality-to-your-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/priorities-matching-reality-to-your-values/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/213085702_8d5e812d9d.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2958&#34; alt=&#34;New Changed Priorities Ahead&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/213085702_8d5e812d9d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Upon returning from my trip to Utah, I&#39;ve found myself caught in a whirlwind of activity, trying to catch up with all sorts of projects. This hasn&#39;t given me time to act on the important things that are normally part of my routine, nor the amazing insights I gained in the desert of the Canyonlands. That&#39;s one reason this post is late. It is a pattern I&#39;ve noticed in myself before, when I lived in Korea and was trying to establish a match between the life and wanted and the life I ended up living.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every now and then, it&#39;s good to take stock of how closely the life you&#39;re actually living matches the life you want to be living. Are the things that are important to you getting their due, or are they just sitting on the back burner, day after day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I find that stress tends to lead me to give up on my routines and plans with the excuse of surviving or making do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s like that saying about putting your head down and plowing through. You don&#39;t know (or don&#39;t want to know) where you&#39;re going, you just need to get through whatever&#39;s in front you, as fast as possible, without regard to finesse or tact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But the problem with doing that is that sometimes you move forward only to look up to find yourself somewhere you didn&#39;t mean to go&lt;/strong&gt;. Then you&#39;ve got to go back or find another way. You&#39;ve wasted effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or worse, because you haven&#39;t taken the time to plot your course, you end up barreling into another crisis situation, and the only way to deal with that is to do the same thing that got you there in the first place. Then, you become a slave to events, moving in the direction set by each crisis. At first, you are just telling yourself, &#34;I just need to get through this week, then everything will be back on track.&#34; But when that week passes, you haven&#39;t taken the time to set your course, and it becomes another week or &#39;getting through,&#39; then another, then another, until you find yourself lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Warrior is Not a Fighter</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-warrior-is-not-a-fighter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-warrior-is-not-a-fighter/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&#34;attachment_2347&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;] A classic depiction of a Buddhist warrior, often as guardians in temples to keep away demons[/caption]
“When I was in the army, I was a soldier. I was a puppet doing whatever anybody told me to do, even if it meant going against what my heart told me was right. I didn’t know nothing about being a warrior until I hit the streets and marched alongside my brothers for something I really believed in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freeing the Zoo Humans: Why I Want to Become a MovNat Instructor</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/movnat-instructor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/movnat-instructor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/cagedworld.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2117&#34; title=&#34;cagedworld&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/cagedworld-283x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;283&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“Learning is all about freedom. The more you know, the more options you have. Knowledge is both liberating and empowering.” ~Erwan Le Corre&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time I read &lt;a title=&#34;MovNat Men&#39;s Health Article&#34; href=&#34;http://www.menshealth.com/fitness/fitness-survive-wild&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chris McDougall&#39;s article on MovNat in Men&#39;s Health&lt;/a&gt; back in 2009, I couldn&#39;t stop staring at the computer screen, rolling over what it meant in my mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Somewhere, in the forests of Brazil, &lt;a title=&#34;Erwan Le Corre MovNat Sampler&#34; href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m61t3ObnSP0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;there was a man living in harmony with nature&lt;/a&gt;, climbing trees, vaulting over rocks, carrying logs, jumping from boulder to boulder, teaching people to grow past the limits of their sad, domesticated bodies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever seen something and immediately felt, &#34;I have &lt;em&gt;got&lt;/em&gt; to do that. If there is one thing I must do in my life, this...is...it!&#34;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t just want to go do one workshop and be done with it. I wanted to live it. I wanted to be that wild and free. I wanted to get so good, I&#39;d give Le Corre, the founder, a run for his money. I wanted to spread the word, show people that being healthy &lt;a title=&#34;Fitness is Not Health&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/fitness-is-not-health/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;doesn&#39;t mean hours on a treadmill&lt;/a&gt; or tedious, repetitive movement. It can--it should--mean &lt;a title=&#34;Move and Be Free&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/move-and-be-free/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;vibrant, moving, freedom&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the article provided more information on the history of Methode Naturelle, the precursor to MovNat, than information on MovNat itself. MovNat at the time was small and not well-known. I was in college, broke, beat down by my studies at one of the most masochistic universities in the country, and &lt;strong&gt;very, very far away from running wild and free in the forests of Brazil&lt;/strong&gt;. I was at a dead end, but the seed had been planted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Things You Need for a Complete Life (my mother agrees)</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/3-things-complete-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/3-things-complete-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/2259908021_e2ac9dd376.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2068&#34; title=&#34;Three Leaves&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/2259908021_e2ac9dd376-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;One of the most frustrating things about this blog is that I don&#39;t really know what I&#39;m writing about. It&#39;s my view on life, but it&#39;s been a real pain figuring out what the overarching theme on my life is. I mean, how do you tie together my interest in &lt;a title=&#34;Empty Your Cup: Accepting Ignorance to Learn&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/empty-your-cup-accepting-ignorance-to-learn/&#34;&gt;Buddhist spirituality&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title=&#34;A New Understanding of Fitness and the Human Body&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/a-new-understanding-of-fitness-and-the-human-body/&#34;&gt;evolutionary fitness&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title=&#34;Returning to the Dojo: The Importance of Martial Arts&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/&#34;&gt;martial arts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title=&#34;Book Review: The Omnivore’s Dilemma&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/book-review-the-onivores-dilemma/&#34;&gt;local food&lt;/a&gt;, environmentalism, &lt;a title=&#34;The Value of Failure&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-value-of-failure/&#34;&gt;positive psychology&lt;/a&gt;, and holistic personal health and growth? To me, all of those things are one and the same, but Google keyword searches don&#39;t generally group them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then I realized that this blog isn&#39;t really about &lt;em&gt;those &lt;/em&gt;things. It is about the approach to living that &lt;em&gt;led&lt;/em&gt; me to those things.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what are the keywords of my life? What about my approach to life led me to adopt evolutionary fitness instead of Fatbusters 2.0?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt; I Prefer the Term...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since reading &lt;em&gt;Shambhala: The Sacred Path of the Warrior&lt;/em&gt;, I&#39;ve spent some time thinking about the words I want to describe me and my lifestyle. I have already written a lot about Integrity, and I know that is a central part of who I want to be and what I believe characterizes the Warrior Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since all good things come in threes, I needed two more words. Naturally, I looked to the most annoying things about me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money is a Gift; Lessons Learned in Business</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/money-is-a-gift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/money-is-a-gift/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1892&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;stevendepolo on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stevendepolo/3703145222/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1892&#34; title=&#34;gifts&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/gifts-300x200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently been burned in two business interactions that left me hurting both financially and personally. Not only did I lose money, I felt taken advantage of and cheapened. I invited my clients to undervalue my hard work by undervaluing it myself. It’s a hard pill to swallow, but I realize it’s all part of the learning process, and the more I delve into business, the more I realize how much &lt;a title=&#34;The Principles of ‘Good’ Business&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-principles-of-good-business/&#34;&gt;good business&lt;/a&gt; relies on good character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Linchpin; and, How to Create a Self-Study Course to Master Anything</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-linchpin-and-how-to-create-a-self-study-course-to-master-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-linchpin-and-how-to-create-a-self-study-course-to-master-anything/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&#34;attachment_1872&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Vola Vale on Flickr&#34;][/caption]
“The best contribution one can make to humanity is to improve oneself.” - Anon
 I’ve always felt that learning is one of the best ways to improve oneself (I guess you could get philosophical and point out that self-improvement is essentially learning in one form or another). Reading books is one of the best ways to learn, which is why I include a lot of book reviews here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret of Unleashing Creativity</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-secret-of-unleashing-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-secret-of-unleashing-creativity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1868&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;416style on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/sookie/149498941/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1868&#34; title=&#34;Blank Canvas&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/149498941_c1e8d9cd08-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Sometimes you&#39;ve got to let everything go - purge yourself. If you are unhappy with anything . . . whatever is bringing you down, get rid of it. Because you&#39;ll find that when you&#39;re free, your true creativity, your true self comes out.” - Tina Turner&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creativity! The word rings of freedom, personal fulfillment, making a difference. It is how we contribute to the world around us and &lt;em&gt;create&lt;/em&gt; new realities out of our ideas. Most of us were very creative when we were young. When I was younger, I was immensely creative. I would write short stories daily. I was constantly drawing things on my school papers, and I filled up several sketchbooks. I even wrote poetry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, I thought that my creativity was the result of a messy, hectic life, but my life got a lot messier in college, right about the time my creativity disappeared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did You Forget Why You Came This Way?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/did-you-forget-why-you-came-this-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/did-you-forget-why-you-came-this-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1862&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;David Spinks on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/davidspinks/4453498888/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1862&#34; title=&#34;Above the Clouds&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/4453498888_f576a9afd5-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyday, I wake up earlier than I want to, and work longer than I want do, at a job that wasn’t my idea, creating something that was never on my radar for things I want to accomplish in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, why do I do it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presumably to get paid so that I can live, but walking through the snow yesterday to the school where I work, I couldn’t help but wonder what the point of making enough money to live was. What would I do with the living that I earned? Just make more living, more money, so that I could go on buying food and renting a roof over my head?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I felt the need to rise above the clouds of my day-to-day for a little bit, to get a wider perspective on my life and why I do what I do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The One Thing You Can Do To Make Everything Better</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-one-thing-you-can-do-to-make-everything-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-one-thing-you-can-do-to-make-everything-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1850&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;tanakawho on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/28481088@N00/1069809120/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1850&#34; title=&#34;lotus&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/lotus-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He who has health, has hope. And he who has hope, has everything&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.thinkexist.com/quotation/he_who_has_health-has_hope-and_he_who_has_hope/149145.html&#34;&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;” - Proverb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Leave all the afternoon for exercise and recreation, which are as necessary as reading. I will rather say more necessary because health is worth more than learning.” - Thomas Jefferson&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the one thing you can do to improve almost every aspect of your life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be honest, I don’t know you, but the thing that makes the biggest difference in my day to day life is looking after my health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this means eating right, &lt;a title=&#34;Lessons Learned as a Trainer and Athlete&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/lessons-learned-as-a-trainer-and-athlete/&#34;&gt;exercising regularly and intensely&lt;/a&gt;, and getting enough sleep. It means I take my health into my own hands, instead of just accepting what the government or the media tells me. It’s your body; take the time to get to know it, what makes it happy, and what is good for it, instead of relying on people who have zero interest in your well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few of the really obvious effects looking after my health has had. Most of them have nothing to do with the body itself, but instead are reflections on the areas of life that we really live for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Education of Millionaires</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-the-education-of-millionaires/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-the-education-of-millionaires/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/The-Education-of-Millionaires.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1844&#34; title=&#34;The-Education-of-Millionaires&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/The-Education-of-Millionaires-198x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;198&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Every now and then, a book comes along that redefines the way you see the world. Michael Ellsberg&#39;s book is just such a one. It snares you with its controversial premise: &lt;strong&gt;higher education fails to provide the skills necessary to be successful in the real world&lt;/strong&gt;. It keeps you reading by explaining what skills you &lt;em&gt;do &lt;/em&gt;need and how to get them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone who has every wondered why, with their expensive degree and pristine grades, they are stuck working meaningless jobs that make no use of their skills, this book provides both the answer and the solution to bettering their chances to make it. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;The Education of Millionaires&#34; href=&#34;http://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/education-of-millionaires-michael-ellsberg/1103297348?ean=9781591844204&amp;amp;itm=1&amp;amp;usri=the+education+of+millionaires&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Education of Millionaires&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; basically presents a course list for success in business and entrepreneurship&lt;/strong&gt;. It is a strong advocate of &lt;a title=&#34;The Principles of &#39;Good&#39; Business&#34; href=&#34;http://wp.me/p15g8X-tF&#34;&gt;business with integrity&lt;/a&gt; and success as a means to make a positive difference in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principles of &#39;Good&#39; Business</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-principles-of-good-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-principles-of-good-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1840&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;digitalmoneyworld on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/digitalcurrency/2438117961/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1840&#34; title=&#34;gold&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/gold-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Success means having the courage, the determination, and the will to become the person you believe you were meant to be” -George Sheehan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently finished a series three books on how to change the world, how to give as much as possible to your community, and how to help others get the things they need. The first was a book on how to become wealthy, the second was a book about becoming indispensable to your company, and the third was simply a book about selling. Yes, these were business books, but not business books in the way I usually think about the genre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Holiday Thanks You&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-holiday-thanks-yous/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-holiday-thanks-yous/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1856&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;jenny downing on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jenny-pics/3108467816/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1856&#34; title=&#34;holidaytrees&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/holidaytrees-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love this time of year. The cozy winter drinks, the warm crackling fires after a day in the cold, people bundled up but still extending warm greetings and presents. While it&#39;d be great to be this thoughtful all year, it is still nice to step out of our self-centered mindset, even if just for a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The holidays are a time when people take a moment to remember the important people in their lives. My usual holiday tradition has been to write handwritten cards to all the people who have made a difference in my life in the past year. It&#39;s sort of a massive thank you note for the intangible things that my friends have done for me throughout the year, whether that was just to be there and listen, to hang out and have fun, or give me much-needed help or advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, however, I got so caught up in my move to South Korea that I didn&#39;t get around to making all the cards. So, if you don&#39;t get something from me, please know that doesn&#39;t mean I forgot, just that life has been very busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I wanted to take this opportunity to say thank you to my community. This past year, I&#39;ve learned that so much of what makes us who we are is who makes up our community. We are, to a very large extent, the result of our friends, families, followers, and teachers. &lt;strong&gt;I want to acknowledge just how much of who I am is the result of the generous contributions of others who have seen something in me worth supporting&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Going to Make It</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/were-going-to-make-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/were-going-to-make-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1836&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;mikbaird on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mikebaird/2087879492/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1836&#34; title=&#34;clearingthewave&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/clearingthewave-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a point in every challenging experience where you go from questioning whether you&#39;ve got what it takes to survive and to feeling secure that things will be alright. You&#39;ve been staring up at an impending wave, not sure you&#39;ll get to the other side, but now you&#39;re on top, and you can see the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me living in Korea, I passed that point a few days ago. Nothing really has changed around me, but something inside me clicked. Finding my balance point is less of a daily struggle, I&#39;m starting to groove my daily paths and activities and get a sense for my surroundings. A and I have slowly transformed our apartment into a living space that reflects the kind of lives we want to live, so we are no longer fitting ourselves into someone else&#39;s living space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like I can see further and, while I may not feel that I&#39;ve accomplished that state of security just yet, I know it is attainable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empty Your Cup: Accepting Ignorance to Learn</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/empty-your-cup-accepting-ignorance-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/empty-your-cup-accepting-ignorance-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1828&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Neal on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/31878512@N06/4748872561/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1828&#34; title=&#34;teacup&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/teacup-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A university professor went to visit a famous Zen master. While the master quietly served tea, the professor talked about Zen. The master poured the visitor&#39;s cup to the brim, and then kept pouring. The professor watched the overflowing cup until he could no longer restrain himself. &#34;It&#39;s overfull! No more will go in!&#34; the professor blurted. &#34;You are like this cup,&#34; the master replied, &#34;How can I show you Zen unless you first empty your cup.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently moved to South Korea to teach English to kids for a year. Adjusting to the new culture has been both humorous and challenging; things that I usually consider very simple have become extremely difficult. Basics of living—eating healthy, exercising regularly, and even basic hygiene—have new rules and best practices that I just don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve had to accept that I really don’t know how to do much around here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Call to Write</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-call-to-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-call-to-write/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1822&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;229&#34; caption=&#34;aussiegall in Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/aussiegall/5630368331/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1822&#34; title=&#34;bloom&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/bloom-229x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;229&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As long as we are persistence in our pursuit of our deepest destiny, we will continue to grow. We cannot choose the day or time when we will fully bloom. It happens in its own time.” --Denis Waitley&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I haven’t posted to Warrior Spirit in a very long time. My concern was that the topic of the blog was becoming too vague and nebulous. I aspire to write stories for adventure magazines and grand science-fiction epics, neither of which were things this blog showcased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides that, I haven’t found Warrior Spirit to be especially rewarding. There is very little community interaction on the blog. Articles don’t get shared often, nobody links to the blog, and I don’t get many comments. Sometimes I felt like I was writing in a vacuum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to put it to rest and focus on other, more concrete projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then, I received a direct request to continue Warrior Spirit&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Myth&#39;s to Live By</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-myths-to-live-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-myths-to-live-by/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/mythstoliveby.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-1814&#34; title=&#34;mythstoliveby&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/mythstoliveby.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;128&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We are all the heroes of our own personal myths. No surprise there. What is really surprising is that all of our myths follow the same basic story arc. At least, this is the claim of Joseph Campbell, whose research into the mythologies of the world over has revealed that all cultures have strikingly similar myth’s underlying the basic fabric of society, the guide the development of the members of that society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Willpower</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-willpower/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-willpower/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/willpowerbook.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-1796&#34; title=&#34;willpowerbook&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/willpowerbook.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;144&#34; height=&#34;220&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Life is full of paradox. Eating fat doesn’t make you fat. Running in shoes can be bad for your feet. Giving yourself free reign to express your every desire and emotion can mire your personal growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last one will require some explanation, especially since there is a lot of talk here on Warrior Spirit about the importance of listening to your heart and following your dreams, no matter what comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve just finished a book summarizing the psychological research on the topic of willpower and self-control. The book, &lt;em&gt;Willpower, &lt;/em&gt;by psychologists Roy F. Baumeister and John Tierney, is rife with examples of how the failure to set and follow limitations leads to a breakdown of character. It is mainly a survey of the research, but what makes it readable is the authors’ sincere interest in helping the reader, and the interviews with such characters as endurance artist David Blaine (who spent 63 hours encased in a block of ice in Times Square) and Amanda Palmer (known for her tabloid-friendly outbursts). The authors also draw examples on how willpower can be utilized from Ophrah, Eric Clapton and Henry Morton Stanley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Out of the Box!</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/get-out-of-the-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/get-out-of-the-box/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1793&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;sxld on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/sxld/6123441787/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1793&#34; title=&#34;inthebox&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/inthebox-300x198.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;198&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are people living very happily right now without a home. There are people enjoying life floating on a boat or migrating from place to place with all their belongings on the backs of steppe ponies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are happy, successful people without stable, secure, 9-5 jobs. There are happy, fulfilled people working in mailrooms, stockrooms, and vast libraries, with minimal human interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are folks who are do all their work at night, hardly ever see the light of day, and who are perfectly healthy and well adjusted. There are some people, who do bring value to their communities, who live without any money at all, relying on their own ingenuity and the charity of their friends to get by, or they live as part of a self-sustaining community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a slightly more radical note, there are people getting a really good education without going to school and who have their dream jobs without ever finishing college, despite what our parents told us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the Worst that Could Happen</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/whats-the-worst-that-could-happen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/whats-the-worst-that-could-happen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1789&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Elsie esq. on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/elsie/4537706/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1789&#34; title=&#34;lightening&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/lightening-300x237.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;237&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My girlfriend and I have been planning to live and work abroad for the past year, and recently all of our plans completely fell apart thanks to a school that went back on our contract. The result was that we spent two weeks scrambling for another position, another job, or just anything to move our lives forward. For two weeks, we were in total limbo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aging Gloriously</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/aging-gloriously/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/aging-gloriously/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1784&#34; align=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;me&amp;#39;nthedogs on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/66176388@N00/5194802905/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1784&#34; title=&#34;stag&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/stag-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember in Bambi how much of a wimp Bambi was as a young buck? Compared to his father, the king of the forest, he was still just a whelp, even though technically a fully grown deer. His father, on the other hand, was a fully mature stag, quite literally an embodiment of the spirit of the forest. How often do we see out own parents that way: at the peak of their power, rather than in decline?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grow to Live: Why Constant Improvement is Necessary</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/grow-to-live-why-constant-improvement-is-necessary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/grow-to-live-why-constant-improvement-is-necessary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1778&#34; align=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Rob Young on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/rob-young/2042586449/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1778&#34; title=&#34;brucelee&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/brucelee-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously, if you always put limits on what you can do, physical or anything else, it’ll spread over into the rest of your life. It’ll spread into your work, into your morality, into your entire being. There are no limits. There are plateaus, but you must not stay there, you must go beyond them. If it kills you, it kills you. A man must constantly exceed his level. -Bruce Lee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bruce Lee was one of the greatest martial artists who ever lived. But did he think that gave him an excuse to stop improving? If the above quotation is any indication, the answer is no. Bruce Lee was always growing and always pushing his limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service with a Smile</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/service-with-a-smile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/service-with-a-smile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1774&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Highways Agency on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/highwaysagency/6011466786/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1774&#34; title=&#34;HA0476 Traffic Officers New Uniform. August 2009. This set of images describes several subjects including Traffic Officers on the network, in their TO vehicles, helping to the public and working at Regional Control Centre.&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/servesmile-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They say kids these days seem to have a sense of entitlement. Since ‘they’ were referring to ‘kids’ my age (aka, me) I tended to disagree with this statement. Apparently a lot of kids my age are turning down low-level service oriented jobs because we think we are above that sort of work. I tell myself I am endowed with good old fashioned values, can exercise self-discipline, and am not afraid to get my hands dirty. I can do menial tasks well and cheerfully, glad at the opportunity to be a part of something, even if just a small part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what’s more, I LOVE helping other people! I live to serve!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then my dad asked me to help him take the car in for service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>True Mastery Questions Everything</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/true-mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/true-mastery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1768&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;kaibara87 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kaibara/2756361218/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1768&#34; title=&#34;sidekick&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/sidekick-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My karate instructor is an independent thinker. In a field that is basically defined by its adherence to tradition, his insistence on questioning everything is pretty gutsy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving Up On My Dream of Being a Soldier</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/giving-up-on-my-dream-of-being-a-soldier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/giving-up-on-my-dream-of-being-a-soldier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1760&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;The U.S. Army on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/soldiersmediacenter/478415299/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1760&#34; title=&#34;soldier&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/soldier-300x186.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;186&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always had an interest in joining the military. I wanted to be a jet fighter pilot, or a special forces operative. For the first time in my life, I have no reason to be afraid of the physical demands of the job; I routinely best soldiers in fitness competitions, and I could pass the special forces entrance exams. I’m confident enough in myself to withstand the rigors of training, and I feel more certain than ever that I could benefit from the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I have had to let go of that dream as I’ve come to understand the realities of what a soldier does. In order to live out my dream, I would have to compromise on a lot of things that are really important to me. This isn’t because of the nature of the military generally, but rather the way the system is set up currently. I could get behind fighting against Hitler in World War II, but I have never been very good at investing myself in other peoples’ agendas if I don’t believe in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Imminence of Death</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-immanence-of-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-immanence-of-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1754&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Kretyen on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kretyen/2957442267/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1754&#34; title=&#34;vulture&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/vulture-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I was a little kid, I’ve had a powerful sense of the imminence of my own death. Not that I expected to die in the near future, but I was always painfully aware that one day would be my last, and eventually, I would cease to experience anything ever again. I would get panic attacks mulling over the reality of my mortality. For a 9 year-old kid, that’s pretty heavy stuff. I still sometimes catch my mind wandering over to the other side, and as a result, my whole life I’ve carried with me an urgency to make the most of my time. I don’t know whether this is common or not, but I’m just acutely aware that one day, there will be no more me.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Can&#39;t You Have What You Want?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-cant-you-have-what-you-want/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-cant-you-have-what-you-want/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1750&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;AZRainman on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/azrainman/992631266/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1750&#34; title=&#34;Reach for the Clouds&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/reachfortheclouds-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day I find myself surrounded by people who are unhappy with their lot in life. They don&#39;t have the body they want, the job they want, the partner they want, or the skills they want. Every day they want to be something they aren&#39;t, and every day instad of making progress towards their dreams, they distract themselves or rationalize away their inability to have what they want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ve Got to Be A Little Crazy</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youve-got-to-be-a-little-crazy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youve-got-to-be-a-little-crazy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve often wondered how great things get accomplished in this world. It&#39;s so hard to get past the day-to-day of basic social niceties, the need to make a living, following current fashion trends, and doing what&#39;s expected of you. How does anyone have time to do anything else? Where do you find the time to redefine a field when most modern fields require all your time just to stay current? How do you become all that you can be when being the bare minimum is a full time job?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking your productive potential; reshape your standards to fit your goals</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/unlocking-you-productive-potential-reshape-your-standards-to-fit-your-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/unlocking-you-productive-potential-reshape-your-standards-to-fit-your-goals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1740&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;190&#34; caption=&#34;seier+seier on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/seier/2164161632/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1740&#34; title=&#34;biggoals&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/biggoals-190x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;190&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post from Eric Fulwiler, an Account Executive at VaynerMedia, am NYC digital agency specializing in social. He blogs at &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ericfulwiler.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog.ericfulwiler.com&lt;/a&gt;, and you can find him on Twitter @EFulwiler.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do we find certain  activities easier than others? It&#39;s so easy for us to sit down and watch a 3-hour baseball game (at least, for some of us), but it&#39;s so hard for us to sit down for 3 hours and write a Powerpoint presentation. Part of it is certainly because baseball is more entertaining than Powerpoint (again, for some of us), but the bigger issue here is the standards and expectations that we have created for ourselves. We have standards embedded within our mentality that dictate the ease and attractiveness of certain activities. We have chosen to believe that baseball is easier than Powerpoint. And these choices have resulted in standards that frequently present obstacles to our personal or professional productivity. But for those of us who accept that we can control these standards, we can realign them to further our goals, and significantly increase our productivity and potential.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Merits of Minimalism</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-merits-of-minimalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-merits-of-minimalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1736&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;striatic on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/striatic/729822/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1736&#34; title=&#34;stuff&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/stuff-300x297.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;297&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have spent the last week helping my family move our home, which is partly why I&#39;ve been remiss in posting for so long. We are downsizing because the kids are out of the nest (even though I still live at home and my sister just moved back after college. Go figure). My parents are trying to save space and money, but doing so required us to come to grips with the fact that we have tons of stuff, massive quantities of things we didn&#39;t even remember we owned, from all over the world, much of it outdated and unusable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving Nails</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/driving-nails/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/driving-nails/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1722&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Orin Zebest on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/orinrobertjohn/5591952304/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1722&#34; title=&#34;fence&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/fence-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When I was a kid, I used to read a lot of morality tales, and one of my favorite was about the effects of harsh words and the effectiveness of apology. Here it is, as best I can remember.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A young boy had a bad temper. He would yell at his sister and his mother, and was very impertinent to his father. Generally, he was a pain, and he was pretty much immune to all forms of discipline and punishment, though his parents tried their best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Truth About My Training and Diet</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-truth-about-my-training-and-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-truth-about-my-training-and-diet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1699&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;I&amp;#39;d rather be able to do this than have a fast Fran time. Source: Raphael Goetter on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/goetter/2567497624/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1699&#34; title=&#34;ironcross&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/ironcross-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a CrossFit trainer, I sometimes feel like I&#39;m not allowed to use, much less espouse, alternative forms of physical training or diet. But since I&#39;ve been caught so many times doing very un-CrossFit-like things, and a lot of people ask me what my training program is, or what my diet is, I thought I&#39;d come clean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Is It Taking So Long to Move Out?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-is-it-taking-so-long-to-move-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-is-it-taking-so-long-to-move-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1695&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;Gerry T on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gerrythomasen/108568250/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1695&#34; title=&#34;pajamas&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/pajamas-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently saw a really humorous series of short videos about how to be suave while living at your parents’ house after college. A young man in a bathrobe introduced himself as so many of us graduates do: a list of impressive academic accomplishments, compelling personality traits, a powerful drive for success, and, oh yeah, unemployed and living at home. The narrator then goes on to explain how to ‘be suave’ while living around your parents. For example, dealing with the fact that your mom still does your laundry, or capitalizing on recurring fashion cycles to make use of your dad’s wardrobe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ingredients for an Excellent Day</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/ingredients-for-an-excellent-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/ingredients-for-an-excellent-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1691&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Advertise2win on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/advertise2win/5383858717/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1691&#34; title=&#34;happydog&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/happydog-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This dog is having a great day&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been trying to find a way to have consistently awesome days, and after much trial and error (most of it documented on this blog), I&#39;ve come up with the following list of activities that seem to contribute to days worth having. The elements are pretty open-ended, and allow for multiple interpretations or ways of meeting the requirements, but they help me make sure I cover all the important bases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Be Less Pleasing and More Likeable</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-be-less-pleasing-and-more-likeable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-be-less-pleasing-and-more-likeable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1687&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;tibchris on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/arcticpuppy/4536529954/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1687&#34; title=&#34;big smile&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/big-smile-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I tried to please people, they never gave me their approval. When I stopped trying, they sought my approval.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accept That You&#39;re Just Weird</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/accept-that-youre-just-weird/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/accept-that-youre-just-weird/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1683&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Thomas Shahan on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/opoterser/2913192415/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1683&#34; title=&#34;weirdspider&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/weirdspider-300x195.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;195&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have come to the realization that I am a weird dude.  Furthermore, I have finally accepted that I am one of the weirdest  people I know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while, I was holding out that I just had a few  eccentricities related to my exercise and dietary habits. After a while,  though, these things started to impact other areas of my life, and the  weirdness started to grow. An interest in barefoot running turned into a  general refusal to wear shoes. A concern with healthy food led to  eating raw meat. It became very hard to deny that I’m just strange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Need to Question the Foundations of our Culture</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/we-need-to-question-the-foundations-of-our-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/we-need-to-question-the-foundations-of-our-culture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1674&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;The U.S. Army on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/soldiersmediacenter/4685688778/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1674&#34; title=&#34;100604-D-7203C-005.JPG&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/question-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traffic has been especially bad lately. As I worked my way through New York traffic the other day, I was astounded at how many miles of road there are and that every single one is choked with traffic. There are just so many cars on the road. It is worrying to me knowing all the resources that not only went into producing those cars, but also go into keeping them running every single day. It’s not that there are a lot of cars. There is an incomprehensible number. As far as the eye can see, nothing but smog-spewing vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can this be sustainable?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cash or Friends? Where are Your Priorities?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/cash-or-friends-where-are-your-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/cash-or-friends-where-are-your-priorities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1668&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Refracted Moments(TM) on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/refractedmoments/223052548/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1668&#34; title=&#34;cash&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/cash-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cash or friends? Despite our assertion that the latter is more important, our behavior often suggests that we value money more than our relationships. We tend to work ourselves to death, and if there is any time left over, we think about seeing our friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My best friend is returning home from a year working in West Virginia, in a town that is 3 hours from the nearest interstate, in some of the most beautiful country I’ve ever seen. When he left to go work there, I drove down with him, and now that he is coming back, I’ve offered to drive down to get the rest of his stuff and help him bring it home. He has already driven half of it back, so we will be leaving together to get the rest, spending a week down there, and then driving home again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I explained to some friends that I would be out of town next week, and why, they seemed surprised that I would go to so much trouble just to provide my friend with company on his long drive back and forth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Compete Human Being</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-compete-human-being/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-compete-human-being/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A  human being should be able to change a diaper, plan an invasion,  butcher a hog, conn a ship, design a building, write a sonnet, balance  accounts, build a wall, set a bone, comfort the dying, take orders, give  orders, cooperate, act alone, solve equations, analyze a new problem,  pitch manure, program a computer, cook a tasty meal, fight efficiently,  die gallantly. Specialization is for insects.” - Lazarus Long&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Campbell pointed out in his book &lt;em&gt;Myths to Live By &lt;/em&gt;that,  as humans have become more and more specialized, they have started to  feel like bigger and bigger chunks of their being are empty. When all  you are comfortable doing is studying and researching and you can’t feel  capable in the physical or social realm, you discover big areas of life  completely closed off to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give Yourself a Mission</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/give-yourself-a-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/give-yourself-a-mission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1654&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;The U.S. Army on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/soldiersmediacenter/3729394795/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1654&#34; title=&#34;mission&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/mission-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say that you do not recognize before you and around you  any but those office-holders whole commissions have been signed by a  minister or a king; and that the men whom God has put above these  office-holders, ministers, and kings, by giving them a mission to follow  out instead of a post to fill—I say that they escape your narrow,  limited field of observation. - The Count of Monte Cristo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the usual question we ask kids—“What do you want  to be when you grow up?”—is the wrong sort of question. Instead, we  should be asking them, “What do you want to do?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Count of Monte Cristo points out in the above  quotation, there are two kinds of people in the world: those who fill  posts and those who pursue missions. The two are not always mutually  exclusive, but they are usually very separate ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To me, the difference seems to be that a post is limiting while a mission is empowering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing a New eBook</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/announcing-a-new-ebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/announcing-a-new-ebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I mentioned last week that I was working on an eBook for  all my excellent readers. I’m sure you’ve been dying for details since  then (or maybe not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, I’m putting together a collection of ‘Spirit  Quest’ stories from some of my friends who are living inspiring lives.  It occurred to me that having examples of inspiration might provide some  extra push for my readers who are trying to figure life out (that would  be everyone, I guess).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have You Ever Had an Original Thought?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/have-you-ever-had-an-original-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/have-you-ever-had-an-original-thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1634&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; caption=&#34;lightmatter on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/lightmatter/90526652/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1634&#34; title=&#34;thinker&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/thinker-200x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reading a short piece on creative motivation last  week that asserted that very few of our thoughts are truly our own.  According to the author, most of what we think falls into the category  of ‘monkey-mind,’ which is a term I recognized from studying Buddhism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically it refers to the thought process that jumps from  one topic to another without ever really getting anywhere. Like a  distracted monkey in a playpen, the mind simply takes up whatever  catches its interest for a moment. It may play with the idea for a  while, but quickly discards it for another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrast this with true clarity of thought in which the  mind is focused on a singular aim at the exclusion of all else. By  remaining focused and mostly empty, the clear mind can direct all its  energies to accomplishing some task or plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m No Expert...And I Don&#39;t Want to Be</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/im-no-expert-and-i-dont-want-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/im-no-expert-and-i-dont-want-to-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1626&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;kevinpoh on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kevinpoh/3650866967/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1626&#34; title=&#34;Tai Chi Master&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/master-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started this blog, I had no aspirations to do  anything more than share my thoughts about life and the world. I figured some of the things I was going through might be  interesting to others, mainly my family. I didn’t really set out to tell  anyone how to live their life or even provide advice. I was just  sharing my experience of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This differs markedly from how blogs are getting used these days as a platform to establish the author as an expert with no other credentials besides the blog itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dreaming Against All Odds</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/dreaming-against-all-odds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/dreaming-against-all-odds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1613&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;Hamed Saber on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hamed/327939900/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1613&#34; title=&#34;dreamer&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/dreamer-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You don’t need eyes to see. You just need to believe.” - Caroline Casey, TEDWomen, Dec 2010&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is dedicated to my friend Steffi, who just graduated college and who isn’t settling for the conventional aspirations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speaker above is legally blind, and yet she dreamed  about being a racecar driver. That didn’t work out, but she did ride an  elephant across India and was a very high powered executive for a number  of years. She never let her eyesight slow her down or lower her  expectations for herself. And she certainly never let anyone else’s idea  of what she should be able to do determine what she aimed for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worry Less, Do More</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/worry-less-do-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/worry-less-do-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1601&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;211&#34; caption=&#34;Bark on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/barkbud/4257136773/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1601&#34; title=&#34;Try Not to Worry So Much&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/worry-211x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;211&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since finishing the CrossFit sectionals, I’ve been taking a  break from fitness for the last two weeks. Basically I have tried to  relax about fitness and just do what I feel like in terms of exercise  and nutrition. I expected to lose some ground with my training, but I  felt that I was due for a break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The funny thing is I have actually gotten stronger and  faster. I recently ran a few quarter-mile intervals and put up some of  my fastest times ever. My front lever has become so solid I can do  bicycle crunches while holding myself horizontal. Clearly, I just needed  some rest to develop the latent strength. Leading up to sectionals, I  was so uptight about workouts and diet, and I did pretty well, but now  that I’ve stopped worrying so much, I seem to be doing just as well  anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It seems that I do just as well (or better) not worrying about stuff and I do when I worry.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why worry?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can I Preach It, if I Don&#39;t Live It?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/can-i-preach-it-if-i-dont-live-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/can-i-preach-it-if-i-dont-live-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1606&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;226&#34; caption=&#34;Mike Cattell on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mikecattell/4411829834/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1606&#34; title=&#34;pews&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/pews-226x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;226&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be too easy to be perfect all the time. It is  far more difficult to accept that you’re not perfect but to believe  that you have worthwhile things to say despite that, and to say those  things with conviction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the last two weeks, I’d been in a bit of a rut.  Things that used to excite me didn’t appeal to me anymore. Exercise,  gymnastics, trail running, and even writing all seemed tedious and  boring. All I wanted to do all day was go home and sleep, and when I got  home, I didn’t want to sleep. I was just generally out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also seemed to be messing up everything good in my life.  Professionally, I’d given up a lot of hours training to work on my  writing, with the result that I was pretty broke. My  iPad-as-laptop-replacement experiment was a failure, so I had to buy a  new laptop. My relationship with my girlfriend was in a rough patch,  which just makes everything else seems hellish. I wasn’t sleeping well,  and all I wanted to eat was peanut butter and jelly sandwiches, which  was a problem because I don’t keep jelly at my house and most bread  gives me indigestion. My room was a mess, and I was out of clean  underwear and floss (surprisingly discouraging, actually).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to say that things have improved, though I still  need to invest in some floss, but I wanted to talk a little bit about  the weirdness of being an inspirational writer and not always feeling  inspired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn to Love Pain</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learn-to-love-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learn-to-love-pain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1593&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Nathan Phillips on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/npphoto/4383990220/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1593&#34; title=&#34;pain&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/pain-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you could get past pain and discomfort by  accepting it and relaxing into it? I don’t mean that the pain goes away,  but rather that you become okay with it. You still feel it, but it  doesn’t bother you. You can get on with whatever it is you’re doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Born to Run</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-born-to-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-born-to-run/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0307279189/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=warrspir-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399349&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0307279189&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;Format=_SL160_&amp;amp;ASIN=0307279189&amp;amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;amp;WS=1&amp;amp;tag=warrspir-20&amp;amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/ir?t=&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=0307279189&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399349&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to run barefoot for a long time, since the Vibram FiveFingers came out several years ago. Unfortunately, I’ve also been injuring myself since that time. Undaunted, I’ve kept trying new methods to learn, different ways to ease into it, and different cross-training and recovery techniques. In the end, it was a kind shoestore clerk and an epic story that made the difference. The clerk at the shoe store gave me a barefoot running instructional book (free just for showing interest in a pair of shoes he ordered that I didn’t even have to purchase). The epic story was &lt;em&gt;Born to Run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Need for Inspiration in Fitness</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-need-for-inspiration-in-fitness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-need-for-inspiration-in-fitness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1578&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Zach Dischner on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/zachd1_618/4760723894/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1578&#34; title=&#34;mountainclimbing&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/mountainclimbing-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was going on a rant about all the problems with the fitness industry the other day, as I often do, and one of the few things I said of value was that fitness isn’t about the body, at least not ultimately. It is about the spirit. We mainly want to have healthy bodies so that we can enjoy life, feel confident and strong, experience lots of cool adventures, and play with our grandkids. Most people don’t want to lose weight just for the sake of losing weight, but because they believe it will make them happier. After all, isn’t that why we do everything – in order to be happy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quit Your Belly Achin&#39;</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/quit-your-belly-achin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/quit-your-belly-achin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1573&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;mdanys on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mindaugasdanys/3766009204/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1573&#34; title=&#34;Angry Child&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3766009204_8721a00dde-300x252.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;252&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;There are a thousand reasons for failure, but not a single excuse.&#34; - a cool t-shirt&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you make a mistake even worse? You whine and complain about it and make lots of excuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little while ago, I performed a CrossFit workout in which I wasn&#39;t too happy with my performance. It was a surprisingly difficult one, involving a lot of burpees, followed by a lot of overhead squats, followed by muscle ups. I&#39;m very good at the first and the last movement, and apparently not so hot at the second. But I was so keen on getting to my strength - the muscle ups - that when I finally did, I lost all my focus and went crazy. The result was that I got just a single muscle up in two minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the buzzer went off, I let out an angry yell, uttering a curse I never use in my daily life. It just sort of slipped out, and I was immediately ashamed of myself. Not because I had cursed - lots of people do that - but that I had gotten so angry that I did something so out of character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forays in Barefoot Running</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/forays-in-barefoot-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/forays-in-barefoot-running/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1570&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;chumley80 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/29937348@N05/5247371406/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1570&#34; title=&#34;Runners Feet&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5247371406_ffb0cc0563-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve started barefoot running. Not just going out to the mail in my bare feet. Not jogging in light shoes. Full on, running down the road with no shoes on, barefoot running. So far my maximum distance is about 3/4 mile, and I&#39;m taking it slowly, but it is addictive, and holding back is the hardest part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons in Minimalism from Camping</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-in-minimalism-from-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-in-minimalism-from-camping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1564&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; caption=&#34;f_r_e on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/garrulus/1743162782/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1564 &#34; title=&#34;backpack&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/backpack.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was but a wee lad, my dad used to drag me kicking and screaming into the woods to partake in an activity which, due to its lack of video games, easily available chocolate, and LEGOs, I was not too keen on. That activity was camping. As a kid, I hated it. Now, it is necessary to my spiritual well-being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are We Having Fun Yet?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/are-we-having-fun-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/are-we-having-fun-yet/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&#34;attachment_1557&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; caption=&#34;Dirceu Soares on Flickr&#34;][/caption]
Are you having fun?
I don&#39;t mean bounce-off-the-walls giddy. Nor do I mean partying until 3am every day.
But basically, do you enjoy your days? Do you get a kick out of your schedule? Do you have something interesting and new to excite you planned every day?
Do you want to get out of bed every morning?
A lot of my friends do not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Trust the Experts</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/dont-trust-the-experts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/dont-trust-the-experts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1553&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;281&#34; caption=&#34;HA! Designs - Artbyheather on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hadesigns/2211510558/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1553 &#34; title=&#34;Venerable Expert&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/2211510558_c43cf4bd3c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;281&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was a child, I had an annoying tendency to question everything my teachers told me. This got me sent to the principle on more than one occasion. As an adult, I tried to suppress this habit and like the rest of us, very quickly became enamored of experts. Until last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After spending a few months working with so-called fitness experts, I was finally ready to become one myself by getting my Level 1 CrossFit trainer certification. I drove the presenters insane with my questions, because I knew that they were oversimplifying, leaving stuff out, or were just plain wrong. I had done my own research, from a number of different sources, and come to my own conclusions. I was not ready to drink the Kool-Aid, no matter how expertly prepared or convincingly presented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break Out of Your Comfort Zone</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/break-out-of-your-comfort-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/break-out-of-your-comfort-zone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1549&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Pink Sherbet Photography on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pinksherbet/2822640646/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1549&#34; title=&#34;comfort&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/comfort-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever noticed that moving to college is just as uncomfortable and awkward as moving back home afterwards? Or that starting a new job is just as nerve-wracking as being unemployed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But eventually, we get used to the new routine, and we wonder how we ever got along without it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is the wonder - and frustration - of human adaptation: &lt;strong&gt;we can feel comfortable doing things we hate and supremely out of our element doing things we love and want to do&lt;/strong&gt;.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are We Waiting For?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/what-are-we-waiting-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/what-are-we-waiting-for/</guid>
      <description>What would it take for you to drop everything and go after what you want?
A lot of people wait for someone close to them to pass away. That&#39;s what it takes to remind them that life is too precious to waste in going through the motions.
Some people need a wake up call in the form of catastrophic failure. After spending a fortune and many years in law school, they lose their job as a lawyer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Your Own Good Days</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-make-your-own-good-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-make-your-own-good-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1540&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Mana_benz on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mana_benz/3421649195/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1540&#34; title=&#34;Sunrise&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3421649195_fd89f134f2-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I had a terrible Wednesday. On that day, I did poorly on a workout I was confident I could do well in. I had to leave Kenpo early because I was so exhausted and beat up, and when I got home, I had a stomach ache. I started panicking about how hungry I was because I thought if I ate food so late I would not be able to sleep, and I was already exhausted. My mom and girlfriend can attest to how immature I was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day was totally different. It was sunny, for one, and I made sure to get enough sleep. Even though traffic kept me from making some appointments, I brushed it off and wore a smile all day long. I had a great time chaperoning my 7th and 8th grade cross country team, and ended the day tired but not exhausted.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Personal Epic</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-personal-epic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-personal-epic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- p.p1 {margin: 8.0px 0.0px 0.0px 0.0px; text-indent: 18.0px; font: 13.0px Optima} p.p3 {margin: 8.0px 0.0px 0.0px 0.0px; text-indent: 18.0px; font: 13.0px Optima; min-height: 15.0px} li.li2 {margin: 8.0px 0.0px 0.0px 0.0px; font: 13.0px Optima} ul.ul1 {list-style-type: disc} --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1537&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;Sammydavisdog on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/25559122@N06/2414295906/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1537&#34; title=&#34;perseus&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/perseus-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, I&#39;m Khaled. This is my blog, Warrior Spirit. It&#39;s kind of my personal epic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem a little presumptuous to suggest that my life is worthy of an epic, and maybe it’s not yet. However, I believe that if I treat it as epic-worthy, it will live up to that calling. The whole point is simply to live as awesome a life as possible and hope that it proves worthy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Weakness the Smart Way</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/overcoming-weakness-the-smart-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/overcoming-weakness-the-smart-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1528&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;fPat on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/fpat/3375999258/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1528&#34; title=&#34;tigers&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/tigers-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I undertook the fourth installment of the CrossFit Sectionals Open Workouts. It looked right up my alley, involving two movements I am very good at - burpees and muscle ups - and only one that I wasn&#39;t - heavy overhead squat (really, I&#39;m not good at much that is heavy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I was confident I would do well. All I had to do was suffer through the squats in order to get to one of my strengths. Unfortunately, I found the squats too much, and I didn&#39;t even manage to finish them before the timer buzzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I felt defeated. Even with the advantage of having my strengths, I was stopped by one thing that I&#39;m weak at.&lt;/strong&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What It Means to be a Writer</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/what-it-means-to-be-a-writer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/what-it-means-to-be-a-writer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;clear: both;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1525&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;JohnONolan on Flicker&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/johnonolan/4898796303/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1525&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/writer1-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I was a little boy, I&#39;ve wanted to be a writer. Back then, that meant I got to spend all day writing stories, which was something I loved doing. I couldn&#39;t imagine a better way to spend my time than telling stories about dragons and spaceships. Since that&#39;s what writers did, I wanted to be a writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living an Adventurous Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/living-an-adventurous-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/living-an-adventurous-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1511&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Gjeewaytee on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40066970@N08/4178946564/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1511&#34; title=&#34;adventure&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/adventure-300x226.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;226&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started learning gymnastics, I wasn&#39;t the only adult at the gym. But I was the only adult on the rings and I was the only person there with no formal gymnastics experience as a child (excluding the Parkour crowd and one other guy who had started in college).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given my previous experience, my age, and my chosen apparatus of still rings, there weren&#39;t many who thought I would go far. After all, there weren&#39;t many (if any) who had come into gymnastics late with the intent of picking up much beyond tumbling and flips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my coach and I moved slowly, exploring different ways to progress and learn that might be unique to my situation. Every training session was an adventure, because I didn&#39;t know anyone who had done what I was trying to do. I didn&#39;t know what to expect, or how I would ultimately fare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Warrior Spirit</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-warrior-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-warrior-spirit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Hello World&#34;]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/20110331-213409.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/20110331-213409.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20110331-213409.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d like to inject a little more of me into my posts. After all, this blog was started by me as a sort of online journal. I was reluctant to assume that all my readers found my life all that interesting, but I thought I&#39;d just write about it. I am a storyteller, after all, not just an essayist. Since the story I know best is my own, I wanted to tell that story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the way, I got swept up by all these other great blogs that also tell stories, but which also provide lots of useful information besides. Somehow, the information stuck out more than the stories, and I focused on that. As a result, I feel that Warrior Spirit has kind of drifted from being personal to trying too hard to be useful. The result I think has been less connection with my readers. The blog has grown and grown, and for that I&#39;m thankful, but I feel a little like I&#39;ve sold out (except without the monetary rewards).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&#39;m going to try to tell more of my stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start Your Day Right with an Anchor</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/building-your-day-around-an-anchor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/building-your-day-around-an-anchor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;lulu lemon athletica on Flickr&#34;]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/20110329-101320.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/20110329-101320.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20110329-101320.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image of the lone warrior training every day at dawn is a popular one in the martial arts. Like clockwork, the Warrior rises before her companions have even stirred to run through her training. She does this in the mornings, so that there is no possibility of distraction. It is her source of strength, for even in the midst of a quest, she finds time to hone her skills and focus her mind for the day&#39;s coming struggles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you ever feel frustrated by the inconsistency in your days? While change and excitement are great, I&#39;ve always found that I really appreciate having at least a few things that are steady that I can turn to in order to get into the right mindset for the day. Alternatively, having something later in the day that I can expect helps me forget all the troubles and problems that have cropped up. An afternoon run will do wonders to help you put the stresses of a long workday behind you so that you can focus your energies on being with your family in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Until You Break</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/go-until-you-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/go-until-you-break/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;willem! on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/20110326-085423.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/20110326-085423.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20110326-085423.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a tendency in difficult times to stop before the end of our rope. Things start to get too hard and the voice in our head says, &#34;We are almost finished. We&#39;d better stop before we actually fail.&#34; And so we stop to rest, even though there was no concrete evidence of our immiment failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Us vs. Nature: The Need for Understanding</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/usvnature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/usvnature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1427&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/100_0067.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1427&#34; title=&#34;Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/100_0067-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we had no choice but to destroy the natural world or destroy ourselves, which do you think we would pick? Let’s say that Nature has decided she has had enough. She won’t kill us outright, but she has determined to eliminate all aspects of our unsustainable lives, which means she sends her warriors to take out our property, vehicles, and infrastructure. Insects would lay waste to crops, sacrificing themselves to the pesticides, leaving organic foods untouched (assuming the crops themselves didn’t turn against us by simply refusing to produce). Rodents would flood our homes, tearing them apart from the inside, leaving us unscathed by demolishing everything manufactured, everything chemically-treated, everything unnatural. Trees and plants would suddenly demonstrate an uncanny determination to grow roots under, over, and into our buildings and roads, slowly but inexorably pulling them to pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping in Touch in a Disconnected World</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/keeping-in-touch-in-a-disconnected-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/keeping-in-touch-in-a-disconnected-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1412&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;cynthiacloskey on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/cynthiacloskey/2439736125/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1412&#34; title=&#34;letters&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/letters-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My generation is surrounded by hundreds of ways to instantaneously get in touch with old friends. We have Facebook, MySpace, Twitter, iPhones, Droids, Wi-fi hotspots, 3G networks, text messages, e-mail, instant messaging, and even that old standby, the telephone. And yet, almost all of my old friends claim that they are horrible at staying in touch. On a whim, they can say hello to someone with the touch of a button, and yet, we hear from one another so infrequently many of us wonder what the point of social technology is in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warrior Spirit Evolves</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/warrior-spirit-evolves/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/warrior-spirit-evolves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay...I&#39;ve really got it this time. Seriously. &lt;strong&gt;I now know what this blog is about&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, I&#39;ve said that a lot before, but this time it&#39;s real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check it out. See that snazzy new subtitle. This blog isn&#39;t about me anymore (well, I guess it will always kind of be about me). It&#39;s about &lt;em&gt;Us&lt;/em&gt;, trying to make ourselves the best we can be, so that we can be the most awesome, helpful, revolutionary, world-changing people we can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Best Use Your Teacher</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-best-use-your-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-best-use-your-teacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1400&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;286&#34; caption=&#34;velvettangerine on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/velvettangerine/3922005142/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1400&#34; title=&#34;teacher&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/teacher-286x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;286&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re trying to learn something or achieve a skill, a teacher can be a big help, since they have already done what you want to do. But there are some pitfalls to having a teacher, especially if you try to put all the responsibility for your progress on their shoulders. The best way to use a teacher is as a resource for your own learning, not as the basis or sole motivation for your goals.&lt;em&gt; (if you&#39;re short on time, you can skip to the end of the article for a summary, a policy I&#39;ll be using more regularly)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a trainer, I work with a lot of people who want to get in great shape, but don&#39;t really want to put in the effort. Sure, they do the exercises I recommend when they show up, and they push themselves pretty hard. But then I won&#39;t see them for weeks. They have lessons maybe once a month, very intermittently, and as a result, they don&#39;t move towards their goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have trainees who see me about that often, but who do make progress. The difference is in the way they view our relationship. To the first group, I am responsible for their fitness progress. &lt;strong&gt;To the second group, I am merely a resource for them as they make their own journey towards fitness&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Art of Non-Conformity</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-the-art-of-non-conformity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-the-art-of-non-conformity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1385&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;118&#34; caption=&#34;Clicking this image will take you to Amazon.com&#34;]&lt;a style=&#34;border: none;&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0399536108?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=warrspir-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0399536108&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1385 &#34; title=&#34;514+B0WuCVL._SL160_&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/514+B0WuCVL._SL160_.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;118&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why jump off the bridge just because everyone else is doing it? You can step back from the bridge, turn around, and walk away into new adventures that had previously been only fleeting ideas. You can also help other people walk away from the bridge, or you can rewrite the rules the brought to the bridge in the first place. The possibilities are unlimited, but it all begins with the deliberate decision to think differently - Chris Guillebeau., &lt;em&gt;The Art of Non-Conformity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been a while since I did a book review, as I&#39;ve been reading several books at once. Nevertheless, I&#39;ve finally managed to finish one, by fellow blogger and inspiration Chris Guillebeau of &lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisguillebeau.com/3x5/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Art of Non-Conformity&lt;/a&gt;. Chris is a self-described traveler and writer. He pays the bills by writing (which he can do from anywhere), and spends as much time as possible travelling the world with the ultimate goal of visiting every country. His book, &lt;em&gt;The Art of Non-Conformity,&lt;/em&gt; provides readers with a glimpse of his unorthodox worldviews which, he maintains, are much more empowering and liberating than the traditional worldview we are taught to follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End of Choice</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-end-of-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-end-of-choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1365&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;275&#34; caption=&#34;jah on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jahdakinebrah/64881299/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1365&#34; title=&#34;choices&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/choices-275x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;275&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The history of free men is never really written by chance but by choice - their choice” - Dwight D. Eisenhower&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/letter-to-the-president/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Letter to the President&lt;/a&gt;, a reader brought &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.organicconsumers.org/articles/article_22449.cfm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article &lt;/a&gt;to my attention, explaining how the organic elite, such entities as Whole Foods, Organic Valley, and Stonyfield Farms, have expressed their acceptance of GM crops. Whole Foods has apparently decided to stop opposing GM crops, and in return they are demanding compensation for farmers. The article also points out that most of Whole Foods products are not organic (no surprise), and that most of them are also contaminated with GM foods (also no surprise, since GM corn soybeans are used to make most of the additives in foods, including soy lecithin, modified food starch, dextrose, xantham gum, etc). So, despite their green image, Whole Foods has a vested interest in keeping labels off of foods with GMOs in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living on Principle</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/living-on-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/living-on-principle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1357&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;ground.zero on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/groundzero/96516632/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1357&#34; title=&#34;determination&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/determination-300x171.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;171&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have habits outside the norm, people look at you funny, even when they admire what you do. I avoid sugar at all costs. Everyone I know thinks this is a good idea in terms of nutrition and health, something they&#39;d hypothetically like to do, but they don&#39;t really envision themselves as able to give up sugar. It is just too far outside of the normal American dietary experience. My friends ask wistfully how they can lose weight or have my energy levels. I tell them, don&#39;t eat sugar, and they respond with, &#34;I wish I could do that, but I just couldn&#39;t give up sugar. I love it too much. How can you live without eating sugar?&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Shouldn&#39;t Always Do Your Best</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-you-shouldnt-always-do-your-best/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-you-shouldnt-always-do-your-best/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1342&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Alex E. Proimos&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/proimos/4199675334/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1342&#34; title=&#34;Head in Hands&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/failure-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only the mediocre are always at their best - Jean Giradoux&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My gymnastics coach recently revealed to me that Olympic gymnasts are only able to perform their routines at the time they compete. Most of the time, they use spotters, and they periodize their training so that they peak when they compete. Many of them can&#39;t even perform some of their hardest skills on an everyday basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this isn&#39;t especially unique in the world of elite athletes, it does reveal an interesting aspect of excellence: &lt;strong&gt;when you are performing at such a high level, you cannot always be at your best&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing My Own Game</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/playing-my-own-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/playing-my-own-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1339&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Scatterbrained on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/iamagenious/767028837/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1339&#34; title=&#34;game&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/game-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/book-review-the-8020-principle/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The 80/20 Principle&lt;/a&gt;, I undertook some exercises recommended by the author to identify my &#39;happiness islands&#39; and my &#39;achievement islands&#39;, times in my life when I was especially happy or productive. The pattern that emerged was that I have been especially productive when I&#39;m either working for myself or have the freedom to set my own agenda and goals. My happiness is also strongly correlated with my independence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tired of Tardiness</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/tired-of-tardiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/tired-of-tardiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1323&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;blue2likeyou on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/29254399@N08/3187186308/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1323&#34; title=&#34;clock&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/clock1-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last two days, I&#39;ve done a pretty poor job of keeping on top of my own schedule. I&#39;ve been rushing around to everything, have been late to two very important appointments, and haven&#39;t had the mental clarity to focus on getting anything done. I offer my apologies to all affected, including the readers of my blog. It&#39;s not much in the way of consolation, but I&#39;ve been suffering more than those I let down; my ability to get enough food and sleep has been pretty well undermined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Mistakes to Learn</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/make-mistakes-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/make-mistakes-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1313&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Jeffrey Montes on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jm-photography/4866200549/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1313&#34; title=&#34;SONY DSC&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/paint-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The man who makes no mistakes does not usually make anything. - William Connor Magee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the productivity newsletters I subscribe to, Psychotactics, recently sent out an article on the best strategies to learn and retain knowledge. The author explained that almost every attempt we make to acquire knowledge is done in such a way as to make it very unlikely we will actually be able to hold on to that knowledge. The reason is simply because we are afraid to test our knowledge and make mistakes and mistakes are the key to knowledge retention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Appreciation</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/teacher-appreciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/teacher-appreciation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1247&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Abhijit Tembhekar on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/abhijittembhekar/3345977842/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1247&#34; title=&#34;apple&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/apple-300x201.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wax on, wax off. - Mr. Miyagi, the Karate Kid (1984)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warriors are always seeking to grow and learn new things, so it makes sense that we&#39;d have a lot of teachers in our life. As the year comes to a close and I contemplate my card list, I&#39;m realizing that most of the people on it are my teachers and mentors. In the past two years, I&#39;ve acquired an unusually large number of teachers, of exceptionally good quality, and I realize that all the growth and knowledge I&#39;ve acquired is largely thanks to their efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mythic Warriors: Link</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/mythic-warriors-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/mythic-warriors-link/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1244&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Copyright Nintendo, Inc&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/link.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1244&#34; title=&#34;link&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/link-300x112.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;112&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sword wields no strength unless the hand that holds it has courage. You may be destined to become the hero of legend...but your current power would disgrace the proud green of the hero&#39;s tunic you wear. You must use your courage to seek power...and find it you must. Only then will you become the hero for whom this world despairs. - Hero&#39;s Shade, The Legend of Zelda: Twilight Princess&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clad in a green tunic and wielding the legendary Master Sword, Link is the hero of &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda&lt;/em&gt; series of games from Nintendo. Throughout the game&#39;s long history, he has faced countless foes ranging from evil wizards to psychotic masks, solved numerous mind-bending puzzles, and repeatedly saved the world from oblivion. All the while managing to get some time in for leisurely fishing, mini-games, favors for random folks, and practicing his various instruments. Variously depicted as a boy or a young man, Link is the possessor of the Triforce of Courage and is perhaps one of the greatest examples of heroism our young video-game addicted selves might have been exposed to. He has all the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/warrior-philosophies/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;traits of a true Warrior&lt;/a&gt;, and exemplifies the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/what-is-warrior-spirit/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Warrior Spirit&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Writer&#39;s Struggles as a Blogger</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-writers-struggles-as-a-blogger/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-writers-struggles-as-a-blogger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1223&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;amanky on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/amanky/2219631791/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1223&#34; title=&#34;blogging&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/blogging-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;Blogging is not rocket science, it’s about being yourself, and putting what you have into it.&#34; -Unknown&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogging is both a wonderful and a frustrating experience for a writer. On the one hand, it gives you the opportunity to put your ideas out there with no publishing costs and the freedom to write whatever you want. On the other hand, it leaves all the publicity up to you. It&#39;s like a journal that people might actually care about and read, and it creates the possibility of a self-crafted audience. I&#39;ve come a long way as a blogger, but I still find that I have a lot to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Warrior Spirit?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/what-is-warrior-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/what-is-warrior-spirit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1215&#34; title=&#34;Warrior Spirit&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/TShirtBack-300x240.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The warrior stands defiant, spear in hand, looking over a vast plain. Below him is a world full of challenge and adversity, dangerous enemies and tempting shortcuts. Beyond is a great mountain range, full of promise certainly, but hiding even greater challenges. On the other side...who knows? Hope, transcendence, enlightenment. Or perhaps darker, more sinister rewards hide behind those peaks. All the Warrior knows is that he has decided to scale them, carve a path through the plains and over the mountains, leading the way for others who seek a better life on the other side, guiding them and defending the tribe from the dangers ahead. He knows he may not survive, but he has prepared well and is among the greatest, most capable leaders of his tribe. He is confident and eager to begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Just Face Your Fears, Learn to Love Them</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/dont-just-face-your-fears-learn-to-love-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/dont-just-face-your-fears-learn-to-love-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1203&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;epSos.de on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/epsos/4376727123/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1203&#34; title=&#34;Fear&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/Fear-300x168.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;168&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must not fear. Fear is the mind-killer. Fear is the little-death that brings total obliteration. I will face my fear. I will permit it to pass over me and through me. And when it has gone past I will turn the inner eye to see its path. Where the fear has gone there will be nothing. Only I will remain. &lt;em&gt;-Bene Gesserit Litany Against Fear, Frank Herbert&#39;s&lt;/em&gt; Dune&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say the thing that most scares us is the unfamiliar. We seem naturally wary of things that we don&#39;t know very well, even parts of ourselves that we haven&#39;t dealt with in a very long time. We also shy away from things we have simply never experienced before. Unfortunately, this includes many of the things we&#39;d like to live up to and achieve. So we have a problem; anyone who wants to grow and develop as a human being, to achieve their true potential (aka, their Warrior Spirit), must go from what they know, through what they don&#39;t know, and therefore, must face their fears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Story</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/KhaledPortrait.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1068&#34; title=&#34;KhaledPortrait&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/KhaledPortrait-300x224.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;224&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“Today you are You, that is truer than true. There is no one alive who is Youer than You.” - Dr. Seuss&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the responses I got from all of you on that &lt;a href=&#34;http://polldaddy.com/s/444345CCC43313A2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;survey &lt;/a&gt;I sent out, most of the interest in what I write comes from knowing me. So I thought I&#39;d write out my story, so those of you who didn&#39;t know me before the blog can understand where I&#39;m coming from, where I get my stories and interpretations, and why I care so much about standing up to mediocrity and forging my own destiny.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
