<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>impermanence on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/impermanence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in impermanence on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/impermanence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re Not the One Who Will Achieve Your Dreams</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youre-not-the-one-who-will-achieve-your-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youre-not-the-one-who-will-achieve-your-dreams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“The recipe for perpetual ignorance is: Be satisfied with your opinions and content with your knowledge.” -Elbert Hubbard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We know what we are, but know now what we may be.” - William Shakespeare&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/6527715119_b568570ab2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2499&#34; title=&#34;The Illusion of the Self&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/6527715119_b568570ab2-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest obstacles to accomplishing our greatest dreams and goals is the fear of growth. We are unwilling to change, even in a positive way, because growth is painful. Even when we get stronger as a result, we tend to shy away from the necessary discomfort that comes with the process of improving ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After all, growth only comes as the result of learning to deal with challenges that are slightly beyond us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem is that,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;in order to accomplish our goals, we must grow.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we didn&#39;t need to grow, we would already be doing what we dream about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on our particular dream, the kind of change and growth we need will be different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to get stronger, faster, healthier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to make more connections and meet more people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to gain deeper insight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to learn new ideas and master new theories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to see the world in a slightly different way that empowers us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to play a bigger game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We need to be comfortable with the things that scare us at the moment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To a large extent, that last one covers all the others, and it is significant because it is integral to our sense of who we are. &lt;strong&gt;Our fears create our limiting image of ourselves&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
