<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>the legend of zelda on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/the-legend-of-zelda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in the legend of zelda on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/the-legend-of-zelda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mythic Warriors: Link</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/mythic-warriors-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/mythic-warriors-link/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1244&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Copyright Nintendo, Inc&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/link.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1244&#34; title=&#34;link&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/link-300x112.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;112&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sword wields no strength unless the hand that holds it has courage. You may be destined to become the hero of legend...but your current power would disgrace the proud green of the hero&#39;s tunic you wear. You must use your courage to seek power...and find it you must. Only then will you become the hero for whom this world despairs. - Hero&#39;s Shade, The Legend of Zelda: Twilight Princess&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clad in a green tunic and wielding the legendary Master Sword, Link is the hero of &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda&lt;/em&gt; series of games from Nintendo. Throughout the game&#39;s long history, he has faced countless foes ranging from evil wizards to psychotic masks, solved numerous mind-bending puzzles, and repeatedly saved the world from oblivion. All the while managing to get some time in for leisurely fishing, mini-games, favors for random folks, and practicing his various instruments. Variously depicted as a boy or a young man, Link is the possessor of the Triforce of Courage and is perhaps one of the greatest examples of heroism our young video-game addicted selves might have been exposed to. He has all the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/warrior-philosophies/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;traits of a true Warrior&lt;/a&gt;, and exemplifies the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/what-is-warrior-spirit/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Warrior Spirit&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
