<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>weakness on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/weakness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in weakness on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/weakness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Vulnerability is Actually Strength</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-vulnerability-is-actually-strength/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-vulnerability-is-actually-strength/</guid>
      <description>Some books change our lives. Daring Greatly was that kind of book for me. In the midst of an internal crisis this summer, I came across this book by Brene Brown, renowned researcher and author on vulnerability, courage, worthiness, and shame.
One of Brown&#39;s key points is that, in order to do great things, we have to embrace vulnerability. That feeling of exposing yourself is scary, but it&#39;s necessary because only by really reaching outside our comfort zones, by risking real pain or loss, can we achieve something really worth striving for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Ways Accepting Your Weaknesses Can Empower You</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/6-ways-accepting-your-weaknesses-can-empower-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/6-ways-accepting-your-weaknesses-can-empower-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/weakness.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3173&#34; alt=&#34;weakness&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/weakness-300x153.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;153&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;One of the quirks of having subjective conscious experience (aka, self-awareness) is that we have a very different perspective on ourselves than we do on other people. For example, &lt;a title=&#34;Attribution Bias&#34; href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attribution_bias&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;attribution bias&lt;/a&gt; tells us that we tend to assume other peoples&#39; actions are the result of their character more than their circumstances, while we openly acknowledge that we are affected by circumstances when it suits us. For example, if we see someone else lie to avoid a fine, we would tend to judge them as generally dishonest. If we do the same thing, we would cite our tight finances and tell ourselves that normally we&#39;re honest, law-abiding citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;However, this can create some interesting conflicts as well. We may assume we&#39;re stronger or more reliable than we really are, or that we will be happy in a situation that won&#39;t really make us happy. Maybe the idea of living in New York excites you, but you know that you hate cars and crowds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basically, we don’t like to admit that we are as flawed as other people, but if we are to be honest about who we are, if we are to live with integrity, we have to have an accurate view of ourselves, flaws and all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Weakness the Smart Way</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/overcoming-weakness-the-smart-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/overcoming-weakness-the-smart-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1528&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;fPat on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/fpat/3375999258/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1528&#34; title=&#34;tigers&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/tigers-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I undertook the fourth installment of the CrossFit Sectionals Open Workouts. It looked right up my alley, involving two movements I am very good at - burpees and muscle ups - and only one that I wasn&#39;t - heavy overhead squat (really, I&#39;m not good at much that is heavy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I was confident I would do well. All I had to do was suffer through the squats in order to get to one of my strengths. Unfortunately, I found the squats too much, and I didn&#39;t even manage to finish them before the timer buzzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I felt defeated. Even with the advantage of having my strengths, I was stopped by one thing that I&#39;m weak at.&lt;/strong&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
