<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wealth on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/wealth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wealth on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/wealth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Grow Your Most Valuable Asset</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-grow-your-most-valuable-asset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-grow-your-most-valuable-asset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An asset is a resource that can create value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The formal definition by the International Accounting Standards Board is a resource controlled by the enterprise as a result of past events and from which future economic benefits are expected to flow to the entity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Kiyosaki, the author of&lt;em&gt;Rich Dad, Poor Dad&lt;/em&gt;, defines an asset is something that puts money in your pocket, like an investment or the royalties you get on your book, or even the time you spend working at your job (which provides a 1-to-1 exchange of value).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what&#39;s you&#39;re greatest asset? What is the one thing you have that can create an infinite amount of value in the world, both tangible and intangible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mind&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You in the 1%? You Should Be</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/are-you-in-the-1-you-should-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/are-you-in-the-1-you-should-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is an old story of a Roman, Cincinnatus, who was called upon by the Senate in an emergency. Rome&#39;s army had been trapped in the field, leaving the city vulnerable to an attack, and the government nominated Cincinnatus as dictator, giving him 6 months of absolute power. He defeated the enemy in 16 days and immediately gave up his office to return to his farm, becoming a legend of civic virtue and restraint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of us associate the word &#39;dictator&#39; with a corrupt, power-hungry leader, and that is certainly what most Roman dictators were. But the lesson here is that the office of dictator, and later of emperor, was sullied by the corrupt men who sought and held it, not by the nature of its duties. There were some dictators of sound principles, and some emperors as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night, I watched the documentary &lt;em&gt;Park Avenue,&lt;/em&gt; which is about the wealth gap in America and the political landscape that has made it so entrenched. I&#39;m not especially politically aware (something I&#39;m working on), so it was shocking to see just how bad things are. The 400 richest Americans control as much wealth as 50% of the country, 150 million people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I&#39;ve thought this was just the way our system worked: campaigning was expensive, so businesses and wealthy individuals took advantage of this to offer contributions in exchange for laws that further entrenched their wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I didn&#39;t know was that in 1971, soon-to-be Supreme Court Justice Lewis F. Powell wrote a letter to the US Chamber of Commerce, a call-to-arms to US businesses to take a more active role in shaping policy. This was in response to the sweeping political setbacks that had been experienced by corporations in the 60s and early 70s. They heeded the call, and corporate lobbying began to take on the shape it has today.&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;Thus, our current system of government-by-corporation was not the result of a broken system, but &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;was directly pursued by the corporations themselves in response to a perceived threat to their power&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result has been the shrinking of the middle class, a huge growth in the income gap, and a polarization of American society between the extremely wealthy and the extremely poor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To be wealthy in this country is to benefit from corrupt politics and to be a part of a system that oppresses the American people. Or so we have come to believe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investing in Yourself</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/investing-in-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/investing-in-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You experience a windfall and suddenly, your bank account is $1000 fatter. It&#39;s not a ton of money, but it&#39;s enough to give you some breathing room in the next month or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what do you do with it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you pay off some of your student debt?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you take a trip to India?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you buy a new dress?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you &lt;a title=&#34;You May Be Illiterate&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/you-may-be-illiterate/&#34;&gt;learn how to program&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of us would spend our money on things we want to fill a need or something we want to &lt;a title=&#34;How Much Do You Cost? How Much Do You Create?&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/how-much-do-you-cost-how-much-do-you-create/&#34;&gt;consume&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But what if our default mode of spending was to invest in ourselves. Instead of having money leak out of the system, keep it in a cycle to generate more and more. Find ways to convert cash into personal capital.&lt;/strong&gt; Use that money to make yourself more valuable or increase your ability to generate value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If You Have to Cross a Moral Swamp, a Map is Always a Good Idea</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/if-you-have-to-cross-a-moral-swamp-a-map-is-always-a-good-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/if-you-have-to-cross-a-moral-swamp-a-map-is-always-a-good-idea/</guid>
      <description>The e-mail I sent out this past weekend was about developing an awareness of the way we construct our morality and whether it restricts or enables us. In a nutshell:
 A morality basically tells us how we should behave to be happy/good people Moralities can be stated in two ways:  To be good, you must not-do/avoid/exclude X. To be good, you must do/include/experience Y.   While on the surface, the end result may be the same, the first morality leads to a sense of constant wariness, while the other leads to a stance of accepting life&#39;s opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Committing to Health Teaches you to Stand Out</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-being-healthy-empowers-you-to-stand-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-being-healthy-empowers-you-to-stand-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/sunflower.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright  wp-image-3114&#34; alt=&#34;sunflower&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/sunflower.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Being in good shape puts you at odds with a lot of society. It denies--or at least minimizes--the value of some of our culture&#39;s greatest accomplishments: abundant food, two cars in every driveway, accessible technology, drugs for every ailment. It&#39;s generally poor form to question or refuse these blessings of civilization. It angers the other sheep when you start asking questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, our society is not structured to help individuals achieve their greatest potential in health. We&#39;ve done a very good job of eliminating the stressors that temper our bodies, with the result that our daily lives do not provide the stimulus we need to stay in our best shape. &lt;strong&gt;Now, if we want to develop our bodies, we have to go out of our way to do it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be healthy, we need to take time out of our life in order to perform extensive and inconvenient maintenance (unless you&#39;re one of those people who &lt;em&gt;actually enjoys&lt;/em&gt; being active, then maybe you take time out of your life for your job). The alternative is to simply accept what most of the American population does: that chronic disease is inevitable, that the ability to lift and carry more than you weigh is impossible, that hoisting yourself over an object by your own strength is beyond human capability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to the norm, we have to eat differently, act differently, move differently, sleep differently. To a certain extent, we have to purposefully ostracize ourselves, choose certain friends that can support our habit, and stick out. Other&#39;s may respect and even envy health, but that doesn&#39;t make it any easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lifestyles of the Rich and Famous&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That lifestyle sounds a lot like the one followed by many game-changers and amazingly successful people. From what I&#39;ve read and researched, starting a successful business that makes a difference requires you to live by a different set of rules. You do things and believe in possibilities that other people don&#39;t even consider. You question the status quo about money or the kind of influence you can have. You certainly don&#39;t play by the standard rules of go-to-school-get-good-grades-get-a-safe-job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So essentially, to break out of the status quo in anything, whether it&#39;s health, wealth, influence, or comedy, you have to be a radical&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
