<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>80/20 on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/80/20/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 80/20 on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/80/20/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The 80/20 Principle in Training</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-8020-principle-in-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-8020-principle-in-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2889&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;576&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/16761_702845749494_1943566062_n-1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-2889 &#34; alt=&#34;Dunebashing: 80% Play, 20% Sweat&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/16761_702845749494_1943566062_n-1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;576&#34; height=&#34;386&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Dunebashing: 80% Play, 20% Sweat[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;This was a concept that I had trouble understanding from my MovNat trainer certification. I have read &lt;a title=&#34;Book Review: The 80/20 Principle&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/book-review-the-8020-principle/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The 80/20 Principle by Richard Koch&lt;/a&gt;, so it was more an issue of understanding how to apply it to physical adaptation than a failure to grasp the concept. This article is what I came up with.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The few things that work fantastically well should be identified, cultivated, nurtured, and multiplied. - Richard Koch, &lt;em&gt;The 80/20 Principle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;80% of our results comes from 20% of our efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the 80/20 rule in a nutshell. It means that only 20% of our effort is responsible for most of our results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20% of our clients supply 80% of our income&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20% of our work time is when we get 80% of our assignments done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We watch 20% of our movie collection 80% of the time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, that last one may not be totally accurate. Perhaps, if you&#39;re me, it&#39;s more like you watch 10% of your movie collection 90% of the time, but the point is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The majority of our results come from a surprisingly small minority of our efforts or resources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is good news, because it means we can cut out 80% of the busy work and dedicate more of our time to the 20% that actually makes a difference. Or we can retain 80% of our current results and spend much less time on achieving them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In training, that means we should focus on the exercises that make the most difference to our health and ability&lt;/strong&gt;. These would be exercises that trigger a powerful, full-body adaptation response. Heavy strength training would be preferable to isolation biceps curls, for example (sorry biceps curls, I know everyone picks on you).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
