<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>distractions on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/distractions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in distractions on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/distractions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Guest Post: Letting Go of Distractions to Simply Do What You Love</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/guest-post-letting-go-of-distractions-to-simply-do-what-you-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/guest-post-letting-go-of-distractions-to-simply-do-what-you-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3834&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/karatekick.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;karatekick&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a reader story from Claire Higgins, a coach, yoga instructor, and martial artist who is sharing her story of returning to the core of her passion for training: Karate itself. It&#39;s a great story illustrating how easy it can be to get pulled off track from doing the things we love in the name of supporting the things we love (like the classic case of a parent working so hard they don&#39;t see their family, justifying it all by saying it&#39;s for the family&#39;s well-being, when in fact, all they want is to spend more time together).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I entered personal training to get fitter for Karate (it was CrossFit inspired). Soon, I was expected to work out several times a week on top of a demanding Karate schedule, dedicated yoga practice and teaching, and driving 4 hrs a day for my last (very stressful) job. So I built a home gym, complete with an olympic bar that I didn&#39;t use often enough as I was so exhausted. My Karate performance improved a lot but I was so tired I felt miserable at training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal trainer was fabulous but my aim was never to get better at lifting or scoring bigger numbers. It was to swing a faster punch, build more stamina, and develop more explosive speed so that I could get my 2nd dan. My Karate teacher smiled patiently at me, explaining that the heavier weights, hanging, and handstands wouldn&#39;t help there. He recommended lighter weights, faster reps, and working out THROUGH Karate training, not FOR it. But for some reason, I couldn&#39;t yet change my mindset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
