<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>choice on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/choice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in choice on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/choice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Question that Will Set You Free</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-question-that-will-set-you-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-question-that-will-set-you-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;True freedom isn&#39;t doing whatever we feel like. It&#39;s being able to do what we want to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a difference between doing what we want and doing what we feel like. The former takes discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is stressful. Besides all of the frustrations of making ends meet and getting work done, there never seems to be enough time to do everything you should be doing. Besides work, you&#39;ve got your health, exercise, self-improvement, relationships, education, volunteering, cooking, playing...the list goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sometimes, it can get overwhelming, and it&#39;s so much easier to just turn on the autopilot and let things drag you along without thinking.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you ever find yourself doing any of the following?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Trade Happiness to Live &#39;Right?&#39;: Claim Your Light</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/do-you-trade-happiness-to-live-right-claim-your-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/do-you-trade-happiness-to-live-right-claim-your-light/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Our deepest fear is not that we are inadequate. Our deepest fear is that we are powerful beyond measure. It is our light, not our darkness that most frightens us. We ask ourselves, Who am I to be brilliant, gorgeous, talented, and fabulous? Actually, who are you &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; to be? You are a child of God. Your playing small does not serve the world. There is nothing enlightened about shrinking so that other people will not feel insecure around you. We are all meant to shine, as children do. We were born to make manifest the glory of God that is within us. It is not just in some of us; it is in everyone and as we let our own light shine, we unconsciously give others permission to do the same. As we are liberated from our own fear, our presence automatically liberates others. - Marianne Williamson&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I moved to Boulder was the belief that it would be a good place to live car-free, to find affordable and plentiful local food, to swear off modern, wasteful comforts (like shoes), and to pursue minimalism by selling my iPad and other non-essentials. Basically, to live the way I believed was Right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turned out to be much harder that I thought. I never found the spiritual and emotional fulfillment promised. Instead, I was limited in my activities because I could only go so far without a car, I was always hungry because of my insistence on absurdly high food quality, and I was dirty and ratty because my clothes were so worn out and overused. I was a burden to my friends, always leaning on them to drive me places I couldn&#39;t bike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I was doing the right thing, and that if I held on long enough, things would start to work out (if you&#39;ve read my book, you know I did this with eating Paleo, and CrossFit). When they never did, I got really frustrated and started to feel bitterness and resentment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up cleaving so strongly to the way I believed I &#39;should&#39; be that I completely lost sight of what actually made me happy and ended up undermining my self-esteem and sanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I knew a lot of people who weren&#39;t terribly worried about doing things right. They simply went after the things that made them feel good, made them happy, or seemed interesting. Their standard was, &#34;Does this make me happy?&#34; and not, &#34;Is this the right way?&#34; I put so much effort into figuring out the right way and following it, but I was lost and floundering. &lt;strong&gt;It didn&#39;t seem fair that others could be so seemingly lax in their morals but have the peace-of-mind and sense of purpose that I lacked.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of those people who was living the dream while happily skipping through life in time with her own drummer, was my little sister.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Moment of Your Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-most-important-moment-of-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-most-important-moment-of-your-life/</guid>
      <description>“Excellence is never an accident. It is always the result of high intention, sincere effort, and intelligent execution; it represents the wise choice of many alternatives - choice, not chance, determines your destiny.” - Aristotle
 Every moment of every day is full of choices. Some choices are trivial and some have life-altering consequences.
 Laugh or get angry Eat healthy or eat conveniently Read or watch TV Walk or run Play or work Love or hate Marriage or dating Create or consume College or work Write or don&#39;t  There are No Turning Points I often catch myself thinking that I need some big event to &#39;turn over a new leaf&#39; or otherwise start living the life I want/being the person I want to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End of Choice</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-end-of-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-end-of-choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1365&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;275&#34; caption=&#34;jah on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jahdakinebrah/64881299/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1365&#34; title=&#34;choices&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/choices-275x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;275&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The history of free men is never really written by chance but by choice - their choice” - Dwight D. Eisenhower&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/letter-to-the-president/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Letter to the President&lt;/a&gt;, a reader brought &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.organicconsumers.org/articles/article_22449.cfm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article &lt;/a&gt;to my attention, explaining how the organic elite, such entities as Whole Foods, Organic Valley, and Stonyfield Farms, have expressed their acceptance of GM crops. Whole Foods has apparently decided to stop opposing GM crops, and in return they are demanding compensation for farmers. The article also points out that most of Whole Foods products are not organic (no surprise), and that most of them are also contaminated with GM foods (also no surprise, since GM corn soybeans are used to make most of the additives in foods, including soy lecithin, modified food starch, dextrose, xantham gum, etc). So, despite their green image, Whole Foods has a vested interest in keeping labels off of foods with GMOs in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happiness is a Choice</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/happiness-is-a-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/happiness-is-a-choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1199&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Jayel Aheram&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/aheram/2228606820/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1199&#34; title=&#34;smile&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/smile-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most People are about as happy as they make up their minds to be &lt;em&gt;- Abraham Lincoln&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/book-review-the-8020-principle/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The 80/20 Principle, &lt;/a&gt;I was struck by how many useful strategies are presented for increasing one&#39;s happiness. Having spent most of my young adult life pursuing happiness and learning what behaviors and life situations lead to happiness, I was not struck so much by the idea that you can cultivate happiness as by the new approaches to the old problem. I had always taken it for granted that I could be more or less happy, and that was in my control. So it came as a bit of a shock for me when the author spent the larger portion of the section on happiness trying to convince his readers that they happiness was something they could actually control. He cited all sorts of studies and authors showing that people have a say in their happiness level, that we are not simply at the mercy of circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
