<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>boulder on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/boulder/</link>
    <description>Recent content in boulder on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/boulder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In the Barefootsteps of Erwan Le Corre</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/in-the-barefootsteps-of-erwan-le-corre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/in-the-barefootsteps-of-erwan-le-corre/</guid>
      <description>Boulder&#39;s magic strikes again.
I was out for a barefoot run last week and decided to explore a new trail. I was getting the usual stares, when one woman held my gaze. I smiled politely, and she did too, but she didn&#39;t just turn back to her hike. Instead, she yelled, &#34;Another barefooter like me!&#34; I saw shoes, but when I stopped, I realized they were light moccasins. We walked a while together until we reached a side trail where she removed her shoes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned About Landing a Job in Boulder</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-learned-about-landing-a-job-in-boulder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-learned-about-landing-a-job-in-boulder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2868&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;332&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/4273787940_2c1c65f67a.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2868&#34; alt=&#34;A job to let me land safely...can you tell I had trouble with the image for this post?&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/4273787940_2c1c65f67a.jpg&#34; width=&#34;332&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A job to let me land safely...can you tell I had trouble with the image for this post?[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m happy to announce that I have finally landed a job in Boulder, which means that I can stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you know, &lt;a title=&#34;Live What You Preach: Maintaining Faith in my Move to Boulder&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/live-what-you-preach-maintaining-faith-in-my-move-to-boulder/&#34;&gt;keeping upbeat&lt;/a&gt; in the face of difficult prospects has been hard. Especially going into March, which would have been the limit of my savings, I was worried I was going to hit a wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luckily, just as I reached the end of my financial rope, a job came through&lt;/strong&gt;. Funny how that works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, now I have the issue of having too many things to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the usual workaday job at the grocery store, I was also given my first tutoring assignment, and landed my first paid freelance magazine article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Freeing the Zoo Humans: Why I Want to Become a MovNat Instructor&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/movnat-instructor/&#34;&gt;Coaching MovNat&lt;/a&gt; is still my preferred form of employment, but that hasn&#39;t resulted in any paying arrangements. However, I&#39;m still giving it as much attention as I can spare, going around to gyms and studios offering to run workshops and introduce myself to as wide an audience as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My guess is that I will use the consistent job to get established while developing more lucrative opportunities that allow me to work on my own time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This period of my life is certainly one of the most challenging and uncomfortable, but I can tell it is also fostering a lot of growth. It&#39;s the kind of uncomfortable experience that you know is good for you, even if you&#39;d rather not have to go through it. Sort of like exercise (which I guess I&#39;m fairly good at).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few short lessons I&#39;ve learned:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Moving to Boulder</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/im-moving-to-boulder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/im-moving-to-boulder/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&#34;attachment_2768&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;576&#34;]Flatirons, here I come[/caption]
“The first step towards getting somewhere is to decide that you are not going to stay where you are.” - Anon
 By the time you read this, I will have landed in Boulder, CO, my new home for the foreseeable future.
That&#39;s a little scary to say now. I only decided to move here 30 days ago.
The road that brought me here was sort of a surprise, like a forest path you don&#39;t see until you&#39;re right on top of it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
