<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mountains on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/mountains/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mountains on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/mountains/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Your Mountain is Waiting. Do You Dare Conquer it?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/your-mountain-is-waiting-do-you-dare-conquer-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/your-mountain-is-waiting-do-you-dare-conquer-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/164348283_bb687e7e4b_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2202&#34; title=&#34;Your Mountain&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/164348283_bb687e7e4b_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;You won&#39;t lag behind, because you&#39;ll have the speed.&lt;br /&gt;
You&#39;ll pass the whole gang and you&#39;ll soon take the lead.&lt;br /&gt;
Wherever you fly, you&#39;ll be the best of the best.&lt;br /&gt;
Wherever you go, you will top all the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Dr. Seuss, &lt;em&gt;Oh the Places You&#39;ll Go!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s make things really easy for you. After all, you&#39;re only human. Be happy with what you can do and don&#39;t expect too much of yourself. You want to write? Well, don&#39;t hold yourself to a writing a bestseller. That&#39;s too hard. Settle for just finishing a book. Or, you know what, why not just write a blog? That&#39;s doable. Then you don&#39;t have to worry about failing. World-shattering success is too chancy, and if you&#39;re just not destined for it, why waste your time and go through all that anguish?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I hope the sarcasm in that last paragraph was overwhelmingly, sickeningly obvious.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world&#39;s greatest athletes have just gathered in London at the Olympics to showcase the very best of what humanity has to offer in terms of physical prowess. We love watching them perform, but rarely do any of us entertain the notion that we could aspire to gold medal success in any aspect of life. We&#39;re happy, even encouraged, to aim for something modest, lest we disappoint ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After all, to reach far is to risk all, and the fall from the top is a lot farther.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
