<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>freedom on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/freedom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in freedom on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/freedom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Moment of Your Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-most-important-moment-of-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-most-important-moment-of-your-life/</guid>
      <description>“Excellence is never an accident. It is always the result of high intention, sincere effort, and intelligent execution; it represents the wise choice of many alternatives - choice, not chance, determines your destiny.” - Aristotle
 Every moment of every day is full of choices. Some choices are trivial and some have life-altering consequences.
 Laugh or get angry Eat healthy or eat conveniently Read or watch TV Walk or run Play or work Love or hate Marriage or dating Create or consume College or work Write or don&#39;t  There are No Turning Points I often catch myself thinking that I need some big event to &#39;turn over a new leaf&#39; or otherwise start living the life I want/being the person I want to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End of Choice</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-end-of-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-end-of-choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1365&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;275&#34; caption=&#34;jah on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jahdakinebrah/64881299/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1365&#34; title=&#34;choices&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/choices-275x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;275&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The history of free men is never really written by chance but by choice - their choice” - Dwight D. Eisenhower&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/letter-to-the-president/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Letter to the President&lt;/a&gt;, a reader brought &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.organicconsumers.org/articles/article_22449.cfm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article &lt;/a&gt;to my attention, explaining how the organic elite, such entities as Whole Foods, Organic Valley, and Stonyfield Farms, have expressed their acceptance of GM crops. Whole Foods has apparently decided to stop opposing GM crops, and in return they are demanding compensation for farmers. The article also points out that most of Whole Foods products are not organic (no surprise), and that most of them are also contaminated with GM foods (also no surprise, since GM corn soybeans are used to make most of the additives in foods, including soy lecithin, modified food starch, dextrose, xantham gum, etc). So, despite their green image, Whole Foods has a vested interest in keeping labels off of foods with GMOs in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom-Promoting Jobs</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/freedom-promoting-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/freedom-promoting-jobs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; caption=&#34;Candlemaker on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/5/8016593_21260c4b3f.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; &#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/8016593_21260c4b3f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;330&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a repost of an article I wrote for another blog on career advice for young people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“You just have to do your own thing, no matter what anyone says. It&#39;s your life.” &lt;em&gt;- Ethan Embry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of reasons out there why you would want to avoid a job like the plague. After all, there is a reason Robert Kiyosaki, author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.wordpress.com/four-books-that-changed-my-life-this-summer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rich Dad, Poor Dad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, refers to the dreaded word as a mere acronym for &lt;strong&gt;J&lt;/strong&gt;ust &lt;strong&gt;O&lt;/strong&gt;ver &lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;roke. Nevertheless, getting a job is the easiest way there is to make money, if not necessarily the most desirable, and as such is an invaluable method for providing the necessary foundation to jump off to freedom. Let’s be ridiculous and say we want a job with few hours, lots of freedom, and plenty of money. Where on earth do you find one like that? Before we go on, let me define what exactly I mean when I say Job.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
