<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>agency on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/agency/</link>
    <description>Recent content in agency on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/agency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Question that Will Set You Free</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-question-that-will-set-you-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-question-that-will-set-you-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;True freedom isn&#39;t doing whatever we feel like. It&#39;s being able to do what we want to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a difference between doing what we want and doing what we feel like. The former takes discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is stressful. Besides all of the frustrations of making ends meet and getting work done, there never seems to be enough time to do everything you should be doing. Besides work, you&#39;ve got your health, exercise, self-improvement, relationships, education, volunteering, cooking, playing...the list goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sometimes, it can get overwhelming, and it&#39;s so much easier to just turn on the autopilot and let things drag you along without thinking.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you ever find yourself doing any of the following?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Environment Broken, or are You?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/is-the-environment-broken-or-are-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/is-the-environment-broken-or-are-you/</guid>
      <description>From one perspective, our world is broken. The ecosystem is collapsing, the majority of humans live isolated from nature, our society pushes unhealthy foods and inactivity, and it encourages immaturity while punishing us for impulsiveness.
Proponents of this belief think, &#34;If only the world matched the one that was best for us, we would all be healthy, fit, happy, and productive. If only the world were set up to encourage human potential, we wouldn&#39;t be so frustrated.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
