<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>habit on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/habit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in habit on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/habit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Question that Will Set You Free</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-question-that-will-set-you-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-question-that-will-set-you-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;True freedom isn&#39;t doing whatever we feel like. It&#39;s being able to do what we want to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a difference between doing what we want and doing what we feel like. The former takes discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is stressful. Besides all of the frustrations of making ends meet and getting work done, there never seems to be enough time to do everything you should be doing. Besides work, you&#39;ve got your health, exercise, self-improvement, relationships, education, volunteering, cooking, playing...the list goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sometimes, it can get overwhelming, and it&#39;s so much easier to just turn on the autopilot and let things drag you along without thinking.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you ever find yourself doing any of the following?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Be Afraid to Reach for Your Goals</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dont-be-afraid-to-reach-for-your-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dont-be-afraid-to-reach-for-your-goals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_746&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: ~dip on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/dip108/388012741/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-746&#34; title=&#34;hand&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/hand-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People have a lot of preconceived notions about what they deserve: what they deserve to be called, what they deserve to have, what they deserve to be paid, who they deserve to love and be loved by. We set limits on our own potential, not because we want to hold ourselves back, but rather because we think it is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/why-we-love-the-status-quo/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;just way&lt;/a&gt;. The thought pattern might go like this: &#34;I&#39;ve only been writing regularly for a few weeks, so I don&#39;t deserve a published novel.&#34; &lt;strong&gt;Ironically, people often are afraid to reach for their goals, because they don&#39;t think they are worthy of them&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: normal;&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
