<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>work on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in work on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>If You Don&#39;t Show Up, Life Won&#39;t Either</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/if-you-dont-show-up-life-wont-either/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/if-you-dont-show-up-life-wont-either/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Work is love made visible. - Khalil Gibran&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have run into two conflicting theories on how success works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You get lucky. Opportunities come along or they don&#39;t. You have to be in the right place at the right time or you just won&#39;t get very far. Some people have it, and some people don&#39;t.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Success is entirely dependent on your willingness to put in hard work and dedicate yourself to accomplishing what you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who lean on the first explanation usually don&#39;t see themselves as very abundant or successful. They feel a lot of frustration around their lives and their dreams, and so they claim that it&#39;s all luck to shirk responsibility for what they see as failing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a friend who has done really well, but he gives off a constant anxiety about losing it all. He uses the &#34;I got lucky&#34; argument in a way that absolves him of responsibility for his success, but my guess is he also doesn&#39;t want to think it would be his fault if things don&#39;t turn out well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other option is a more empowering viewpoint, but it is also often used to offer excuses. For example, insisting your success is based purely on your hard work might give you permission to ignore others&#39; needs and the realities of the world (market demands, consumer interests, quality of your services, importance of outside help and connections, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, of course there&#39;s a balance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cash or Friends? Where are Your Priorities?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/cash-or-friends-where-are-your-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/cash-or-friends-where-are-your-priorities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1668&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Refracted Moments(TM) on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/refractedmoments/223052548/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1668&#34; title=&#34;cash&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/cash-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cash or friends? Despite our assertion that the latter is more important, our behavior often suggests that we value money more than our relationships. We tend to work ourselves to death, and if there is any time left over, we think about seeing our friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My best friend is returning home from a year working in West Virginia, in a town that is 3 hours from the nearest interstate, in some of the most beautiful country I’ve ever seen. When he left to go work there, I drove down with him, and now that he is coming back, I’ve offered to drive down to get the rest of his stuff and help him bring it home. He has already driven half of it back, so we will be leaving together to get the rest, spending a week down there, and then driving home again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I explained to some friends that I would be out of town next week, and why, they seemed surprised that I would go to so much trouble just to provide my friend with company on his long drive back and forth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Fight the Tide</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/dont-fight-the-tide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/dont-fight-the-tide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1309&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;jtravism on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jtravism/2427479094/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1309&#34; title=&#34;tide&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/tide-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The illimitable, silent, never-resting thing called Time, rolling, rushing on, swift, silent, like an all-embracing ocean-tide, on which we and all the universe swim like exhalations, like apparitions which are, and then are not: this is forever very” -Thomas Carlyle&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I interviewed a prospective student for the University of Chicago, as a way to give back to the institution that gave me such a cool diploma (written in English though is may be). After I had gone through all my questions, I asked if she had any questions for me. She did. Her question was, &#34;If you could go back and change one thing in the four years of college, what would it be?&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zen Habits Handbook for Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/zen-habits-handbook-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/zen-habits-handbook-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_950&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: kristofabrath on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kristofabrath/3206231510/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-950&#34; title=&#34;zen&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/zen-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smile, breathe, and go slowly &lt;em&gt;- Thich Nhat Hanh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when I was in college, drowning under the immense workload and the complexities of balancing my social life, personal life, and scholastic commitments, I stumbled upon a blog that saved my academic standing as well as my sanity. The blog is called Zen Habits, and it was a godsend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Should Blow it All to Travel</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-you-should-blow-it-all-to-travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-you-should-blow-it-all-to-travel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_743&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: DragonWoman on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/dragonwoman/31029572/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-743 &#34; title=&#34;china&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/china.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We know that travel is essential to a complete education. Traveling abroad teaches understanding of other people, cultures and communities, and these types of experiences offer young people a greater ability to be successful in today&#39;s global society. &lt;em&gt;- Michael Palmer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An old friend from my days interning at Forbes gave me some interesting advice today. As a well-established manager, she would have been able to make a very good argument for starting to seriously look at a career, putting down professional roots, building up my financial profile and really setting myself up for the long, steady path to independence and security. Instead, she pretty much recommended I risk it all and travel, try to work in some other countries, because, after all at my age and in this economic climate, there isn&#39;t much to lose. &lt;strong&gt;Take the big risks while you&#39;re young&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Work a Day in Your Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/never-work-a-day-in-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/never-work-a-day-in-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/worker.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-411&#34; title=&#34;worker&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/worker.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some jobs you would do regardless of whether you were paid or not. And then there are some jobs you would only do if you were paid. I&#39;m a little shocked and terrified at the number of people who are paid to perform the functions necessary to making our civilization run, who perform jobs I can&#39;t imagine spending eight years of my life doing. I am torn between admiration for their ability to keep upbeat and cheerful and pity at the sheer tedium of their jobs. But we all have to make a living.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
