<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>focus on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/focus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in focus on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/focus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Right Action, Right Intent</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/right-action-right-intent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/right-action-right-intent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1232&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Alice PopKorn on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alicepopkorn/1676300378/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1232&#34; title=&#34;meditation&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/meditation-300x222.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;222&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;We make sacred pact. I promise teach karate to you, you promise learn. I say, you do, no questions.&#34; -Mr. Miyagi, Karate Kid (1984)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad has been baking a lot of bread recently, experimenting with different ingredients and developing his own unique style of bread. When I read his cookbook, I found out why. Instead of simply giving him a bread recipe, the author of his book explains what each step is intended to accomplish: the various factors that determine how much flour to use, how long to let the bread rise, why you let the bread rise, and what occurs in the dough during baking. It borders on chemistry, but the result is that my dad has a much better grasp of why each step must be taken, and can make adjustments to get his desired effect. If he wants to get a crispier crust, he knows what to change and how to compensate to avoid ruining his loaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Work a Day in Your Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/never-work-a-day-in-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/never-work-a-day-in-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/worker.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-411&#34; title=&#34;worker&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/worker.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some jobs you would do regardless of whether you were paid or not. And then there are some jobs you would only do if you were paid. I&#39;m a little shocked and terrified at the number of people who are paid to perform the functions necessary to making our civilization run, who perform jobs I can&#39;t imagine spending eight years of my life doing. I am torn between admiration for their ability to keep upbeat and cheerful and pity at the sheer tedium of their jobs. But we all have to make a living.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
