<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>power on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/power/</link>
    <description>Recent content in power on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/power/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Magical Power of Attention, Your Most Valuable Asset</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-magical-power-of-attention-your-most-valuable-asset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-magical-power-of-attention-your-most-valuable-asset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of us don&#39;t realize how powerful and valuable our attention is. As a result, we let it leak away and rarely bother to develop it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it so powerful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you put your attention on grows.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim Ferriss made this point in The 4-Hour Body when he showed that simply tracking your weight daily, without even attempting to make changes, led to consistent weight loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not necessarily saying there is some magical energy created by humans concentrating on specific things. It probably has to do with small micro-behaviors that start to accumulate when we have something in the forefront of our mind. Maybe constantly thinking about your weight leads your brain to subtly adjust weight-loss metabolic processes or change your appetite in small ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or maybe humans are magical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You in the 1%? You Should Be</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/are-you-in-the-1-you-should-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/are-you-in-the-1-you-should-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is an old story of a Roman, Cincinnatus, who was called upon by the Senate in an emergency. Rome&#39;s army had been trapped in the field, leaving the city vulnerable to an attack, and the government nominated Cincinnatus as dictator, giving him 6 months of absolute power. He defeated the enemy in 16 days and immediately gave up his office to return to his farm, becoming a legend of civic virtue and restraint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of us associate the word &#39;dictator&#39; with a corrupt, power-hungry leader, and that is certainly what most Roman dictators were. But the lesson here is that the office of dictator, and later of emperor, was sullied by the corrupt men who sought and held it, not by the nature of its duties. There were some dictators of sound principles, and some emperors as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night, I watched the documentary &lt;em&gt;Park Avenue,&lt;/em&gt; which is about the wealth gap in America and the political landscape that has made it so entrenched. I&#39;m not especially politically aware (something I&#39;m working on), so it was shocking to see just how bad things are. The 400 richest Americans control as much wealth as 50% of the country, 150 million people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I&#39;ve thought this was just the way our system worked: campaigning was expensive, so businesses and wealthy individuals took advantage of this to offer contributions in exchange for laws that further entrenched their wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I didn&#39;t know was that in 1971, soon-to-be Supreme Court Justice Lewis F. Powell wrote a letter to the US Chamber of Commerce, a call-to-arms to US businesses to take a more active role in shaping policy. This was in response to the sweeping political setbacks that had been experienced by corporations in the 60s and early 70s. They heeded the call, and corporate lobbying began to take on the shape it has today.&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;Thus, our current system of government-by-corporation was not the result of a broken system, but &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;was directly pursued by the corporations themselves in response to a perceived threat to their power&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result has been the shrinking of the middle class, a huge growth in the income gap, and a polarization of American society between the extremely wealthy and the extremely poor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To be wealthy in this country is to benefit from corrupt politics and to be a part of a system that oppresses the American people. Or so we have come to believe.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
