<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>encouragement on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/encouragement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in encouragement on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/encouragement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Judge the Newbs</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dont-judge-the-newbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dont-judge-the-newbs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/5770042200_bc1b1f00c3.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3160&#34; alt=&#34;5770042200_bc1b1f00c3&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5770042200_bc1b1f00c3-300x160.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;It saddens me when I see people who have accomplished something judging others who are trying to do the same thing. I see this a lot among trainers, particularly those in unorthodox fitness methods like CrossFit and MovNat. We like to remind other people what they are doing wrong, how they are ignorant, unskilled, or lazy, too focused on strength/flexibility/skill and neglecting our pet trait, how they are clearly too wimpy to do &#39;real&#39; exercise, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is only natural. We&#39;ve put a lot of effort into unlocking the secretes of superpowers, so we want to enjoy the status that gives us. I did it all the time, until I remembered how incompetent I was when I started. &lt;/strong&gt;But it doesn&#39;t actually help anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;For example, I was working out with some friends the other day while another gym-goer was loudly, clumsily, doing his own workout. My buddies noticed and snickered, whispering among themselves how what he was doing was both dangerous and inappropriate for his apparent level of fitness.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wasn&#39;t the first time this particular group of friends had indulged in this kind of behavior, so I spoke up. &lt;strong&gt;First, I reminded them that the fact that he was out there at all, clearly pushing his limits and trying something new and challenging, was a good thing. Second, every single one of us in that group had gone through a similar phase when we did things that we realized were stupid in retrospect&lt;/strong&gt;. I tried a lot of weird things, some stupid and some legitimate but misplaced in my training:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Underdog</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-underdog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-underdog/</guid>
      <description>I am small.
I am new to this dog park. I don&#39;t have many friends, and my collar is a hand-me-down.
I am young, and know little of the ways of the big dogs.
I&#39;m not a purebred, that&#39;s for sure.
I still have a lot of tricks to learn, and I&#39;m not terribly good at the ones I do know.
I am an underdog.
But if you think you can bark me out of here, you are dead wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
