<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>camping on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/camping/</link>
    <description>Recent content in camping on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/camping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5 Stories of A Little Boy in Nature</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/5-stories-of-a-little-boy-in-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/5-stories-of-a-little-boy-in-nature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSC_1618.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter  wp-image-2874&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_1618&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/DSC_1618-1024x685.jpg&#34; width=&#34;574&#34; height=&#34;383&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up this morning and sat on the edge of my futon to meditate, A&#39;s breathing setting the backdrop for my own deeper, regulated breath. I had finally managed to wake up early enough that the apartment was silent; there were no dogs scrabbling around in the kitchen, and our roommate was still asleep as well. I was determined to make the most of this time when it would be easier to focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After sitting, I picked up a book I&#39;d been intending to start for months, &lt;i&gt;Last Child in the Woods.&lt;/i&gt; I read a few pages into the first chapter, remembering stories my dad used to tell about exploring the forest just outside town, hunting squirrels with a rifle. The book is about the epidemic of what the author calls, &#34;nature deficit disorder,&#34; a condition arising from a severe and notable lack of interaction with the natural world in children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to think about my own experiences with nature and came up with very little. I had hated leaving my precious computer games and Nintendo as a child, but when I really thought about it, I did spend quite a lot of time outdoors. Some of my strongest memories were formed in the natural world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons in Minimalism from Camping</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-in-minimalism-from-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-in-minimalism-from-camping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1564&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; caption=&#34;f_r_e on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/garrulus/1743162782/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1564 &#34; title=&#34;backpack&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/backpack.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was but a wee lad, my dad used to drag me kicking and screaming into the woods to partake in an activity which, due to its lack of video games, easily available chocolate, and LEGOs, I was not too keen on. That activity was camping. As a kid, I hated it. Now, it is necessary to my spiritual well-being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Us vs. Nature: The Need for Understanding</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/usvnature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/usvnature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1427&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/100_0067.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1427&#34; title=&#34;Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/100_0067-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we had no choice but to destroy the natural world or destroy ourselves, which do you think we would pick? Let’s say that Nature has decided she has had enough. She won’t kill us outright, but she has determined to eliminate all aspects of our unsustainable lives, which means she sends her warriors to take out our property, vehicles, and infrastructure. Insects would lay waste to crops, sacrificing themselves to the pesticides, leaving organic foods untouched (assuming the crops themselves didn’t turn against us by simply refusing to produce). Rodents would flood our homes, tearing them apart from the inside, leaving us unscathed by demolishing everything manufactured, everything chemically-treated, everything unnatural. Trees and plants would suddenly demonstrate an uncanny determination to grow roots under, over, and into our buildings and roads, slowly but inexorably pulling them to pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Time Spent Outdoors</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-benefits-of-time-spent-outdoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-benefits-of-time-spent-outdoors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_954&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;222&#34; caption=&#34;Source: ©Hεαṿεṉlÿ Phøτøģɾαρhÿ on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/oooheavenlyooo/3986200282/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-954&#34; title=&#34;nature&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/nature-222x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;222&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man&#39;s heart away from nature becomes hard.  &lt;em&gt;-Standing Bear&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The natural world is all around us. Every city is merely an island of human habitation amidst a vast sea of countryside and forests. A mere hour outside of New York, one of the biggest metropolises in the world, one can find beautiful and surprisingly isolated parks and hiking trails. The hills around LA are still pretty wild (apparently coyotes are a major concern out there). Most cities have parks, little spaces where the city&#39;s fabric is cut out to reveal the nature underneath, just waiting to burst through into sunlight. These are places people can go to escape the hustle of the city for a while. There is something calming and serene about nature. I always feel complete and more balanced when surrounded by trees, and there is a lot to be said for seeking out a regular connection with the outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons on Friendship from Camp</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-on-friendship-from-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-on-friendship-from-camp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_721&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: sausyn on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/sausyn/2373020779/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-721&#34; title=&#34;friends&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/friends.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could learn a lot from crayons; some are sharp, some are pretty, some are dull, while others bright, some have weird names, but they all have to share the same box -&lt;em&gt;Anon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a great deal of my childhood at a wonderful summer camp in Northern Minnesota, where it seemed like everyone was a potential friend and all the friends you made were &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/best-friends-for-life/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;true friends&lt;/a&gt;. How great would that be in real life? So often the friends we make have agendas, or only hang around us at certain times and with certain people. There is often a sense of insincerity, or somewhat impure friendship. But at Summer Camp, the friends you made at horseback riding were just as good for sailing (assuming they &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; sail), and you could eat with them, camp with them, play games with them, or just sit and watch the lake together. There is a strange and wondrous ease about camp friends that is so rare and hard to find elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Friends (for Life)</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/best-friends-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/best-friends-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;mceTemp&#34;&gt;
&lt;dl class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34;&gt;
&lt;dt class=&#34;wp-caption-dt&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/friends.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of you have asked who the people in the canoe on the top banner are. It&#39;s no surprise that one of them is me. The other person is a guy who has been like a brother to me since fifth grade, when I stumbled awkwardly on to the shores of this country, a naive Arab with no clue how to handle this overwhelming America, as it were. He took me under his wing, and attempted (in vain) to teach me the ways of the American schoolboy. Since then, we&#39;ve been through almost everything together: we&#39;ve gotten to the point of mutual hatred, we&#39;ve come to appreciate the man-hug, we got our Eagle Scout badges at the same time and held a joint ceremony, we&#39;ve SCUBA dived together, and undertaken the most sacred of modern manly bonding rituals: Playing through Halo&#39;s Co-op Campaign on Legendary difficulty. He was my inspiration to get better at video games, and sports, and we&#39;ve been up until 3 AM countless times arguing the finer points of moral philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pigeonholing Myself</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/pigeonholing-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/pigeonholing-myself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/pigeon.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-507&#34; title=&#34;pigeon&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/pigeon.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In high school, we have so many dreams and activities. In order to be competitive for college, we fill our transcripts with a crazy variety of activities: math club, Boy Scouts, flying lessons, karate, cross country, guitar, piano lessons. This is in addition to our classes, which tend to cover a wide range of subjects: precalc, biology, English, painting. Then in college, we start off with a fairly broad range of topics to study, and as we move towards our major, the subjects narrow down to one or two: psychology and international studies of the Middle East. Then, after college, we get a job and are expected to become experts in one single field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to consider myself a renaissance man, with interests in a wide range of activities, but I&#39;m not so sure anymore. After all, I spend so much of my time studying fitness and in training. My conversations with people tend to gravitate towards talk about health, fitness, and nutrition. Last night while bartending,  a guy at the bar wanted to watch the NFL draft, and I had no clue how to have a conversation with him. I never really followed or understood football, but it made be wonder if I&#39;m either out of touch with society or simply too narrow in my interests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing What I Never Had: My Connection to the Real Food Community</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/missing-what-i-never-had-my-connection-to-the-real-food-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/missing-what-i-never-had-my-connection-to-the-real-food-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/countryside.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-478&#34; title=&#34;countryside&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/countryside.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I have an interesting relationship with the sustainable food community. I am deeply passionate about it, but I have never actually been a part of it. I can practically come to tears reading Mother Earth News and get lost in stories about people raising heritage chickens, constructing their own homes,, tending gardens, living in harmony with nature and experiencing a familial closeness that few Americans ever experience anymore. But I have never done any of these things. I think I grew some bean sprouts once in elementary school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this apparent lack of connection, every time I read these stories or talk with people who live these lives, I feel an unmistakable sense of nostalgia. It seems strange to feel nostalgic for something I&#39;ve never experienced, but I strongly &lt;em&gt;miss&lt;/em&gt; these things. I miss raising chickens, I miss knowing the names of the trees and what they are good for, I miss being in tune with the seasons. It is as if a quiet part of me, long dormant, stirs every time it hears something related to how things used to be. There is a spiritual connection to that life of harmony that is so powerful in me it almost hurts to live a life that is not in accordance to its desires. But where did it come from? Has it always been there, as a primordial connection to the land and community inherent in all humans? Or is it something that grew in me in response to the decay I see in our disharmonious world and the hope offered by a return to a different lifestyle whose values so closely mirror my deepest ideals?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ties That Bind</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-ties-that-bind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-ties-that-bind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/web.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-424&#34; title=&#34;web&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/web.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;224&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my path down alternative fitness and nutrition and spirituality, I&#39;m discovering that members of my various communities all seem to agree on certain things. Most CrossFitters tend to agree that we should move as our bodies were meant to, and often think in terms of evolutionary biology and anatomy. This parallels a similar trend in the local and traditional food community to look back to how our ancestors ate to determine the best way to eat now. In fact, the CrossFitters also extend this mentality to nutrition, and I&#39;m sure many traditional foodies would as well if fitness were as central to their lives as nutrition is to a CrossFitter&#39;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traits of a Warrior: Humility</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-humility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-humility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/humility.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-407&#34; title=&#34;humility&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/humility.jpg?w=210&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;210&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most important lessons I&#39;ve learned from CrossFit is humility. Workouts that sound easy never are, and I am always amazed at how quickly my muscles will tire, how a weight that sounds light quickly becomes unbearable. To make things worse, we are always talking about how some crazy CrossFitter completed the same WOD in unrealistically fast times. CrossFit is a community, and so we know that the same workout that destroyed everyone at our gym was a walk in the park for someone else. Personally, this is hard to swallow. I know I&#39;ve made amazing strides since I started, but an unweighted barbell still gets painfully heavy after a few minutes, and burpees can still leave me begging for mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make things worse, I&#39;ve come to learn that getting frustrated does not make things any better. After 5 months of training, my snatch max hasn&#39;t changed a single pound. But trying to use frustration to motivate myself only causes my technique to fall apart. There is a fine line between determination and frustration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Superhero Training</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/superhero-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/superhero-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/khaledbatman.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-339&#34; title=&#34;khaledbatman&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/khaledbatman.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People ask me why I train so hard. The answer is simple. I&#39;m training to be Batman... (as Superman was technically an alien, it would be a bit ridiculous for me to train to be him, since there&#39;s no way I could ever achieve that level of strength and fitness as an Earthling).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My CrossFit coaches have offered to pay my registration fee for the New England CrossFit Sectionals in March. While those who know me can attest to the fact that I didn&#39;t really need much motivation to train hard in the past, going to the Sectionals has given me a new kind of motivation and intensity to train. Knowing that I am going to be competing against some of the fittest people in New England, many of them bigger and stronger than me, has gotten me to really kick my training into high gear.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
