<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>inspiring on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/inspiring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in inspiring on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/inspiring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3 Tips to Understand and Inspire Others</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/3-tips-to-understand-and-inspire-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/3-tips-to-understand-and-inspire-others/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Have you ever made an agreement with someone which you thought was crystal-clear, only to find them doing exactly the opposite? When you confront them, they respond with, “I didn’t mean it that way,” or, “I thought you meant something else.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I ran into that problem a lot, and I assumed they were making up excuses. After all, words have specific meanings, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Wrong!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy of a WS Blog Post</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/anatomy-of-a-ws-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/anatomy-of-a-ws-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“Writing is an exploration. You start from nothing and learn as you go.” E.L. Doctorow&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/3397858623_ff8e4ce060.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-2445&#34; title=&#34;Anatomy of a Blogger&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3397858623_ff8e4ce060.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;322&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An old writing teacher once told me it&#39;s better to be wordy and get the point across than try to cater to short attention spans and leave everyone scratching their heads. I learned in high school that if you write an engaging story, people will read 20 page sci-fi action adventures, long for high school creative writing. If you make it appeal to their emotions, they will even enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same thing goes for blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a writer with a blog, I want to make sure every post I write is engaging and inspiring. Learning how to write in this medium has been a long and arduous process. I am still refining it, but in recent months, I&#39;ve had a bit of success reaching new readers, so I wanted to share my current working template of my blog posts. Not all of them match this, of course (this one doesn&#39;t), but it serves as a loose framework to aim for.  It largely depends on how much time I have and how much energy I have after chasing &lt;del&gt;psychotic&lt;/del&gt; energetic Korean children around all day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
