<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>growth on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/growth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in growth on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/growth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Acorn and the Oak Tree; How to Let Go of Striving so You Can Grow</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/acorn-oak-let-go-striving-grow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/acorn-oak-let-go-striving-grow/</guid>
      <description>Most people don&#39;t think much of acorns, but are very impressed by oak trees. Thus, most people think of an acorn as nothing more than a means to an oak tree. The acorn itself is worthless. All that matters is the tree that comes out of it.
But then we may make the mistake of creating an environment that is ideal for a fully grown oak, not a young acorn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pains of Transitions</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-pains-of-transitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-pains-of-transitions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sorry I&#39;ve been MIA for the last few weeks. A rushed departure from Boulder meant that I wasn&#39;t able to write anything. But 30+ hours on the road is lots of time for thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life has changed in a big way, and I don&#39;t yet know what will emerge on the other side of this summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 1.17em; line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;Breaking&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last few months have been filled with all sorts of traumas, some big and some small, the hallmark of transition. That, too, is normal. Joseph Campbell pointed out that the hero&#39;s journey always requires some kind of death and rebirth. No matter the promised rewards, the death is always terrifying. The hero is faced with obliteration in order to become someone stronger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Skill You&#39;ll Ever Learn</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-most-important-skill-youll-ever-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-most-important-skill-youll-ever-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Go eagerly where the fear is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are at a party. Across the snack table, you notice a small crowd gathering around an underdressed guy in jeans and a t-shirt. He turns out to be a well-known science-fiction book agent. Just the person you are looking to meet since finishing your novel. You want to talk to that person. But he looks busy, probably wouldn&#39;t appreciate &lt;em&gt;another &lt;/em&gt;awestruck peon, and you wouldn&#39;t get much talk time anyway. You are convinced it would be a waste of time. So you decide to ask the host for his e-mail address on your way out and write later. You have very good reasons not to introduce yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then...as you turn back to the friends you came with, you wonder, why are you even making reasons? You aren&#39;t making that effort for anyone else in the room. Just this one guy who it would be a great idea &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;to talk to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&#39;s when you know: if you leave this party without introducing yourself, you will leave defeated. You will have found exactly the thing that you need to do to move forward, and shied away from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The things you need to do to move forward are always the things you fear doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Millennial Manifesto: The Responsibility to be Great</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-millennial-manifesto-the-passion-of-a-new-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-millennial-manifesto-the-passion-of-a-new-generation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are the Millennials. Constantly connected, over-educated, and fired with passion, we have been accused of laziness, entitlement, and narcissism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we are to inherit the world, a world that is more and more defined by change: entire business platforms rise and fall in the course of a few months. I have no doubt that history repeats itself, but with over 7 billion people, nations with the power to manufacture unfathomable quantities of goods, and an information network that rivals the human brain, I feel justified in saying &lt;strong&gt;the world we inherit will be unique in human history&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Brave New World&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all the negative adjectives thrown our way, one thing I have seen among my peers is a truly inspiring degree of passion, a desire to remake the world, to set their own rules and live by their own principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a powerful vision of a world far different than the one we were born into. Many of us have become distrustful of established power structures. We have seen the green revolution co-opted by corporate interests. Growing up in a globalized world has revealed to us that we cannot blindly pursue power without thought for the repercussions on the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything is vulnerable to questioning now&lt;/strong&gt;, and so many of my friends are unsatisfied with what life has given them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And lets be honest, life hasn&#39;t give them much. Youth unemployment in the US ranges from 20%-30% (depending on the study and the criteria), an abysmally high number. We are underemployed, not unemployable. We came of age into a world that didn&#39;t have a place for us, that couldn&#39;t utilize us, that expects us to wait idly on the sidelines and be grateful for placeholders like internships and volunteerism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That, right there, that&#39;s the sense of entitlement we&#39;re accused of. But shall we instead deign to accept meager returns? &lt;strong&gt;I think it&#39;s better to constantly be chafing at the bit, &lt;a title=&#34;Grow to Live: Why Constant Improvement is Necessary&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/grow-to-live-why-constant-improvement-is-necessary/&#34;&gt;striving for more&lt;/a&gt; and the chance to make an impact.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a way, Warrior Spirit is a blog for millennials: it admits a sense of higher purpose, the right to excellence, and even the &lt;a title=&#34;Are You in the 1%? You Should Be&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/are-you-in-the-1-you-should-be/&#34;&gt;responsibility to be great&lt;/a&gt;. At the same time, it asserts the importance of getting your hands dirty, doing the nitty-gritty, and having the pragmatic know-how to make our vision of the world a reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Reasons...</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/5-reasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/5-reasons/</guid>
      <description>... you should do it.
1. Because you can Sometimes that&#39;s the best reason of all: your potential, and the drive to realize it. You know you can run farther, love more truthfully, lift heavier, earn more, learn more. You know that you can do better.
Yet, day after day, you find yourself in the same place you were yesterday, not living up to your potential.
This starts to irritate you, but you try to be grateful for what you have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing Hope</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/choosing-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/choosing-hope/</guid>
      <description>Wandering the bookstore, I am always amazed at the wide variety of interests and ideas humans cultivate and share. There are people who spend months or years working on books about what I consider trivial topics and stories about everything under the sun. I feel amazed at the power of the human spirit and our many stories, the sheer richness of our culture and civilization.
This contrasts strongly with a general misanthropy I&#39;ve noticed among some of my communities, particularly the local food and paleo/ancestral health communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MovNat Guest Post: Accept Frailty to Grow Strong</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/movnat-guest-post-accept-frailty-to-grow-strong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/movnat-guest-post-accept-frailty-to-grow-strong/</guid>
      <description>I was recently featured on the MovNat blog, talking about how much of a pansy I am (sort of). I thought I&#39;d just share that article for today.
One thing they never tell you about barefoot running is how painful it can be. When you step out on a trail for your first totally unshod trek, eager to run wild and free though the forest, you are suddenly struck with an unexpected problem: tiny pebbles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Little Chieftain; Are You Waiting for Permission to Live?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-little-chieftain-are-you-waiting-for-permission-to-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-little-chieftain-are-you-waiting-for-permission-to-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/4822540384_173d27437c.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2834&#34; alt=&#34;The Chief&#39;s Headdress&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/4822540384_173d27437c.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;334&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The once was a tribe of people living in an ancient land. They chose from among their number one to lead them, a chief, who was the most skilled in hunting, diplomacy, and wisdom. He or she was to be a beacon for the tribe, a person to inspire a sense of belonging and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One year, as the current chief was dying, there were two candidates to replace her. Both boys were truly skilled in the art of warriorship, and both possessed wisdom beyond their years. They were of the same age, at the cusp of manhood, but one still acted like a little boy. He felt like someone or something had to give him permission to be a man. The other acted as if manhood were already his. He took an air of fatherhood around the children and acted like an equal among the elders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, the tribe still had trouble deciding, for both boys were exceptionally skilled and passed all the tests of intellect and insight. After a long day being interviewed, the two of them found themselves alone in the chief&#39;s room, the elders having retired to discuss. Sitting in the back of the room were the chieftain&#39;s robes and headdress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As boys are wont to do, they grew curious about that which is forbidden them, and finally they decided try on these magical garments. They had been fashioned for an adult, and clearly would fit neither boy, but they wanted to feel what it would be like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first boy threw the robe around his scrawny shoulders and lowered the headdress over his brow. His friend only barely managed to stifle a laugh, and truly the boy in the robes felt strange and uncomfortable. He hunched, as if trying to get away from the feathers that adorned his head. They robes didn&#39;t fit, physically or otherwise, but he assumed they would feel more comfortable over time, just as his bow had felt awkward until he had taken it on several hunts. He knew that if he were selected, the tribe&#39;s permission would give him the certainty he needed to fill the outfit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the other boy donned the garb, and the large robe slipped down his narrow shoulders. But when the first boy looked on his friend smiling and standing tall under the too-large headdress, he saw that this boy wore the cloak and feathers like they were already his. The way he stood, the way he bore them proudly instead of uncertainly, said that he could already see himself as the chief. Perhaps there were skills to be learned, but this boy was not shy of being called chief and being looked to for guidance. Though the garb didn&#39;t fit physically, it seemed to belong to this boy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first boy told his friend what he saw and he left the room to tell the elders he was withdrawing. And the little chief who had always been a chief led his tribe on to many great victories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;I’m Moving to Boulder&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/im-moving-to-boulder/&#34;&gt;Having arrived in Boulder&lt;/a&gt;, I set about trying to establish a life here. Income was (is) hard to come by. I live in a shared apartment, and I&#39;ve applied to a lot of part-time jobs to try to get things started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Live What You Preach: Maintaining Faith in my Move to Boulder&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/live-what-you-preach-maintaining-faith-in-my-move-to-boulder/&#34;&gt;It&#39;s pretty scary sometimes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I met a guy, not even my age, who goes to work in a suit and tie, who owns his own condo, and who doesn&#39;t just work because he needs a bit of money as he sets up for his next step, but who is a contributing member of society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I am quite mature in regards to psychology, emotional intelligence, and personal integrity, but &lt;strong&gt;in terms of my material prosperity, I still envision my life like a student, someone dependent, in transition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned from a Year Living and Working in Korea</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-learned-from-a-year-living-and-working-in-korea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-learned-from-a-year-living-and-working-in-korea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;My year in Korea has come to its end. Friday was my last teaching day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I have done in the past, I like to look back as this chapter of my life comes to a close and review what I&#39;ve learned. Putting the experiences into a larger context helps me learn from my mistakes and consolidate my successes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot has happened in my first year of living completely independent of my parents, in a country that is literally on the other side of the world from my hometown. Here is what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since Joseph Campbell writes about the hero&#39;s journey, I thought he would be especially appropriate to help illustrate reflection on this rite of passage. So, this is a Campbell-themed post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re Not the One Who Will Achieve Your Dreams</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youre-not-the-one-who-will-achieve-your-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youre-not-the-one-who-will-achieve-your-dreams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“The recipe for perpetual ignorance is: Be satisfied with your opinions and content with your knowledge.” -Elbert Hubbard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We know what we are, but know now what we may be.” - William Shakespeare&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/6527715119_b568570ab2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2499&#34; title=&#34;The Illusion of the Self&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/6527715119_b568570ab2-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest obstacles to accomplishing our greatest dreams and goals is the fear of growth. We are unwilling to change, even in a positive way, because growth is painful. Even when we get stronger as a result, we tend to shy away from the necessary discomfort that comes with the process of improving ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After all, growth only comes as the result of learning to deal with challenges that are slightly beyond us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem is that,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;in order to accomplish our goals, we must grow.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we didn&#39;t need to grow, we would already be doing what we dream about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on our particular dream, the kind of change and growth we need will be different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to get stronger, faster, healthier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to make more connections and meet more people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to gain deeper insight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to learn new ideas and master new theories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to see the world in a slightly different way that empowers us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to play a bigger game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We need to be comfortable with the things that scare us at the moment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To a large extent, that last one covers all the others, and it is significant because it is integral to our sense of who we are. &lt;strong&gt;Our fears create our limiting image of ourselves&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Am I Too Young to Matter?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/am-i-too-young-to-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/am-i-too-young-to-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2017&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/221737671_c0383274df.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-2017&#34; title=&#34;Sad Baby&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/221737671_c0383274df-225x300.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/steelmore/221737671/&#34;&gt;Just Taken Pics on Flickr&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You can only be young once. But you can always be immature.” -Dave Barry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently had a conversation on Twitter in which I was sharing some insights on health and life. My conversation partner thought that I was making some very good points, and all was going well. Then she revealed that she is married with kids, and suddenly I thought, &#34;What wisdom can I offer this person, who has seen so much more of life than I?&#34; I was embarrassed, even though she had agreed with my ideas and said that her experiences confirmed them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized that I have a belief that I cannot offer much to the world because I am so young. All of my ideas have only been around a short time, and the hard trial of years hasn&#39;t yet tested their worth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But is my youth really that much of a handicap?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I share my insights on life, there is a voice in my head saying people older than me might dismiss my ideas because I&#39;m only 25. They might wonder how much I could possibly have gleaned from my life in that short time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I&#39;m encouraging happiness, I worry they will think that I haven&#39;t accepted that life is hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I&#39;m talking about difficulty, I worry they will think that I have an entitlement complex, that I expect the world to be handed to me because I&#39;m young and don&#39;t yet know how to do hard work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s really no way to win over stubborn old people (especially when you&#39;re not sure they really think that way at all).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grow to Live: Why Constant Improvement is Necessary</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/grow-to-live-why-constant-improvement-is-necessary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/grow-to-live-why-constant-improvement-is-necessary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1778&#34; align=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Rob Young on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/rob-young/2042586449/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1778&#34; title=&#34;brucelee&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/brucelee-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously, if you always put limits on what you can do, physical or anything else, it’ll spread over into the rest of your life. It’ll spread into your work, into your morality, into your entire being. There are no limits. There are plateaus, but you must not stay there, you must go beyond them. If it kills you, it kills you. A man must constantly exceed his level. -Bruce Lee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bruce Lee was one of the greatest martial artists who ever lived. But did he think that gave him an excuse to stop improving? If the above quotation is any indication, the answer is no. Bruce Lee was always growing and always pushing his limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warrior Spirit Evolves</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/warrior-spirit-evolves/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/warrior-spirit-evolves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay...I&#39;ve really got it this time. Seriously. &lt;strong&gt;I now know what this blog is about&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, I&#39;ve said that a lot before, but this time it&#39;s real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check it out. See that snazzy new subtitle. This blog isn&#39;t about me anymore (well, I guess it will always kind of be about me). It&#39;s about &lt;em&gt;Us&lt;/em&gt;, trying to make ourselves the best we can be, so that we can be the most awesome, helpful, revolutionary, world-changing people we can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Mistakes to Learn</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/make-mistakes-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/make-mistakes-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1313&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Jeffrey Montes on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jm-photography/4866200549/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1313&#34; title=&#34;SONY DSC&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/paint-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The man who makes no mistakes does not usually make anything. - William Connor Magee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the productivity newsletters I subscribe to, Psychotactics, recently sent out an article on the best strategies to learn and retain knowledge. The author explained that almost every attempt we make to acquire knowledge is done in such a way as to make it very unlikely we will actually be able to hold on to that knowledge. The reason is simply because we are afraid to test our knowledge and make mistakes and mistakes are the key to knowledge retention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Just Face Your Fears, Learn to Love Them</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/dont-just-face-your-fears-learn-to-love-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/dont-just-face-your-fears-learn-to-love-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1203&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;epSos.de on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/epsos/4376727123/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1203&#34; title=&#34;Fear&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/Fear-300x168.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;168&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must not fear. Fear is the mind-killer. Fear is the little-death that brings total obliteration. I will face my fear. I will permit it to pass over me and through me. And when it has gone past I will turn the inner eye to see its path. Where the fear has gone there will be nothing. Only I will remain. &lt;em&gt;-Bene Gesserit Litany Against Fear, Frank Herbert&#39;s&lt;/em&gt; Dune&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say the thing that most scares us is the unfamiliar. We seem naturally wary of things that we don&#39;t know very well, even parts of ourselves that we haven&#39;t dealt with in a very long time. We also shy away from things we have simply never experienced before. Unfortunately, this includes many of the things we&#39;d like to live up to and achieve. So we have a problem; anyone who wants to grow and develop as a human being, to achieve their true potential (aka, their Warrior Spirit), must go from what they know, through what they don&#39;t know, and therefore, must face their fears.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
