<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>social media on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/social-media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in social media on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/social-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is Facebook controlling who your friends are?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/is-facebook-controlling-who-your-friends-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/is-facebook-controlling-who-your-friends-are/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/05/laptop.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-578&#34; title=&#34;laptop&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/laptop.jpg?w=199&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Something I&#39;ve noticed happened with Facebook and other social networks is that many of the friends I interact with online are not the same ones I&#39;d normally interact with in person. In some cases, they are people I don&#39;t even enjoy being around in person, but are nevertheless fun and interesting to talk to in the sterile little chat box. This got me to thinking about how the mediums we use for social interaction affect that interaction. I&#39;m certainly more flirtatious online than in person, but what if the effects go deeper than tone?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pigeonholing Myself</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/pigeonholing-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/pigeonholing-myself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/pigeon.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-507&#34; title=&#34;pigeon&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/pigeon.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In high school, we have so many dreams and activities. In order to be competitive for college, we fill our transcripts with a crazy variety of activities: math club, Boy Scouts, flying lessons, karate, cross country, guitar, piano lessons. This is in addition to our classes, which tend to cover a wide range of subjects: precalc, biology, English, painting. Then in college, we start off with a fairly broad range of topics to study, and as we move towards our major, the subjects narrow down to one or two: psychology and international studies of the Middle East. Then, after college, we get a job and are expected to become experts in one single field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to consider myself a renaissance man, with interests in a wide range of activities, but I&#39;m not so sure anymore. After all, I spend so much of my time studying fitness and in training. My conversations with people tend to gravitate towards talk about health, fitness, and nutrition. Last night while bartending,  a guy at the bar wanted to watch the NFL draft, and I had no clue how to have a conversation with him. I never really followed or understood football, but it made be wonder if I&#39;m either out of touch with society or simply too narrow in my interests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Would You Even Be Able to Say that to my Face?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/would-you-even-be-able-to-say-that-to-my-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/would-you-even-be-able-to-say-that-to-my-face/</guid>
      <description>Just found this interestging article in Times online, entitled, &#34;Does Facebook Replace Face Time or Enhance It?&#34; Considering I write a blog, which i share on Facebook and Twitter and which has engendered intersting duscussion at times, I thought I&#39;d comment.
The gist of the article is a dilemma between whether Facebook causes people to avoid interacting in real time or if it improves their real life relationships. The author describes his relationship with an old friend, which has degenerated to the point where she hasn&#39;t returned a phone call in over a year, but has poked him, sent him facebook gifts, and interacted in the various mini-games and applications on Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Stand Out</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/learning-to-stand-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/learning-to-stand-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Standing out&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/entrepreneur1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;412&#34; height=&#34;309&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have already talked about one aspect of the mindset associated with this post-college, recessionary jobhunt, that of having confidence in my employability. I wanted to share some recent developments in my strategies and the way I&#39;m approaching things now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
