<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>facebook on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/facebook/</link>
    <description>Recent content in facebook on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/facebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Keeping in Touch in a Disconnected World</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/keeping-in-touch-in-a-disconnected-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/keeping-in-touch-in-a-disconnected-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1412&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;cynthiacloskey on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/cynthiacloskey/2439736125/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1412&#34; title=&#34;letters&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/letters-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My generation is surrounded by hundreds of ways to instantaneously get in touch with old friends. We have Facebook, MySpace, Twitter, iPhones, Droids, Wi-fi hotspots, 3G networks, text messages, e-mail, instant messaging, and even that old standby, the telephone. And yet, almost all of my old friends claim that they are horrible at staying in touch. On a whim, they can say hello to someone with the touch of a button, and yet, we hear from one another so infrequently many of us wonder what the point of social technology is in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Facebook controlling who your friends are?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/is-facebook-controlling-who-your-friends-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/is-facebook-controlling-who-your-friends-are/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/05/laptop.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-578&#34; title=&#34;laptop&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/laptop.jpg?w=199&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Something I&#39;ve noticed happened with Facebook and other social networks is that many of the friends I interact with online are not the same ones I&#39;d normally interact with in person. In some cases, they are people I don&#39;t even enjoy being around in person, but are nevertheless fun and interesting to talk to in the sterile little chat box. This got me to thinking about how the mediums we use for social interaction affect that interaction. I&#39;m certainly more flirtatious online than in person, but what if the effects go deeper than tone?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Would You Even Be Able to Say that to my Face?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/would-you-even-be-able-to-say-that-to-my-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/would-you-even-be-able-to-say-that-to-my-face/</guid>
      <description>Just found this interestging article in Times online, entitled, &#34;Does Facebook Replace Face Time or Enhance It?&#34; Considering I write a blog, which i share on Facebook and Twitter and which has engendered intersting duscussion at times, I thought I&#39;d comment.
The gist of the article is a dilemma between whether Facebook causes people to avoid interacting in real time or if it improves their real life relationships. The author describes his relationship with an old friend, which has degenerated to the point where she hasn&#39;t returned a phone call in over a year, but has poked him, sent him facebook gifts, and interacted in the various mini-games and applications on Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
