<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>merrell on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/merrell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in merrell on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/merrell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Epic Tale of the Triumph of Will Over Utter Stupidity</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/an-epic-tale-of-the-triumph-of-will-over-utter-stupidity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/an-epic-tale-of-the-triumph-of-will-over-utter-stupidity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on the travel blog I kept while living in Korea.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/DSC_4519-e1331562897868.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had pretty much given up around the 20km mark. My left arch had been cramping since I passed 10km and my feet felt like the road was molten asphalt. I was still moving my feet, but it was more of a shuffle as I gingerly placed each step carefully to avoid even the tiniest jolt to my worn out suspension. I glared resentfully at every pair of cushy, padded, motion-controlled sneakers that cruised by me, their owners floating on a soft cloud of running technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had wondered if running a marathon in my &#39;barefoot&#39; Merrell Trailgloves was a good idea, but it turned out to be much worse than I had imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was only my second marathon. The first one I had run in racing flats, and I didn&#39;t think there would be too much difference, but it turns out half an inch of foam was the difference between crippling pain and a challenging run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had also had a running partner the first time. My dad and I had jogged steadily around the streets of Philly, chatting and sharing observations about the city. Here, in South Korea, I was running alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I talked myself into putting one foot in front of the other. Somehow, I made it through the twenties and starting chipping away at kilometer 30, then 31, then 32. Each one seemed longer than the one before. With every...single...step my body wanted to stand still. &#34;Please let me walk, just two steps. I&#39;ll do anything!&#34; it begged me. Still I ran.&lt;img title=&#34;More...&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/trans.gif&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
