<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self-motivation on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/self-motivation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in self-motivation on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/self-motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Can I Preach It, if I Don&#39;t Live It?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/can-i-preach-it-if-i-dont-live-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/can-i-preach-it-if-i-dont-live-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1606&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;226&#34; caption=&#34;Mike Cattell on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mikecattell/4411829834/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1606&#34; title=&#34;pews&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/pews-226x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;226&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be too easy to be perfect all the time. It is  far more difficult to accept that you’re not perfect but to believe  that you have worthwhile things to say despite that, and to say those  things with conviction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the last two weeks, I’d been in a bit of a rut.  Things that used to excite me didn’t appeal to me anymore. Exercise,  gymnastics, trail running, and even writing all seemed tedious and  boring. All I wanted to do all day was go home and sleep, and when I got  home, I didn’t want to sleep. I was just generally out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also seemed to be messing up everything good in my life.  Professionally, I’d given up a lot of hours training to work on my  writing, with the result that I was pretty broke. My  iPad-as-laptop-replacement experiment was a failure, so I had to buy a  new laptop. My relationship with my girlfriend was in a rough patch,  which just makes everything else seems hellish. I wasn’t sleeping well,  and all I wanted to eat was peanut butter and jelly sandwiches, which  was a problem because I don’t keep jelly at my house and most bread  gives me indigestion. My room was a mess, and I was out of clean  underwear and floss (surprisingly discouraging, actually).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to say that things have improved, though I still  need to invest in some floss, but I wanted to talk a little bit about  the weirdness of being an inspirational writer and not always feeling  inspired.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
