<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self-talk on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/self-talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in self-talk on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/self-talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Can I do This?: A Question to Improve Performance on Everything</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/can-i-do-this-a-question-to-improve-performance-on-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/can-i-do-this-a-question-to-improve-performance-on-everything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3855&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/question-e1418143667521.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;question&#34; width=&#34;761&#34; height=&#34;566&#34; /&gt;Perhaps you&#39;ve heard the old advice that it&#39;s important to psych yourself up before a big test or meeting. Remind yourself how awesome you are! Tell yourself, &#34;I can do this! I&#39;m a rockstar!&#34; Maybe you&#39;ve even done this, despite all feelings to the contrary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve ever been in an airplane during extreme turbulence, you don&#39;t want to overhear your pilot insisting, &#34;I can do this! Yeah!&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they are talking at all, you want to hear specific actions that they will be taking to make things better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a reason for this. Our minds actually interpret insistent statements like these as a sign that there is something really wrong. After all, if you were confident, you wouldn&#39;t even need to bother with the motivation at all, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it turns out there&#39;s a better way to motivate yourself, one that feels less like a desperate plea to convince yourself of something you just don&#39;t believe, and that actually helps you do better, rather than simply feel better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask the simple question, &#34;Can I do this?&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
