<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>runs on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/runs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in runs on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/runs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Start Your Day Right with an Anchor</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/building-your-day-around-an-anchor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/building-your-day-around-an-anchor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;lulu lemon athletica on Flickr&#34;]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/20110329-101320.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/20110329-101320.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20110329-101320.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image of the lone warrior training every day at dawn is a popular one in the martial arts. Like clockwork, the Warrior rises before her companions have even stirred to run through her training. She does this in the mornings, so that there is no possibility of distraction. It is her source of strength, for even in the midst of a quest, she finds time to hone her skills and focus her mind for the day&#39;s coming struggles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you ever feel frustrated by the inconsistency in your days? While change and excitement are great, I&#39;ve always found that I really appreciate having at least a few things that are steady that I can turn to in order to get into the right mindset for the day. Alternatively, having something later in the day that I can expect helps me forget all the troubles and problems that have cropped up. An afternoon run will do wonders to help you put the stresses of a long workday behind you so that you can focus your energies on being with your family in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
