<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>intuition on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/intuition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in intuition on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/intuition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Listen to Your Intuition: It Could Save Your Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/listen-to-your-intuition-it-could-save-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/listen-to-your-intuition-it-could-save-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Listen to your intuition. It will tell you everything you need to know. - Anthony J. D&#39;Angelo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/brainhalves.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3144&#34; alt=&#34;brainhalves&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/brainhalves-300x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;He stood out among the other men at the table. He had a sense of practiced confidence about him, and whenever he spoke to the event facilitator--the only woman in the room--his responses seemed too playful, too well-rehearsed, and she laughed as if on cue. When it was his turn to introduce himself to the group, a label popped unsolicited into my head: pickup artist. I filed it to verify in time, and sure enough, he revealed that to be his background. Later during the workshop, he made vague reference to some challenges he was working on, without actually defining them. That voice in my head immediately supplied the details: trouble with commitment. Again, as the class progressed, he revealed that to be exactly his difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve never considered myself to be a great judge of people. In college, I&#39;d meet particularly jovial people at parties thinking they were simply really happy, only to be told later that they were obviously drunk. I figured that if I couldn&#39;t identify the telltale signs of something so blatant as drunkenness, I should never trust my judgements about people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock the Vast Knowledge in Your Ancient DNA</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/unlock-the-vast-knowledge-in-your-ancient-dna/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/unlock-the-vast-knowledge-in-your-ancient-dna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently discovered a secret store of untapped skill and agility that anyone can use. I was out running on a trail with no shoes on, struggling mightily not to stub my toes on all the rocks and stones. It was mentally exhausting. I&#39;d just finished a novel: &lt;em&gt;God Emperor of Dune.&lt;/em&gt; One of the main characters in this book has conscious access to all his ancestor&#39;s memories and experiences, encoded in his DNA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It occurred to me that &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; body also contains the DNA of all of my ancestors, millions of whom probably spent a lot of time running on rugged trails. In fact, encoded into my DNA and all that has arisen out of it are the instincts of tens of millions (maybe more) organisms, not all human, that spent their entire lives navigating wild, treacherous terrain. Along the way, there must have been some creation of an instinct that helped these creatures manage rocky trails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, no matter how my life had progressed, &lt;strong&gt;I could not deny that there was in fact some remnant of all that history within me, if only in the way my DNA was constructed&lt;/strong&gt;. The experience of my ancestors, all the way back to the first proto-life, had created the blueprint for my existence and the framework around which my brain and nervous system were built. It seemed reasonable to think that perhaps there were some useful instincts prebuilt into me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to try something. I stopped consciously thinking about where to put my feet. I let go of the need to control my body and leaned forward to pick up speed, forcing my reflexes to direct my actions in order to avoid injury. I trusted my feet and my body&#39;s intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
