<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>khaled allen on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/khaled-allen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in khaled allen on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/khaled-allen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A 10 Minute Exercise that Will Change Your Day</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-10-minute-exercise-that-will-change-your-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-10-minute-exercise-that-will-change-your-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3907&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/watch-e1421889550877.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;watch&#34; width=&#34;698&#34; height=&#34;210&#34; /&gt;Imagine what your life would be like and what you&#39;d accomplish if you started &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; day full of passion, purpose and drive. Not just a few days a month, or a few hours of each day, but every hour of every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re probably thinking that&#39;d be great, but it&#39;s not realistic. After all, moods and mindsets are fickle, and people are either born with drive or they&#39;re not, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found myself asking the same question recently, and I decided to see if I could find an answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all my research on high achieving individuals, from the ultra-wealthy to the ultra-accomplished, I noticed that the biggest difference was their mindset. They ask different kinds of questions and see the world in a different way than the majority of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For an example of this, check out &lt;a title=&#34;KhanAcademy Interviews Elon Musk&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vDwzmJpI4io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sal Khan&#39;s interview of Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It dawned on me that an essential technique for increasing people&#39;s capabilities was to find a way for them to consistently elevate their mindset. Each day spent in a state of openness to possibility compounds on the previous ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is, for most of us, our mindset is determined by our mood, which is often determined by the events of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed a way to make sure that every day started with an empowered mindset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2015 Strategy Part 2: The Logistics of Being Awesome</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-2-the-logistics-of-being-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-2-the-logistics-of-being-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3880&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/timeclock-e1420568994227.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;timeclock&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;245&#34; /&gt;Last week, I shared &lt;a title=&#34;My 2015 Strategy Part 1: Dreams and Aspirations&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/my-2015-strategy-part-1-dreams-and-aspirations/&#34;&gt;my overarching strategy for 2015&lt;/a&gt; and how I got there, with a simple, but very helpful exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, I was planning to talk about specific actions and the structures I&#39;m going to put into place to support my plans, but it became a longer article than I&#39;d expected. So, I&#39;m going to limit it to logistics now, and actions on Thursday, because dreams without action will stay that way, and action without logistics will fizzle out real fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Quick Definitions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize not everyone here is a military history buff (or UPS admirer), so you may not be entirely familiar with what logistics are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, logistics are the support systems that enable an army to do its job. This includes things like food, transportation systems, and even lifestyle. The best trained Navy SEAL is useless without the entire support system that puts him in the right place to start his mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your personal life, it is important to create a system to support you. This includes things like your habits, your environment, and your routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good logistics are just as essential as good strategy and good tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Logistics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with last week&#39;s post was that I didn&#39;t account for time, energy, or financial resources; I simply wrote down everything I want to do in the next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this week, I&#39;ll show you how to handle the rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wake Up: The Not-So-Secret Key to Happiness</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/wake-up-the-not-so-secret-key-to-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/wake-up-the-not-so-secret-key-to-happiness/</guid>
      <description>“People say that what we’re all seeking is a meaning for life. I don’t think that’s what we’re really seeking. I think that what we’re seeking is an experience of being alive, so that our life experiences on the purely physical plane will have resonances with our own innermost being and reality, so that we actually feel the rapture of being alive.”- Joseph Campbell
 We spend so much time worrying about the future or reliving the past that we rarely if ever experience the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock the Vast Knowledge in Your Ancient DNA</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/unlock-the-vast-knowledge-in-your-ancient-dna/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/unlock-the-vast-knowledge-in-your-ancient-dna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently discovered a secret store of untapped skill and agility that anyone can use. I was out running on a trail with no shoes on, struggling mightily not to stub my toes on all the rocks and stones. It was mentally exhausting. I&#39;d just finished a novel: &lt;em&gt;God Emperor of Dune.&lt;/em&gt; One of the main characters in this book has conscious access to all his ancestor&#39;s memories and experiences, encoded in his DNA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It occurred to me that &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; body also contains the DNA of all of my ancestors, millions of whom probably spent a lot of time running on rugged trails. In fact, encoded into my DNA and all that has arisen out of it are the instincts of tens of millions (maybe more) organisms, not all human, that spent their entire lives navigating wild, treacherous terrain. Along the way, there must have been some creation of an instinct that helped these creatures manage rocky trails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, no matter how my life had progressed, &lt;strong&gt;I could not deny that there was in fact some remnant of all that history within me, if only in the way my DNA was constructed&lt;/strong&gt;. The experience of my ancestors, all the way back to the first proto-life, had created the blueprint for my existence and the framework around which my brain and nervous system were built. It seemed reasonable to think that perhaps there were some useful instincts prebuilt into me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to try something. I stopped consciously thinking about where to put my feet. I let go of the need to control my body and leaned forward to pick up speed, forcing my reflexes to direct my actions in order to avoid injury. I trusted my feet and my body&#39;s intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money is a Gift; Lessons Learned in Business</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/money-is-a-gift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/money-is-a-gift/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1892&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;stevendepolo on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stevendepolo/3703145222/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1892&#34; title=&#34;gifts&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/gifts-300x200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently been burned in two business interactions that left me hurting both financially and personally. Not only did I lose money, I felt taken advantage of and cheapened. I invited my clients to undervalue my hard work by undervaluing it myself. It’s a hard pill to swallow, but I realize it’s all part of the learning process, and the more I delve into business, the more I realize how much &lt;a title=&#34;The Principles of ‘Good’ Business&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-principles-of-good-business/&#34;&gt;good business&lt;/a&gt; relies on good character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Linchpin; and, How to Create a Self-Study Course to Master Anything</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-linchpin-and-how-to-create-a-self-study-course-to-master-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-linchpin-and-how-to-create-a-self-study-course-to-master-anything/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&#34;attachment_1872&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Vola Vale on Flickr&#34;][/caption]
“The best contribution one can make to humanity is to improve oneself.” - Anon
 I’ve always felt that learning is one of the best ways to improve oneself (I guess you could get philosophical and point out that self-improvement is essentially learning in one form or another). Reading books is one of the best ways to learn, which is why I include a lot of book reviews here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret of Unleashing Creativity</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-secret-of-unleashing-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-secret-of-unleashing-creativity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1868&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;416style on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/sookie/149498941/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1868&#34; title=&#34;Blank Canvas&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/149498941_c1e8d9cd08-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Sometimes you&#39;ve got to let everything go - purge yourself. If you are unhappy with anything . . . whatever is bringing you down, get rid of it. Because you&#39;ll find that when you&#39;re free, your true creativity, your true self comes out.” - Tina Turner&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creativity! The word rings of freedom, personal fulfillment, making a difference. It is how we contribute to the world around us and &lt;em&gt;create&lt;/em&gt; new realities out of our ideas. Most of us were very creative when we were young. When I was younger, I was immensely creative. I would write short stories daily. I was constantly drawing things on my school papers, and I filled up several sketchbooks. I even wrote poetry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, I thought that my creativity was the result of a messy, hectic life, but my life got a lot messier in college, right about the time my creativity disappeared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did You Forget Why You Came This Way?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/did-you-forget-why-you-came-this-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/did-you-forget-why-you-came-this-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1862&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;David Spinks on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/davidspinks/4453498888/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1862&#34; title=&#34;Above the Clouds&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/4453498888_f576a9afd5-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyday, I wake up earlier than I want to, and work longer than I want do, at a job that wasn’t my idea, creating something that was never on my radar for things I want to accomplish in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, why do I do it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presumably to get paid so that I can live, but walking through the snow yesterday to the school where I work, I couldn’t help but wonder what the point of making enough money to live was. What would I do with the living that I earned? Just make more living, more money, so that I could go on buying food and renting a roof over my head?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I felt the need to rise above the clouds of my day-to-day for a little bit, to get a wider perspective on my life and why I do what I do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The One Thing You Can Do To Make Everything Better</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-one-thing-you-can-do-to-make-everything-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-one-thing-you-can-do-to-make-everything-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1850&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;tanakawho on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/28481088@N00/1069809120/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1850&#34; title=&#34;lotus&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/lotus-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He who has health, has hope. And he who has hope, has everything&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.thinkexist.com/quotation/he_who_has_health-has_hope-and_he_who_has_hope/149145.html&#34;&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;” - Proverb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Leave all the afternoon for exercise and recreation, which are as necessary as reading. I will rather say more necessary because health is worth more than learning.” - Thomas Jefferson&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the one thing you can do to improve almost every aspect of your life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be honest, I don’t know you, but the thing that makes the biggest difference in my day to day life is looking after my health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this means eating right, &lt;a title=&#34;Lessons Learned as a Trainer and Athlete&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/lessons-learned-as-a-trainer-and-athlete/&#34;&gt;exercising regularly and intensely&lt;/a&gt;, and getting enough sleep. It means I take my health into my own hands, instead of just accepting what the government or the media tells me. It’s your body; take the time to get to know it, what makes it happy, and what is good for it, instead of relying on people who have zero interest in your well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few of the really obvious effects looking after my health has had. Most of them have nothing to do with the body itself, but instead are reflections on the areas of life that we really live for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Education of Millionaires</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-the-education-of-millionaires/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-the-education-of-millionaires/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/The-Education-of-Millionaires.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1844&#34; title=&#34;The-Education-of-Millionaires&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/The-Education-of-Millionaires-198x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;198&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Every now and then, a book comes along that redefines the way you see the world. Michael Ellsberg&#39;s book is just such a one. It snares you with its controversial premise: &lt;strong&gt;higher education fails to provide the skills necessary to be successful in the real world&lt;/strong&gt;. It keeps you reading by explaining what skills you &lt;em&gt;do &lt;/em&gt;need and how to get them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone who has every wondered why, with their expensive degree and pristine grades, they are stuck working meaningless jobs that make no use of their skills, this book provides both the answer and the solution to bettering their chances to make it. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;The Education of Millionaires&#34; href=&#34;http://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/education-of-millionaires-michael-ellsberg/1103297348?ean=9781591844204&amp;amp;itm=1&amp;amp;usri=the+education+of+millionaires&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Education of Millionaires&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; basically presents a course list for success in business and entrepreneurship&lt;/strong&gt;. It is a strong advocate of &lt;a title=&#34;The Principles of &#39;Good&#39; Business&#34; href=&#34;http://wp.me/p15g8X-tF&#34;&gt;business with integrity&lt;/a&gt; and success as a means to make a positive difference in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principles of &#39;Good&#39; Business</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-principles-of-good-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-principles-of-good-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1840&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;digitalmoneyworld on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/digitalcurrency/2438117961/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1840&#34; title=&#34;gold&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/gold-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Success means having the courage, the determination, and the will to become the person you believe you were meant to be” -George Sheehan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently finished a series three books on how to change the world, how to give as much as possible to your community, and how to help others get the things they need. The first was a book on how to become wealthy, the second was a book about becoming indispensable to your company, and the third was simply a book about selling. Yes, these were business books, but not business books in the way I usually think about the genre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Holiday Thanks You&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-holiday-thanks-yous/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-holiday-thanks-yous/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1856&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;jenny downing on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jenny-pics/3108467816/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1856&#34; title=&#34;holidaytrees&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/holidaytrees-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love this time of year. The cozy winter drinks, the warm crackling fires after a day in the cold, people bundled up but still extending warm greetings and presents. While it&#39;d be great to be this thoughtful all year, it is still nice to step out of our self-centered mindset, even if just for a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The holidays are a time when people take a moment to remember the important people in their lives. My usual holiday tradition has been to write handwritten cards to all the people who have made a difference in my life in the past year. It&#39;s sort of a massive thank you note for the intangible things that my friends have done for me throughout the year, whether that was just to be there and listen, to hang out and have fun, or give me much-needed help or advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, however, I got so caught up in my move to South Korea that I didn&#39;t get around to making all the cards. So, if you don&#39;t get something from me, please know that doesn&#39;t mean I forgot, just that life has been very busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I wanted to take this opportunity to say thank you to my community. This past year, I&#39;ve learned that so much of what makes us who we are is who makes up our community. We are, to a very large extent, the result of our friends, families, followers, and teachers. &lt;strong&gt;I want to acknowledge just how much of who I am is the result of the generous contributions of others who have seen something in me worth supporting&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Going to Make It</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/were-going-to-make-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/were-going-to-make-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1836&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;mikbaird on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mikebaird/2087879492/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1836&#34; title=&#34;clearingthewave&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/clearingthewave-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a point in every challenging experience where you go from questioning whether you&#39;ve got what it takes to survive and to feeling secure that things will be alright. You&#39;ve been staring up at an impending wave, not sure you&#39;ll get to the other side, but now you&#39;re on top, and you can see the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me living in Korea, I passed that point a few days ago. Nothing really has changed around me, but something inside me clicked. Finding my balance point is less of a daily struggle, I&#39;m starting to groove my daily paths and activities and get a sense for my surroundings. A and I have slowly transformed our apartment into a living space that reflects the kind of lives we want to live, so we are no longer fitting ourselves into someone else&#39;s living space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like I can see further and, while I may not feel that I&#39;ve accomplished that state of security just yet, I know it is attainable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empty Your Cup: Accepting Ignorance to Learn</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/empty-your-cup-accepting-ignorance-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/empty-your-cup-accepting-ignorance-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1828&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Neal on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/31878512@N06/4748872561/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1828&#34; title=&#34;teacup&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/teacup-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A university professor went to visit a famous Zen master. While the master quietly served tea, the professor talked about Zen. The master poured the visitor&#39;s cup to the brim, and then kept pouring. The professor watched the overflowing cup until he could no longer restrain himself. &#34;It&#39;s overfull! No more will go in!&#34; the professor blurted. &#34;You are like this cup,&#34; the master replied, &#34;How can I show you Zen unless you first empty your cup.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently moved to South Korea to teach English to kids for a year. Adjusting to the new culture has been both humorous and challenging; things that I usually consider very simple have become extremely difficult. Basics of living—eating healthy, exercising regularly, and even basic hygiene—have new rules and best practices that I just don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve had to accept that I really don’t know how to do much around here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Call to Write</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-call-to-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-call-to-write/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1822&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;229&#34; caption=&#34;aussiegall in Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/aussiegall/5630368331/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1822&#34; title=&#34;bloom&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/bloom-229x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;229&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As long as we are persistence in our pursuit of our deepest destiny, we will continue to grow. We cannot choose the day or time when we will fully bloom. It happens in its own time.” --Denis Waitley&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I haven’t posted to Warrior Spirit in a very long time. My concern was that the topic of the blog was becoming too vague and nebulous. I aspire to write stories for adventure magazines and grand science-fiction epics, neither of which were things this blog showcased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides that, I haven’t found Warrior Spirit to be especially rewarding. There is very little community interaction on the blog. Articles don’t get shared often, nobody links to the blog, and I don’t get many comments. Sometimes I felt like I was writing in a vacuum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to put it to rest and focus on other, more concrete projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then, I received a direct request to continue Warrior Spirit&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving Up On My Dream of Being a Soldier</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/giving-up-on-my-dream-of-being-a-soldier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/giving-up-on-my-dream-of-being-a-soldier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1760&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;The U.S. Army on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/soldiersmediacenter/478415299/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1760&#34; title=&#34;soldier&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/soldier-300x186.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;186&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always had an interest in joining the military. I wanted to be a jet fighter pilot, or a special forces operative. For the first time in my life, I have no reason to be afraid of the physical demands of the job; I routinely best soldiers in fitness competitions, and I could pass the special forces entrance exams. I’m confident enough in myself to withstand the rigors of training, and I feel more certain than ever that I could benefit from the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I have had to let go of that dream as I’ve come to understand the realities of what a soldier does. In order to live out my dream, I would have to compromise on a lot of things that are really important to me. This isn’t because of the nature of the military generally, but rather the way the system is set up currently. I could get behind fighting against Hitler in World War II, but I have never been very good at investing myself in other peoples’ agendas if I don’t believe in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Personal Epic</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-personal-epic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-personal-epic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- p.p1 {margin: 8.0px 0.0px 0.0px 0.0px; text-indent: 18.0px; font: 13.0px Optima} p.p3 {margin: 8.0px 0.0px 0.0px 0.0px; text-indent: 18.0px; font: 13.0px Optima; min-height: 15.0px} li.li2 {margin: 8.0px 0.0px 0.0px 0.0px; font: 13.0px Optima} ul.ul1 {list-style-type: disc} --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1537&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;Sammydavisdog on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/25559122@N06/2414295906/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1537&#34; title=&#34;perseus&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/perseus-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, I&#39;m Khaled. This is my blog, Warrior Spirit. It&#39;s kind of my personal epic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem a little presumptuous to suggest that my life is worthy of an epic, and maybe it’s not yet. However, I believe that if I treat it as epic-worthy, it will live up to that calling. The whole point is simply to live as awesome a life as possible and hope that it proves worthy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Warrior Spirit</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-warrior-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-warrior-spirit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Hello World&#34;]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/20110331-213409.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/20110331-213409.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20110331-213409.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d like to inject a little more of me into my posts. After all, this blog was started by me as a sort of online journal. I was reluctant to assume that all my readers found my life all that interesting, but I thought I&#39;d just write about it. I am a storyteller, after all, not just an essayist. Since the story I know best is my own, I wanted to tell that story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the way, I got swept up by all these other great blogs that also tell stories, but which also provide lots of useful information besides. Somehow, the information stuck out more than the stories, and I focused on that. As a result, I feel that Warrior Spirit has kind of drifted from being personal to trying too hard to be useful. The result I think has been less connection with my readers. The blog has grown and grown, and for that I&#39;m thankful, but I feel a little like I&#39;ve sold out (except without the monetary rewards).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&#39;m going to try to tell more of my stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Story</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/KhaledPortrait.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1068&#34; title=&#34;KhaledPortrait&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/KhaledPortrait-300x224.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;224&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“Today you are You, that is truer than true. There is no one alive who is Youer than You.” - Dr. Seuss&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the responses I got from all of you on that &lt;a href=&#34;http://polldaddy.com/s/444345CCC43313A2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;survey &lt;/a&gt;I sent out, most of the interest in what I write comes from knowing me. So I thought I&#39;d write out my story, so those of you who didn&#39;t know me before the blog can understand where I&#39;m coming from, where I get my stories and interpretations, and why I care so much about standing up to mediocrity and forging my own destiny.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
