<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to my website on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome to my website on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 17:06:06 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What I learned from my aviation accident</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/lessons-aviation-accident/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 17:06:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/lessons-aviation-accident/</guid>
      <description>Last month, I completed my commercial pilot checkride and earned my certificate. Along the way, I matured as a pilot in ways that I did not expect. I thought that I would simply learn a few new maneuvers and become more precise, but what I actually learned was an entirely new way to think about flying, thanks to an accident that occurred.
During a training flight, an instructor and I inadvertently starved the plane&amp;rsquo;s engine of fuel, resulting in an engine-out landing in a corn field that totaled the aircraft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gated Mastery-Based Learning</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/gated-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 21:43:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/gated-learning/</guid>
      <description>Hollow Knight is one of my favorite games, even though it is also one of the most difficult I&amp;rsquo;ve ever played. But it is so well-designed that the difficulty doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel unfair. Your pause screen clearly indicates empty spaces for powers and upgrades you have yet to find.
The most difficult areas and bosses are closed to you until you have the abilities you need to beat them. In some cases, you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to try a harder section or boss before you have all the power-ups, but there are no penalties for failing in these cases (not even losing a life).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathdocs</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/project/mathdocs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 15:42:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/project/mathdocs/</guid>
      <description>Github
Goals The goal of this project was:
To build a tool for myself to support my educational objectives that I could use regularly To test out an idea I had about mathematics knowledge being structured like code, with inheritance and relationships, rather than a linear process of building towards a big proof or result To gain familiarity with Django (this was my first time working with Django) To expose myself to a CSS framework other than Bootstrap Overview This project is a Django app that allows me to document mathematics knowledge in a way similar to how I document code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunrise Lamp</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/project/sunrise-lamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 21:44:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/project/sunrise-lamp/</guid>
      <description>Project Notebook Github, includes STL
Final Demo Goal The goal of this project was to build a sunrise simulation lamp using an Arduino and a Neopixel ring. This is essentially a proof of concept, since I would probably want to use a much bigger Neopixel ring for a real lamp. This one also has a real-time clock board (RTC) that enables the device to keep time even when the Arduino is not drawing power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Parsec Gaming Client</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/project/raspberry-pi-parsec/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 12:08:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/project/raspberry-pi-parsec/</guid>
      <description>This is a project to use a Raspberry Pi to stream games from my CLX gaming PC to various locations in the house using Parsec.
Software Getting the Raspberry Pi to act as a streaming solution wasn&amp;rsquo;t as simple as the instructions from Parsec indicated. The biggest issues we faced (I did this with my friend Sam Cipriani) were latency from attempting to stream a graphics intensive application into the Pi, and then output that onto a big, high resolution TV screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback and Difficulty in Video Games</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/persistence-in-video-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 10:46:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/persistence-in-video-games/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished playing through Halo 2&amp;rsquo;s legendary co-op campaign, which, for those who are not masochistic gamers, is considered one of the most poorly balanced, excessively difficult games ever made. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t played, imagine being a delicate butterfly, made of crystal, trying to survive in a rock tumbler. With another butterfly. Who is tied to your wings, so when one of you dies, you both do. And the rocks are actually trying to hit you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drink Table</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/project/drink-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 11:55:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/project/drink-table/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Solving Process</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/problem-solving-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 10:36:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/problem-solving-process/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been preparing for a coding interview recently, and as a result I have given a lot of thought to how I tend to solve problems.
When I started back in to school, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a great problem-solving process. I had always been &amp;ldquo;the smart kid&amp;rdquo; and didn&amp;rsquo;t need to do anything special that I was aware of in order to solve most of the problems I encountered. The only exception to that was some of the very difficult games I like to play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/daybook/kubernetes-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 17:33:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/daybook/kubernetes-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Using this tutorial to learn Kubernetes concepts: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X48VuDVv0do. minikube needs to run in a virtual environment, so we need to specify the vm-driver, hypberkit in our case.
minikube start --vm-driver=hyperkit
Once minikube is set up, it spins up a VM and then you can use kubectl to query it. Minikube is a node, running virtually in your own computer.
Basic Commands Usage creat a pod: kubectl create .... We don&amp;rsquo;t notmally work with pods directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Avoided Becoming the Flavor-of-the-Month Intern</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/how-i-avoided-becoming-the-flavor-of-the-month-intern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/how-i-avoided-becoming-the-flavor-of-the-month-intern/</guid>
      <description>Last year, I had the amazing opportunity to intern at a NASA center. They were looking for someone with JavaScript experience to update a data collections tool that had been underutilized because it was not searchable and had a poor UI. The plan was to rebuild it with a shiny new graph-based database and to update the frontend to use React. Basically, modernize it and clean it up.
All this was what my supervisors and their bosses wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cats Are Evil</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/cats-are-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/cats-are-evil/</guid>
      <description>We have a new cat whose name is probably the most on-the-nose name a cat can have: Misjif. He&amp;rsquo;s so mischievious he even spelled mischief wrong.
Take all the things that make cats cat-like&amp;ndash;climbs everything, yowls in the middle of the night, clever in all the wrong ways, velociraptor-like learning curve and love of mayhem&amp;ndash;and turn them up to CAT. That is Misjif. Also cute. He&amp;rsquo;s stinkin&amp;rsquo; adorable, which makes all of this worse: you can&amp;rsquo;t stay mad at him (though trust me I&amp;rsquo;m working really hard on that).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortcuts In Moderation</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/shortcuts-in-moderation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/shortcuts-in-moderation/</guid>
      <description>When I started learning to bake bread, I used active dry yeast. It was easy and with the right recipe, I could get reasonably good results without all the complications of a sourdough starter. But I always aspired to make bread with the starter, and for a while, I believed that using a starter was the only real way to make bread. I also thought that once I moved to using a starter, I would never make bread the &amp;ldquo;easy way&amp;rdquo; again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Silence</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/on-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/on-silence/</guid>
      <description>In 2013, I decided to stop writing regularly in my blog, which I had been posting to daily since 2009 when I graduated college. I had what should have felt like success with a reasonable audience, an ebook and launch, collaborations, guest posts, even some money from my writing.
Then, in 2013 I stopped abruptly. I suddenly found the act of expressing my opinions offensive and exhausting, just a lot of ego-stroking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Reading List Problem-solving Process Spend some time with the problem &amp;ldquo;What would make this easy?&amp;rdquo; Make it like something familiar Make it concrete Test Look for shortcuts and refine What worked? Why? Can it be combined with something else or consolidated? What didn&amp;rsquo;t work? Why? Do I need that? Can we bypass the problem entirely? What should be changed to improve? Is that feasible? Repeat with a smaller version of the big cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/code-portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/code-portfolio/</guid>
      <description>Personal Projects IoT: Sunrise simulation lamp with Arduino, Neopixel, and 3D printed enclosure. Project Page, Github. Gaming: Stream and play games from powerful gaming PC to customized Raspberry Pi with custom 3D printed case. Project page. Software: Custom-built documentation/wiki for Abstract Algebra. Github. Software: Voice-controlled NLP personal assistant with custom-built command-line todo list. Github. Software: Online LaTeX scratchpad used by CU and FRCC students for quick math typesetting App, Github. Undergraduate Research Projects Software: EVA suit simulated telemetry-feed for NASA SUITS competition team.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
