<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>webcomics on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/webcomics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in webcomics on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/webcomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pigeonholing Myself</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/pigeonholing-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/pigeonholing-myself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/pigeon.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-507&#34; title=&#34;pigeon&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/pigeon.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In high school, we have so many dreams and activities. In order to be competitive for college, we fill our transcripts with a crazy variety of activities: math club, Boy Scouts, flying lessons, karate, cross country, guitar, piano lessons. This is in addition to our classes, which tend to cover a wide range of subjects: precalc, biology, English, painting. Then in college, we start off with a fairly broad range of topics to study, and as we move towards our major, the subjects narrow down to one or two: psychology and international studies of the Middle East. Then, after college, we get a job and are expected to become experts in one single field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to consider myself a renaissance man, with interests in a wide range of activities, but I&#39;m not so sure anymore. After all, I spend so much of my time studying fitness and in training. My conversations with people tend to gravitate towards talk about health, fitness, and nutrition. Last night while bartending,  a guy at the bar wanted to watch the NFL draft, and I had no clue how to have a conversation with him. I never really followed or understood football, but it made be wonder if I&#39;m either out of touch with society or simply too narrow in my interests.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
