<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>discipline on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/discipline/</link>
    <description>Recent content in discipline on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/discipline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Integrity: The Complete Human</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-meaning-of-integrity-the-complete-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-meaning-of-integrity-the-complete-human/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_767&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;Source: poeticaldistractions on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/visualpoeticaldistractions/3481595328/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-767&#34; title=&#34;david&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/david-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“The truth of the matter is that you always know the right thing to do. The hard part is doing it.” - General Norman Schwarzkopf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is largely about the development of character. The most important quality of character is integrity, because without it, character has no meaning. So what is integrity, anyway? The word is vaguely defined in most discussions, and looking back over my posts, I realize I have never actually clarified what it is I am talking about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returning to the Dojo: The Importance of Martial Arts</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_713&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; caption=&#34;Source: Pieter Baert on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pietel/15322162/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-713&#34; title=&#34;karate&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/karate2.jpg?w=201&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was a child I have had this instinctive urge for expansion and growth. To me, the function and duty of a quality human being is the sincere and honest development of one&#39;s potential. - Bruce Lee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I attended my first class of American Kenpo Karate in over five years. My old teacher told me in an e-mail to bring my old Gi, which I had kept, anticipating an eventual return to the art. When I went to dig it out from a trunk under my bed, I found my old belts, one soft, well-worn, and white, and the other stiff and bright, un-faded yellow. I grabbed the white belt and headed to class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I stepped into the dance studio where the class was being held, my old instructor, taller and leaner than I remembered, looked at me without recognition. It &lt;em&gt;had &lt;/em&gt;been a long time. He was shocked at the growth he saw in me and had trouble connecting the old Khaled with the one who stood before him. And then he looked down and saw I was wearing my old white belt and asked, &#34;Where&#39;s your belt?&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom Through Discipline</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/freedom-through-discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/freedom-through-discipline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_695&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;Source: Laniee75 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/laniee75/4213598676/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-695&#34; title=&#34;OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/discipline.jpg?w=225&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Seek freedom and become captive of your desires. Seek discipline and find your liberty.” - Frank Herbert&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to follow a very strict diet, and was religious about exercising. Rain or shine, groggy or energetic, sugar cravings or not, I followed my program. Ultimately, it turned out my particular program was a little intense and led to some problems, and so I have lately abandoned it for a more intuitive approach, meaning I do things when I feel like it, meaning I often don&#39;t do what I&#39;m supposed to do. At first, this felt liberating, but I&#39;ve begun to realize that I have given up something very important by letting go of my confining routines: my freedom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Things Can Happen to Good People</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/bad-things-can-happen-to-good-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/bad-things-can-happen-to-good-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/accident.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-459&#34; title=&#34;accident&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/accident.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A lot of people who restrict their diet for the sake of health have little to console themselves with when they must forgo all the little pleasures in life. All they can do is remind themselves that they will be spared the debilitating chronic diseases that will likely afflict their less-disciplined friends. Unfortunetly (or not) it isn&#39;t that simple. Sometimes, those of us with the healthiest of habits end up the victim while our chain smoking, sugar-munching friends live their whole lives without the smallest issues.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
