<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fitness on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/fitness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fitness on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/fitness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Foundation of Empowered Living</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-foundation-of-empowered-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-foundation-of-empowered-living/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first task of the aspiring hero is to train her body. Only when she has learned how to master the external world can she begin the far more difficult task of mastering the internal world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;The Entrepreneurial Benefits of Healthy Living&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-entrepreneurial-benefits-of-healthy-living/&#34;&gt;I&#39;ve talked before about how success-oriented types tend to discount the importance of health&lt;/a&gt;. We tell ourselves that we need to put in as much work as we can, now, when we&#39;re young and resilient. Once we&#39;ve earned our leisure time, we will make up for all the lost sleep, convenient food, drinking, and hours spent hunched in front of a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We tend to ignore just how much this neglect is impacting our ability to do quality work right now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to talk about the importance of fitness in particular, and why a &lt;strong&gt;physical practice&lt;/strong&gt; is so essential to mastering yourself and unleashing your true potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training my body, becoming stronger and more coordinated, has had a huge impact on my sense of &lt;a title=&#34;How Moving Well Can Make You Confident and Popular&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/two-reasons-play-is-a-big-deal/&#34;&gt;self-confidence&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title=&#34;Practicing Courage Through Movement&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/practicing-courage-throught-movement/&#34;&gt;courage&lt;/a&gt;, and I believe it is an essential thing for any aspiring Warrior to find peace with his or her body. Your body is not just who you are, but it is also your mode of expression in the world. Learn to cultivate it, to appreciate it, and to &lt;a title=&#34;Listen to Your Intuition: It Could Save Your Life&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/listen-to-your-intuition-it-could-save-your-life/&#34;&gt;trust it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Training Ground for the Spirit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many epics, myths, and legends, young heroes spend their early training in physical preparation. This isn&#39;t because the physical is more important than the mental and the spiritual, but because it is the most basic realm we must master.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can a hero expect to overcome the more challenges of ideas, thoughts, principles, motivation, and loyalty if they cannot manage their own bodies and move through the world? &lt;strong&gt;Physical competence is a foundational prerequisite for mental and spiritual competencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Reasons You Shouldn&#39;t Make Your Own Decisions</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/3-reasons-you-shouldnt-make-your-own-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/3-reasons-you-shouldnt-make-your-own-decisions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/deciding.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3183&#34; alt=&#34;deciding&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/deciding-300x225.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I was recently looking for a good meal replacement option to make sure I get enough calories and protein on days when I don&#39;t have the time to prepare a good meal. While this may seem like a non-issue, I&#39;ve made a commitment to only eating whole foods, so it&#39;s a bit trickier than it seems. I know how to make this decision, because I&#39;ve done it before and I&#39;m certainly qualified, as a person who knows what&#39;s best for himself and as a trainer with a lot of experience dealing with nutrition. Yet, despite all that, my first inclination was to ask around with my trainer buddies, to check Paleo/Primal blogs, and to put the question to Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Even with the knowledge that I would make the best decision for myself without any input, I still wanted someone else to make the decision for me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I&#39;m the kind of person that &lt;a title=&#34;Insecurity, the Root of All Evil&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/insecurity-the-root-of-all-evil/&#34;&gt;questions my thinking&lt;/a&gt; process (in case you haven&#39;t picked up on that by now), I wanted to figure out why I felt the need to ask around. After all, I have rarely asked for input on what I should be doing for my own training. Ask 50 trainers what you should be doing and you&#39;ll get 50 different answers; it&#39;s really something you need to decide for yourself. Once you&#39;ve done that, then find a trainer who can help you reach that goal. I find it&#39;s better to make my own decisions and my own mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not saying outside input isn&#39;t valuable. When you want to learn something, definitely seek out qualified teachers. I saw that Gold Medal Bodies was teaching a lot of people to do previously unattainable gymnastics skills, so I got &lt;a title=&#34;Review of Gold Medal Bodies Floor 1 Training Program&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/review-of-gold-medal-bodies-floor-1-training-program/&#34;&gt;one of their programs&lt;/a&gt;. But when you&#39;re making a decision, you already have all the information you need, and you know yourself well enough to know what&#39;s good for you, then asking for additional input is just pushing it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, why was I hesitating and looking for outside opinions? I came up with a few answers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Gold Medal Bodies Floor 1 Training Program</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/review-of-gold-medal-bodies-floor-1-training-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/review-of-gold-medal-bodies-floor-1-training-program/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/Floor-One_small.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-2422&#34; title=&#34;Floor-One_small&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/Floor-One_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;351&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I have always been inspired by gymnasts, who seem to defy gravity. When I started strengthening my own body, the first methods I used were based on gymnastics bodyweight movements: handstand pushups, pistol squats, jumps, dives, rolls, and pullups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it was always difficult to program a good bodyweight routine, and I spent years making progress then stalling, revising my approach, moving forward, stalling, etc. Most resources assume that if you&#39;re going to use the same movements as gymnasts, you must train as intensely as gymnasts, regardless of your goals. The programs were either too demanding, required too much time, or were absurdly complicated. It was a frustrating process, and the simplicity of barbell training was very tempting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I found &lt;a title=&#34;Gold Medal Bodies&#34; href=&#34;http://www.goldmedalbodies.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gold Medal Bodies&lt;/a&gt;, I got really excited. They specifically addressed the fact that, while gymnasts take these training methods to extremes for their sport, the movements and programs themselves don&#39;t need to be so difficult for the average person. In fact, Gold Medal Bodies (GMB) emphasized that they don&#39;t provide gymnastic training but rather draw from gymnastics (as well as yoga and martial arts).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their attitude towards training also mirrored my own: useful, holistic, comprehensive, not self-destructive, and fun. They really stress &lt;a title=&#34;Integrity of Movement, and My First RKC Class&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/integrity-of-movement-and-my-first-rkc-class/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;integrity of movement &lt;/a&gt;and body control, and consolidating strength exercises into applicable skills. Generally, I think they are one of the best things to happen to training. I downloaded their free handstand tutorial and in 1 week found myself finally getting a solid handstand, after 3 years of shaky results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was determined to try out GMB&#39;s main training programs, and after mentioning it in my book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Warrior Spirit Principles of Holistic Health&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/store/warrior-spirit-principles-of-holistic-health/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Warrior Spirit Principles of Holistic Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, they offered me my choice of program, so here is the review after my first two weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitness is Not Health</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/fitness-is-not-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/fitness-is-not-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2008&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/tomsaint/3752937440/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-2008 &#34; title=&#34;Tired Runners&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3752937440_4641fa806d.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Rennett Stowe on Flickr[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In writing my fitness book and thinking about how I want to explain my views to others, I&#39;ve realized that I was never really comfortable with fitness as we normally conceive it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitness is a confusing term these days. It has become so confusing, in fact, that you can have Fitness without Health. You can be very good at the Fitness thing, exercising religiously, following the right diet, wearing the right $70 Yoga pants, and be completely miserable. Originally meant to be a means to promote our holistic health, Fitness has taken on a life of its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To define Fitness, I want put aside dictionary definitions and focus on what most people mean when they talk about Fitness. I&#39;m concerned with ideas and conceptions, not academic or scientific definitions that have little to do with how people interact with the term in their real lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most, fitness is synonymous with athletic performance: the better your fitness, the better athlete you are. It is also synonymous with health: the better your fitness, the healthier you are. So, the assumption is that athletes are healthy, meaning their bodies express the full range of human function, painlessly, and for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Unhealthy Athlete&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we know that not all great athletes are healthy. The standards of a sport do not always require holistic human health to perform well (think golf), and sometimes the requirements of excellence in a sport actually favor adaptations that cause health problems. When an elite runner dies of heart failure, what do we make of it? How do we reconcile the awe-inspiring performance of gymnasts with the spine and shoulder problems that come with the intensive practice?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Understanding of Fitness and the Human Body</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-new-understanding-of-fitness-and-the-human-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-new-understanding-of-fitness-and-the-human-body/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/245952551_797503484e.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright  wp-image-1995&#34; title=&#34;Bodies in Motion&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/245952551_797503484e.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;360&#34; height=&#34;270&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Many people treat their bodies as if they were rented from Hertz--something they are using to get around in but nothing they genuinely care about understanding. - Chungliang Al Huang&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until recently, it was thought that a human being could be perfectly healthy eating only parts of food, as long as they were in sufficient quantities and ratios. The nutrient model of diet claimed that we simply needed sufficient protein, carbohydrates, and fats, plus vitamins, in order to be healthy. Foods were broken down, proteins, vitamins, and minerals extracted, removed, concentrated, and added back in sufficient quantities. We had mastered the science of nutrition and were entering a golden age of health and convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much for that...the nutrient model has been discredited lately, as it became more and more obvious that the benefits of whole foods, eaten fresh and close to the source, simply could not be copied by even the most carefully scientifically balanced meals. Sometimes this was because of the limits of our technology, but just as often, there were factors we hadn&#39;t even identified that seemed to make the difference between health-promoting and obesity-inducing food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitness and exercise is where nutrition was a few years ago. We are only now starting to pull out of the mistaken belief that movement-related health can be broken down into its constituent parts and fed in concentrations to promote certain kinds of growth. Happily, we have mostly discarded the notion that the body can respond to training muscles in isolation on weight machines. Unfortunately, we still pull movement apart into elements like strength, speed, power, agility, coordination, balance, and flexibility, just as we used to think of food only in terms of its proteins, carbohydrates, fats, vitamins, and minerals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move and Be Free</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/move-and-be-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/move-and-be-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1974&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/amagill/4614314729/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-1974 &#34; title=&#34;movement&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/movement.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; AMagill on Flickr[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&#39;t freedom to move the most fundamental freedom there is? - Erwan Le Corre, founder MovNat&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine that walking tires you out quickly. You cannot walk more than five minutes before desperately needing a rest. Add to that the fact that you are too weak to carry a day&#39;s worth of food more than five minutes. Let&#39;s say you&#39;re also too inflexible to sit comfortably on the ground for very long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now try to imagine all the places you cannot go: anywhere without cars, regular and cheap food, or chairs. You are strongly dependent on the presence and goodwill of other people for things as simple as your comfort. Because of your inability to move your body and endure hardship, you have fewer options for where you can go and the things you can do. You literally could not go more than five minutes without needing someone or something to help you. If you get stuck or behind schedule, you&#39;re screwed because you cannot run to catch a bus, much less a few miles to the nearest gas station if your car breaks down out of cell phone range on an urgent errand. You are dependent, in a very visceral sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Gentle, Be Powerful</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/be-gentle-be-powerful/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/be-gentle-be-powerful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1884&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Espara on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/esparta/2214658212/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1884&#34; title=&#34;Sleeping Tiger&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/2214658212_9d9183226f-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I have never taken any exercise except sleeping and resting.” - Mark Twain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intensity in exercise is good. Most of us aren’t getting enough of it. Instead we settle for lifting weights we can handle comfortably and running at speeds that just break a sweat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then there are those of us who do nothing but high intensity exercise. We’re CrossFitters and Traceurs, MMA fighters and sprinters. We only have one speed, and that’s insane! We are not know for our gentleness, with others or ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to be one of those. Until I got injured, which happened a lot actually. When you’re body is constantly working near its limits, there is not much time for healing or recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My most recent injury was a pulled muscle in my hip that immobilized my lower back. I couldn’t even bend over to tie my shoes. I had zero flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of options and fed up with being in pain all the time, I started practicing yoga to regain my flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started it only as a therapeutic form of exercise, but I noticed that I felt much better on days I started with some yoga than those without. Clearly yoga was addressing some aspect of my physical training I’d been neglecting with all the CrossFit and gymnastics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intense stretching didn&#39;t help at all. The painful deep tissue massage didn&#39;t help, either. But slow, comfortable, gentle yoga slowly untied my back and improved my flexibility in other areas as well. When I finally started being gentle and kind to my body, it stopped punishing me with pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intensity vs. Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/intensity-vs-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/intensity-vs-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1640&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Daisyree Bakker on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/27875041@N02/4425848358/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1640&#34; title=&#34;bear&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/bear-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d rather train to outrun a bear than to fight one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am more likely to actually attain my goal of outrunning a  bear, and will be able to apply that skill in a variety of  environments. If there are trees, I can climb them. If there is water, I  can swim. Climbing cliffs and rocks is another option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If, however, I simply train to be massively strong in  hopes of eventually overpowering the bear, I am starting at a distinct  disadvantage. Additionally, if I do face the bear in a fight, even if I  win (which is extremely unlikely), I am much more likely to get injured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Born to Run</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-born-to-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-born-to-run/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0307279189/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=warrspir-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399349&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0307279189&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;Format=_SL160_&amp;amp;ASIN=0307279189&amp;amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;amp;WS=1&amp;amp;tag=warrspir-20&amp;amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/ir?t=&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=0307279189&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399349&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to run barefoot for a long time, since the Vibram FiveFingers came out several years ago. Unfortunately, I’ve also been injuring myself since that time. Undaunted, I’ve kept trying new methods to learn, different ways to ease into it, and different cross-training and recovery techniques. In the end, it was a kind shoestore clerk and an epic story that made the difference. The clerk at the shoe store gave me a barefoot running instructional book (free just for showing interest in a pair of shoes he ordered that I didn’t even have to purchase). The epic story was &lt;em&gt;Born to Run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Need for Inspiration in Fitness</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-need-for-inspiration-in-fitness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-need-for-inspiration-in-fitness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1578&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Zach Dischner on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/zachd1_618/4760723894/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1578&#34; title=&#34;mountainclimbing&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/mountainclimbing-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was going on a rant about all the problems with the fitness industry the other day, as I often do, and one of the few things I said of value was that fitness isn’t about the body, at least not ultimately. It is about the spirit. We mainly want to have healthy bodies so that we can enjoy life, feel confident and strong, experience lots of cool adventures, and play with our grandkids. Most people don’t want to lose weight just for the sake of losing weight, but because they believe it will make them happier. After all, isn’t that why we do everything – in order to be happy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned as a Trainer and Athlete</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/lessons-learned-as-a-trainer-and-athlete/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/lessons-learned-as-a-trainer-and-athlete/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;cliff1066 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/20110403-133920.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/20110403-133920.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20110403-133920.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been a personal trainer now for about two years, and I&#39;ve been actively training myself for about three. It has been quite a journey, and I&#39;ve come a long way. When I started, I could only dream of doing a pull up. Now it is my strongest movement. Handstands were so far beyond my abilities as to be pure fantasy, and now I spend a lot of time inverted. I&#39;ve travelled a long road in a short amount of time, and I&#39;ve learned a few lessons along the way that I thought I would share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Enemy of the Good</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-enemy-of-the-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-enemy-of-the-good/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;﻿&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;350&#34; caption=&#34;linh.ngân on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3515/3295481102_6b38448f44.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; &#34; title=&#34;Imperfect Flower&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3295481102_6b38448f44.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;350&#34; height=&#34;350&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my chosen fitness niche, there is a tendency to only focus on what gets results and ignore the rest. CrossFitters tend to scoff at bodybuilders and pro football players alike. The belief is that these individuals are wasting their time as far as fitness is concerned because they are too specialized and not lined up for optimal health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, strict adherents of the Paleo diet tend to dismiss those who only follow it partially. Anyone who knows anything about nutrition wouldn’t go near a loaf of bread, ever! If you do, you don’t take your health seriously. You should either change your ways or give up completely. So say the perfectly fit. Go the whole 9 yards, or not at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Best Use Your Teacher</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-best-use-your-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-best-use-your-teacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1400&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;286&#34; caption=&#34;velvettangerine on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/velvettangerine/3922005142/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1400&#34; title=&#34;teacher&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/teacher-286x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;286&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re trying to learn something or achieve a skill, a teacher can be a big help, since they have already done what you want to do. But there are some pitfalls to having a teacher, especially if you try to put all the responsibility for your progress on their shoulders. The best way to use a teacher is as a resource for your own learning, not as the basis or sole motivation for your goals.&lt;em&gt; (if you&#39;re short on time, you can skip to the end of the article for a summary, a policy I&#39;ll be using more regularly)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a trainer, I work with a lot of people who want to get in great shape, but don&#39;t really want to put in the effort. Sure, they do the exercises I recommend when they show up, and they push themselves pretty hard. But then I won&#39;t see them for weeks. They have lessons maybe once a month, very intermittently, and as a result, they don&#39;t move towards their goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have trainees who see me about that often, but who do make progress. The difference is in the way they view our relationship. To the first group, I am responsible for their fitness progress. &lt;strong&gt;To the second group, I am merely a resource for them as they make their own journey towards fitness&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Odd Duck: My Stranger Health Habits</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/an-odd-duck-my-stranger-health-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/an-odd-duck-my-stranger-health-habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1288&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Bobby MacInnes on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/lonetown/1087101701/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1288&#34; title=&#34;odd duck&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/odd-duck-300x200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the name of health, I engage in some practices that others find pretty weird. I actually don&#39;t find them that odd, and they aren&#39;t really inconvenient to me. I actually really enjoy them. But since they aren&#39;t mainstream, they garner some odd looks. I thought I&#39;d list some of them for your entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Health Revolution</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-health-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-health-revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1285&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;eva101 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/evapro/425230963/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1285&#34; title=&#34;protest&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/protest-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A little rebellion now and then... is a medicine necessary for the sound health of government.”- Thomas Jefferson&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently stumbled upon an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/dr-mark-hyman/healthy-living-join-the-health-_b_799191.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;article &lt;/a&gt;claiming that being healthy is a revolutionary act, a difficult process that necessitates you make choices that put you in opposition to the mainstream and the social norm. To be healthy requires you be willing to ostracise yourself in the name of your own well-being because the sad truth is that our society has made poor health the trend and the norm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Instant Under the Bar</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/an-instant-under-the-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/an-instant-under-the-bar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1274&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Marc-Andre Casavant on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/casavant/4415188448/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1274&#34; title=&#34;olylift&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/olylift-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, over the course of something like two hours and 15-20 failed attempts, I managed to snatch 165 lbs, which is significant because that is my bodyweight (a snatch is an Olympic weightlifting movement in which you take a bar from the ground to overhead in one motion). I had set a bodyweight snatch as a goal almost a year ago, and had gotten to 160 lbs long before, but that elusive 5 lbs seemed impossible. Yesterday, I decided I would nail it, and in the end, it was mostly this determination that made the difference, rather than any actual performance improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-book Review: A Simple Guide to Eating Well</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/e-book-review-a-simple-guide-to-eating-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/e-book-review-a-simple-guide-to-eating-well/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/simpleguide.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1209&#34; title=&#34;simpleguide&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/simpleguide-237x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;237&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This is a review of an e-book by a fellow blogger that I&#39;ve followed for years. His blog, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zentofitness.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Zen to Fitness&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;em&gt; is inspired by the idea that health and vitality should not be a struggle. I am not an affiliate marketer for his book; this review is simply me sharing insights on an interesting book I read by a blogger who has inspired my own fitness pursuits.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having spent a great deal of time learning about and exploring many different kinds of diets, I’ve come across a lot of overly complicated explanations of how to eat healthy. Everyone seems to think their way is best, but I’ve found that the basic principles of diets that actually work are always the same: eat meals balanced in proteins, carbohydrates, and fats, made from fresh, high quality ingredients. Avoid too much sugar, and enjoy your food, eating when you’re hungry until you’re full. Whether it’s Paleo, Primal, Zone, Locavore, Vegtarian, Vegan, or Traditional, these principles always seem to hold. Of course, exponents of each diet focus on what makes them different, and this just leads to confusion. Vegans will tell you that eating meat leads to bodily decay, while the Paleo crowd will tell you that not eating meat leads to decrepitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Process of Living</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-process-of-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-process-of-living/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_974&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;Source: mdezemery on flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mdezemery/311283302/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-974&#34; title=&#34;walking&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/walking-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;The journey is what brings us happiness not the destination.&#34; -&lt;em&gt;Dan Millman, The Peaceful Warrior&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the overriding themes that I refer to a lot is the idea that many important endeavors are ongoing. There is no end goal in mind, and having an end goal can often derail our efforts to improve. Instead, simply going through your routine, growing slowly and naturally, will get you where you want to go with less frustration and less pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are What Your Ancestors Ate</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/you-are-what-your-ancestors-ate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/you-are-what-your-ancestors-ate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_962&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: alexdecarvalho on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/adc/2344498516/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-962&#34; title=&#34;caveman&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/caveman-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meat and veggies, nuts and seeds, some fruit, little starch, and no sugar -&lt;em&gt;The Paleo Diet in a nutshell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of my friends know I &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/my-paleo-journey/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;follow an approximately Paleo diet&lt;/a&gt;, and a lot of people argue with me as to why it is silly to eat like Paleolithic humans. I thought I would take the time to dispel some myths and misunderstandings about this &#39;diet&#39;, and hopefully win a few converts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unconventional Fitness Truths</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/unconventional-fitness-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/unconventional-fitness-truths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_883&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Source: JcOlivera.com on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/unconventional.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-883&#34; title=&#34;Guy exercising outdoor in Venice Beach&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/unconventional-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A bear, however hard he tries, grows tubby without exercise.” -Winnie the Pooh&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I began CrossFit two years ago, I&#39;ve learned some things about fitness that seem very counterintuitive. When I started training other people, one of my biggest challenges had been convincing people that what they&#39;ve always thought about fitness is wrong. Here are some common misconceptions that I&#39;ve discovered to be false, along with some strange truths that you wouldn&#39;t suspect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returning to the Dojo: The Importance of Martial Arts</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_713&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; caption=&#34;Source: Pieter Baert on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pietel/15322162/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-713&#34; title=&#34;karate&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/karate2.jpg?w=201&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was a child I have had this instinctive urge for expansion and growth. To me, the function and duty of a quality human being is the sincere and honest development of one&#39;s potential. - Bruce Lee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I attended my first class of American Kenpo Karate in over five years. My old teacher told me in an e-mail to bring my old Gi, which I had kept, anticipating an eventual return to the art. When I went to dig it out from a trunk under my bed, I found my old belts, one soft, well-worn, and white, and the other stiff and bright, un-faded yellow. I grabbed the white belt and headed to class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I stepped into the dance studio where the class was being held, my old instructor, taller and leaner than I remembered, looked at me without recognition. It &lt;em&gt;had &lt;/em&gt;been a long time. He was shocked at the growth he saw in me and had trouble connecting the old Khaled with the one who stood before him. And then he looked down and saw I was wearing my old white belt and asked, &#34;Where&#39;s your belt?&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Athleticism Good for Your Health?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/is-athleticism-good-for-your-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/is-athleticism-good-for-your-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; caption=&#34;Source: RobW_ on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/48/136462415_5455bf750a.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Statue of an Athlete from the Ancient Olympic Games&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/136462415_5455bf750a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent visit to my sports doctor, brought on by yet another overuse injury, prompted me to wonder if being an athlete is actually good for one&#39;s health and fitness. After all, the only reason I was at the doctor was because I am an athlete. I had injured my shoulder on a leisurely kayak tour of a small Connecticut lake. The shoulder was prone to such a pansy injury because I regularly engage in extreme fitness, aka, CrossFit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you are probably wondering, as was I, how can an athlete with shoulders capable of doing multiple strict muscle-ups be completely incapacitated by something as tame as kayaking? I honestly don&#39;t have an answer. But the experience got me to wondering about the distinctions between fitness, health, and athleticism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Brain is Making You Weak</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/your-brain-is-making-you-weak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/your-brain-is-making-you-weak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/06/brain.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-611&#34; title=&#34;brain&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/brain.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;There&#39;s a lot in the fitness community on how diet and exercise impact fitness and strength, and even a fair amount on sleep. Less discussed is the impact of mental state and the way the nervous system can interact with muscles to have a huge impact on athletic performance and strength. Since I&#39;ve been reading some alternative theories lately, I thought I&#39;d share some things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nervous Inhibition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s an interesting fact: by default, the nervous system limits muscle tension to 30% of what the associated tendons can bear. So if you can only lift 100lbs, it&#39;s not because your muscles are weak, it&#39;s because your brain is holding you back to protect the tendons. Probably the biggest factor limiting how strong we are is our own nervous system keeping our muscles down to protect us. Another related phenomenon is that the brain will inhibit agonist (primary mover) muscles if it perceives the antagonist is weak, in order to protect the joint. For example, your bicep will be inhibited if your triceps is weak because the brain will worry that, should things get out of hand, the triceps won&#39;t be able to counteract the bicep force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Engine is Bigger than Yours: Efficiency vs. Effectiveness in CrossFit</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-engine-is-bigger-than-yours-efficiency-vs-effectiveness-in-crossfit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-engine-is-bigger-than-yours-efficiency-vs-effectiveness-in-crossfit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/060910_1718_myengineisb1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt;Generally, when presented with any given task, we seek out the most efficient way to complete that task. The less time it takes, the less effort involved, the better. Not so often do we ask ourselves whether we&#39;re doing the right task or not. Is what we are doing actually the most effective way to reach our goals, or is it just busy-work? A Honda is more efficient than a Ferrari, but a Ferrari will get your where you&#39;re going much, much faster, making it more effective if your goal is saving time in transit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the Aftermath of Wino</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/in-the-aftermath-of-wino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/in-the-aftermath-of-wino/</guid>
      <description>Five rounds for time:
 21 thrusters @ 75lb 21 double unders</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Things Can Happen to Good People</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/bad-things-can-happen-to-good-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/bad-things-can-happen-to-good-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/accident.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-459&#34; title=&#34;accident&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/accident.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A lot of people who restrict their diet for the sake of health have little to console themselves with when they must forgo all the little pleasures in life. All they can do is remind themselves that they will be spared the debilitating chronic diseases that will likely afflict their less-disciplined friends. Unfortunetly (or not) it isn&#39;t that simple. Sometimes, those of us with the healthiest of habits end up the victim while our chain smoking, sugar-munching friends live their whole lives without the smallest issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epic Fail</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/epic-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/epic-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/failure.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-438&#34; title=&#34;failure&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/failure.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, I failed epically. The workout for today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many rounds as possible, in 10 minutes, of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 deadlifts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 hang cleans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 front squats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 push jerks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All with 95 lbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, it&#39;s a ton of work, and much of it involving very technical movements. I was aiming to complete 7 rounds (so 49 of everything) because the previous record was 6 and change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I completed 6 rounds with about a minute and a half left. I was already dying. My vision was blurry and my legs felt like jelly, but I pushed through the sets. I got to the push jerks with 30 seconds left and without taking any rest, started into them. As the clock ticked to 0 seconds, I became distanced from my body, aware of but not feeling the burning in every muscle (a sensation that I had never experienced before), until the very last rep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Superhero Training</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/superhero-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/superhero-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/khaledbatman.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-339&#34; title=&#34;khaledbatman&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/khaledbatman.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People ask me why I train so hard. The answer is simple. I&#39;m training to be Batman... (as Superman was technically an alien, it would be a bit ridiculous for me to train to be him, since there&#39;s no way I could ever achieve that level of strength and fitness as an Earthling).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My CrossFit coaches have offered to pay my registration fee for the New England CrossFit Sectionals in March. While those who know me can attest to the fact that I didn&#39;t really need much motivation to train hard in the past, going to the Sectionals has given me a new kind of motivation and intensity to train. Knowing that I am going to be competing against some of the fittest people in New England, many of them bigger and stronger than me, has gotten me to really kick my training into high gear.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
