<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mental toughness on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/mental-toughness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mental toughness on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/mental-toughness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mental Toughness, and the CrossFit Northeast Sectionals</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/mental-toughness-and-the-crossfit-northeast-sectionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/mental-toughness-and-the-crossfit-northeast-sectionals/</guid>
      <description>I just got back from two days of the most intense physical and mental challenges of my life, the CrossFit Northeast Sectionals, the first step on the road to the 2010 CrossFit games, the winners of which are considered the fittest man and woman on Earth.
I&#39;m too tired right now to write a detailed play-by-play, so right now, I just want to share some thoughts.
I was certainly one of the smaller guys going into this competition, and I have only been CrossFitting for a little over a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Superhero Training</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/superhero-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/superhero-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/khaledbatman.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-339&#34; title=&#34;khaledbatman&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/khaledbatman.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People ask me why I train so hard. The answer is simple. I&#39;m training to be Batman... (as Superman was technically an alien, it would be a bit ridiculous for me to train to be him, since there&#39;s no way I could ever achieve that level of strength and fitness as an Earthling).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My CrossFit coaches have offered to pay my registration fee for the New England CrossFit Sectionals in March. While those who know me can attest to the fact that I didn&#39;t really need much motivation to train hard in the past, going to the Sectionals has given me a new kind of motivation and intensity to train. Knowing that I am going to be competing against some of the fittest people in New England, many of them bigger and stronger than me, has gotten me to really kick my training into high gear.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
