<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>parkour on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/parkour/</link>
    <description>Recent content in parkour on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/parkour/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3 Unexpected Benefits of Natural Movement</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/3-unexpected-benefits-of-natural-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/3-unexpected-benefits-of-natural-movement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/threedeer.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3046&#34; alt=&#34;threedeer&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/threedeer.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started training with natural movements, as opposed to the contrived, isolated, and repetitive movements that used to make up the bulk of my training program, I was mainly interested in the obvious benefits: catlike reflexes, amazing strength, awe-inspiring toughness, and ninja skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly, I was focused on the physical benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I discovered after training this way for a while that it was changing me in other ways, too. I started to relate to my body differently than I had before, even during my years training CrossFit. Instead of feeling constantly inadequate, always being a step behind where I needed to be, I started to feel capable where I was right now, even as I trained to continue improving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve written extensively on the &lt;a title=&#34;Move and Be Free&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/move-and-be-free/&#34;&gt;physical&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title=&#34;How Moving Well Can Make You Confident and Popular&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/two-reasons-play-is-a-big-deal/&#34;&gt;mental&lt;/a&gt; benefits of natural movement, and plenty of other people have as well, so I just wanted to share some of the less obvious benefits I&#39;ve found from my training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Understanding of Fitness and the Human Body</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-new-understanding-of-fitness-and-the-human-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-new-understanding-of-fitness-and-the-human-body/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/245952551_797503484e.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright  wp-image-1995&#34; title=&#34;Bodies in Motion&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/245952551_797503484e.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;360&#34; height=&#34;270&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Many people treat their bodies as if they were rented from Hertz--something they are using to get around in but nothing they genuinely care about understanding. - Chungliang Al Huang&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until recently, it was thought that a human being could be perfectly healthy eating only parts of food, as long as they were in sufficient quantities and ratios. The nutrient model of diet claimed that we simply needed sufficient protein, carbohydrates, and fats, plus vitamins, in order to be healthy. Foods were broken down, proteins, vitamins, and minerals extracted, removed, concentrated, and added back in sufficient quantities. We had mastered the science of nutrition and were entering a golden age of health and convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much for that...the nutrient model has been discredited lately, as it became more and more obvious that the benefits of whole foods, eaten fresh and close to the source, simply could not be copied by even the most carefully scientifically balanced meals. Sometimes this was because of the limits of our technology, but just as often, there were factors we hadn&#39;t even identified that seemed to make the difference between health-promoting and obesity-inducing food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitness and exercise is where nutrition was a few years ago. We are only now starting to pull out of the mistaken belief that movement-related health can be broken down into its constituent parts and fed in concentrations to promote certain kinds of growth. Happily, we have mostly discarded the notion that the body can respond to training muscles in isolation on weight machines. Unfortunately, we still pull movement apart into elements like strength, speed, power, agility, coordination, balance, and flexibility, just as we used to think of food only in terms of its proteins, carbohydrates, fats, vitamins, and minerals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movement Naturale</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/movement-naturale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/movement-naturale/</guid>
      <description>A break from the usual thought-provoking stuff to share something I&#39;m getting really passionate about: Movement Naturale! This was the original functional fitness program developed by the French before WWI. I read about it years ago, and it was what initially sparked my interest in other functional fitness programs like CrossFit. Partly because it was so intense, I didn&#39;t really entertain the notion of getting into it right off the bat, but now that I&#39;ve developed a good base from CrossFit and have started trail running, I&#39;m probably going to start incorporating some of it into my fitness program.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
