<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>glamour on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/glamour/</link>
    <description>Recent content in glamour on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/glamour/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Livin&#39; La Vida Expat</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/livin-la-vida-expat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/livin-la-vida-expat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/3901537243_085c10c684.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2054&#34; title=&#34;Expat Living&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3901537243_085c10c684-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“Never write about a place until you&#39;re away from it, because that gives you perspective.&#34; -Ernest Hemingway&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an American expat living in South Korea. Glamourous, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up as an expat living in Kuwait and Dubai. My American dad hung out with Arabs and Westerners alike, so we had friends from all over. My sister and I went to an American school and were taught English at the expense of Arabic (actually, many wealthy Arabs sent their kids to the American school as well. It was the trendy thing to do). While most kids might have spent their lazy summers playing baseball at the neighborhood park or just playing in the street, we spent every day rambling around exclusive beach clubs. We were able to afford luxuries that we wouldn&#39;t have been able to have in the States, like a live-in nanny. I grew accustomed to a lifestyle that was very different from what I&#39;d find in America when we &#39;returned&#39;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Vintage Expat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I&#39;m a complete nerd, the word expat brings to mind &lt;strong&gt;Ernest Hemingway&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Gertrude Stein&lt;/strong&gt;, chilling at cafes in Paris where they can be &lt;a title=&#34;Get Out of the Box!&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/get-out-of-the-box/&#34;&gt;free to think&lt;/a&gt; their own thoughts which eventually find their way back home to change society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I&#39;m &lt;a title=&#34;We’re Going to Make It&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/were-going-to-make-it/&#34;&gt;living in Korea&lt;/a&gt;, I realize that the reality is more like my childhood in the Middle East. Being an expat is about escaping responsibility and living it up. It involves a surprising amount of alcohol (though I&#39;m sure Hemingway, at least, did not limit his imbibing to dainty French coffees), and a lot of partying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think this perception is limited to my experience in Korea. I just finished John Wood&#39;s book, &lt;em&gt;Leaving Microsoft to Change the World,&lt;/em&gt; and the author shares his commentary on the lifestyle of Microsoft expats living in Sydney and Beijing, which is one of &lt;strong&gt;glamour&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;escapism&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;entitlement&lt;/strong&gt;. Those who epitomize the lifestyle do it because they can live the high life, making a relatively high income and taking advantage of favorable economics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Wood&#39;s case, he and his girlfriend were both emblematic of the expat lifestyle in China. As a Microsoft employee, Wood had plenty of money, and living in China, which was less developed than it is today, he was able to have all sorts of luxuries he wouldn&#39;t get otherwise, such as a personal driver. His girlfriend had come from the rural Midwest and was so hooked on the glamorous life that she refused to go on vacations that didn&#39;t involve resorts and 4-star hotels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think I would be going too far to suggest that for many, living abroad is seen as an extended vacation with perks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing wrong with that, and if it occurs in a context of &lt;a title=&#34;Empty Your Cup: Accepting Ignorance to Learn&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/empty-your-cup-accepting-ignorance-to-learn/&#34;&gt;learning new perspectives&lt;/a&gt; living in a new country, all the better.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
