<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>inspire on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/inspire/</link>
    <description>Recent content in inspire on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/inspire/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tell a Story, Change the World</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/tell-a-story-change-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/tell-a-story-change-the-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/5989736193_952566e542.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2436&#34; title=&#34;Storytelling&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5989736193_952566e542-300x204.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;204&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Storytelling is the most powerful way to put ideas into the world today. - Robert McAfee Brown&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To create a better reality, first tell as story about it so real and compelling that all uncertainty and fear is replaced by excitement and a desire for something better.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are funny sometimes. Even when we want something better than what we have, we are reluctant to move towards it until we are assured it is safe. Most people will always prefer the known reality they have over the unknown they might have, even if could be better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncertainty is a huge demotivator&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was starting to change my life for the better, the biggest obstacle to progress was the inability to see the reality I wanted to become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No matter how much I pushed myself to meet people, I could not see myself as socially confident, and so I never became comfortable with it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No matter how many pushups I did, I never saw myself as strong, and so they were always hard and my progress was painfully slow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No matter how much I wrote, I never saw myself as a writer, and so I had only marginal success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eventually, I realized the problem wasn&#39;t my lack of practice. It was the fact that I was clinging to the wrong picture of who I was.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, instead of focusing on the logistics, I started to focus on the image in my head, the vision I had of what and who I was. I started to imagine myself doing all the great things I was trying to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I imagined every detail of the me who was socially confident and engaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I painted a detailed image of a strong, muscular, fast, athletic me, doing all the cool things I wanted to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I called myself a writer, over and over, and talked as if that was how I made my living.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when my mind became comfortable with the image, my reality started to conform to it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
