<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>olympic on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/olympic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in olympic on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/olympic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ll Never Be Good Enough...Until You Are</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youll-never-be-good-enough-until-you-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youll-never-be-good-enough-until-you-are/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/05/barbell.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-574&#34; title=&#34;barbell&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/barbell.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;221&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an athlete, one of the most common de-motivators I deal with is the assertion, made either by myself or well-meaning friends trying to help me deal with frustration at limited progress, that professional and Olympic athletes (those I aspire to be like) are genetic abnormalities. Thus, I should not expect myself to perform at their level, and should not hold myself to similar expectations of progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, I have agreed with this statement. After all, I&#39;m just a genetically average human, right? Even with all the determination in the world (and I have plenty of that) I just don&#39;t have the right bone length, muscle fiber ratios, metabolic eccentricities, to make it to the big leagues. So I shouldn&#39;t even try, and certainly not become frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I realized I have no idea what my genetic make-up is. For all I know, I am an Olympic sprinter who just needs the right training to unleash his genetic potential. People tell me I&#39;m too tall to be a gymnast, too lanky to be a good lifter, but there have been unlikely champions in every sport imaginable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
