<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Life Lessons from Philosophy: Socrates</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/life-lessons-from-philosophy-socrates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/life-lessons-from-philosophy-socrates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/croweb/2836991287/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1055&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/socrates-247x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bencrowe on Flickr&#34; width=&#34;247&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I am the wisest man in Athens, for I know one thing, and that is that I know nothing. &lt;em&gt;-Socrates&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post from my friend David, an avid philosophizer and community development manager at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://familyrefugecenter.wordpress.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Family Refuge Center&lt;/a&gt;. He&#39;s the guy in the front of the canoe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One’s first philosophy class is, almost certainly, like a glass of Champaign: 80% froth, 20% golden delight.  Indeed, class discussion was probably a maddening waste of time, and the lecturer was forever pandering to the behests of the idiots; but there were kernels of wisdom to be digested, if you knew where to look.  The first item you read was, undoubtedly, Plato’s account of the Trial of Socrates.  Within this dialogue, you could not have possibly ignored that the wisest man- in the wisest city- claimed to know nothing at all.  This kernal personifies the phrase: &#34;hiding in plain sight&#34; for as it is echoed innumerably, for most, it is passed over like a thrift store gem in a heap of dusty trifles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-zen-and-the-art-of-motorcycle-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-zen-and-the-art-of-motorcycle-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>I recently completed the book Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance, by Robert M. Pirsig, which, contrary to its name, is not a book about Zen or motorcycle maintenance, except in a very roundabout way.
The book is set in the motorcycle roadtrip of a father, the narrator, and his son, Chris, but the real meat of the book is contained in a series of chataquas, or talks, investigating a philosophical conundrum central to Western thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Was Going to College a Mistake?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/was-going-to-college-a-mistake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/was-going-to-college-a-mistake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am in the midst of reading &lt;em&gt;Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance &lt;/em&gt;by Robert M. Pirsig&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;and the author spends a lot of time talking about the educational system in the United States, indeed, all of Western civilization. As a recent college graduate, this is something I&#39;ve actually questioned a lot myself. I don&#39;t know about most of my peers, but I never really thought of college as a necessity, or even a forgone conclusion. When I applied to college, I did it in the context of an expectation - I went to a college-prep school and was at the top of my class, everybody at that school expected me to go to college - but I personally did not necessarily want to go to college. I chose to go, consciously, because I was convinced that it would help me achieve my goals. I did, however, entertain other options.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
