<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sleep on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/sleep/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sleep on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/sleep/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My 2015 Strategy Part 2: The Logistics of Being Awesome</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-2-the-logistics-of-being-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-2-the-logistics-of-being-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3880&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/timeclock-e1420568994227.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;timeclock&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;245&#34; /&gt;Last week, I shared &lt;a title=&#34;My 2015 Strategy Part 1: Dreams and Aspirations&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/my-2015-strategy-part-1-dreams-and-aspirations/&#34;&gt;my overarching strategy for 2015&lt;/a&gt; and how I got there, with a simple, but very helpful exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, I was planning to talk about specific actions and the structures I&#39;m going to put into place to support my plans, but it became a longer article than I&#39;d expected. So, I&#39;m going to limit it to logistics now, and actions on Thursday, because dreams without action will stay that way, and action without logistics will fizzle out real fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Quick Definitions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize not everyone here is a military history buff (or UPS admirer), so you may not be entirely familiar with what logistics are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, logistics are the support systems that enable an army to do its job. This includes things like food, transportation systems, and even lifestyle. The best trained Navy SEAL is useless without the entire support system that puts him in the right place to start his mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your personal life, it is important to create a system to support you. This includes things like your habits, your environment, and your routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good logistics are just as essential as good strategy and good tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Logistics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with last week&#39;s post was that I didn&#39;t account for time, energy, or financial resources; I simply wrote down everything I want to do in the next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this week, I&#39;ll show you how to handle the rest.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
