<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>running on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/running/</link>
    <description>Recent content in running on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/running/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Epic Tale of the Triumph of Will Over Utter Stupidity</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/an-epic-tale-of-the-triumph-of-will-over-utter-stupidity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/an-epic-tale-of-the-triumph-of-will-over-utter-stupidity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on the travel blog I kept while living in Korea.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/DSC_4519-e1331562897868.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had pretty much given up around the 20km mark. My left arch had been cramping since I passed 10km and my feet felt like the road was molten asphalt. I was still moving my feet, but it was more of a shuffle as I gingerly placed each step carefully to avoid even the tiniest jolt to my worn out suspension. I glared resentfully at every pair of cushy, padded, motion-controlled sneakers that cruised by me, their owners floating on a soft cloud of running technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had wondered if running a marathon in my &#39;barefoot&#39; Merrell Trailgloves was a good idea, but it turned out to be much worse than I had imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was only my second marathon. The first one I had run in racing flats, and I didn&#39;t think there would be too much difference, but it turns out half an inch of foam was the difference between crippling pain and a challenging run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had also had a running partner the first time. My dad and I had jogged steadily around the streets of Philly, chatting and sharing observations about the city. Here, in South Korea, I was running alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I talked myself into putting one foot in front of the other. Somehow, I made it through the twenties and starting chipping away at kilometer 30, then 31, then 32. Each one seemed longer than the one before. With every...single...step my body wanted to stand still. &#34;Please let me walk, just two steps. I&#39;ll do anything!&#34; it begged me. Still I ran.&lt;img title=&#34;More...&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/trans.gif&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Truth About My Training and Diet</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-truth-about-my-training-and-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-truth-about-my-training-and-diet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1699&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;I&amp;#39;d rather be able to do this than have a fast Fran time. Source: Raphael Goetter on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/goetter/2567497624/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1699&#34; title=&#34;ironcross&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/ironcross-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a CrossFit trainer, I sometimes feel like I&#39;m not allowed to use, much less espouse, alternative forms of physical training or diet. But since I&#39;ve been caught so many times doing very un-CrossFit-like things, and a lot of people ask me what my training program is, or what my diet is, I thought I&#39;d come clean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Born to Run</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-born-to-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-born-to-run/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0307279189/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=warrspir-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399349&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0307279189&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;Format=_SL160_&amp;amp;ASIN=0307279189&amp;amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;amp;WS=1&amp;amp;tag=warrspir-20&amp;amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/ir?t=&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=0307279189&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399349&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to run barefoot for a long time, since the Vibram FiveFingers came out several years ago. Unfortunately, I’ve also been injuring myself since that time. Undaunted, I’ve kept trying new methods to learn, different ways to ease into it, and different cross-training and recovery techniques. In the end, it was a kind shoestore clerk and an epic story that made the difference. The clerk at the shoe store gave me a barefoot running instructional book (free just for showing interest in a pair of shoes he ordered that I didn’t even have to purchase). The epic story was &lt;em&gt;Born to Run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forays in Barefoot Running</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/forays-in-barefoot-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/forays-in-barefoot-running/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1570&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;chumley80 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/29937348@N05/5247371406/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1570&#34; title=&#34;Runners Feet&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5247371406_ffb0cc0563-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve started barefoot running. Not just going out to the mail in my bare feet. Not jogging in light shoes. Full on, running down the road with no shoes on, barefoot running. So far my maximum distance is about 3/4 mile, and I&#39;m taking it slowly, but it is addictive, and holding back is the hardest part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wilderness in Your Backyard</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-wilderness-in-your-backyard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-wilderness-in-your-backyard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1506&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Ed Townend on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/townendphotography/2365226378/sizes/l/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1506&#34; title=&#34;duck&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/duck-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning while I was practicing Karate by a forest stream (yeah, I do things like that), a duck hen floated by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stopped to watch her go and was struck by how at-home she seemed. If I blocked out the houses at the top of the hill, I could imagine we were out in the untamed wilderness. She didn&#39;t seem bothered by the fact that there were houses and cars and roads just over the hill, nor by the fact that there was a human by her stream. She was a duck, in the river, in the forest, just as things should be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start Your Day Right with an Anchor</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/building-your-day-around-an-anchor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/building-your-day-around-an-anchor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;lulu lemon athletica on Flickr&#34;]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/20110329-101320.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/20110329-101320.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20110329-101320.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image of the lone warrior training every day at dawn is a popular one in the martial arts. Like clockwork, the Warrior rises before her companions have even stirred to run through her training. She does this in the mornings, so that there is no possibility of distraction. It is her source of strength, for even in the midst of a quest, she finds time to hone her skills and focus her mind for the day&#39;s coming struggles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you ever feel frustrated by the inconsistency in your days? While change and excitement are great, I&#39;ve always found that I really appreciate having at least a few things that are steady that I can turn to in order to get into the right mindset for the day. Alternatively, having something later in the day that I can expect helps me forget all the troubles and problems that have cropped up. An afternoon run will do wonders to help you put the stresses of a long workday behind you so that you can focus your energies on being with your family in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Limits of My Experience</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/learning-the-limits-of-my-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/learning-the-limits-of-my-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;mceTemp&#34; style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1035&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Johan J.Ingles-Le Nobel on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jingleslenobel/4326713557/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1035&#34; title=&#34;river&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/river-300x204.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;204&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As I have said, the first thing is to be honest with yourself. You can never have an impact on society if you have not changed yourself... Great peacemakers are all people of integrity, of honesty, but humility.” -&lt;em&gt;Nelson Mandela&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went for a 5k run today, the first I&#39;ve undertaken in over a year. Despite all the intense anaerobic exercise I do at CrossFit, the fact that I can run a 5:05 mile, and my powerful legs, I found it extremely difficult. So difficult, in fact, that I walked near the end and got a time that was worse than my best high school time. My ankles are sore and I feel more beat up than usual. But really, I&#39;m not that surprised I didn&#39;t do as well as I thought I could. After all, I may be a very well-rounded athlete, but I know that distance running has become a definite area of neglect in my training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unconventional Fitness Truths</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/unconventional-fitness-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/unconventional-fitness-truths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_883&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Source: JcOlivera.com on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/unconventional.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-883&#34; title=&#34;Guy exercising outdoor in Venice Beach&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/unconventional-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A bear, however hard he tries, grows tubby without exercise.” -Winnie the Pooh&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I began CrossFit two years ago, I&#39;ve learned some things about fitness that seem very counterintuitive. When I started training other people, one of my biggest challenges had been convincing people that what they&#39;ve always thought about fitness is wrong. Here are some common misconceptions that I&#39;ve discovered to be false, along with some strange truths that you wouldn&#39;t suspect.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
