<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 10:46:49 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Feedback and Difficulty in Video Games</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/persistence-in-video-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 10:46:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/persistence-in-video-games/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished playing through Halo 2&amp;rsquo;s legendary co-op campaign, which, for those who are not masochistic gamers, is considered one of the most poorly balanced, excessively difficult games ever made. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t played, imagine being a delicate butterfly, made of crystal, trying to survive in a rock tumbler. With another butterfly. Who is tied to your wings, so when one of you dies, you both do. And the rocks are actually trying to hit you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Solving Process</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/problem-solving-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 10:36:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/problem-solving-process/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been preparing for a coding interview recently, and as a result I have given a lot of thought to how I tend to solve problems.
When I started back in to school, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a great problem-solving process. I had always been &amp;ldquo;the smart kid&amp;rdquo; and didn&amp;rsquo;t need to do anything special that I was aware of in order to solve most of the problems I encountered. The only exception to that was some of the very difficult games I like to play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Avoided Becoming the Flavor-of-the-Month Intern</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/how-i-avoided-becoming-the-flavor-of-the-month-intern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/how-i-avoided-becoming-the-flavor-of-the-month-intern/</guid>
      <description>Last year, I had the amazing opportunity to intern at a NASA center. They were looking for someone with JavaScript experience to update a data collections tool that had been underutilized because it was not searchable and had a poor UI. The plan was to rebuild it with a shiny new graph-based database and to update the frontend to use React. Basically, modernize it and clean it up.
All this was what my supervisors and their bosses wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cats Are Evil</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/cats-are-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/cats-are-evil/</guid>
      <description>We have a new cat whose name is probably the most on-the-nose name a cat can have: Misjif. He&amp;rsquo;s so mischievious he even spelled mischief wrong.
Take all the things that make cats cat-like&amp;ndash;climbs everything, yowls in the middle of the night, clever in all the wrong ways, velociraptor-like learning curve and love of mayhem&amp;ndash;and turn them up to CAT. That is Misjif. Also cute. He&amp;rsquo;s stinkin&#39; adorable, which makes all of this worse: you can&amp;rsquo;t stay mad at him (though trust me I&amp;rsquo;m working really hard on that).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortcuts In Moderation</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/shortcuts-in-moderation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/shortcuts-in-moderation/</guid>
      <description>When I started learning to bake bread, I used active dry yeast. It was easy and with the right recipe, I could get reasonably good results without all the complications of a sourdough starter. But I always aspired to make bread with the starter, and for a while, I believed that using a starter was the only real way to make bread. I also thought that once I moved to using a starter, I would never make bread the &amp;ldquo;easy way&amp;rdquo; again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Silence</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/on-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/on-silence/</guid>
      <description>In 2013, I decided to stop writing regularly in my blog, which I had been posting to daily since 2009 when I graduated college. I had what should have felt like success with a reasonable audience, an ebook and launch, collaborations, guest posts, even some money from my writing.
Then, in 2013 I stopped abruptly. I suddenly found the act of expressing my opinions offensive and exhausting, just a lot of ego-stroking.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
