<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>competition on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/competition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in competition on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/competition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fight: Learn Confidence through Combative Play</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/fight-learn-confidence-through-combative-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/fight-learn-confidence-through-combative-play/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I’ve been experimenting with a new approach to fitness and movement, inspired by a teacher I greatly respect: &lt;a title=&#34;Evolve Move Play&#34; href=&#34;http://www.evolvemoveplay.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rafe Kelley of &lt;em&gt;Evolve Move Play&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;His philosophy is that humans evolved movement rehearsal (aka, play) to learn and refine the skills we needed to survive. Some of these were simply moving about the environment, but for men especially, the ultimate goal was hunting or fighting other humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Removing this context from training robs it of some of its most valuable aspects. Competition encourages growth, whether that is with a training partner or an opponent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 1.17em; line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;Respecting Your Opponent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;As a kid, I was unstoppable in contests where there were no losers: straight A&#39;s and every academic award I qualified for. But on a sports field, I preferred playing defense to scoring goals. My contribution to winning was keeping my side from losing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;When I started &lt;a title=&#34;Returning to the Dojo: The Importance of Martial Arts&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;martial arts&lt;/a&gt;, it was exciting but also uncomfortable because I had to become more assertive. After getting beaten a few times, I learned to &lt;a title=&#34;Learn to Stand Alone&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/learn-to-stand-alone/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;stand my ground&lt;/a&gt;. I didn&#39;t get violent, but I stopped inviting others to walk all over me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Play is the perfect place to teach people how to safely assert themselves without hurting others, both physically and emotionally, so that when it becomes important in life, they don’t go overboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End of Competition</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-end-of-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-end-of-competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_967&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: thaiqn on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thaiqn/2884683655/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-967&#34; title=&#34;dodgeball&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/dodgeball-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is the character of a brave and resolute man not to be ruffled by adversity and not to desert his post” &lt;em&gt;- Marcus Tullius Cicero&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My old school no longer plays dodgeball. It is against the rules. The children are urged to forget the game. In fact, we no longer play any games with a score, for fear of engendering competition. The fear is that kids will lord it over one another, put down the losers and gloat in their victory. They will brag and tease and ostracize their peers, or will feel hurt and put down. Some parents and administrators probably worry that kids who lose at dodgeball are more likely to do something violent to vent their frustration. I think this prevents kids from developing strong character.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
