<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>humility on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/humility/</link>
    <description>Recent content in humility on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/humility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>6 Ways Accepting Your Weaknesses Can Empower You</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/6-ways-accepting-your-weaknesses-can-empower-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/6-ways-accepting-your-weaknesses-can-empower-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/weakness.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3173&#34; alt=&#34;weakness&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/weakness-300x153.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;153&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;One of the quirks of having subjective conscious experience (aka, self-awareness) is that we have a very different perspective on ourselves than we do on other people. For example, &lt;a title=&#34;Attribution Bias&#34; href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attribution_bias&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;attribution bias&lt;/a&gt; tells us that we tend to assume other peoples&#39; actions are the result of their character more than their circumstances, while we openly acknowledge that we are affected by circumstances when it suits us. For example, if we see someone else lie to avoid a fine, we would tend to judge them as generally dishonest. If we do the same thing, we would cite our tight finances and tell ourselves that normally we&#39;re honest, law-abiding citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;However, this can create some interesting conflicts as well. We may assume we&#39;re stronger or more reliable than we really are, or that we will be happy in a situation that won&#39;t really make us happy. Maybe the idea of living in New York excites you, but you know that you hate cars and crowds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basically, we don’t like to admit that we are as flawed as other people, but if we are to be honest about who we are, if we are to live with integrity, we have to have an accurate view of ourselves, flaws and all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Egos Beyond This Point</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/no-egos-beyond-this-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/no-egos-beyond-this-point/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;If your practice is good, you may become proud of it. What you do is good, but something more is added to it. Pride is extra. Right effort is to get rid of something extra. - Shunryu Suzuki&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/humbledog.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2843&#34; alt=&#34;SONY DSC&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/humbledog.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;334&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The theme of this year is definitely &lt;a title=&#34;Empower Yourself Through Humility&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/empower-yourself-through-humility/&#34;&gt;humility&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have this annoying habit of questioning authority in all its forms, even when it&#39;s authority I normally support, i.e., my MovNat trainers at my &lt;a title=&#34;Playing in the Woods, Mountain Lions, and Braised Chicken&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/playing-in-the-woods-mountain-lions-and-braised-chicken/&#34;&gt;recent certification&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop was well run and everyone got a lot out of it, but at one point, I found something to pick on and made a big deal out of nothing. I realize, looking back, that I had primed myself for a confrontation by the attitude I brought in to the certification, which was one of proving myself rather than learning something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After it all went down, I was pretty upset, not so much with the trainers, who handled it very professionally, but with myself for being bothered and for feeling the need to do or say anything. After all, it wasn&#39;t &lt;em&gt;my &lt;/em&gt;workshop, nor was it my responsibility. I spent a troubled evening losing sleep and &lt;strong&gt;trying to figure out what it was inside me that was causing me so much anxiety&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I eventually figured out it was the desire to prove myself rather than let go and simply learn. I reached out to my sister for advice, and she wisely suggested &lt;strong&gt;I make a distinction between observation (learning) and judging (reacting)&lt;/strong&gt;. So, the next morning, after a sincere and humbling apology (damage control), I made a point of simply observing and withholding judgement for the remaining three days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Needless to say, I learned a lot more that way than with my original approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empower Yourself Through Humility</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/empower-yourself-through-humility/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/empower-yourself-through-humility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/16112_700950337914_589075632_n-e1360535516995.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2802&#34; alt=&#34;Bowing Before the Buddha&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/16112_700950337914_589075632_n-e1360535516995.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;545&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humility reminds us that we are human. It reminds us not to overestimate our abilities, not to get sloppy and lazy, to always be present and give our best effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humility reminds us that the big tasks, the ones that matter, really are difficult, even for such amazing warriors as ourselves. &lt;strong&gt;Remembering this, we will remain focused, taking the task seriously and bringing to it the attention it deserves.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humility says, &#34;I could mess this up, so I will make sure I don&#39;t.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only the fool forgoes humility for hubris. If he is talented, he will get far, but eventually, the task at hand will be bigger than he can handle casually. Eventually, it will require an acceptance of the need for help, either from other people or deeper wells of energy and focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&#39;ve adopted the habit of bowing upon waking and just before bed. Bowing is an interesting form of devotion because it is an expression of humility. You are honoring whatever you bow to by being humble before it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, that suggests an acknowledgement of how much we rely on certain things and how important mindfulness is. I recite certain gratitudes when I bow. For example, I give thanks for the opportunity to rest and recover at night, and then I bow. This expresses the acknowledgement that I don&#39;t necessarily have the right to peaceful rest -- many people don&#39;t get it. I am thankful for it, but also humbled by it, since I depend on it to function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>But What if You Fail?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/but-what-if-you-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/but-what-if-you-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/5638935174_b3911ed5ca.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2193&#34; title=&#34;Kite in a Tree&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5638935174_b3911ed5ca-300x226.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;226&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#34;I&#39;m sorry to say so/but, sadly it&#39;s true/that bang-ups and hang-ups/can happen to you&#34; - Dr. Seuss, &lt;em&gt;Oh the Place You&#39;ll Go!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was in high school, I was obsessed with D&amp;amp;D. I spent hours on it, and I once created a very elaborate description of a world born of my imagination. At the time, it was the longest thing I&#39;d ever written, about 40 pages. This was a big deal for an aspiring writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, I opened my computer and the document was gone. I was simply left with 40 pages of garbled text symbols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was defeated and considered just forgetting it had ever existed. It had taken so much work, and I felt that if something that big could be destroyed so easily, what was the point?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nobody else in the world would miss it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Limits of My Experience</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learning-the-limits-of-my-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learning-the-limits-of-my-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;mceTemp&#34; style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1035&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Johan J.Ingles-Le Nobel on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jingleslenobel/4326713557/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1035&#34; title=&#34;river&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/river-300x204.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;204&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As I have said, the first thing is to be honest with yourself. You can never have an impact on society if you have not changed yourself... Great peacemakers are all people of integrity, of honesty, but humility.” -&lt;em&gt;Nelson Mandela&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went for a 5k run today, the first I&#39;ve undertaken in over a year. Despite all the intense anaerobic exercise I do at CrossFit, the fact that I can run a 5:05 mile, and my powerful legs, I found it extremely difficult. So difficult, in fact, that I walked near the end and got a time that was worse than my best high school time. My ankles are sore and I feel more beat up than usual. But really, I&#39;m not that surprised I didn&#39;t do as well as I thought I could. After all, I may be a very well-rounded athlete, but I know that distance running has become a definite area of neglect in my training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traits of a Warrior: Humility</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-humility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-humility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/humility.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-407&#34; title=&#34;humility&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/humility.jpg?w=210&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;210&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most important lessons I&#39;ve learned from CrossFit is humility. Workouts that sound easy never are, and I am always amazed at how quickly my muscles will tire, how a weight that sounds light quickly becomes unbearable. To make things worse, we are always talking about how some crazy CrossFitter completed the same WOD in unrealistically fast times. CrossFit is a community, and so we know that the same workout that destroyed everyone at our gym was a walk in the park for someone else. Personally, this is hard to swallow. I know I&#39;ve made amazing strides since I started, but an unweighted barbell still gets painfully heavy after a few minutes, and burpees can still leave me begging for mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make things worse, I&#39;ve come to learn that getting frustrated does not make things any better. After 5 months of training, my snatch max hasn&#39;t changed a single pound. But trying to use frustration to motivate myself only causes my technique to fall apart. There is a fine line between determination and frustration.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
