<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>challenge on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/challenge/</link>
    <description>Recent content in challenge on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/challenge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Warrior Mindset Part 2: Transform Challenges Into Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-warrior-mindset-part-2-transform-challenges-into-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-warrior-mindset-part-2-transform-challenges-into-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2737&#34; alt=&#34;&#39;Iron Knights&#39; patrol the Arghandab&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5418579692_5b570e142d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shawn Rhodes, founder of Shoshin Consulting, is a traveler, teacher and above all, a lifelong student. After growing up in the mountains training in martial arts and eastern philosophy, he followed his own warrior&#39;s calling and joined the U.S. Marines. There, he accompanied infantry Marines through two combat tours in Iraq, documenting their trials and victories for international news outlets like CNN and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-2723&#34; alt=&#34;rhodessmaller&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/rhodessmaller-e1358734605767-150x150.jpg&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;TIME. While living and fighting alongside this tribe of modern-day warriors, he discovered the link between the warrior&#39;s path and mastery in life. He returned to the U.S. with the passion to share a vision of what humans are capable of when they embrace their own inner warrior and return to a mindset where all paths are possible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is the second in a three-part series on The Warrior&#39;s Path. Each installment will explore the evolution of the warrior mindset. Rooted in ancient methods warriors followed for thousands of years, adopting this mindset can help anyone to regain balance, direction, and control of their health, success, and life.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/part-i-of-the-warrior-mindset-turn-problems-into-challenges/&#34;&gt;the first part &lt;/a&gt;of this series, readers learned how to use the ancient mindset of the warrior to see life in a new way. Instead of viewing the world as a place that acts upon our lives, we learned everyone has the ability to choose how to process situations. &lt;b&gt;Seeing each problem in life as a challenge to shift our mindset is the first stage of warriorhood.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second installment of this series, we will learn the next stage in the evolution of the warrior mindset is &lt;strong&gt;turning those challenges into opportunities, and why it’s the supreme form of power&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, many people - especially young men - get stuck in the first stage of a warrior’s development. They’ve learned to see the problems in their lives as challenges, but they make a key mistake that freezes their development: they see each challenge as a threat and a test of their strength. We’ve all seen the chest-puffing and rooster dance from two guys at the bar or on the schoolyard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Need to Prove&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m convinced, after seeing firsthand people spend months trying to kill each other in modern war, that much of the violence in this world comes from people feeling threatened and wanting to protect what they see as ‘theirs‘: their life, their property, their ideologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These folks aren’t operating from the mindset of mature warriors; they are approaching their lives like a guard defending a castle, afraid of the walls crumbling at any moment. Without their bravado and one-upmanship, others might discover just how fragile their self-image really is. People frozen in this stage may be extremely skilled fighters, but they rush blindly into battles without examining the playing field for the best - and easiest - ways to win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one of the most famous texts outlining the warrior mindset - The Hagakure - its author Yamamoto Tsunemoto likens a skilled warrior on the battlefield to a hawk taking down a single bird in a flock. Experienced warriors focus their minds on a task - or an opponent - and are unconcerned with the opinions of others in the flock or social circle. &lt;b&gt;Instead, they are more concerned with performance than they are with proving their competence. &lt;/b&gt;This makes them extremely effective at whatever they set their minds to, whether it’s being a fighter or an artist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;If you are young and still exploring your relationship to your world by comparing your strength against others, the sooner you move past needing to prove yourself, the sooner you can embrace a deeper kind of power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Warrior Mindset Part 1: Turn Problems Into Challenges</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/part-i-of-the-warrior-mindset-turn-problems-into-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/part-i-of-the-warrior-mindset-turn-problems-into-challenges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2726&#34; alt=&#34;5646268901_1d5d96a8e1&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5646268901_1d5d96a8e1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-2723 alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;rhodessmaller&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/rhodessmaller-200x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;151&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post from Shawn Rhodes, founder of Shoshin Consulting. Shawn is a traveler, teacher and above all, a lifelong student. After growing up in the mountains training in martial arts and eastern philosophy, he followed his own warrior&#39;s calling and joined the U.S. Marines. There, he accompanied infantry Marines through two combat tours in Iraq, documenting their trials and victories for international news outlets like CNN and TIME. While living and fighting alongside this tribe of modern-day warriors, he discovered the link between the warrior&#39;s path and mastery in life. He returned to the U.S. with the passion to share a vision of what humans are capable of when they embrace their own inner warrior and return to a mindset where all paths are possible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is the first in a three-part series on The Warrior&#39;s Path. Each installment will explore the evolution of the warrior mindset.  Rooted in ancient methods warriors followed for thousands of years, these installments will give readers a glimpse into how traditional and modern warriors see the world.  Adopting this mindset can help anyone regain balance, direction, and control of their health, success, and life.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional role of the fighter - the person who trains from a young age to be skilled in combat - is disappearing. For better or worse, the mindset learned from a lifetime of turning problems to one’s advantage on the battlefield or the boardroom is being lost. Technology is changing the face of war and our world. The traditional warrior&#39;s path - years of intense physical training, exposure to the elements, mental exhaustion, moments that burn into memory - is not for everyone. That doesn&#39;t mean you can&#39;t benefit from the way warriors learn to see themselves and the world, however. I believe this valiant spirit lives inside everyone, and that we can all benefit from learning how to approach the world like a warrior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;A select few still hear the call to embrace warriorhood; not the call to control others with force, but to turn their focus inward to the battlefield of their own lives. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This calling is universal to every place and age. As we allow ourselves to become dependent on external distractions to fill our inner voids, the call to seize control of our destinies and live with a courageous spirit is louder than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many of us turn to television, alcohol, drugs, and even chronic exercise in the hope it will distract us from our responsibility as human beings and warriors: the mission of the warrior is to discover all they are capable of being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forget the Resolution! Set a Challenge!</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/forget-the-resolution-set-a-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/forget-the-resolution-set-a-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/forget-the-resolution-set-a-challenge/418636_674776395704_416458635_n1/&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2646&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wp-image-2646 aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;418636_674776395704_416458635_n(1)&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/418636_674776395704_416458635_n1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;581&#34; height=&#34;389&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Resolutions are boring. I resolve to behave better this year, blah, blah, blah... This is a whole new &lt;em&gt;YEAR &lt;/em&gt;we&#39;re talking about, not just the turn of an hourglass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s so great about a resolution anyway? Sure, it&#39;s an opportunity to start anew, to take a stab at &lt;a title=&#34;You’re Not Broken, So You Can’t “Fix” Yourself&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/youre-not-broken-so-you-cant-fix-yourself/&#34;&gt;fixing something that you think is broken&lt;/a&gt; about yourself, to be better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why do we want to be better? Is it just to feel good about ourselves? Or are we &lt;a title=&#34;You Can’t Afford to be Attached to Your Health, So Make it About Others&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/you-cant-afford-to-be-attached-to-your-health-so-make-it-about-others/&#34;&gt;trying to accomplish something greater&lt;/a&gt; in our lives than self-satisfaction?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you want to lose weight, or gain muscle, or workout more, or write more, or become financially independent, or eat more local food, or get a promotion, or learn a new language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All attainable goals, great things for anyone to do. Which is fine. If you are aiming for mediocrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we need - what &lt;em&gt;you &lt;/em&gt;need - is something epic, something grand, something game-changing, something that matters to you specifically, something for which you in particular were destined.&lt;/strong&gt; Your bliss, to use the terminology of Joseph Campbell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you follow your bliss... doors will open where you would not have thought there would be doors; and where there wouldn&#39;t be a door for anyone else. - Joseph Campbell&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You don&#39;t need another resolution. You need a challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why My Favorite Students are the Most Difficult</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-my-favorite-students-are-the-most-difficult/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-my-favorite-students-are-the-most-difficult/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/brickwall.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1875&#34; title=&#34;brickwall&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/brickwall-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“When we long for life without difficulties, remind us that oaks grow strong in contrary winds and diamonds are made under pressure” - Peter Marshall&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an English teacher, I deal with kids of all ability levels. There are the star students who do all the homework, even the assignments you don’t really expect anyone to do, answer all the questions perfectly, and are polite, engaged and generally perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there are the students who fall asleep in class, which is a good day because when they are awake they are disruptive, harassing other students, yelling for no apparent reason, and making the classroom a living hell. Trying to teach them is like talking to a brick wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guess which students I appreciate more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bad ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not at first. The first few weeks working as a teacher, I loathed dealing with them. I wanted to just ignore their failing grades and total lack of understanding, but the little voice in my head said that, as the teacher, I should go over and help, even if it wouldn’t make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it did make a difference. In fact, it made a big difference. The kids improved (slightly) but their attitudes improved a lot. They tried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More importantly, I improved as a teacher&lt;/strong&gt;. I started to get a sense of what worked and what didn’t. If I could learn to motivate the worst students, I would be that much better at motivating everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And honestly, I could teach the best students with my eyes closed (actually, they can teach themselves). Unfortunately, as teachers it is so tempting to give all our attention to the good students, since they clearly appreciate and value us. But now, with my new perspective on the frustrating kids, I actually enjoy working with them. When I bring that kind of energy to the interaction, it makes it more pleasant for everyone, and then they start to make an effort.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
