<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>minnesota on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/minnesota/</link>
    <description>Recent content in minnesota on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/minnesota/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Midwest Trip Wrap-Up</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/midwest-trip-wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/midwest-trip-wrap-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_622&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Graffiti Graveyard, Duluth, MN&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/06/100_0535.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-622&#34; title=&#34;100_0535&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/100_0535.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apologies for the delay. Upon arriving home I discovered my home in the midst of packing to move and have thus been distracted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Logistics from Hell&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon leaving Wisconsin, I made my way, via bus, to the Twin Cities of Minneapolis-St. Paul. Even though I&#39;m not from the state, whenever anyone refers to &#39;the cities&#39; it is this metropolis I immediately think of, even when I&#39;m elsewhere. The bus ride was uneventful, except for the fact that I missed my first bus and then had to negotiate my way on to the next bus out. 5-minutes of lateness cost me $80 in new bus far and a taxi ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More logistical problems at the MSP airport prevented me from renting a car from my originally planned company. I thought I&#39;d be stuck completely but they recommended me to another company, which actually ended up costing me less. So it worked out in the end, I made it out of the cities and got on the long, beautiful, pine-wrapped highway of Minnesota, en route to the Northwoods and the lake country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson&lt;/strong&gt;: This was exactly the fear that had kept me from travelling in the first place. I dealt with it and got to the places I wanted to go. So I learned that I am smart enough and resourceful enough to manage if things go astray. Still, the reliance on my own cash was a little unsettling. What if I ran out of money? I have long ago stopped carrying Daddy&#39;s Credit Card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Memory Lane on I-35&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drive up to camp was relaxing. I&#39;d been on the road all day anyway, but it was nice to drive my own (rented) car. I got up to camp around 11:30, feeling completely at home like always. I managed to find some people who knew me sharing a fire in the sailing house and sat with them for an hour, hanging out like we&#39;d been seeing each other all year. There was very little catch up talk and a lot of comfortable silence and random tangents. I slept in a cabin, all alone, which I should know by now is a bad idea. No matter how old I get, the intermediate cabins freak me out with all the windows open and their big, empty wooden rooms. I spent many a summer night as a kid bawling my eyes out in terror in those cabins, and old memories like that never really fade completely. While not afraid per se, I was unconsciously tense all night and didn&#39;t actually manage to fall asleep until the sun came up, lulled by the haunting call of the loon and the wind in the pines.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
