<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>death on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/death/</link>
    <description>Recent content in death on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/death/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Solution to the Meaning of Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-solution-to-the-meaning-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-solution-to-the-meaning-of-life/</guid>
      <description>I promised last week to explain the epiphany that led me to make peace with my fear of death. It was based on the realization that I am connected to all of my ancestors. This is going to get deep, so bear with me.
So here&#39;s the explanation. Zooming out from my personal experience of life, I&#39;m just one iteration of a genetic lineage. In fact, from a particular perspective, the real agent of this experience of existence is not me, Khaled, a human individual alive here and now, but rather the series of individual organisms connected by a genetic history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Turn Fear into Inspiration</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-i-turn-fear-into-inspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-i-turn-fear-into-inspiration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/skull.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3084&#34; alt=&#34;skull&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/skull-202x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;202&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I&#39;ve been struggling with my mortality lately. Every few years, I go through periods of my life when I&#39;m hyperaware that I won&#39;t be around forever, that this is my only chance to live, and afterwards it will be Eternity of....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I&#39;m not unique in this way. All humans know they are going to die, and that awareness has been a driving force in human behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know how other people respond to that reality. I experience a compression of time, and all of a sudden, the decades between now and my death seem utterly trivial, the end as urgent and imminent as the next five minutes. It&#39;s really unpleasant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do believe in more compassionate explanations of existence than the walking-bag-of-chemical-reactions-becomes-worm-food. The Buddhist and Taoist concepts of universal oneness have a ring of truth to me. Of course, knowing that intellectually is very different from knowing it as a foundational principle of your worldview. Despite everything, I have to admit the dark, hopeless view often seems more real to me, even if it doesn&#39;t really make sense based on my beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This awareness of the &lt;a title=&#34;The Imminence of Death&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-immanence-of-death/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;imminence of death&lt;/a&gt; has been a defining feature of my life since I was very young. It has shaped my worldview and left a strong impression on my sense of values. For a long time, I simply accepted it as a terrible curse, but &lt;strong&gt;I eventually realized that I could choose what it meant to me&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I chose to to interpret it in a way that empowers me and allows me to be happy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Imminence of Death</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-immanence-of-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-immanence-of-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1754&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Kretyen on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kretyen/2957442267/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1754&#34; title=&#34;vulture&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/vulture-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I was a little kid, I’ve had a powerful sense of the imminence of my own death. Not that I expected to die in the near future, but I was always painfully aware that one day would be my last, and eventually, I would cease to experience anything ever again. I would get panic attacks mulling over the reality of my mortality. For a 9 year-old kid, that’s pretty heavy stuff. I still sometimes catch my mind wandering over to the other side, and as a result, my whole life I’ve carried with me an urgency to make the most of my time. I don’t know whether this is common or not, but I’m just acutely aware that one day, there will be no more me.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
