<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wilderness on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/wilderness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wilderness on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/wilderness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lessons in Minimalism from Camping</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-in-minimalism-from-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-in-minimalism-from-camping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1564&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; caption=&#34;f_r_e on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/garrulus/1743162782/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1564 &#34; title=&#34;backpack&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/backpack.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was but a wee lad, my dad used to drag me kicking and screaming into the woods to partake in an activity which, due to its lack of video games, easily available chocolate, and LEGOs, I was not too keen on. That activity was camping. As a kid, I hated it. Now, it is necessary to my spiritual well-being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wilderness in Your Backyard</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-wilderness-in-your-backyard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-wilderness-in-your-backyard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1506&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Ed Townend on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/townendphotography/2365226378/sizes/l/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1506&#34; title=&#34;duck&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/duck-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning while I was practicing Karate by a forest stream (yeah, I do things like that), a duck hen floated by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stopped to watch her go and was struck by how at-home she seemed. If I blocked out the houses at the top of the hill, I could imagine we were out in the untamed wilderness. She didn&#39;t seem bothered by the fact that there were houses and cars and roads just over the hill, nor by the fact that there was a human by her stream. She was a duck, in the river, in the forest, just as things should be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Us vs. Nature: The Need for Understanding</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/usvnature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/usvnature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1427&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/100_0067.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1427&#34; title=&#34;Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/100_0067-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we had no choice but to destroy the natural world or destroy ourselves, which do you think we would pick? Let’s say that Nature has decided she has had enough. She won’t kill us outright, but she has determined to eliminate all aspects of our unsustainable lives, which means she sends her warriors to take out our property, vehicles, and infrastructure. Insects would lay waste to crops, sacrificing themselves to the pesticides, leaving organic foods untouched (assuming the crops themselves didn’t turn against us by simply refusing to produce). Rodents would flood our homes, tearing them apart from the inside, leaving us unscathed by demolishing everything manufactured, everything chemically-treated, everything unnatural. Trees and plants would suddenly demonstrate an uncanny determination to grow roots under, over, and into our buildings and roads, slowly but inexorably pulling them to pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Time Spent Outdoors</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-benefits-of-time-spent-outdoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-benefits-of-time-spent-outdoors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_954&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;222&#34; caption=&#34;Source: ©Hεαṿεṉlÿ Phøτøģɾαρhÿ on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/oooheavenlyooo/3986200282/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-954&#34; title=&#34;nature&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/nature-222x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;222&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man&#39;s heart away from nature becomes hard.  &lt;em&gt;-Standing Bear&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The natural world is all around us. Every city is merely an island of human habitation amidst a vast sea of countryside and forests. A mere hour outside of New York, one of the biggest metropolises in the world, one can find beautiful and surprisingly isolated parks and hiking trails. The hills around LA are still pretty wild (apparently coyotes are a major concern out there). Most cities have parks, little spaces where the city&#39;s fabric is cut out to reveal the nature underneath, just waiting to burst through into sunlight. These are places people can go to escape the hustle of the city for a while. There is something calming and serene about nature. I always feel complete and more balanced when surrounded by trees, and there is a lot to be said for seeking out a regular connection with the outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
