<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>optimism on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/optimism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in optimism on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/optimism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Optimism of Ancestral Health</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-optimism-of-ancestral-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-optimism-of-ancestral-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/7478267850_38dff958ff.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-2396&#34; title=&#34;Optimistic Flower&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/7478267850_38dff958ff.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;334&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I am an optimist. It does not seem too much use being anything else. - Winston Churchill&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans break down. This is an accepted truth. Eventually (all too soon), we lose function. We become decrepit, slow, weak, riddled with pain, and ugly. Instead of crystallizing our wisdom &lt;a title=&#34;Aging Gloriously&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/aging-gloriously/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;as we age&lt;/a&gt;, our minds decay. Injuries do not heal, at least not without external intervention, and the greatest triumph of humankind is the medical and pharmaceutical industries that graciously prolong our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is the mainstream view on the human body. Athletes are exceptional (they get their own label, after all), a healthy lifestyle requires a specifying adjective, &lt;a title=&#34;Fitness is Not Health&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/fitness-is-not-health/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;isn&#39;t even that healthy&lt;/a&gt;, and sickness is the norm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrast that with the view of the Ancestral Health communities. &lt;strong&gt;We believe that a human being, in its pristine state, is a force to be reckoned with, a marvel of biological engineering, ecological integrity, and spiritual subtlety.&lt;/strong&gt; We heal ourselves, not via magic or superfoods, but because healing is what a healthy body does, and we&#39;ve done everything in our power to remove the obstacles to being normal, which is to say, ridiculously, vibrantly, off-the-wall healthy. Fitness is not even a sufficient term to encompass &lt;a title=&#34;A New Understanding of Fitness and the Human Body&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/a-new-understanding-of-fitness-and-the-human-body/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;what we meant&lt;/a&gt; by movement/&lt;a title=&#34;Fitness is Play&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/fitness-is-play/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;play&lt;/a&gt;/physically expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among those in the Ancestral Health communities--Paleo, &lt;a title=&#34;Freeing the Zoo Humans: Why I Want to Become a MovNat Instructor&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/movnat-instructor/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MovNat&lt;/a&gt;, Primal, Weston A. Price, barefoot runners--there is a belief in the inherent durability and resilience of the human being. Not only can it move and survive without reliance on extensive protection, but it can actually thrive without such crutches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t speak for everyone; there is a fair amount of division, &lt;a title=&#34;Why I Left Paleo Behind, and Why I’m Returning&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/why-i-left-paleo-behind-and-why-im-returning/&#34;&gt;which led me to wander alone for a while&lt;/a&gt;. But it is safe to say there are many who see these ideas as a path to something greater than a simple advantage in the rat-race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Your Own Good Days</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-make-your-own-good-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-make-your-own-good-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1540&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Mana_benz on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mana_benz/3421649195/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1540&#34; title=&#34;Sunrise&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3421649195_fd89f134f2-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I had a terrible Wednesday. On that day, I did poorly on a workout I was confident I could do well in. I had to leave Kenpo early because I was so exhausted and beat up, and when I got home, I had a stomach ache. I started panicking about how hungry I was because I thought if I ate food so late I would not be able to sleep, and I was already exhausted. My mom and girlfriend can attest to how immature I was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day was totally different. It was sunny, for one, and I made sure to get enough sleep. Even though traffic kept me from making some appointments, I brushed it off and wore a smile all day long. I had a great time chaperoning my 7th and 8th grade cross country team, and ended the day tired but not exhausted.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abundance and Scarcity Thinking</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/abundance-and-scarcity-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/abundance-and-scarcity-thinking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; caption=&#34;Source: incurable_hippie on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3289/2596821107_15c018ec9f.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Abundance&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/2596821107_15c018ec9f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;182&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to get really sleepy around 9pm. This drives my friends crazy, since that is when they normally hang out, and it is about when I start thinking about turning in. They wonder why I&#39;m so energetically spent all the time, and my answer, ironically, is that it&#39;s because I exercise a lot. Besides that, I would explain that I have to get up at 5am a couple times a week, or 6:30 at the latest. This was an excuse I&#39;d use for myself as well, to justify my general desire to do less and sleep more. I just didn&#39;t have the energy to spare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I learned a lesson from a good friend, who actually recently joined my gym. He shows up to all my morning classes, and all the other morning classes, and &lt;em&gt;he &lt;/em&gt;is the one who is always trying to keep me up past 9pm. We were hanging out, late by my standards, and I was acting tired. When someone commented on it, I slipped into my usual explanation and my friend immediately jumped in to say that he got up at the same time every day. That shut me up pretty quick.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
