<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>peacetime on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/peacetime/</link>
    <description>Recent content in peacetime on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/peacetime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Warrior Mindset Part 3: The Warrior’s Obligation</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-warrior-mindset-part-3-the-warriors-obligation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-warrior-mindset-part-3-the-warriors-obligation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2756&#34; alt=&#34;Swords into Plowshares&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/2981939103_1cbae339fb.jpg&#34; width=&#34;407&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#34;They shall beat their swords into plowshares and their spears into pruning hooks. Nation will not take up sword against nation, nor will they train for war anymore.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;
-Isaiah 2:4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post from Shawn Rhodes, founder of Shoshin Consulting. After growing up in the mountains training in martial arts and eastern philosophy, he followed his own warrior’s calling and joined the U.S. Marines. There, he accompanied infantry Marines through two tours in Iraq, documenting their trials and victories for international news outlets like CNN and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;rhodessmaller&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/rhodessmaller-e1358734605767-150x150.jpg&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;TIME. While living and fighting alongside this tribe of modern-day warriors, he discovered the link between the warrior’s path and mastery in life. He returned to the U.S. with the passion to share a vision of what humans are capable of when they embrace their own inner warrior and return to a mindset where all paths are possible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is the third in a three-part series on The Warrior&#39;s Path. Each installment will explore the evolution of the warrior mindset. Rooted in ancient methods warriors followed for thousands of years, adopting this mindset can help anyone to regain balance, direction, and control of their health, success, and life.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/part-i-of-the-warrior-mindset-turn-problems-into-challenges/&#34;&gt;the first part&lt;/a&gt; of this series, I showed readers how past and present-day warriors learn to shift their mindsets, allowing them to transform the problems they face into challenges of responsibility for the quality of their lives. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-warrior-mindset-part-2-transform-challenges-into-opportunities/&#34;&gt;part two&lt;/a&gt;, readers stepped into the mindset of a mature and experienced warrior, a person who is confident in their abilities and no longer feels the need to prove themselves. As a result of this mindset, they see experiences in their lives as opportunities for growth as warriors and human beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the next stage in a warrior’s development?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer this, it would be helpful to examine the roles that warriors throughout history have played when they - as a culture - existed in peacetime. It makes sense that skillful warriors would eventually work themselves out of a job by either death or victory. However, the warrior tradition in human cultures has grown to allow for periods of peace. In fact, some of the most skilled warrior societies were based on achieving internal and external peace. Japanese culture, for instance, gave rise to the renowned Samurai.  The word for ‘warrior’ - &lt;i&gt;bushi  &lt;/i&gt;(武士) &lt;i&gt;– &lt;/i&gt;is comprised of symbols for ‘a spear being removed or taken away.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are very few warriors who experienced and fought in prolonged combat who would choose that lifestyle for themselves and their families. It is a paradox that to achieve peace one must confront war (internally, externally, or both), but it is true. &lt;b&gt;A warriors’ ultimate objective is to bring peace to themselves and their world&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a warrior finds a place of peace, their real challenge begins.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
