<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>martial arts on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/martial-arts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in martial arts on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/martial-arts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Guest Post: Letting Go of Distractions to Simply Do What You Love</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/guest-post-letting-go-of-distractions-to-simply-do-what-you-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/guest-post-letting-go-of-distractions-to-simply-do-what-you-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3834&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/karatekick.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;karatekick&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a reader story from Claire Higgins, a coach, yoga instructor, and martial artist who is sharing her story of returning to the core of her passion for training: Karate itself. It&#39;s a great story illustrating how easy it can be to get pulled off track from doing the things we love in the name of supporting the things we love (like the classic case of a parent working so hard they don&#39;t see their family, justifying it all by saying it&#39;s for the family&#39;s well-being, when in fact, all they want is to spend more time together).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I entered personal training to get fitter for Karate (it was CrossFit inspired). Soon, I was expected to work out several times a week on top of a demanding Karate schedule, dedicated yoga practice and teaching, and driving 4 hrs a day for my last (very stressful) job. So I built a home gym, complete with an olympic bar that I didn&#39;t use often enough as I was so exhausted. My Karate performance improved a lot but I was so tired I felt miserable at training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal trainer was fabulous but my aim was never to get better at lifting or scoring bigger numbers. It was to swing a faster punch, build more stamina, and develop more explosive speed so that I could get my 2nd dan. My Karate teacher smiled patiently at me, explaining that the heavier weights, hanging, and handstands wouldn&#39;t help there. He recommended lighter weights, faster reps, and working out THROUGH Karate training, not FOR it. But for some reason, I couldn&#39;t yet change my mindset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fight: Learn Confidence through Combative Play</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/fight-learn-confidence-through-combative-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/fight-learn-confidence-through-combative-play/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I’ve been experimenting with a new approach to fitness and movement, inspired by a teacher I greatly respect: &lt;a title=&#34;Evolve Move Play&#34; href=&#34;http://www.evolvemoveplay.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rafe Kelley of &lt;em&gt;Evolve Move Play&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;His philosophy is that humans evolved movement rehearsal (aka, play) to learn and refine the skills we needed to survive. Some of these were simply moving about the environment, but for men especially, the ultimate goal was hunting or fighting other humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Removing this context from training robs it of some of its most valuable aspects. Competition encourages growth, whether that is with a training partner or an opponent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 1.17em; line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;Respecting Your Opponent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;As a kid, I was unstoppable in contests where there were no losers: straight A&#39;s and every academic award I qualified for. But on a sports field, I preferred playing defense to scoring goals. My contribution to winning was keeping my side from losing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;When I started &lt;a title=&#34;Returning to the Dojo: The Importance of Martial Arts&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;martial arts&lt;/a&gt;, it was exciting but also uncomfortable because I had to become more assertive. After getting beaten a few times, I learned to &lt;a title=&#34;Learn to Stand Alone&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/learn-to-stand-alone/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;stand my ground&lt;/a&gt;. I didn&#39;t get violent, but I stopped inviting others to walk all over me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Play is the perfect place to teach people how to safely assert themselves without hurting others, both physically and emotionally, so that when it becomes important in life, they don’t go overboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Night That Changed My Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-night-that-changed-my-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-night-that-changed-my-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; title=&#34;Karate Kid&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/Photo1-e1325776082759.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;485&#34; /&gt;Wax On. Wax Off. - Mr Miyagi, Karate Kid&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a repost from my adventure blog, &lt;a title=&#34;A Story Worth Telling&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Story Worth Telling&lt;/a&gt;. This story seemed relevant to both sites, so I thought I&#39;d share it here too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as I love travelling, I don&#39;t necessarily think that travelling automatically leads to good stories, and ultimately, I don&#39;t want this to be a travel blog. Stories comes from overcoming all sorts of challenges. It just so happens that most of the time, travelling forces us to step outside of our comfort zone and face new challenges. Like masses of rowdy Korean children or &lt;a title=&#34;The Garbage Bag Hunt&#34; href=&#34;http://wp.me/p1Zk76-3m&#34;&gt;strangely elusive garbage bags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I have a few stories worth telling that have nothing to do with travelling. The best stories are about a turning point or a moment that changed everything. Here is one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was sitting up alone, way after everyone else had gone to sleep, watching a movie on TV that had me completely riveted. I had just gotten back to the States after spending the summer of my junior year of college in Jordan studying Arabic. In Jordan, I had started exercising after being totally sedentary for most of college, but after getting home, I had fallen off the wagon, and I was in only slightly better shape than I had been when I left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie I was watching was &lt;em&gt;The Karate Kid, &lt;/em&gt;and it set me down a course that has completely changed almost everything about me, from my body, to the way I see the world, my belief in my own judgement, and my ability to talk to girls.&lt;img title=&#34;More...&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/trans.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grow to Live: Why Constant Improvement is Necessary</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/grow-to-live-why-constant-improvement-is-necessary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/grow-to-live-why-constant-improvement-is-necessary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1778&#34; align=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Rob Young on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/rob-young/2042586449/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1778&#34; title=&#34;brucelee&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/brucelee-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously, if you always put limits on what you can do, physical or anything else, it’ll spread over into the rest of your life. It’ll spread into your work, into your morality, into your entire being. There are no limits. There are plateaus, but you must not stay there, you must go beyond them. If it kills you, it kills you. A man must constantly exceed his level. -Bruce Lee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bruce Lee was one of the greatest martial artists who ever lived. But did he think that gave him an excuse to stop improving? If the above quotation is any indication, the answer is no. Bruce Lee was always growing and always pushing his limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>True Mastery Questions Everything</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/true-mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/true-mastery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1768&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;kaibara87 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kaibara/2756361218/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1768&#34; title=&#34;sidekick&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/sidekick-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My karate instructor is an independent thinker. In a field that is basically defined by its adherence to tradition, his insistence on questioning everything is pretty gutsy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Best Use Your Teacher</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-best-use-your-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-best-use-your-teacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1400&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;286&#34; caption=&#34;velvettangerine on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/velvettangerine/3922005142/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1400&#34; title=&#34;teacher&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/teacher-286x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;286&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re trying to learn something or achieve a skill, a teacher can be a big help, since they have already done what you want to do. But there are some pitfalls to having a teacher, especially if you try to put all the responsibility for your progress on their shoulders. The best way to use a teacher is as a resource for your own learning, not as the basis or sole motivation for your goals.&lt;em&gt; (if you&#39;re short on time, you can skip to the end of the article for a summary, a policy I&#39;ll be using more regularly)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a trainer, I work with a lot of people who want to get in great shape, but don&#39;t really want to put in the effort. Sure, they do the exercises I recommend when they show up, and they push themselves pretty hard. But then I won&#39;t see them for weeks. They have lessons maybe once a month, very intermittently, and as a result, they don&#39;t move towards their goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have trainees who see me about that often, but who do make progress. The difference is in the way they view our relationship. To the first group, I am responsible for their fitness progress. &lt;strong&gt;To the second group, I am merely a resource for them as they make their own journey towards fitness&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Appreciation</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/teacher-appreciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/teacher-appreciation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1247&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Abhijit Tembhekar on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/abhijittembhekar/3345977842/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1247&#34; title=&#34;apple&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/apple-300x201.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wax on, wax off. - Mr. Miyagi, the Karate Kid (1984)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warriors are always seeking to grow and learn new things, so it makes sense that we&#39;d have a lot of teachers in our life. As the year comes to a close and I contemplate my card list, I&#39;m realizing that most of the people on it are my teachers and mentors. In the past two years, I&#39;ve acquired an unusually large number of teachers, of exceptionally good quality, and I realize that all the growth and knowledge I&#39;ve acquired is largely thanks to their efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Right Action, Right Intent</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/right-action-right-intent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/right-action-right-intent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1232&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Alice PopKorn on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alicepopkorn/1676300378/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1232&#34; title=&#34;meditation&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/meditation-300x222.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;222&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;We make sacred pact. I promise teach karate to you, you promise learn. I say, you do, no questions.&#34; -Mr. Miyagi, Karate Kid (1984)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad has been baking a lot of bread recently, experimenting with different ingredients and developing his own unique style of bread. When I read his cookbook, I found out why. Instead of simply giving him a bread recipe, the author of his book explains what each step is intended to accomplish: the various factors that determine how much flour to use, how long to let the bread rise, why you let the bread rise, and what occurs in the dough during baking. It borders on chemistry, but the result is that my dad has a much better grasp of why each step must be taken, and can make adjustments to get his desired effect. If he wants to get a crispier crust, he knows what to change and how to compensate to avoid ruining his loaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returning to the Dojo: The Importance of Martial Arts</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_713&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; caption=&#34;Source: Pieter Baert on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pietel/15322162/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-713&#34; title=&#34;karate&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/karate2.jpg?w=201&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was a child I have had this instinctive urge for expansion and growth. To me, the function and duty of a quality human being is the sincere and honest development of one&#39;s potential. - Bruce Lee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I attended my first class of American Kenpo Karate in over five years. My old teacher told me in an e-mail to bring my old Gi, which I had kept, anticipating an eventual return to the art. When I went to dig it out from a trunk under my bed, I found my old belts, one soft, well-worn, and white, and the other stiff and bright, un-faded yellow. I grabbed the white belt and headed to class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I stepped into the dance studio where the class was being held, my old instructor, taller and leaner than I remembered, looked at me without recognition. It &lt;em&gt;had &lt;/em&gt;been a long time. He was shocked at the growth he saw in me and had trouble connecting the old Khaled with the one who stood before him. And then he looked down and saw I was wearing my old white belt and asked, &#34;Where&#39;s your belt?&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Athleticism Good for Your Health?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/is-athleticism-good-for-your-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/is-athleticism-good-for-your-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; caption=&#34;Source: RobW_ on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/48/136462415_5455bf750a.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Statue of an Athlete from the Ancient Olympic Games&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/136462415_5455bf750a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent visit to my sports doctor, brought on by yet another overuse injury, prompted me to wonder if being an athlete is actually good for one&#39;s health and fitness. After all, the only reason I was at the doctor was because I am an athlete. I had injured my shoulder on a leisurely kayak tour of a small Connecticut lake. The shoulder was prone to such a pansy injury because I regularly engage in extreme fitness, aka, CrossFit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you are probably wondering, as was I, how can an athlete with shoulders capable of doing multiple strict muscle-ups be completely incapacitated by something as tame as kayaking? I honestly don&#39;t have an answer. But the experience got me to wondering about the distinctions between fitness, health, and athleticism.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
