<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>entrepreneurship on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/entrepreneurship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in entrepreneurship on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/entrepreneurship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Entrepreneurial Benefits of Healthy Living</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-entrepreneurial-benefits-of-healthy-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-entrepreneurial-benefits-of-healthy-living/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve noticed an interesting trend among ambitious businesspeople: a tendency to neglect their health.
They seem to think that they can get away with treating their bodies poorly. In the pursuit of success, they end up pulling all-nighter after all-nighter, eating cheap, quick junk food to get back to work as soon as possible, drinking tons of coffee, and spending hours hunched over the keyboard.
I&#39;ve been in those kinds of situations, and I admire their dedication, but I&#39;ve also come to learn that a weak body leads to a weak mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You Fed Up Yet?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/are-you-fed-up-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/are-you-fed-up-yet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1254&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;mdanys on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mindaugasdanys/3766009204/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1254&#34; title=&#34;screaming&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/screaming-300x252.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;252&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Consult not your fears but your hopes and your dreams. Think not about your frustrations, but about your unfulfilled potential. Concern yourself not with what you tried and failed in, but with what it is still possible for you to do.” - Pope John XXIII&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am fed up with reading about all these ways to make things happen, with making plans and taking false starts. You might recall my response to &lt;em&gt;The 4-Hour Workweek&lt;/em&gt;, in which I established a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/a-radical-idea/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;very doable plan&lt;/a&gt; that ultimately got sidetracked. All I got out of that experience was a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/choose-your-words-carefully/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;new way to see the world&lt;/a&gt; which ought to enable me to live the life I want. It freed me from accepting the normal path and got me to thinking that I can design my own life. But from what I can see I never actually went past designing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I have to wonder why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Left My Job: To Start Again</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-i-left-my-job-to-start-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-i-left-my-job-to-start-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1177&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Stevie Rocco on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stevier/4114137266/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1177&#34; title=&#34;road&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/road-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To learn something new, take the path that you took yesterday.” - John Burroughs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was my last day at the CrossFit gym where I had worked for the past year as a coach and personal trainer. I decided several weeks ago to leave the gym and pursue other opportunities on my own, and I finally took the step of leaving. It was a difficult decision, not so much because of financial reasons, but more because I loved working with the amazing athletes and dedicated individuals who came to train with us. Nevertheless, I am excited to be moving forward with my plans, even though there is a great degree of apprehension regarding my financial security. I feel that sometimes we have to pull apart everything we&#39;ve built for ourselves to build something new, or backtrack the path we&#39;ve already been down to look for new turn-offs with a better idea of where we want to go this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Stand Out</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learning-to-stand-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learning-to-stand-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Standing out&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/entrepreneur1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;412&#34; height=&#34;309&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have already talked about one aspect of the mindset associated with this post-college, recessionary jobhunt, that of having confidence in my employability. I wanted to share some recent developments in my strategies and the way I&#39;m approaching things now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
