<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>personal growth on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/personal-growth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in personal growth on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/personal-growth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My 2015 Strategy Part 3: Specific, Measurable, Actions</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-3-specific-measurable-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-3-specific-measurable-actions/</guid>
      <description>Alright! It&#39;s the end of the second week in January and we&#39;re finally done with all the ways to plan out an epic 2015. Part 1 focused on the big picture strategy. Part 2 focused on the foundational habits that need to happen to provide the time, energy, and financial resources to make it happen. Part 3 will focus on the specific actions to take.
For the underlying theory, go here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2015 Strategy Part 1: Dreams and Aspirations</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-1-dreams-and-aspirations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-1-dreams-and-aspirations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3875&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/newyear-e1420164792163.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;newyear&#34; width=&#34;698&#34; height=&#34;280&#34; /&gt;At the end of 2014, I sat down and wrote down all the things I would do if time and money were no issue. It&#39;s a really helpful exercise in figuring out what your mission in life is and where you find fulfillment, one I&#39;ll share in the Exercise section in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I thought, &#34;Okay, so I&#39;ll have a list of things that I can start thinking about doing, SOMEDAY.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Mission&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it turned out that most of the things I wanted to do didn&#39;t require time or money at all. Here&#39;s what I ended up writing, abridged:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;I would write a genre-bending science-fiction novel....I would travel to Tibet, hike the Himalayas, have tea with the Dalai Lama, and encounter a snow leopard in the wild...I would become a valuable resource for all of my friends, providing support, resources, and strategy to help them achieve their goals and dreams...I would travel back to Korea to study with my Krav Maga teacher for an extended sabbatical, and also go to Japan to study with a living ninjutsu master....I would read all the classics...I would find a way to see my friends face-to-face, or at least have more phone conversations, especially with the ones who have stuck with my for years....I would spend more time in nature, camping more than once a year....I would rekindle my love of gaming, playing more RPGs, computer strategy games, and card games with friends....I would get back into flying regularly....Start a business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I distilled those dreams down into the following list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a novel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See Tibet, meet the Dalai Lama, and see a snow leopard in the wild&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Become a martial arts master -- Krav Maga, Kenpo, Ninjutsu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend more face-to-face time with friends and become a valuable support to them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play more games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend more time in nature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start a business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of these, the one that resonated the most and seemed the most central to my idea of success and fulfillment was being there for my friends and supporting people. So that is my mission: &lt;strong&gt;to help the people in my life achieve their dreams by showing them how to be heroic in their own lives and communities.&lt;/strong&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategies for Success in 2015</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/strategies-for-success-in-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/strategies-for-success-in-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3869&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/chess-e1419979014150.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chess&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;406&#34; /&gt;I don&#39;t like resolutions. &lt;a title=&#34;Forget the Resolution! Set a Challenge!&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/forget-the-resolution-set-a-challenge/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Remember 2013&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with resolutions is that they simply set a goal. They don&#39;t provide a way to actually accomplish that goal, and often, they don&#39;t even determine if the goal is worth pursuing in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s no wonder so many people set resolutions on January 1st only to see them fall apart in a month. &lt;strong&gt;Most resolutions are chosen on a whim, or are the result of compounding pain, not compelling vision.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not that resolutions themselves are bad, it&#39;s that they are missing the essentials of good growth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A clear mission/purpose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solid strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actionable goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key aspects of the Warrior Spirit is being dedicated to a cause or a mission. Having that foundation is what gives you the ability to muster superhuman determination in whatever you choose to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But...you can&#39;t know what goals matter unless you have a clear idea of your mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the first step in creating a strategy for 2015 is to refocus on your mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Going to Make It</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/were-going-to-make-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/were-going-to-make-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1836&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;mikbaird on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mikebaird/2087879492/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1836&#34; title=&#34;clearingthewave&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/clearingthewave-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a point in every challenging experience where you go from questioning whether you&#39;ve got what it takes to survive and to feeling secure that things will be alright. You&#39;ve been staring up at an impending wave, not sure you&#39;ll get to the other side, but now you&#39;re on top, and you can see the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me living in Korea, I passed that point a few days ago. Nothing really has changed around me, but something inside me clicked. Finding my balance point is less of a daily struggle, I&#39;m starting to groove my daily paths and activities and get a sense for my surroundings. A and I have slowly transformed our apartment into a living space that reflects the kind of lives we want to live, so we are no longer fitting ourselves into someone else&#39;s living space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like I can see further and, while I may not feel that I&#39;ve accomplished that state of security just yet, I know it is attainable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Warrior Spirit</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-warrior-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-warrior-spirit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Hello World&#34;]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/20110331-213409.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/20110331-213409.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20110331-213409.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d like to inject a little more of me into my posts. After all, this blog was started by me as a sort of online journal. I was reluctant to assume that all my readers found my life all that interesting, but I thought I&#39;d just write about it. I am a storyteller, after all, not just an essayist. Since the story I know best is my own, I wanted to tell that story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the way, I got swept up by all these other great blogs that also tell stories, but which also provide lots of useful information besides. Somehow, the information stuck out more than the stories, and I focused on that. As a result, I feel that Warrior Spirit has kind of drifted from being personal to trying too hard to be useful. The result I think has been less connection with my readers. The blog has grown and grown, and for that I&#39;m thankful, but I feel a little like I&#39;ve sold out (except without the monetary rewards).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&#39;m going to try to tell more of my stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Left My Job: To Start Again</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-i-left-my-job-to-start-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-i-left-my-job-to-start-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1177&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Stevie Rocco on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stevier/4114137266/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1177&#34; title=&#34;road&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/road-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To learn something new, take the path that you took yesterday.” - John Burroughs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was my last day at the CrossFit gym where I had worked for the past year as a coach and personal trainer. I decided several weeks ago to leave the gym and pursue other opportunities on my own, and I finally took the step of leaving. It was a difficult decision, not so much because of financial reasons, but more because I loved working with the amazing athletes and dedicated individuals who came to train with us. Nevertheless, I am excited to be moving forward with my plans, even though there is a great degree of apprehension regarding my financial security. I feel that sometimes we have to pull apart everything we&#39;ve built for ourselves to build something new, or backtrack the path we&#39;ve already been down to look for new turn-offs with a better idea of where we want to go this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Story</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/KhaledPortrait.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1068&#34; title=&#34;KhaledPortrait&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/KhaledPortrait-300x224.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;224&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“Today you are You, that is truer than true. There is no one alive who is Youer than You.” - Dr. Seuss&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the responses I got from all of you on that &lt;a href=&#34;http://polldaddy.com/s/444345CCC43313A2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;survey &lt;/a&gt;I sent out, most of the interest in what I write comes from knowing me. So I thought I&#39;d write out my story, so those of you who didn&#39;t know me before the blog can understand where I&#39;m coming from, where I get my stories and interpretations, and why I care so much about standing up to mediocrity and forging my own destiny.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If Failure is Not An Option, You Won&#39;t Fail</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/if-failure-is-not-an-option-you-wont-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/if-failure-is-not-an-option-you-wont-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1030&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;wolfsavard on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wolfsavard/4716421032/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1030&#34; title=&#34;nets&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/nets-300x200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;Do or do not. There is no try.&#34; - &lt;em&gt;Yoda,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Return of the Jedi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently learned a back handspring, and a front flip, among some other more complex gymnastics moves. Every time I want to try one without my coach to spot me, he considers whether I&#39;m ready, nods and says, &#34;Alright, give it a shot. The chance of seriously injuring yourself is probably less than 60/40.&#34; He is joking, sort of, but it is true that many of the stunts I attempt are actually quite dangerous. And that is why I don&#39;t mess up. &lt;strong&gt;Without safety nets, I can&#39;t afford to fail.&lt;/strong&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
