<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dreams on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/dreams/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dreams on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/dreams/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Are you a Doer, or a Dreamer?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/are-you-a-doer-or-a-dreamer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/are-you-a-doer-or-a-dreamer/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across this article on Cracked (warning, it is quite inflammatory and contains a lot of strong language, as well as some offensive videos). As the name implies, it is a criticism of people&#39;s unwillingness to admit the reality of how the world works. It&#39;s targeted at my generation: the Millennials, which has been characterized by a sense of entitlement, aloofness, and a rejection of traditional notions of consumption and wealth (because we&#39;re poor, we&#39;ve made wealth into a sin).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Enough for You?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/what-is-enough-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/what-is-enough-for-you/</guid>
      <description>If you could boil your day down to one or two things, what would they be?
Yesterday, Anna and I met a father and husband in Boulder on a very unfortunate errand: bailing his 22-year-old son out of jail. He shared all sorts of stories about his life, his long marriage, and his career. He had spent time as a developer for schools, then as a contractor, but his real passion, he said, was restoring antique furniture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Other Side of the Register</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-other-side-of-the-register/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-other-side-of-the-register/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;True compassion is true understanding. - Attributed to the Buddha&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My worst nightmare is standing behind the checkout counter at the local supermarket. He has been working there every day for 17 years, 8-10 hours. He goes to bed knowing that, upon waking, all he has to look forward to is another day, another week, another month, another year of standing at the same counter, scanning other peoples&#39; stuff, much of it stuff he can&#39;t afford. It&#39;s not that he&#39;s come to enjoy the job, but he has become numb to the quiet panic that pervades every one of his days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m describing an archetype, not an actual person, the life I don&#39;t want to lead, but a life I know many people do live. It is a life I cannot comprehend and one I&#39;m terrified of finding myself in. Knowing others who live it makes me uneasy because of the assumptions I have about human potential. I don&#39;t know anyone who aspires to being a cashier, and the mindset that can be happy and accept it is one I simply don&#39;t understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make a Dream Come True</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-make-a-dream-come-true/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-make-a-dream-come-true/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/?attachment_id=2693&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2693&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter  wp-image-2693&#34; alt=&#34;Achieving Goals Feels Good&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/66728_700953401774_1869754869_n1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;592&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn&#39;t very often that we get to cross out a big goal in our lives, but that is exactly what I did at the end of November. I&#39;d been dreaming of &lt;a title=&#34;Freeing the Zoo Humans: Why I Want to Become a MovNat Instructor&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/movnat-instructor/&#34;&gt;becoming a MovNat trainer&lt;/a&gt; since I heard about the method in 2009. Around April of last year, when MovNat announced they were offering trainer certifications, I finally decided to make this dream a reality. I couldn&#39;t afford the certification with what I was making as an ESL teacher; I would have to raise the money by &lt;a title=&#34;Lessons Learned on Finishing My First Book&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/lessons-learned-on-finishing-my-first-book/&#34;&gt;writing and promoting&lt;/a&gt; an eBook, which I published in September of 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By November of 2012, I had raised enough from donations for the eBook (as well as a few t-shirt sales) to sign up for my MovNat trainer certification in March 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a long road to get there, but the most valuable thing I got out of the whole experience won&#39;t be the MCT certification itself. &lt;strong&gt;Instead, it is the confidence that I can affect my life without permission from anyone else&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving Up On My Dream of Being a Soldier</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/giving-up-on-my-dream-of-being-a-soldier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/giving-up-on-my-dream-of-being-a-soldier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1760&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;The U.S. Army on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/soldiersmediacenter/478415299/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1760&#34; title=&#34;soldier&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/soldier-300x186.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;186&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always had an interest in joining the military. I wanted to be a jet fighter pilot, or a special forces operative. For the first time in my life, I have no reason to be afraid of the physical demands of the job; I routinely best soldiers in fitness competitions, and I could pass the special forces entrance exams. I’m confident enough in myself to withstand the rigors of training, and I feel more certain than ever that I could benefit from the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I have had to let go of that dream as I’ve come to understand the realities of what a soldier does. In order to live out my dream, I would have to compromise on a lot of things that are really important to me. This isn’t because of the nature of the military generally, but rather the way the system is set up currently. I could get behind fighting against Hitler in World War II, but I have never been very good at investing myself in other peoples’ agendas if I don’t believe in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living on Principle</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/living-on-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/living-on-principle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1357&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;ground.zero on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/groundzero/96516632/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1357&#34; title=&#34;determination&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/determination-300x171.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;171&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have habits outside the norm, people look at you funny, even when they admire what you do. I avoid sugar at all costs. Everyone I know thinks this is a good idea in terms of nutrition and health, something they&#39;d hypothetically like to do, but they don&#39;t really envision themselves as able to give up sugar. It is just too far outside of the normal American dietary experience. My friends ask wistfully how they can lose weight or have my energy levels. I tell them, don&#39;t eat sugar, and they respond with, &#34;I wish I could do that, but I just couldn&#39;t give up sugar. I love it too much. How can you live without eating sugar?&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patience</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/patience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1226&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;WasabiDoobie on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wasabidoobie/2448490111/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1226&#34; title=&#34;patience&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/patience-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Genius is only a greater aptitude for patience.” - George-Louis Leclerc de Buffon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have had a lot of waiting to do as my plans start to gain momentum. There are long periods during which nothing seems to bear any fruit. Farm to Table went silent for a long time, with almost no new comments or community engagement, leading me to get very discouraged. I was lacking motivation in my workouts and didn&#39;t really feel like I was making any progress. My blog seemed to be wallowing in obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, all of sudden things started to move very quickly, and I realized that it was the quiet times when things were starting to move towards a tipping point. I am getting a lot of people reaching out to connect over Farm to Table, there is a new energy in my training, and I am making all sorts of friends while reconnecting with old ones. It&#39;s almost more than I can handle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
