<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>value-driven living on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/value-driven-living/</link>
    <description>Recent content in value-driven living on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/value-driven-living/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Priorities: Matching Reality to Your Values</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/priorities-matching-reality-to-your-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/priorities-matching-reality-to-your-values/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/213085702_8d5e812d9d.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2958&#34; alt=&#34;New Changed Priorities Ahead&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/213085702_8d5e812d9d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Upon returning from my trip to Utah, I&#39;ve found myself caught in a whirlwind of activity, trying to catch up with all sorts of projects. This hasn&#39;t given me time to act on the important things that are normally part of my routine, nor the amazing insights I gained in the desert of the Canyonlands. That&#39;s one reason this post is late. It is a pattern I&#39;ve noticed in myself before, when I lived in Korea and was trying to establish a match between the life and wanted and the life I ended up living.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every now and then, it&#39;s good to take stock of how closely the life you&#39;re actually living matches the life you want to be living. Are the things that are important to you getting their due, or are they just sitting on the back burner, day after day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I find that stress tends to lead me to give up on my routines and plans with the excuse of surviving or making do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s like that saying about putting your head down and plowing through. You don&#39;t know (or don&#39;t want to know) where you&#39;re going, you just need to get through whatever&#39;s in front you, as fast as possible, without regard to finesse or tact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But the problem with doing that is that sometimes you move forward only to look up to find yourself somewhere you didn&#39;t mean to go&lt;/strong&gt;. Then you&#39;ve got to go back or find another way. You&#39;ve wasted effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or worse, because you haven&#39;t taken the time to plot your course, you end up barreling into another crisis situation, and the only way to deal with that is to do the same thing that got you there in the first place. Then, you become a slave to events, moving in the direction set by each crisis. At first, you are just telling yourself, &#34;I just need to get through this week, then everything will be back on track.&#34; But when that week passes, you haven&#39;t taken the time to set your course, and it becomes another week or &#39;getting through,&#39; then another, then another, until you find yourself lost.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
