<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ego on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/ego/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ego on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/ego/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>No Egos Beyond This Point</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/no-egos-beyond-this-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/no-egos-beyond-this-point/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;If your practice is good, you may become proud of it. What you do is good, but something more is added to it. Pride is extra. Right effort is to get rid of something extra. - Shunryu Suzuki&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/humbledog.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2843&#34; alt=&#34;SONY DSC&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/humbledog.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;334&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The theme of this year is definitely &lt;a title=&#34;Empower Yourself Through Humility&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/empower-yourself-through-humility/&#34;&gt;humility&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have this annoying habit of questioning authority in all its forms, even when it&#39;s authority I normally support, i.e., my MovNat trainers at my &lt;a title=&#34;Playing in the Woods, Mountain Lions, and Braised Chicken&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/playing-in-the-woods-mountain-lions-and-braised-chicken/&#34;&gt;recent certification&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop was well run and everyone got a lot out of it, but at one point, I found something to pick on and made a big deal out of nothing. I realize, looking back, that I had primed myself for a confrontation by the attitude I brought in to the certification, which was one of proving myself rather than learning something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After it all went down, I was pretty upset, not so much with the trainers, who handled it very professionally, but with myself for being bothered and for feeling the need to do or say anything. After all, it wasn&#39;t &lt;em&gt;my &lt;/em&gt;workshop, nor was it my responsibility. I spent a troubled evening losing sleep and &lt;strong&gt;trying to figure out what it was inside me that was causing me so much anxiety&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I eventually figured out it was the desire to prove myself rather than let go and simply learn. I reached out to my sister for advice, and she wisely suggested &lt;strong&gt;I make a distinction between observation (learning) and judging (reacting)&lt;/strong&gt;. So, the next morning, after a sincere and humbling apology (damage control), I made a point of simply observing and withholding judgement for the remaining three days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Needless to say, I learned a lot more that way than with my original approach.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
