<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>perceptions on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/perceptions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in perceptions on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/perceptions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking your productive potential; reshape your standards to fit your goals</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/unlocking-you-productive-potential-reshape-your-standards-to-fit-your-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/unlocking-you-productive-potential-reshape-your-standards-to-fit-your-goals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1740&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;190&#34; caption=&#34;seier+seier on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/seier/2164161632/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1740&#34; title=&#34;biggoals&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/biggoals-190x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;190&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post from Eric Fulwiler, an Account Executive at VaynerMedia, am NYC digital agency specializing in social. He blogs at &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ericfulwiler.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog.ericfulwiler.com&lt;/a&gt;, and you can find him on Twitter @EFulwiler.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do we find certain  activities easier than others? It&#39;s so easy for us to sit down and watch a 3-hour baseball game (at least, for some of us), but it&#39;s so hard for us to sit down for 3 hours and write a Powerpoint presentation. Part of it is certainly because baseball is more entertaining than Powerpoint (again, for some of us), but the bigger issue here is the standards and expectations that we have created for ourselves. We have standards embedded within our mentality that dictate the ease and attractiveness of certain activities. We have chosen to believe that baseball is easier than Powerpoint. And these choices have resulted in standards that frequently present obstacles to our personal or professional productivity. But for those of us who accept that we can control these standards, we can realign them to further our goals, and significantly increase our productivity and potential.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
