<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bliss on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/bliss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bliss on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/bliss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do You Trade Happiness to Live &#39;Right?&#39;: Claim Your Light</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/do-you-trade-happiness-to-live-right-claim-your-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/do-you-trade-happiness-to-live-right-claim-your-light/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Our deepest fear is not that we are inadequate. Our deepest fear is that we are powerful beyond measure. It is our light, not our darkness that most frightens us. We ask ourselves, Who am I to be brilliant, gorgeous, talented, and fabulous? Actually, who are you &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; to be? You are a child of God. Your playing small does not serve the world. There is nothing enlightened about shrinking so that other people will not feel insecure around you. We are all meant to shine, as children do. We were born to make manifest the glory of God that is within us. It is not just in some of us; it is in everyone and as we let our own light shine, we unconsciously give others permission to do the same. As we are liberated from our own fear, our presence automatically liberates others. - Marianne Williamson&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I moved to Boulder was the belief that it would be a good place to live car-free, to find affordable and plentiful local food, to swear off modern, wasteful comforts (like shoes), and to pursue minimalism by selling my iPad and other non-essentials. Basically, to live the way I believed was Right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turned out to be much harder that I thought. I never found the spiritual and emotional fulfillment promised. Instead, I was limited in my activities because I could only go so far without a car, I was always hungry because of my insistence on absurdly high food quality, and I was dirty and ratty because my clothes were so worn out and overused. I was a burden to my friends, always leaning on them to drive me places I couldn&#39;t bike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I was doing the right thing, and that if I held on long enough, things would start to work out (if you&#39;ve read my book, you know I did this with eating Paleo, and CrossFit). When they never did, I got really frustrated and started to feel bitterness and resentment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up cleaving so strongly to the way I believed I &#39;should&#39; be that I completely lost sight of what actually made me happy and ended up undermining my self-esteem and sanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I knew a lot of people who weren&#39;t terribly worried about doing things right. They simply went after the things that made them feel good, made them happy, or seemed interesting. Their standard was, &#34;Does this make me happy?&#34; and not, &#34;Is this the right way?&#34; I put so much effort into figuring out the right way and following it, but I was lost and floundering. &lt;strong&gt;It didn&#39;t seem fair that others could be so seemingly lax in their morals but have the peace-of-mind and sense of purpose that I lacked.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of those people who was living the dream while happily skipping through life in time with her own drummer, was my little sister.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pursue Your Bliss with Integrity</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/pursue-your-bliss-with-integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/pursue-your-bliss-with-integrity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is it that makes it so hard for us to pursue our dreams? Why is it so frustrating to pull together all the elements of our lives in order to move in the direction we so fervently want to go?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Follow Your Bliss - Joseph Campbell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Campbell compared the internal psychological journey of our lives with classic myths that have accompanied humans throughout history: from Genesis to Robin Hood, Coyote to Quetzalcoatl, &lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, the stories that move us all share common themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campbell believed that these themes were reflections of the stages of human development: if we have the &lt;a title=&#34;5 Ways to Boost Your Courage Right Now!&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/5-ways-to-boost-your-courage-right-now/&#34;&gt;courage&lt;/a&gt; to face up to our psychic dragons and to descend into the dark caves and underworlds of our fears and insecurities, we can face the challenges that allow us to become true heroes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we lack that courage, then we stagnate, never living up to our potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;This begs the question of what directs our growth. Campbell&#39;s answer would be that it is our dreams, aspirations, and passions, the thing that we were put on this earth to do, that drive us. Follow your bliss unerringly and with commitment, and you will surely become the hero of your myth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the myths, the greatest treasures are kept in the darkest caves, guarded by the most fearsome monsters. &lt;strong&gt;Likewise, attaining our bliss requires us to &lt;a title=&#34;Insecurity, the Root of All Evil&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/insecurity-the-root-of-all-evil/&#34;&gt;face our most ingrained fears&lt;/a&gt; and negative habits&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Find Your Bliss: 3 Questions to Ask Yourself</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-find-your-bliss-3-questions-to-ask-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-find-your-bliss-3-questions-to-ask-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_3068&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/WDS2013.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-3068&#34; alt=&#34;Happy dancers at the closing party for WDS21013&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/WDS2013-300x199.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Happy dancers at the closing party for WDS21013[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s all well and good to tell people to follow their bliss, but how do you find the thing in the first place? If you haven&#39;t been following it, it probably wandered off years ago and is lost in someone&#39;s backyard howling all alone because you didn&#39;t follow it on the epic exploration of the neighborhood that would have led you to meet that cute neighbor you&#39;d fall in love with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, anyway, clearly you need to find it so you can follow it on to other adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the last weekend at the World Domination Summit, organized by Chris Guillebeau of &lt;a title=&#34;The Art of Non-Conformity&#34; href=&#34;http://chrisguillebeau.com/3x5/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Art of Non-Conformity&lt;/a&gt;, where I was inundated by awesomely inspiring speakers and ideas. As the name implies, the World Domination Summit is a gathering of people intent of making a big impact on the world by living fearlessly and pursuing their remarkable dreams in a conventional world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one of the talks was specifically about how to find your passion or purpose, but several of the speakers touched on the topic. Three ideas in particular seemed especially actionable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forget the Resolution! Set a Challenge!</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/forget-the-resolution-set-a-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/forget-the-resolution-set-a-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/forget-the-resolution-set-a-challenge/418636_674776395704_416458635_n1/&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2646&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wp-image-2646 aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;418636_674776395704_416458635_n(1)&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/418636_674776395704_416458635_n1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;581&#34; height=&#34;389&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Resolutions are boring. I resolve to behave better this year, blah, blah, blah... This is a whole new &lt;em&gt;YEAR &lt;/em&gt;we&#39;re talking about, not just the turn of an hourglass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s so great about a resolution anyway? Sure, it&#39;s an opportunity to start anew, to take a stab at &lt;a title=&#34;You’re Not Broken, So You Can’t “Fix” Yourself&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/youre-not-broken-so-you-cant-fix-yourself/&#34;&gt;fixing something that you think is broken&lt;/a&gt; about yourself, to be better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why do we want to be better? Is it just to feel good about ourselves? Or are we &lt;a title=&#34;You Can’t Afford to be Attached to Your Health, So Make it About Others&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/you-cant-afford-to-be-attached-to-your-health-so-make-it-about-others/&#34;&gt;trying to accomplish something greater&lt;/a&gt; in our lives than self-satisfaction?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you want to lose weight, or gain muscle, or workout more, or write more, or become financially independent, or eat more local food, or get a promotion, or learn a new language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All attainable goals, great things for anyone to do. Which is fine. If you are aiming for mediocrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we need - what &lt;em&gt;you &lt;/em&gt;need - is something epic, something grand, something game-changing, something that matters to you specifically, something for which you in particular were destined.&lt;/strong&gt; Your bliss, to use the terminology of Joseph Campbell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you follow your bliss... doors will open where you would not have thought there would be doors; and where there wouldn&#39;t be a door for anyone else. - Joseph Campbell&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You don&#39;t need another resolution. You need a challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Does it Mean to &#34;Be Yourself?&#34;</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1936&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;MSVG on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/msvg/5084966203/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1936&#34; title=&#34;Look at Yourself&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5084966203_de436b21b5-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are content to be simply yourself and don&#39;t compare or compete, everyone will respect you. -Lao Tsu&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know why it is so hard to be myself, but it seems to be the biggest challenge I have faced in life. From what I read of others’ journeys, it is a universal struggle. Not only is it difficult, it is fraught with dead ends, false trails, and misleading half-truths. For many of us, we don’t even realize we are not being ourselves. We think we are acting spontaneously and expressing a creative individuality, but in fact we are mimicking some idea of individuality or are simply repeating old habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does it mean to ‘be yourself?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think ‘being yourself’ is the kind of thing you can talk about directly. It is the subject of Buddhist meditation, the mystic’s search for communion with the divine, and an entire literature of spiritual, scientific, and cultural studies. So, to explain what I think it means to ‘be yourself’ I will resort to an example.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
