<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nourishment on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/nourishment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nourishment on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/nourishment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Discovering a New Passion in Cooking</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/discovering-a-new-passion-in-cooking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/discovering-a-new-passion-in-cooking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2882&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;574&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSC_1430.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-2882  &#34; alt=&#34;Oh yes, I made that. More importantly, I can do it again&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/DSC_1430-1024x685.jpg&#34; width=&#34;574&#34; height=&#34;383&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Oh yes, I made that. More importantly, I can do it again[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve never considered myself a culinary person. I was never very good at picking up my mom&#39;s recipes as a kid, and I needed a cookbook and a measuring spoon to prepare grilled cheese (I&#39;m not exaggerating at all).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when I became more insistent on healthy eating in college, I had to learn basic cooking technique; if you insist on whole foods, you need to be able to prepare them yourself. This resulted in a lot of stir-fries at first. The only animal I was comfortable handling was fish. I slowly added a simple recipe and a few techniques to my repertoire (mostly via hurried phone calls to my mom, who demonstrated an amazing ability to rescue even my most ill-conceived cooking adventures).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned to cook red meat, I learned to braise, I learned to roast and broil and sauté. I learned knife technique and how to poach an egg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And then, somewhere along the line, I stopped looking up recipes&lt;/strong&gt;. Instead, I would imagine what I wanted to eat and mentally map out the steps to get there, complete with sequence of ingredients, temperature, cook times, heating techniques, and spices. I had done enough trial and error (the errors stuck the most) that I had created a cooking toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t realize I had crossed into amateur chefdom until recently, when I was able to have an informed conversation with a French-trained chef about flavor combinations and methods of preparation and ingredient quality. I think that may have been &lt;a title=&#34;Lessons Learned About Landing a Job in Boulder&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/lessons-learned-about-landing-a-job-in-boulder/&#34;&gt;why he hired me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I realized the recipes I was coming up with were getting fairly complex. Whereas before I might have settled on broiling a fish fillet and some chopped vegetables, now I was browning spiced chicken, caramelizing brussel sprouts, braising them for an hour in ale, and then crisping them under the broiler for the last 10 minutes, just because it seemed like it would be tasty that way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
