<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>yoga on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/yoga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in yoga on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/yoga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Be Gentle, Be Powerful</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/be-gentle-be-powerful/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/be-gentle-be-powerful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1884&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Espara on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/esparta/2214658212/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1884&#34; title=&#34;Sleeping Tiger&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/2214658212_9d9183226f-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I have never taken any exercise except sleeping and resting.” - Mark Twain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intensity in exercise is good. Most of us aren’t getting enough of it. Instead we settle for lifting weights we can handle comfortably and running at speeds that just break a sweat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then there are those of us who do nothing but high intensity exercise. We’re CrossFitters and Traceurs, MMA fighters and sprinters. We only have one speed, and that’s insane! We are not know for our gentleness, with others or ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to be one of those. Until I got injured, which happened a lot actually. When you’re body is constantly working near its limits, there is not much time for healing or recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My most recent injury was a pulled muscle in my hip that immobilized my lower back. I couldn’t even bend over to tie my shoes. I had zero flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of options and fed up with being in pain all the time, I started practicing yoga to regain my flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started it only as a therapeutic form of exercise, but I noticed that I felt much better on days I started with some yoga than those without. Clearly yoga was addressing some aspect of my physical training I’d been neglecting with all the CrossFit and gymnastics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intense stretching didn&#39;t help at all. The painful deep tissue massage didn&#39;t help, either. But slow, comfortable, gentle yoga slowly untied my back and improved my flexibility in other areas as well. When I finally started being gentle and kind to my body, it stopped punishing me with pain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
