<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>zen habits on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/zen-habits/</link>
    <description>Recent content in zen habits on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/zen-habits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zen Habits Handbook for Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/zen-habits-handbook-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/zen-habits-handbook-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_950&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: kristofabrath on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kristofabrath/3206231510/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-950&#34; title=&#34;zen&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/zen-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smile, breathe, and go slowly &lt;em&gt;- Thich Nhat Hanh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when I was in college, drowning under the immense workload and the complexities of balancing my social life, personal life, and scholastic commitments, I stumbled upon a blog that saved my academic standing as well as my sanity. The blog is called Zen Habits, and it was a godsend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Minimalist Warrior</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-minimalist-warrior/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-minimalist-warrior/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/lotus.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-523&#34; title=&#34;lotus&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/lotus.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;198&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I&#39;ve been playing God of War II (a video game, for the un-initiated). In this game, the main character, Kratos, begins the game as the recently appointed god of war, replacing Ares. He has all sorts of powers, wears nifty armor, and has a lot going on in his life. But he is not satisfied. Then, Zeus betrays him. There is a scene of Kratos&#39; armor falling apart, leaving him with nothing but a loincloth, some boots, and his weapons, which is the state he goes through most of the game in. He has a single purpose at that point: to enact vengeance on Zeus. Kratos is a relatively small guy, as far as Greek heroes go - in a face off with Theseus, the Thebian towers over Kratos. Most of Kratos&#39; enemies are decked out in fancy armor, carry ridiculous weapons (usually turned on them by the plucky Spartan), and have access to all sorts of assistance and special powers. Kratos is a minimalist. He powers his way through his environment, using his physical strength and his mental cunning, two simple blades, and little else.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
