<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>courage on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/courage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in courage on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/courage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Fear: Part 2: Tactics to Quell Fear</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-nature-of-fear-part-2-tactics-to-quell-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-nature-of-fear-part-2-tactics-to-quell-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;I must not fear.&lt;br /&gt;
Fear is the mind-killer.&lt;br /&gt;
Fear is the little-death that brings total obliteration.&lt;br /&gt;
I will face my fear.&lt;br /&gt;
I will permit it to pass over me and through me.&lt;br /&gt;
And when it has gone past I will turn the inner eye to see its path.&lt;br /&gt;
Where the fear has gone there will be nothing.&lt;br /&gt;
Only I will remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt;, Frank Herbert&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;The Nature of Fear: Part 1, Fear is a Choice&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-nature-of-fear-part-1-fear-is-a-choice/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click here to read part 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my first night alone in the woods, I had learned that fear is a choice. It came from the fact that I often saw myself as a victim, someone who was generally vulnerable to others&#39; whims and the world&#39;s catastrophes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be thinking, &#34;Of course you were vulnerable! You were alone, asleep, in the forest! If something had happened, there would have been no way to get help.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, I&#39;m much more vulnerable on a highway, where the chance of injury in a way I cannot respond to is much higher. I &lt;em&gt;perceived&lt;/em&gt; myself as vulnerable in the woods, but it&#39;s not a fact of the situation. A tiger doesn&#39;t feel threatened alone in a forest. It is the thing that makes others feel threatened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, the first step to overcoming the fear of sleeping alone in the woods was realizing that my fear was the result of how I chose to view myself and the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That enabled me to question it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step, and the project for the second night, was actually learning to quell fear. As the sun set for the second time on my trip, I wasn&#39;t any less afraid than I had been the night before, but I was more confident in my ability to handle the anxiety that might come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until I saw the signs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the privy were three scrawled notes, memorials to those who had passed away in the last year. Those three letters--R.I.P.--have a lot of power to set an overactive imagination in a particular direction. I imagined that my campsite was the lurking place of a serial killer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much for my confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as I lay in my tent that night, I came up with a few strategies to deal with the new terror.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Fear: Part 1, Fear is a Choice</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-nature-of-fear-part-1-fear-is-a-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-nature-of-fear-part-1-fear-is-a-choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I stepped onto the trail, I gave one last look back at my car, parked by itself in a clearing off the road in upstate Connecticut. I could turn back now. I didn&#39;t have to go out there into the woods. Two hours of driving and I&#39;d been back in my house, surrounded by people and light switches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I turned and headed into the forest. The sun was high, but it would soon begin its long descent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A History of Fear&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear has been a constant companion in my life. When I was very young, I discovered that the night is full of terror. There were ghosts in my closet, monsters under my bed, aliens in the air ducts, and unnameable things down the stairs. I had complex and confusing bedtime rituals to deal with all these dangers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I realized that I would one day die, and my nights took on a whole new form of terror. Sleep seemed like one step away from the eternal unconsciousness of death. I suffered panic attacks thinking about it, and the fear of being alone at night when one of these attacks happened was enough to keep me from sleeping well most of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there were the night terrors, waking dreams of unseeable presences in my room and the urgent need to jump up, despite being apparently paralyzed (psychologists speculate that this form of nightmare is the origin of alien abduction and possession experiences. I&#39;m inclined to agree).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these things got worse in the wilderness. Even sleeping next to my father in a tent, I would lie awake and paralyzed with fear, waiting for anything from a bear to the reanimated corpse of the Camel Woman to attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These fears didn&#39;t subside much as I got older. Even as recently as a few months ago, after an episode of &lt;em&gt;Doctor Who&lt;/em&gt;, I woke up in my bed with dead certainty that there was a stone angel lurking in the living room...only to find myself totally paralyzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything and everything my mind could use to scare itself, it has hoarded and nurtured, bringing to life at the most sinister moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Setting a New Path&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Each time we face our fear, we gain strength, courage, and confidence in the doing.” - Anon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was becoming a serious problem, affecting my sleep and my self-confidence; &lt;strong&gt;it&#39;s very hard to imagine changing the world when you are afraid of the dark&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So I decided to put myself to the test: I would spend three nights alone in the woods.&lt;/strong&gt; I would either learn to control my mind, to see the world for what it is rather than a stage for my personal terror, or I would spend three miserable nights in a near-panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess the second option wasn&#39;t really a great alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asking for Help</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/asking-for-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/asking-for-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One trap that we can fall into is the belief that being excellent means we must never ask for help. After all, if we are heroic, legendary human beings, then we shouldn&#39;t need any help, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even the heroes of myth and legend needed help. In fact, in many cases it was their ability to bring people to their cause that allowed them to be successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why are we so reluctant to ask for help? Here are some possible reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways to Boost Your Courage Right Now!</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/5-ways-to-boost-your-courage-right-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/5-ways-to-boost-your-courage-right-now/</guid>
      <description>Courage is a valuable commodity. Under various guises--moxie, confidence, spunk, gusto--you can turn a shaky idea into a winning proposition, or go from a wallflower to the life of the party. We crave just the FEELING of courage, even if it&#39;s only temporary and hollow, and have created a societal ritual around &#39;liquid courage&#39; and partying to chase that feeling.
Obviously, it&#39;s better to cultivate a more lasting kind of courage, but sometimes you just need a quick boost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practicing Courage Through Movement</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/practicing-courage-throught-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/practicing-courage-throught-movement/</guid>
      <description>Do one thing everyday that scares you. - Eleanor Roosevelt
 After practicing movement and martial arts for so long, I sometimes lose track of the reasons I started in the first place. Lately, I&#39;ve been on a bit of a hiatus, but I was able to get some training time in last weekend. The combination of time off plus the intensity of training reminded me of why I do this in the first place, and, more importantly, why I want to do this every single day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End of Adventure</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-end-of-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-end-of-adventure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1931&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;ButterflySha in Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/butterflysha/140523563/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1931&#34; title=&#34;stay in line&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/stay-in-line-300x121.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;121&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you wait to do everything until you&#39;re sure it&#39;s right, you&#39;ll probably never do much of anything.” -Win Borden&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To really experience life, you&#39;re going to have to get out of line first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I studied Arabic in Jordan, I initially applied to go through a program. It was quite a prestigious program, and it promised all sorts of  exciting (pre-arranged) adventures in addition to a language study at the University of Jordan. The brochure also stressed how safe it was and how secure the travelling student would be, even as they learned to step outside their comfort zone on a study abroad program. I had my misgivings, but when I got a phone call letting me know I was accepted, I was very excited...until the lady got to the part about the cost of the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having lived in the Middle East, I knew that the costs were inflated. I asked if I could just stay with my family there and spare them the living expenses, but the woman (quickly getting annoyed with me for daring to suggest I might have a better experience through other channels) explained that it would detract from the experience. This didn&#39;t answer my question, and she ended the conversation by saying that if I didn&#39;t pay soon, they would give the spot to someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never followed up with that group. I simply signed up for the University of Jordan&#39;s Arabic program directly. Of course, there were some bumps in the road because of that, but when I showed up with twenty or so other students who hadn&#39;t finalized their registrations, I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; had to &#34;step out of my comfort zone&#34; to speak for all of them and cow the program director into letting us all join the program a day late. That would never have happened if I&#39;d went with the &#39;secure&#39; program.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
