<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>millennials on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/millennials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in millennials on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/millennials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Millennial Manifesto: The Responsibility to be Great</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-millennial-manifesto-the-passion-of-a-new-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-millennial-manifesto-the-passion-of-a-new-generation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are the Millennials. Constantly connected, over-educated, and fired with passion, we have been accused of laziness, entitlement, and narcissism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we are to inherit the world, a world that is more and more defined by change: entire business platforms rise and fall in the course of a few months. I have no doubt that history repeats itself, but with over 7 billion people, nations with the power to manufacture unfathomable quantities of goods, and an information network that rivals the human brain, I feel justified in saying &lt;strong&gt;the world we inherit will be unique in human history&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Brave New World&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all the negative adjectives thrown our way, one thing I have seen among my peers is a truly inspiring degree of passion, a desire to remake the world, to set their own rules and live by their own principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a powerful vision of a world far different than the one we were born into. Many of us have become distrustful of established power structures. We have seen the green revolution co-opted by corporate interests. Growing up in a globalized world has revealed to us that we cannot blindly pursue power without thought for the repercussions on the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything is vulnerable to questioning now&lt;/strong&gt;, and so many of my friends are unsatisfied with what life has given them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And lets be honest, life hasn&#39;t give them much. Youth unemployment in the US ranges from 20%-30% (depending on the study and the criteria), an abysmally high number. We are underemployed, not unemployable. We came of age into a world that didn&#39;t have a place for us, that couldn&#39;t utilize us, that expects us to wait idly on the sidelines and be grateful for placeholders like internships and volunteerism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That, right there, that&#39;s the sense of entitlement we&#39;re accused of. But shall we instead deign to accept meager returns? &lt;strong&gt;I think it&#39;s better to constantly be chafing at the bit, &lt;a title=&#34;Grow to Live: Why Constant Improvement is Necessary&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/grow-to-live-why-constant-improvement-is-necessary/&#34;&gt;striving for more&lt;/a&gt; and the chance to make an impact.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a way, Warrior Spirit is a blog for millennials: it admits a sense of higher purpose, the right to excellence, and even the &lt;a title=&#34;Are You in the 1%? You Should Be&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/are-you-in-the-1-you-should-be/&#34;&gt;responsibility to be great&lt;/a&gt;. At the same time, it asserts the importance of getting your hands dirty, doing the nitty-gritty, and having the pragmatic know-how to make our vision of the world a reality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
