<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thanksgiving on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/thanksgiving/</link>
    <description>Recent content in thanksgiving on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/thanksgiving/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Happy Thanksgiving</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/happy-thanksgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/happy-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gratitude is hugely underestimated as a practice, but theories as diverse as time psychology and Buddhism encourage us to take some time to reflect on all that we have to be grateful for. Since reading &lt;em&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;The Time Paradox&#34; href=&#34;http://www.thetimeparadox.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Time Paradox&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;I have made a habit of keeping a gratitude journal in order to re-tool how I viewed my past from a childhood of frustration and loneliness to one of self-empowerment and creative insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also important to show appreciation to the people who help you out. None of us can change the world on our own, so if we are honest with ourselves, we must realize that we owe a lot of our success to others. If we want to continue receiving that support, it&#39;s a good idea to offer thanks to those who gave it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, in the spirit of Thanksgiving, I offer my appreciation and gratitude.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Thankful For...The Twitter Community I&#39;ve Found</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/im-thankful-for-the-twitter-community-ive-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/im-thankful-for-the-twitter-community-ive-found/</guid>
      <description>Happy Thanksgiving to everyone in the States. Since I am an American, for better or worse, I do celebrate this holiday. After all, it celebrates a brief moment in US history when we had the sense to appreciate the kindness shown by the Native Americans, without whose generosity and hospitality, we would have starved to death in a frigid New England winter. The pilgrims needed food, and the local people helped them out.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
