<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>procrastination on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/procrastination/</link>
    <description>Recent content in procrastination on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/procrastination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tired of Tardiness</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/tired-of-tardiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/tired-of-tardiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1323&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;blue2likeyou on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/29254399@N08/3187186308/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1323&#34; title=&#34;clock&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/clock1-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last two days, I&#39;ve done a pretty poor job of keeping on top of my own schedule. I&#39;ve been rushing around to everything, have been late to two very important appointments, and haven&#39;t had the mental clarity to focus on getting anything done. I offer my apologies to all affected, including the readers of my blog. It&#39;s not much in the way of consolation, but I&#39;ve been suffering more than those I let down; my ability to get enough food and sleep has been pretty well undermined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Beat Procrastination</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-beat-procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-beat-procrastination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_789&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Source: CraigGrocott on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/craigweb/2887922337/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-789&#34; title=&#34;procrastination&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/procrastination-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Do it now! can affect every phase of your life. It can help you do the things you should do but don&#39;t feel like doing. It can keep you from procrastinating when an unpleasant duty faces you. But it can also help you do those things that you want to do. It helps you seize those precious moments that, if lost, may never be retrieved.” - &lt;em&gt;Napoleon Hill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading my blog today, but I have to ask, is there something more important you have to do that you are putting off by checking in? (Or perhaps reading my blog is the most important thing you have to do today, in which case I&#39;m flattered :)). &lt;strong&gt;Procrastination, the sacred art of putting things off to the last minute, is one of the biggest productivity killers in our lives, and also one of the biggest sources of stress and anxiety&lt;/strong&gt;. It is a learned habit, one that can really mess with your sense of well-being and mental health. It cuts into all aspects of our lives, from reading, to shopping, to paying bills, to exercising. So why do we procrastinate, and how can we eliminate this habit?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
