<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>evolutionaryhealth on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/evolutionaryhealth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in evolutionaryhealth on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/evolutionaryhealth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Far do You Take Paleo?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-far-do-you-take-paleo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-far-do-you-take-paleo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Tell me the place you were born, the lives your ancestors led/&lt;br /&gt;
The ground that surrounded the people you love, the streams from which you were fed/&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s the wind that carries the seed, and the seed that carries the song/&lt;br /&gt;
The food that we&#39;re eating is rooted in soil, and it&#39;s soil that is keeping us strong/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Libby Roderick, &#34;Low to the Ground&#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/3736382830_a6cb6c31ed.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2473&#34; title=&#34;Hunters&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3736382830_a6cb6c31ed-300x175.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;175&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where do you draw the line in Paleo? Is it just a diet fad your gym is following, or do you place a higher importance on healthy eating? Do you keep The Paleo in the kitchen, or does it encompass all health behavior? If it is about health, is it restricted to your personal health, or does it encompass the health of your community? Is it more than just a set of health habits, but a lifestyle and a philosophy of living?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many people, Paleo only goes as far as practical. They eat the bacon avocado salads, are quick to find recipes for Paleo-pancakes and are happy to be only as strict their tastes allow. Paleo is confined to the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many more, following the principles of Paleo extends a little beyond convenience and diet. These people are willing to endure inconvenience because Paleo isn’t just a fashionable diet that happens to work. Paleo is about their health. They make an effort to eliminate stress, get enough sleep, and go out of their way to find grassfed meat and locally grown vegetables. Paleo extends to the way they exercise and move, keeping things spontaneous, playful, and intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people push Paleo even further (but not many). They allow Paleo to seep out of their ‘health and fitness’ lives. When it does, Paleo starts to become a lifestyle instead of a diet-and-exercise program. It stops fitting in that convenient compartment we have scheduled for an hour in the morning and after work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a funny thing starts to happen when you let Paleo expand beyond the bounds set by social convenience. &lt;strong&gt;It starts to define it’s own rules of social convenience. It starts to change the way we see the world, instead of itself being limited by the world&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
