<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>graceful losing on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/graceful-losing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in graceful losing on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/graceful-losing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quit Your Belly Achin&#39;</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/quit-your-belly-achin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/quit-your-belly-achin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1573&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;mdanys on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mindaugasdanys/3766009204/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1573&#34; title=&#34;Angry Child&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3766009204_8721a00dde-300x252.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;252&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;There are a thousand reasons for failure, but not a single excuse.&#34; - a cool t-shirt&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you make a mistake even worse? You whine and complain about it and make lots of excuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little while ago, I performed a CrossFit workout in which I wasn&#39;t too happy with my performance. It was a surprisingly difficult one, involving a lot of burpees, followed by a lot of overhead squats, followed by muscle ups. I&#39;m very good at the first and the last movement, and apparently not so hot at the second. But I was so keen on getting to my strength - the muscle ups - that when I finally did, I lost all my focus and went crazy. The result was that I got just a single muscle up in two minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the buzzer went off, I let out an angry yell, uttering a curse I never use in my daily life. It just sort of slipped out, and I was immediately ashamed of myself. Not because I had cursed - lots of people do that - but that I had gotten so angry that I did something so out of character.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
