<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>beaten paths on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/beaten-paths/</link>
    <description>Recent content in beaten paths on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/beaten-paths/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Velvet Ropes</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/velvet-ropes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/velvet-ropes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/5848124382_4f8b14264e.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-1990&#34; title=&#34;Velvet ropes ready to hold you back&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5848124382_4f8b14264e.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;It&#39;s opener there, in the wide open air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out there things happen,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And frequently do,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To people as brainy and footsy as you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Dr. Seuss, &lt;em&gt;Oh the Places You&#39;ll Go!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a place where travelers go, full of wonder and exotic foods and people. Conveniently, everyone speaks English when you need to communicate, but they maintain their quant, authentic accent and obligingly speak in their native tongue among themselves. They can show you around, if you can pay them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a new, distant country, so you&#39;re guaranteed an adventure, and you can rest secure in the knowledge that you are widening your horizons, being cosmopolitan, and expanding your mind. Perhaps many of your friends are still at home, taking vacations to safe, boring places like Florida or Yosemite. But in this country, you can See Things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get very, very comprehensive guide books, written by Seasoned Travelers, and so presented from a perspective you&#39;d understand. There are signs, too, printed so you can read them. The books and the signs will tell you all the best places to go, so you can be sure you won&#39;t miss out on the Complete Experience. Every tourist who comes through has seen these most wondrous sights, and if you didn&#39;t, you&#39;d be missing out. It&#39;s really very easy anyway, so why not just follow the signs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paths are well-marked, and well-trodden. They are paved and kept in good condition (but with careful attention to preserving the suggestion of age, the patina of local culture). You won&#39;t trip or sprain an ankle. All the best restaurants are on these paths, and plenty of comfortable, accommodating places to stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&#39;s it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about the countryside, you ask?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
