<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>startwithwhy on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/startwithwhy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in startwithwhy on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/startwithwhy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrity in Action: Why I&#39;m Not Charging for My Book</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-in-action-why-im-not-charging-for-my-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-in-action-why-im-not-charging-for-my-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2427&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2075441844_b3a8ed26a0.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-2427&#34; title=&#34;Steadfast Rocks&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/2075441844_b3a8ed26a0-300x201.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Sometimes you aren&#39;t supposed to go with the flow[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important principles may and must be inflexible. -Abraham Lincoln&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to explain why I decided to go back to giving away my book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Warrior Spirit Principles of Holistic Health&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/store/warrior-spirit-principles-of-holistic-health/&#34;&gt;The Warrior Spirit Principles of Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, for free or a donation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As some of you know, I had been reading Simon Sinek&#39;s book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;The Golden Circle&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-golden-circle/&#34;&gt;Start with Why&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;which explains that leaders inspire because they lead with WHY they do things, as opposed to WHAT they do. Even if they do ineffective things, they are driven by a purpose, and that comes across in all their actions. They maintain integrity, behaving in accordance with their principles, rather than convenience. The result is that we follow them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of great leaders in history. Not everything they did was the best course of action for every situation, but they were always people of integrity, so we forgave them, believed they had the right purpose, and gave them our loyalty anyway. One of my personal role models, Franklin D. Roosevelt, led the United States through a morally complicated war. There were certainly a great number of poor decisions made by him and his administration, but he had a clear purpose, and everything he did was somehow connected to that purpose. So, for the most part, he had the country&#39;s loyalty and he is remembered as a great leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Well, after I finished my book, I realized that charging $10 for it did not mesh with WHY I&#39;d written the book in the first place.&lt;/strong&gt; I wrote it because I believe that everyone should &lt;a title=&#34;A New Understanding of Fitness and the Human Body&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/a-new-understanding-of-fitness-and-the-human-body/&#34;&gt;know as much as possible &lt;/a&gt;about their health and be fully empowered to &lt;a title=&#34;Move and Be Free&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/move-and-be-free/&#34;&gt;cultivate their bodies&lt;/a&gt;. I also firmly believe that this is a natural right of being human. It&#39;s not something that should be withheld or taken advantage of. I wrote the book to &lt;strong&gt;share&lt;/strong&gt; what I know with my friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I finished &lt;em&gt;Start with Why, &lt;/em&gt;I applied the ideas to my own projects, and it became clear that if my purpose was free and open sharing of my experiences, I couldn&#39;t justify charging money for it. Even if my book was worth money by societal standard, that&#39;s not why I wrote it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, why did I decide to sell it in the first place?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
