<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BWCAW on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/bwcaw/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BWCAW on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/bwcaw/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Traits of a Warrior: Humility</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-humility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-humility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/humility.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-407&#34; title=&#34;humility&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/humility.jpg?w=210&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;210&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most important lessons I&#39;ve learned from CrossFit is humility. Workouts that sound easy never are, and I am always amazed at how quickly my muscles will tire, how a weight that sounds light quickly becomes unbearable. To make things worse, we are always talking about how some crazy CrossFitter completed the same WOD in unrealistically fast times. CrossFit is a community, and so we know that the same workout that destroyed everyone at our gym was a walk in the park for someone else. Personally, this is hard to swallow. I know I&#39;ve made amazing strides since I started, but an unweighted barbell still gets painfully heavy after a few minutes, and burpees can still leave me begging for mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make things worse, I&#39;ve come to learn that getting frustrated does not make things any better. After 5 months of training, my snatch max hasn&#39;t changed a single pound. But trying to use frustration to motivate myself only causes my technique to fall apart. There is a fine line between determination and frustration.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
