<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>conscious living on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/conscious-living/</link>
    <description>Recent content in conscious living on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/conscious-living/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conscious Living for Young People</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/conscious-living-for-young-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/conscious-living-for-young-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/07/meditation.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-649&#34; title=&#34;meditation&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/meditation.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our children don&#39;t inherit the Earth from us. We are borrowing it from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Unknown&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idealism can be a frustrating trait to have. You have such dreams and aspirations, most of which are far beyond your current capabilities. Once your acquire the means to realize your ambitions, you have become so reliant on the system you wanted to change that your idealism has faded to &#39;mature pragmatism.&#39; It is us young people that have so many concerns about living healthy, respecting and protecting the environment, giving our time to help our communities. But it is not until we are older that we have the resources to do that. Oftentimes, acquiring those resources, and the stability and time needed to dedicate those resources, comes at the cost of our activist-souls. As &lt;em&gt;Rich Dad, Poor Dad &lt;/em&gt;illustrates, we find ourselves shackled by a mortgage, a &#39;safe, secure job&#39;, and debt. Thoughts of changing the world are set aside as we struggle to simply get by. Eco-consciousness becomes something we do at the grocery store by &#39;buying green&#39;, and community engagement comes in the form of sending a monthly check to the neighborhood association you never interact with. You know cars are bad, but you&#39;ve got kids who need to get to soccer games, the grocery store is miles away, and the SUV is just so much more useful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
