<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>e-mail on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/e-mail/</link>
    <description>Recent content in e-mail on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/e-mail/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Keeping in Touch in a Disconnected World</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/keeping-in-touch-in-a-disconnected-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/keeping-in-touch-in-a-disconnected-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1412&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;cynthiacloskey on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/cynthiacloskey/2439736125/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1412&#34; title=&#34;letters&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/letters-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My generation is surrounded by hundreds of ways to instantaneously get in touch with old friends. We have Facebook, MySpace, Twitter, iPhones, Droids, Wi-fi hotspots, 3G networks, text messages, e-mail, instant messaging, and even that old standby, the telephone. And yet, almost all of my old friends claim that they are horrible at staying in touch. On a whim, they can say hello to someone with the touch of a button, and yet, we hear from one another so infrequently many of us wonder what the point of social technology is in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliminating Distractions</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/eliminating-distractions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/eliminating-distractions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_702&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: tychay on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/tychay/3333787096/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-702&#34; title=&#34;cleandesk&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/cleandesk.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;_mcePaste&#34;&gt;If while washing dishes, we think only of the cup of tea that awaits us, thus hurrying to get the dishes out of the way as if they were a nuisance, then we are not &#34;washing the dishes to wash the dishes.&#34; What&#39;s more, we are not alive during the time we are washing the dishes.... While drinking the cup of tea, we will only be thinking of other things, barely aware of the cup in our hands. Thus we are sucked away into the future -and we are incapable of actually living one minute of life. - Naht Hahn, &lt;em&gt;Miracle of Mindfulness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern technology is a wonderful thing. It gives us access to more information than we could possibly ever hope to read and understand. It connects us to people all over the world and lets us share ideas and conversations with them on a whim. It puts the entirety of human knowledge at our fingertips. As a college student, I was infinitely grateful for the fact that I could do almost all my research and class readings online without having to spend hours in the bookstacks looking for texts. At the click of a button, I could bring to my attention the latest psychological research and in the same breath skim an article on current events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
