<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>adventure on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/adventure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in adventure on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/adventure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Adventure Next Door</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-adventure-next-door/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-adventure-next-door/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3917&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/mundane-e1422321898327.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mundane&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;321&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently visited the Hemingway House in Key West, where I got to see glimpses of the life of a very interesting man. He lived during a period full of historically significant events, but walking through his house, I could imagine the years crawling quietly by, much as they seem to in my own home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hemingway, however, didn&#39;t just hang out at home. His walls were full of photos of places he&#39;d been and things he&#39;d done, artifacts from his travels, and all the indicators of a life well-spent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine that the average person in 1940, when Hemingway published &lt;em&gt;For Whom the Bell Tolls,&lt;/em&gt; thought it was a fairly mundane time. There was a world war going on, sure, but we in America have essentially been at war since 2001, and in 1940, mainland America had never been directly threatened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, 1940 seems like a romantic era full of heroes and drama, but in reality, it was the individuals, like Hemingway, who brought the heroism and drama to the times. I imagine he would have thought our time was full to the brim with adventure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End of Adventure</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-end-of-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-end-of-adventure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1931&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;ButterflySha in Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/butterflysha/140523563/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1931&#34; title=&#34;stay in line&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/stay-in-line-300x121.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;121&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you wait to do everything until you&#39;re sure it&#39;s right, you&#39;ll probably never do much of anything.” -Win Borden&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To really experience life, you&#39;re going to have to get out of line first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I studied Arabic in Jordan, I initially applied to go through a program. It was quite a prestigious program, and it promised all sorts of  exciting (pre-arranged) adventures in addition to a language study at the University of Jordan. The brochure also stressed how safe it was and how secure the travelling student would be, even as they learned to step outside their comfort zone on a study abroad program. I had my misgivings, but when I got a phone call letting me know I was accepted, I was very excited...until the lady got to the part about the cost of the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having lived in the Middle East, I knew that the costs were inflated. I asked if I could just stay with my family there and spare them the living expenses, but the woman (quickly getting annoyed with me for daring to suggest I might have a better experience through other channels) explained that it would detract from the experience. This didn&#39;t answer my question, and she ended the conversation by saying that if I didn&#39;t pay soon, they would give the spot to someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never followed up with that group. I simply signed up for the University of Jordan&#39;s Arabic program directly. Of course, there were some bumps in the road because of that, but when I showed up with twenty or so other students who hadn&#39;t finalized their registrations, I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; had to &#34;step out of my comfort zone&#34; to speak for all of them and cow the program director into letting us all join the program a day late. That would never have happened if I&#39;d went with the &#39;secure&#39; program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living an Adventurous Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/living-an-adventurous-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/living-an-adventurous-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1511&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Gjeewaytee on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40066970@N08/4178946564/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1511&#34; title=&#34;adventure&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/adventure-300x226.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;226&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started learning gymnastics, I wasn&#39;t the only adult at the gym. But I was the only adult on the rings and I was the only person there with no formal gymnastics experience as a child (excluding the Parkour crowd and one other guy who had started in college).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given my previous experience, my age, and my chosen apparatus of still rings, there weren&#39;t many who thought I would go far. After all, there weren&#39;t many (if any) who had come into gymnastics late with the intent of picking up much beyond tumbling and flips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my coach and I moved slowly, exploring different ways to progress and learn that might be unique to my situation. Every training session was an adventure, because I didn&#39;t know anyone who had done what I was trying to do. I didn&#39;t know what to expect, or how I would ultimately fare.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
