<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>success on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/success/</link>
    <description>Recent content in success on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/success/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Success, 14 Truths</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/success-14-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/success-14-truths/</guid>
      <description>The Basics Stay Healthy: Respect your body. It is your most vital tool. Eat well. Stay active. Sleep.
Respect Yourself: Dress well. Stay clean. Give yourself a clean place to live.
Love Yourself: You must, must, must be your own biggest supporter. Treat yourself with the same compassion you would offer your children. Commit to yourself. Commit to doing what it takes to make yourself happy and successful.
Be Kind: To yourself, to others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Entrepreneurial Benefits of Healthy Living</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-entrepreneurial-benefits-of-healthy-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-entrepreneurial-benefits-of-healthy-living/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve noticed an interesting trend among ambitious businesspeople: a tendency to neglect their health.
They seem to think that they can get away with treating their bodies poorly. In the pursuit of success, they end up pulling all-nighter after all-nighter, eating cheap, quick junk food to get back to work as soon as possible, drinking tons of coffee, and spending hours hunched over the keyboard.
I&#39;ve been in those kinds of situations, and I admire their dedication, but I&#39;ve also come to learn that a weak body leads to a weak mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Kinds of People, Three Kinds of Success. Which are You?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/three-kinds-of-people-three-kinds-of-success-which-are-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/three-kinds-of-people-three-kinds-of-success-which-are-you/</guid>
      <description>How do you define your personal success? When asked what you want in life, do you tell people the job you want to do, or the kind of company and environment you want to work for, or the effect you want to have on the world?
Yesterday, I was meeting with a mentor to figure out what I needed to do to be successful and happy in Boulder now that I&#39;ve quit my job, and to understand why I felt the need to quit my job in the first place (oh yeah, Mom and Dad, by the way, I quit my job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Costs of Success</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-costs-of-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-costs-of-success/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1502&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;` TheDreamSky on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/dhilung/2967604762/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1502&#34; title=&#34;success&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/success-300x227.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;227&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;I too am not a bit tamed—I too am untranslatable;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sound my barbaric yawp over the roofs of the world.&#34; -Walt Whitman&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YAWP!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YAWP!!!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YAWP!!!!!!!!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YAAAAAWWWWP!!!!!!!!!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My girlfriend had me screaming this at the top of my lungs in the middle of a local park, as a exercise in letting myself be heard. After my yell (there was only one) I cringed, waiting for something bad to happen, as if I&#39;d broken some rule by being loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I discovered that I am kind of scared of being noticed, which is sort of a problem if I&#39;m trying to be a world famous author who writes insightful and controversial works on the nature of the human spirit. Presumably, if I do that well, I&#39;d be noticed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, in classic over-analytical fashion, it occured to me that I might be tamping down my excellent writing in order not to be noticed. My subconscious (insidious little bugger) knew that if I wrote all the earth-shattering and poignant things I wanted to write, people would in fact start to notice, and then all my YAWPing would put me in the spotlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, now I&#39;ve figured out what my subconcious has been up to behind my back...NO MORE!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Mistakes to Learn</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/make-mistakes-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/make-mistakes-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1313&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Jeffrey Montes on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jm-photography/4866200549/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1313&#34; title=&#34;SONY DSC&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/paint-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The man who makes no mistakes does not usually make anything. - William Connor Magee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the productivity newsletters I subscribe to, Psychotactics, recently sent out an article on the best strategies to learn and retain knowledge. The author explained that almost every attempt we make to acquire knowledge is done in such a way as to make it very unlikely we will actually be able to hold on to that knowledge. The reason is simply because we are afraid to test our knowledge and make mistakes and mistakes are the key to knowledge retention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traits of a Warrior: Persistence</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-persistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/penguin.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-489&#34; title=&#34;penguin&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/penguin.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;222&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, the workout at my gym was to determine at what weight you could do 10 non-stop power cleans (move a barbell from floor to shoulder in one motion). At 165lbs, my form began to slip and I dragged the knurled bar up my shins, several times, leaving my legs bloody and stinging. I failed the set, only getting 9. Pretty upset with myself, I went to the bathroom to clean up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was taping up my leg, I was thinking about calling it a day. But looking at my leg, I realized there wasn&#39;t any actual damage. All I&#39;d done was scrape some skin, and while it stung, it had no impact on my muscles&#39; ability to perform. I covered the wound in tape to protect it, and got back on the pad, and did the full set as if nothing had happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of times in our lives when we suffer dramatic and painful failures. Our usual response is to throw in the towel, grudgingly accept that we did our best, and nurse our wounded egos. But when we look back, it is clear that our egos were the only things that were really injured by our setback. Our ability to complete the task at hand has not been diminished in any way, we simply have decided, arbitrarily, that we have failed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
