<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>health on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in health on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Entrepreneurial Benefits of Healthy Living</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-entrepreneurial-benefits-of-healthy-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-entrepreneurial-benefits-of-healthy-living/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve noticed an interesting trend among ambitious businesspeople: a tendency to neglect their health.
They seem to think that they can get away with treating their bodies poorly. In the pursuit of success, they end up pulling all-nighter after all-nighter, eating cheap, quick junk food to get back to work as soon as possible, drinking tons of coffee, and spending hours hunched over the keyboard.
I&#39;ve been in those kinds of situations, and I admire their dedication, but I&#39;ve also come to learn that a weak body leads to a weak mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Committing to Health Teaches you to Stand Out</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-being-healthy-empowers-you-to-stand-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-being-healthy-empowers-you-to-stand-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/sunflower.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright  wp-image-3114&#34; alt=&#34;sunflower&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/sunflower.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Being in good shape puts you at odds with a lot of society. It denies--or at least minimizes--the value of some of our culture&#39;s greatest accomplishments: abundant food, two cars in every driveway, accessible technology, drugs for every ailment. It&#39;s generally poor form to question or refuse these blessings of civilization. It angers the other sheep when you start asking questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, our society is not structured to help individuals achieve their greatest potential in health. We&#39;ve done a very good job of eliminating the stressors that temper our bodies, with the result that our daily lives do not provide the stimulus we need to stay in our best shape. &lt;strong&gt;Now, if we want to develop our bodies, we have to go out of our way to do it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be healthy, we need to take time out of our life in order to perform extensive and inconvenient maintenance (unless you&#39;re one of those people who &lt;em&gt;actually enjoys&lt;/em&gt; being active, then maybe you take time out of your life for your job). The alternative is to simply accept what most of the American population does: that chronic disease is inevitable, that the ability to lift and carry more than you weigh is impossible, that hoisting yourself over an object by your own strength is beyond human capability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to the norm, we have to eat differently, act differently, move differently, sleep differently. To a certain extent, we have to purposefully ostracize ourselves, choose certain friends that can support our habit, and stick out. Other&#39;s may respect and even envy health, but that doesn&#39;t make it any easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lifestyles of the Rich and Famous&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That lifestyle sounds a lot like the one followed by many game-changers and amazingly successful people. From what I&#39;ve read and researched, starting a successful business that makes a difference requires you to live by a different set of rules. You do things and believe in possibilities that other people don&#39;t even consider. You question the status quo about money or the kind of influence you can have. You certainly don&#39;t play by the standard rules of go-to-school-get-good-grades-get-a-safe-job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So essentially, to break out of the status quo in anything, whether it&#39;s health, wealth, influence, or comedy, you have to be a radical&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A World Unto Yourself: The Ecological Nature of Health</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-world-unto-yourself-the-ecological-nature-of-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-world-unto-yourself-the-ecological-nature-of-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/86898565_563dab2319.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2828&#34; alt=&#34;Earth Full South Pacific&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/86898565_563dab2319.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;456&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know thyself. - Plato&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human body is a wonderfully complex organism. It puts even the most refined watches to shame in terms of the technical precision that enables it to run, and the ingeniousness with which the human (or any other) body is put together continues to astound doctors, philosophers, psychologists, biologists, theologians, and anyone else who witnesses it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, despite this deep complexity, &lt;strong&gt;we often treat our bodies like simple machines&lt;/strong&gt;. We believe that we can change one thing without accounting for anything else. This comes across in the many fitness fads of bulking up vs. cutting vs. toning, as if our bodies were cars that could be tweaked and fine-tuned. All you need to do is lift heavier, or follow this one routine, or eat this one superfood, or take cold showers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less is More in Health: Minimalist Hygiene Tips</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/save-money-be-really-healthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/save-money-be-really-healthy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/6508860689_92a82bb284.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2819&#34; alt=&#34;A Simple Glass of Water&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/6508860689_92a82bb284.jpg&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“As you simplify your life, the laws of the universe will be simpler; solitude will not be solitude, poverty will not be poverty, nor weakness weakness.” - Henry David Thoreau&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s no surprise to followers of ancestral living that, when it comes to health, less is often more. Of course, we mean less of the right things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;Less additives&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;Less sugar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;Less processing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less cushioning in our shoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less furniture (remember the evils of sitting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, we like living as close to our natural state as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote &lt;a title=&#34;The 6 Strangest Health Habits&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-6-strangest-health-habits/&#34;&gt;a post&lt;/a&gt; a while back about about my strange health habits that have made a big difference for me, and I realized that many of them also helped me save money. I used to have quite a lot of hygiene products in my never-ending attempts to maintain a healthy body. These included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;handsoap&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;bodywash&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;shampoo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;conditioner&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;shaving cream&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;aftershave&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;shaving razors and refills&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;laundry detergent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;dishwashing detergent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chemical deodorant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized that I was spending a lot of money on products that are basically unnecessary. Even eco-friendly products often have a lot of unnecessary stuff in them, and of course the &#39;green&#39; label justifies charging more for them. It didn&#39;t make sense to me that humans needed such complex chemicals just to stay clean. So I started learning about alternatives and DIY-recipes. I&#39;ve since reduced my products down to the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You as Fit as Your Dog? 5 Ways to Play Fetch</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/are-you-as-fit-as-your-dog-5-ways-to-play-fetch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/are-you-as-fit-as-your-dog-5-ways-to-play-fetch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/?attachment_id=2707&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2707&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2707&#34; alt=&#34;Hard at Play&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3244259451_0120de8a9d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We&#39;ve had a series of intense posts lately, and there are more in the schedule (see below for more on that...and a funny video of me falling in the mud), so here&#39;s a much more lighthearted one.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m a strong advocate of spontaneous, playful movement as the best way to get exercise. That&#39;s why I love &lt;a title=&#34;Freeing the Zoo Humans: Why I Want to Become a MovNat Instructor&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/movnat-instructor/&#34;&gt;MovNat&#39;s philosophy&lt;/a&gt;. I feel that play is more engaging, gets your mind off the strain of exercising (so you&#39;ll do more), and &lt;a title=&#34;The Communion of Play; A Day of Natural Movement on the River&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-communion-of-play-a-day-of-natural-movement-on-the-river/&#34;&gt;can be shared as social activity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I&#39;ve been undergoing a self-imposed training program for my &lt;a title=&#34;How to Make a Dream Come True&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/how-to-make-a-dream-come-true/&#34;&gt;MovNat Trainer Certification&lt;/a&gt;, which has been lonely in the cold winter of New England. This past weekend, I finally got my girlfriend (who will now be referred to as Rocketpack instead of the mysterious, A) to come out with me. Seizing on this opportunity for social play, I came up with a game to make my sprint-esque workout more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We played a timeless classic, enjoyed not just by humans, but by our furry friends as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yup, we played fetch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Things That Matter</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-things-that-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-things-that-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-things-that-matter/737679_940187808960_3223248_o1/&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2674&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter  wp-image-2674&#34; title=&#34;A moment of pure bliss&#34; alt=&#34;Two dogs and a glass of wine&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/737679_940187808960_3223248_o1-1024x576.jpg&#34; width=&#34;574&#34; height=&#34;322&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started as a way to live responsibly. Knowing all the suffering and pollution caused by industrial farming and how that impacted my health, I made the commitment to eating organic and supporting local food whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To simplify my decision-making, I made up all sorts of rules about what I could and couldn&#39;t eat. Soon, adhering to the rules became more important than what the rules were meant to help me accomplish, which was eating in harmony. This harmonious way of eating would naturally give rise to health, but when I ran into the Paleo and Primal communities, health itself took the top priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all the obsession over good vs. bad carbs, optimal post-workout nutrition, and coconut substitutions for everything, I realized my diet had become meaningless. By all accounts, I ate well. My food was high quality and nutritious, but all this was lost on me. &lt;strong&gt;I didn&#39;t even taste my meals anymore.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I don&#39;t know how common this is among Paleo eaters and I hope you will leave comments sharing your experiences. It seems to me that obsessing over the health aspects of Paleo (dangerously easy to do given the mindset of the community) could lead us to forget how to enjoy our food for its own sake.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eventually, I came to believe that &lt;a title=&#34;You Can’t Afford to be Attached to Your Health, So Make it About Others&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/you-cant-afford-to-be-attached-to-your-health-so-make-it-about-others/&#34;&gt;my health doesn&#39;t matter&lt;/a&gt;, per se. I didn&#39;t live to be healthy. I was healthy in order to live well. &lt;/strong&gt;How I ate needed to be a reflection of that goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I believe that the very purpose of our life is to seek happiness. That is clear.&#34; - His Holiness the 14th Dalai Lama&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I realized that, I stopped getting so upset with the dietary rules. Eventually, I was able to reconnect with the enjoyment of my food again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, as you get deeper into Paleo, you realize that optimal health requires eating and living sustainably. So, even if your main priority is health, you are forced to aim higher, to prioritize something more general, in order to achieve that. The reality forces a widening of your concerns. If you refuse to see this, you end up chasing your own tail in a never-ended spiral of healthy living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 6 Strangest Health Habits</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-6-strangest-health-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-6-strangest-health-habits/</guid>
      <description>That&#39;s me hanging on the ledge in the middle of the photo.
I will always remember the night I willingly lowered myself into an ice bath as the day I went over the edge and became certifiably weird. Crazy might be a better term for it.
Healthy behavior can seem unusual when viewed from the perspective of the mainstream. After all, the very fact that some behavior stands out as &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Myth of Control in (Paleo) Health</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-myth-of-control-in-paleo-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-myth-of-control-in-paleo-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“The closest to being in control we will ever be is in that moment that we realize we&#39;re not.” - Brian Kessler&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/?attachment_id=2611&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2611&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-2611&#34; alt=&#34;LettingGo&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/LettingGo.jpg&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Last year, my&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/in-memory-of-auntie-phyllis/&#34;&gt; Aunt Phyllis&lt;/a&gt; succumbed to leukemia. I have often wondered if a change in diet could have improved her quality of life, given her more time, or even reversed the disease, based on anecdotes from  the Paleo community. Uncertainty kept me silent. Would it have made things better, or just given her more to worry about? Would I be trivializing her disease or the advice of her doctors? Would it mean I was &lt;i&gt;blaming&lt;/i&gt; her for the leukemia or its progression, by attributing the disease to lifestyle choices? Would it have made her feel ashamed that she had cancer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many, the suggestion that we can directly impact our health, even influencing such big-name diseases as cancer, diabetes, alzhiemer’s, and MS, is unwelcome. &lt;b&gt;It implies that our suffering is our fault, and can lead to a sense of guilt or shame.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if health is a critical factor in our ability to positively impact the world, it is not the final determinant of a person’s worth. Better to judge a person by what they have contributed to the lives of others and how they have made the world a better place. This may seem obvious, but in practice, many of us forget it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, someone else close to me has been diagnosed with a potentially life-threatening condition. Given my knowledge and experience, I&#39;m not sure how to help, or even if I should help at all. How we live if up to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Far do You Take Paleo?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-far-do-you-take-paleo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-far-do-you-take-paleo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Tell me the place you were born, the lives your ancestors led/&lt;br /&gt;
The ground that surrounded the people you love, the streams from which you were fed/&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s the wind that carries the seed, and the seed that carries the song/&lt;br /&gt;
The food that we&#39;re eating is rooted in soil, and it&#39;s soil that is keeping us strong/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Libby Roderick, &#34;Low to the Ground&#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/3736382830_a6cb6c31ed.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2473&#34; title=&#34;Hunters&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3736382830_a6cb6c31ed-300x175.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;175&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where do you draw the line in Paleo? Is it just a diet fad your gym is following, or do you place a higher importance on healthy eating? Do you keep The Paleo in the kitchen, or does it encompass all health behavior? If it is about health, is it restricted to your personal health, or does it encompass the health of your community? Is it more than just a set of health habits, but a lifestyle and a philosophy of living?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many people, Paleo only goes as far as practical. They eat the bacon avocado salads, are quick to find recipes for Paleo-pancakes and are happy to be only as strict their tastes allow. Paleo is confined to the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many more, following the principles of Paleo extends a little beyond convenience and diet. These people are willing to endure inconvenience because Paleo isn’t just a fashionable diet that happens to work. Paleo is about their health. They make an effort to eliminate stress, get enough sleep, and go out of their way to find grassfed meat and locally grown vegetables. Paleo extends to the way they exercise and move, keeping things spontaneous, playful, and intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people push Paleo even further (but not many). They allow Paleo to seep out of their ‘health and fitness’ lives. When it does, Paleo starts to become a lifestyle instead of a diet-and-exercise program. It stops fitting in that convenient compartment we have scheduled for an hour in the morning and after work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a funny thing starts to happen when you let Paleo expand beyond the bounds set by social convenience. &lt;strong&gt;It starts to define it’s own rules of social convenience. It starts to change the way we see the world, instead of itself being limited by the world&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can&#39;t Afford to be Attached to Your Health, So Make it About Others</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/you-cant-afford-to-be-attached-to-your-health-so-make-it-about-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/you-cant-afford-to-be-attached-to-your-health-so-make-it-about-others/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2993512484_4e2bdb7aa5_o.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2405&#34; title=&#34;A Helping Hand&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/2993512484_4e2bdb7aa5_o-e1347370123178-300x223.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;223&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Some people choose not to donate their services because they believe that it somehow devalues them by &#34;giving them away.&#34; In truth, there is nothing that demonstrates the value of your skills more than putting them to good use for a cause you believe in. - Scott Allen&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being in good shape can be dangerous. It can be very easy to slip into feelings of superiority: “I’m stronger than others. I take better care of myself. I look sexier than most people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think this is the worst thing in the world, but when I caught myself sneaking too many glances in the mirror and comparing myself to others at my gym, I started to feel that perhaps my &lt;a title=&#34;Fitness is Not Health&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/fitness-is-not-health/&#34;&gt;priorities&lt;/a&gt; were out of line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, when I was particularly annoyed with my pride, I remembered the story of the Siddhartha Guatama. Siddhartha was a prince who grew up sheltered from suffering but who one day witnessed sickness and death and realized that all his princely luxury, his youth, and his health would fall away. He began to question whether all that he had would truly spare him from suffering or make the world a better place. He gave it all away to seek spiritual enlightenment, eventually achieving &lt;em&gt;nirvana&lt;/em&gt; as the historical Buddha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I realized that, proud as I am of my strong, attractive body, it will one day succumb to death&lt;/strong&gt;. At best, I would remain strong and vital until my twilight years, free of chronic disease, then die suddenly and peacefully. As a believer in the &lt;a title=&#34;The Optimism of Ancestral Health&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-optimism-of-ancestral-health/&#34;&gt;inherent integrity&lt;/a&gt; of the human body, I see this as a distinct possibility. At worst, I’ll succumb to the diseases of aging, watch my strength wither away, and suffer a long, slow decline. &lt;strong&gt;No matter what, I end up being totally useless and utterly repulsive: dead and rotting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any of my sense of self-worth was attached to something as impermanent as my health or appearance, my pride was clearly ill-founded. &lt;strong&gt;These things will disappear, so my self-worth and happiness will suffer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The body, strength, youth, and vitality I worked so hard to attain will inevitably one day fall away from me. In full acceptance of that truth, I had to find a compelling reason to take care of my health regardless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitness is Play</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/fitness-is-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/fitness-is-play/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/6885273501_9df2a14fb4.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2176&#34; title=&#34;On the Swings&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/6885273501_9df2a14fb4-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In our modern world, all fitness regimens are accessory and optional.  It is up to each and every individual to decide if they want to exercise or not, and how.  Even walking has already become an option.  But like it or not, &lt;strong&gt;moving naturally still is, and always will be a biological necessity&lt;/strong&gt;. - Erwan Le Corre&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do kids do to play?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They move&lt;/strong&gt;. They climb, scramble, swing, slide, crawl, roll, and jump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Movement is FUN, plain and simple&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are sports enjoyable? Because they involve movement. &lt;strong&gt;For whatever reason, humans (all animals actually) seem to &lt;a title=&#34;Move and Be Free&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/move-and-be-free/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;enjoy movement&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitness is Not Health</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/fitness-is-not-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/fitness-is-not-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2008&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/tomsaint/3752937440/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-2008 &#34; title=&#34;Tired Runners&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3752937440_4641fa806d.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Rennett Stowe on Flickr[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In writing my fitness book and thinking about how I want to explain my views to others, I&#39;ve realized that I was never really comfortable with fitness as we normally conceive it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitness is a confusing term these days. It has become so confusing, in fact, that you can have Fitness without Health. You can be very good at the Fitness thing, exercising religiously, following the right diet, wearing the right $70 Yoga pants, and be completely miserable. Originally meant to be a means to promote our holistic health, Fitness has taken on a life of its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To define Fitness, I want put aside dictionary definitions and focus on what most people mean when they talk about Fitness. I&#39;m concerned with ideas and conceptions, not academic or scientific definitions that have little to do with how people interact with the term in their real lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most, fitness is synonymous with athletic performance: the better your fitness, the better athlete you are. It is also synonymous with health: the better your fitness, the healthier you are. So, the assumption is that athletes are healthy, meaning their bodies express the full range of human function, painlessly, and for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Unhealthy Athlete&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we know that not all great athletes are healthy. The standards of a sport do not always require holistic human health to perform well (think golf), and sometimes the requirements of excellence in a sport actually favor adaptations that cause health problems. When an elite runner dies of heart failure, what do we make of it? How do we reconcile the awe-inspiring performance of gymnasts with the spine and shoulder problems that come with the intensive practice?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move and Be Free</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/move-and-be-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/move-and-be-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1974&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/amagill/4614314729/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-1974 &#34; title=&#34;movement&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/movement.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; AMagill on Flickr[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&#39;t freedom to move the most fundamental freedom there is? - Erwan Le Corre, founder MovNat&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine that walking tires you out quickly. You cannot walk more than five minutes before desperately needing a rest. Add to that the fact that you are too weak to carry a day&#39;s worth of food more than five minutes. Let&#39;s say you&#39;re also too inflexible to sit comfortably on the ground for very long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now try to imagine all the places you cannot go: anywhere without cars, regular and cheap food, or chairs. You are strongly dependent on the presence and goodwill of other people for things as simple as your comfort. Because of your inability to move your body and endure hardship, you have fewer options for where you can go and the things you can do. You literally could not go more than five minutes without needing someone or something to help you. If you get stuck or behind schedule, you&#39;re screwed because you cannot run to catch a bus, much less a few miles to the nearest gas station if your car breaks down out of cell phone range on an urgent errand. You are dependent, in a very visceral sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The One Thing You Can Do To Make Everything Better</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-one-thing-you-can-do-to-make-everything-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-one-thing-you-can-do-to-make-everything-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1850&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;tanakawho on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/28481088@N00/1069809120/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1850&#34; title=&#34;lotus&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/lotus-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He who has health, has hope. And he who has hope, has everything&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.thinkexist.com/quotation/he_who_has_health-has_hope-and_he_who_has_hope/149145.html&#34;&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;” - Proverb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Leave all the afternoon for exercise and recreation, which are as necessary as reading. I will rather say more necessary because health is worth more than learning.” - Thomas Jefferson&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the one thing you can do to improve almost every aspect of your life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be honest, I don’t know you, but the thing that makes the biggest difference in my day to day life is looking after my health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this means eating right, &lt;a title=&#34;Lessons Learned as a Trainer and Athlete&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/lessons-learned-as-a-trainer-and-athlete/&#34;&gt;exercising regularly and intensely&lt;/a&gt;, and getting enough sleep. It means I take my health into my own hands, instead of just accepting what the government or the media tells me. It’s your body; take the time to get to know it, what makes it happy, and what is good for it, instead of relying on people who have zero interest in your well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few of the really obvious effects looking after my health has had. Most of them have nothing to do with the body itself, but instead are reflections on the areas of life that we really live for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Need to Question the Foundations of our Culture</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/we-need-to-question-the-foundations-of-our-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/we-need-to-question-the-foundations-of-our-culture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1674&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;The U.S. Army on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/soldiersmediacenter/4685688778/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1674&#34; title=&#34;100604-D-7203C-005.JPG&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/question-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traffic has been especially bad lately. As I worked my way through New York traffic the other day, I was astounded at how many miles of road there are and that every single one is choked with traffic. There are just so many cars on the road. It is worrying to me knowing all the resources that not only went into producing those cars, but also go into keeping them running every single day. It’s not that there are a lot of cars. There is an incomprehensible number. As far as the eye can see, nothing but smog-spewing vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can this be sustainable?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Would You Rather Weigh Less, or Feel Better?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/would-you-rather-weigh-less-or-feel-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/would-you-rather-weigh-less-or-feel-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1332&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;PinkSherbertPhotography on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pinksherbet/3206805049/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1332&#34; title=&#34;weight&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/weight-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many people, the answer to that question is actually that they would rather weigh less. For many women especially, weight is the end-all-be-all of the larger world of health. You can be fit as a fiddle, but if you weight “too much” it doesn’t matter a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Odd Duck: My Stranger Health Habits</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/an-odd-duck-my-stranger-health-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/an-odd-duck-my-stranger-health-habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1288&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Bobby MacInnes on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/lonetown/1087101701/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1288&#34; title=&#34;odd duck&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/odd-duck-300x200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the name of health, I engage in some practices that others find pretty weird. I actually don&#39;t find them that odd, and they aren&#39;t really inconvenient to me. I actually really enjoy them. But since they aren&#39;t mainstream, they garner some odd looks. I thought I&#39;d list some of them for your entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Health Revolution</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-health-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-health-revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1285&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;eva101 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/evapro/425230963/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1285&#34; title=&#34;protest&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/protest-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A little rebellion now and then... is a medicine necessary for the sound health of government.”- Thomas Jefferson&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently stumbled upon an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/dr-mark-hyman/healthy-living-join-the-health-_b_799191.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;article &lt;/a&gt;claiming that being healthy is a revolutionary act, a difficult process that necessitates you make choices that put you in opposition to the mainstream and the social norm. To be healthy requires you be willing to ostracise yourself in the name of your own well-being because the sad truth is that our society has made poor health the trend and the norm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Strangely Enticing Joys of Cold Showers</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/coldshower/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/coldshower/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1264&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;olliethebastard on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/olliethebastard/2671744641/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1264&#34; title=&#34;shower&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/shower-300x202.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;202&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Marmalade in the morning has the same effect on taste buds that a cold shower has on the body.” Jeanine Larmoth (I have no idea what that implies, but it was the only reasonably insightful quotation I could find on cold showers)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night I discovered that I cannot fall asleep unless I take a cold shower before bed. This seems to cool my system off and trigger an internal warming mechanism that makes me really cozy and helps me fall asleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are What Your Ancestors Ate</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/you-are-what-your-ancestors-ate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/you-are-what-your-ancestors-ate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_962&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: alexdecarvalho on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/adc/2344498516/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-962&#34; title=&#34;caveman&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/caveman-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meat and veggies, nuts and seeds, some fruit, little starch, and no sugar -&lt;em&gt;The Paleo Diet in a nutshell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of my friends know I &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/my-paleo-journey/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;follow an approximately Paleo diet&lt;/a&gt;, and a lot of people argue with me as to why it is silly to eat like Paleolithic humans. I thought I would take the time to dispel some myths and misunderstandings about this &#39;diet&#39;, and hopefully win a few converts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Time Spent Outdoors</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-benefits-of-time-spent-outdoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-benefits-of-time-spent-outdoors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_954&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;222&#34; caption=&#34;Source: ©Hεαṿεṉlÿ Phøτøģɾαρhÿ on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/oooheavenlyooo/3986200282/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-954&#34; title=&#34;nature&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/nature-222x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;222&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man&#39;s heart away from nature becomes hard.  &lt;em&gt;-Standing Bear&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The natural world is all around us. Every city is merely an island of human habitation amidst a vast sea of countryside and forests. A mere hour outside of New York, one of the biggest metropolises in the world, one can find beautiful and surprisingly isolated parks and hiking trails. The hills around LA are still pretty wild (apparently coyotes are a major concern out there). Most cities have parks, little spaces where the city&#39;s fabric is cut out to reveal the nature underneath, just waiting to burst through into sunlight. These are places people can go to escape the hustle of the city for a while. There is something calming and serene about nature. I always feel complete and more balanced when surrounded by trees, and there is a lot to be said for seeking out a regular connection with the outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Simple Ways to Be Healthier</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/simple-ways-to-be-healthier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/simple-ways-to-be-healthier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_737&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: KOREA.NET on flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/koreanet/4364204653/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-737&#34; title=&#34;green tea&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/green-tea.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;195&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tea is drunk to forget the din of the world. -T’ien Yiheng&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last few years, I&#39;ve spent a lot of time finding ways to be healthier without dedicating huge chunks of time or money that I don&#39;t have. While a lot of the success I&#39;ve come across has been the result of some pretty big changes, I have found that the most basic and important things come from small changes. Increased energy levels, better sleep, better digestion, feeling calmer and more relaxed, less pain, and better relationships have all been the result of the smaller, cheaper alternations I&#39;ve made to my life. When these things fall off, problems occur. Here are some really small changes you can make to improve your life in noticeable ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Athleticism Good for Your Health?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/is-athleticism-good-for-your-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/is-athleticism-good-for-your-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; caption=&#34;Source: RobW_ on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/48/136462415_5455bf750a.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Statue of an Athlete from the Ancient Olympic Games&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/136462415_5455bf750a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent visit to my sports doctor, brought on by yet another overuse injury, prompted me to wonder if being an athlete is actually good for one&#39;s health and fitness. After all, the only reason I was at the doctor was because I am an athlete. I had injured my shoulder on a leisurely kayak tour of a small Connecticut lake. The shoulder was prone to such a pansy injury because I regularly engage in extreme fitness, aka, CrossFit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you are probably wondering, as was I, how can an athlete with shoulders capable of doing multiple strict muscle-ups be completely incapacitated by something as tame as kayaking? I honestly don&#39;t have an answer. But the experience got me to wondering about the distinctions between fitness, health, and athleticism.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
