<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>failure on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/failure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in failure on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/failure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>But What if You Fail?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/but-what-if-you-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/but-what-if-you-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/5638935174_b3911ed5ca.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2193&#34; title=&#34;Kite in a Tree&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5638935174_b3911ed5ca-300x226.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;226&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#34;I&#39;m sorry to say so/but, sadly it&#39;s true/that bang-ups and hang-ups/can happen to you&#34; - Dr. Seuss, &lt;em&gt;Oh the Place You&#39;ll Go!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was in high school, I was obsessed with D&amp;amp;D. I spent hours on it, and I once created a very elaborate description of a world born of my imagination. At the time, it was the longest thing I&#39;d ever written, about 40 pages. This was a big deal for an aspiring writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, I opened my computer and the document was gone. I was simply left with 40 pages of garbled text symbols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was defeated and considered just forgetting it had ever existed. It had taken so much work, and I felt that if something that big could be destroyed so easily, what was the point?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nobody else in the world would miss it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Failure</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-value-of-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-value-of-failure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1942&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Mostly Dans on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/dannyboymalinga/5164496759/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1942&#34; title=&#34;Wipeout&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5164496759_2b60140a4f-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get a lot of criticism for my failed attempt at starting a t-shirt design company. We had one run of t-shirts, I didn&#39;t sell all of them, and my income was so low I couldn&#39;t even cover the cost of the website hosting. I lost a lot of money, too. Some might think this is strong evidence that I shouldn&#39;t go into business, since I couldn&#39;t make even a small project work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have told the naysayers that I intend to try again. The usual response is a look of horror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot by failing, and I want to try applying the lessons to another project and see if I can make something else work. Isn&#39;t that the whole point of learning? &lt;strong&gt;Make the failure worth something by learning from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Mistakes to Learn</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/make-mistakes-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/make-mistakes-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1313&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Jeffrey Montes on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jm-photography/4866200549/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1313&#34; title=&#34;SONY DSC&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/paint-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The man who makes no mistakes does not usually make anything. - William Connor Magee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the productivity newsletters I subscribe to, Psychotactics, recently sent out an article on the best strategies to learn and retain knowledge. The author explained that almost every attempt we make to acquire knowledge is done in such a way as to make it very unlikely we will actually be able to hold on to that knowledge. The reason is simply because we are afraid to test our knowledge and make mistakes and mistakes are the key to knowledge retention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traits of a Warrior: Persistence</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-persistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/penguin.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-489&#34; title=&#34;penguin&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/penguin.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;222&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, the workout at my gym was to determine at what weight you could do 10 non-stop power cleans (move a barbell from floor to shoulder in one motion). At 165lbs, my form began to slip and I dragged the knurled bar up my shins, several times, leaving my legs bloody and stinging. I failed the set, only getting 9. Pretty upset with myself, I went to the bathroom to clean up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was taping up my leg, I was thinking about calling it a day. But looking at my leg, I realized there wasn&#39;t any actual damage. All I&#39;d done was scrape some skin, and while it stung, it had no impact on my muscles&#39; ability to perform. I covered the wound in tape to protect it, and got back on the pad, and did the full set as if nothing had happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of times in our lives when we suffer dramatic and painful failures. Our usual response is to throw in the towel, grudgingly accept that we did our best, and nurse our wounded egos. But when we look back, it is clear that our egos were the only things that were really injured by our setback. Our ability to complete the task at hand has not been diminished in any way, we simply have decided, arbitrarily, that we have failed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epic Fail</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/epic-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/epic-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/failure.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-438&#34; title=&#34;failure&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/failure.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, I failed epically. The workout for today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many rounds as possible, in 10 minutes, of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 deadlifts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 hang cleans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 front squats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 push jerks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All with 95 lbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, it&#39;s a ton of work, and much of it involving very technical movements. I was aiming to complete 7 rounds (so 49 of everything) because the previous record was 6 and change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I completed 6 rounds with about a minute and a half left. I was already dying. My vision was blurry and my legs felt like jelly, but I pushed through the sets. I got to the push jerks with 30 seconds left and without taking any rest, started into them. As the clock ticked to 0 seconds, I became distanced from my body, aware of but not feeling the burning in every muscle (a sensation that I had never experienced before), until the very last rep.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
