<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>strategy on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/strategy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in strategy on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Strategies for Success in 2015</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/strategies-for-success-in-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/strategies-for-success-in-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3869&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/chess-e1419979014150.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chess&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;406&#34; /&gt;I don&#39;t like resolutions. &lt;a title=&#34;Forget the Resolution! Set a Challenge!&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/forget-the-resolution-set-a-challenge/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Remember 2013&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with resolutions is that they simply set a goal. They don&#39;t provide a way to actually accomplish that goal, and often, they don&#39;t even determine if the goal is worth pursuing in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s no wonder so many people set resolutions on January 1st only to see them fall apart in a month. &lt;strong&gt;Most resolutions are chosen on a whim, or are the result of compounding pain, not compelling vision.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not that resolutions themselves are bad, it&#39;s that they are missing the essentials of good growth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A clear mission/purpose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solid strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actionable goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key aspects of the Warrior Spirit is being dedicated to a cause or a mission. Having that foundation is what gives you the ability to muster superhuman determination in whatever you choose to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But...you can&#39;t know what goals matter unless you have a clear idea of your mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the first step in creating a strategy for 2015 is to refocus on your mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can I do This?: A Question to Improve Performance on Everything</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/can-i-do-this-a-question-to-improve-performance-on-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/can-i-do-this-a-question-to-improve-performance-on-everything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3855&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/question-e1418143667521.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;question&#34; width=&#34;761&#34; height=&#34;566&#34; /&gt;Perhaps you&#39;ve heard the old advice that it&#39;s important to psych yourself up before a big test or meeting. Remind yourself how awesome you are! Tell yourself, &#34;I can do this! I&#39;m a rockstar!&#34; Maybe you&#39;ve even done this, despite all feelings to the contrary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve ever been in an airplane during extreme turbulence, you don&#39;t want to overhear your pilot insisting, &#34;I can do this! Yeah!&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they are talking at all, you want to hear specific actions that they will be taking to make things better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a reason for this. Our minds actually interpret insistent statements like these as a sign that there is something really wrong. After all, if you were confident, you wouldn&#39;t even need to bother with the motivation at all, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it turns out there&#39;s a better way to motivate yourself, one that feels less like a desperate plea to convince yourself of something you just don&#39;t believe, and that actually helps you do better, rather than simply feel better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask the simple question, &#34;Can I do this?&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Weakness the Smart Way</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/overcoming-weakness-the-smart-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/overcoming-weakness-the-smart-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1528&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;fPat on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/fpat/3375999258/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1528&#34; title=&#34;tigers&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/tigers-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I undertook the fourth installment of the CrossFit Sectionals Open Workouts. It looked right up my alley, involving two movements I am very good at - burpees and muscle ups - and only one that I wasn&#39;t - heavy overhead squat (really, I&#39;m not good at much that is heavy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I was confident I would do well. All I had to do was suffer through the squats in order to get to one of my strengths. Unfortunately, I found the squats too much, and I didn&#39;t even manage to finish them before the timer buzzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I felt defeated. Even with the advantage of having my strengths, I was stopped by one thing that I&#39;m weak at.&lt;/strong&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
