<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>peer pressure on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/peer-pressure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in peer pressure on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/peer-pressure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Life is Not a Dare. Don&#39;t Make it One</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/life-is-not-a-dare-dont-make-it-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/life-is-not-a-dare-dont-make-it-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just because a challenge exists doesn&#39;t mean we have to overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoah there! That doesn&#39;t sound like the indomitable Warrior Spirit, you might be thinking. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was training CrossFit, I remember putting off the training I wanted to be doing (gymnastics, martial arts, parkour, hiking and climbing) for the training I had been convinced was more hardcore/intense/effective/respectable. I was trying to win someone else&#39;s game for a prize I didn&#39;t even care about, just because it was a challenge issued in a way that got my attention and I have a demon about always being the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my quest to be great at fitness, I adopted CrossFit&#39;s standards and tried to master them, even though the end goal wasn&#39;t what I wanted. I kept telling myself that I would get around to the stuff I really cared about...once I finished this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, this approach to fitness was just one symptom of a deeper tendency to take everything as a challenge. Someone driving an expensive car was a dare to do better. Some guy walking down the street better dressed than I was a challenge. It was toxic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to live in the best city (which was always somewhere I was not)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to have the best girlfriend, which varied between hot, pretty, smart, independent, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to do the most important, best paying job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to be the best looking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to be the most spiritual, and the most patient&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to make the most money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these &#39;bests&#39; were things other people defined, or society in general defined. What made me happy and the &#39;best&#39; were not the same thing. And when I would occasionally attain &#39;the best,&#39; it was only a matter of time before someone else or some other segment of society would issue a new dare, and I&#39;d be dissatisfied again.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
