<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fear on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/fear/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fear on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/fear/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Fear: Part 2: Tactics to Quell Fear</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-nature-of-fear-part-2-tactics-to-quell-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-nature-of-fear-part-2-tactics-to-quell-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;I must not fear.&lt;br /&gt;
Fear is the mind-killer.&lt;br /&gt;
Fear is the little-death that brings total obliteration.&lt;br /&gt;
I will face my fear.&lt;br /&gt;
I will permit it to pass over me and through me.&lt;br /&gt;
And when it has gone past I will turn the inner eye to see its path.&lt;br /&gt;
Where the fear has gone there will be nothing.&lt;br /&gt;
Only I will remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt;, Frank Herbert&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;The Nature of Fear: Part 1, Fear is a Choice&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-nature-of-fear-part-1-fear-is-a-choice/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click here to read part 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my first night alone in the woods, I had learned that fear is a choice. It came from the fact that I often saw myself as a victim, someone who was generally vulnerable to others&#39; whims and the world&#39;s catastrophes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be thinking, &#34;Of course you were vulnerable! You were alone, asleep, in the forest! If something had happened, there would have been no way to get help.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, I&#39;m much more vulnerable on a highway, where the chance of injury in a way I cannot respond to is much higher. I &lt;em&gt;perceived&lt;/em&gt; myself as vulnerable in the woods, but it&#39;s not a fact of the situation. A tiger doesn&#39;t feel threatened alone in a forest. It is the thing that makes others feel threatened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, the first step to overcoming the fear of sleeping alone in the woods was realizing that my fear was the result of how I chose to view myself and the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That enabled me to question it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step, and the project for the second night, was actually learning to quell fear. As the sun set for the second time on my trip, I wasn&#39;t any less afraid than I had been the night before, but I was more confident in my ability to handle the anxiety that might come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until I saw the signs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the privy were three scrawled notes, memorials to those who had passed away in the last year. Those three letters--R.I.P.--have a lot of power to set an overactive imagination in a particular direction. I imagined that my campsite was the lurking place of a serial killer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much for my confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as I lay in my tent that night, I came up with a few strategies to deal with the new terror.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Fear: Part 1, Fear is a Choice</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-nature-of-fear-part-1-fear-is-a-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-nature-of-fear-part-1-fear-is-a-choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I stepped onto the trail, I gave one last look back at my car, parked by itself in a clearing off the road in upstate Connecticut. I could turn back now. I didn&#39;t have to go out there into the woods. Two hours of driving and I&#39;d been back in my house, surrounded by people and light switches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I turned and headed into the forest. The sun was high, but it would soon begin its long descent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A History of Fear&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear has been a constant companion in my life. When I was very young, I discovered that the night is full of terror. There were ghosts in my closet, monsters under my bed, aliens in the air ducts, and unnameable things down the stairs. I had complex and confusing bedtime rituals to deal with all these dangers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I realized that I would one day die, and my nights took on a whole new form of terror. Sleep seemed like one step away from the eternal unconsciousness of death. I suffered panic attacks thinking about it, and the fear of being alone at night when one of these attacks happened was enough to keep me from sleeping well most of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there were the night terrors, waking dreams of unseeable presences in my room and the urgent need to jump up, despite being apparently paralyzed (psychologists speculate that this form of nightmare is the origin of alien abduction and possession experiences. I&#39;m inclined to agree).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these things got worse in the wilderness. Even sleeping next to my father in a tent, I would lie awake and paralyzed with fear, waiting for anything from a bear to the reanimated corpse of the Camel Woman to attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These fears didn&#39;t subside much as I got older. Even as recently as a few months ago, after an episode of &lt;em&gt;Doctor Who&lt;/em&gt;, I woke up in my bed with dead certainty that there was a stone angel lurking in the living room...only to find myself totally paralyzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything and everything my mind could use to scare itself, it has hoarded and nurtured, bringing to life at the most sinister moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Setting a New Path&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Each time we face our fear, we gain strength, courage, and confidence in the doing.” - Anon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was becoming a serious problem, affecting my sleep and my self-confidence; &lt;strong&gt;it&#39;s very hard to imagine changing the world when you are afraid of the dark&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So I decided to put myself to the test: I would spend three nights alone in the woods.&lt;/strong&gt; I would either learn to control my mind, to see the world for what it is rather than a stage for my personal terror, or I would spend three miserable nights in a near-panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess the second option wasn&#39;t really a great alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Skill You&#39;ll Ever Learn</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-most-important-skill-youll-ever-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-most-important-skill-youll-ever-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Go eagerly where the fear is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are at a party. Across the snack table, you notice a small crowd gathering around an underdressed guy in jeans and a t-shirt. He turns out to be a well-known science-fiction book agent. Just the person you are looking to meet since finishing your novel. You want to talk to that person. But he looks busy, probably wouldn&#39;t appreciate &lt;em&gt;another &lt;/em&gt;awestruck peon, and you wouldn&#39;t get much talk time anyway. You are convinced it would be a waste of time. So you decide to ask the host for his e-mail address on your way out and write later. You have very good reasons not to introduce yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then...as you turn back to the friends you came with, you wonder, why are you even making reasons? You aren&#39;t making that effort for anyone else in the room. Just this one guy who it would be a great idea &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;to talk to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&#39;s when you know: if you leave this party without introducing yourself, you will leave defeated. You will have found exactly the thing that you need to do to move forward, and shied away from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The things you need to do to move forward are always the things you fear doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen to Your Intuition: It Could Save Your Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/listen-to-your-intuition-it-could-save-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/listen-to-your-intuition-it-could-save-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Listen to your intuition. It will tell you everything you need to know. - Anthony J. D&#39;Angelo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/brainhalves.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3144&#34; alt=&#34;brainhalves&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/brainhalves-300x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;He stood out among the other men at the table. He had a sense of practiced confidence about him, and whenever he spoke to the event facilitator--the only woman in the room--his responses seemed too playful, too well-rehearsed, and she laughed as if on cue. When it was his turn to introduce himself to the group, a label popped unsolicited into my head: pickup artist. I filed it to verify in time, and sure enough, he revealed that to be his background. Later during the workshop, he made vague reference to some challenges he was working on, without actually defining them. That voice in my head immediately supplied the details: trouble with commitment. Again, as the class progressed, he revealed that to be exactly his difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve never considered myself to be a great judge of people. In college, I&#39;d meet particularly jovial people at parties thinking they were simply really happy, only to be told later that they were obviously drunk. I figured that if I couldn&#39;t identify the telltale signs of something so blatant as drunkenness, I should never trust my judgements about people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Turn Fear into Inspiration</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-i-turn-fear-into-inspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-i-turn-fear-into-inspiration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/skull.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3084&#34; alt=&#34;skull&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/skull-202x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;202&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I&#39;ve been struggling with my mortality lately. Every few years, I go through periods of my life when I&#39;m hyperaware that I won&#39;t be around forever, that this is my only chance to live, and afterwards it will be Eternity of....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I&#39;m not unique in this way. All humans know they are going to die, and that awareness has been a driving force in human behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know how other people respond to that reality. I experience a compression of time, and all of a sudden, the decades between now and my death seem utterly trivial, the end as urgent and imminent as the next five minutes. It&#39;s really unpleasant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do believe in more compassionate explanations of existence than the walking-bag-of-chemical-reactions-becomes-worm-food. The Buddhist and Taoist concepts of universal oneness have a ring of truth to me. Of course, knowing that intellectually is very different from knowing it as a foundational principle of your worldview. Despite everything, I have to admit the dark, hopeless view often seems more real to me, even if it doesn&#39;t really make sense based on my beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This awareness of the &lt;a title=&#34;The Imminence of Death&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-immanence-of-death/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;imminence of death&lt;/a&gt; has been a defining feature of my life since I was very young. It has shaped my worldview and left a strong impression on my sense of values. For a long time, I simply accepted it as a terrible curse, but &lt;strong&gt;I eventually realized that I could choose what it meant to me&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I chose to to interpret it in a way that empowers me and allows me to be happy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Reasons...</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/5-reasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/5-reasons/</guid>
      <description>... you should do it.
1. Because you can Sometimes that&#39;s the best reason of all: your potential, and the drive to realize it. You know you can run farther, love more truthfully, lift heavier, earn more, learn more. You know that you can do better.
Yet, day after day, you find yourself in the same place you were yesterday, not living up to your potential.
This starts to irritate you, but you try to be grateful for what you have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practicing Courage Through Movement</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/practicing-courage-throught-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/practicing-courage-throught-movement/</guid>
      <description>Do one thing everyday that scares you. - Eleanor Roosevelt
 After practicing movement and martial arts for so long, I sometimes lose track of the reasons I started in the first place. Lately, I&#39;ve been on a bit of a hiatus, but I was able to get some training time in last weekend. The combination of time off plus the intensity of training reminded me of why I do this in the first place, and, more importantly, why I want to do this every single day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Just Face Your Fears, Learn to Love Them</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dont-just-face-your-fears-learn-to-love-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dont-just-face-your-fears-learn-to-love-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1203&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;epSos.de on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/epsos/4376727123/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1203&#34; title=&#34;Fear&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/Fear-300x168.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;168&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must not fear. Fear is the mind-killer. Fear is the little-death that brings total obliteration. I will face my fear. I will permit it to pass over me and through me. And when it has gone past I will turn the inner eye to see its path. Where the fear has gone there will be nothing. Only I will remain. &lt;em&gt;-Bene Gesserit Litany Against Fear, Frank Herbert&#39;s&lt;/em&gt; Dune&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say the thing that most scares us is the unfamiliar. We seem naturally wary of things that we don&#39;t know very well, even parts of ourselves that we haven&#39;t dealt with in a very long time. We also shy away from things we have simply never experienced before. Unfortunately, this includes many of the things we&#39;d like to live up to and achieve. So we have a problem; anyone who wants to grow and develop as a human being, to achieve their true potential (aka, their Warrior Spirit), must go from what they know, through what they don&#39;t know, and therefore, must face their fears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If Failure is Not An Option, You Won&#39;t Fail</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/if-failure-is-not-an-option-you-wont-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/if-failure-is-not-an-option-you-wont-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1030&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;wolfsavard on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wolfsavard/4716421032/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1030&#34; title=&#34;nets&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/nets-300x200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;Do or do not. There is no try.&#34; - &lt;em&gt;Yoda,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Return of the Jedi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently learned a back handspring, and a front flip, among some other more complex gymnastics moves. Every time I want to try one without my coach to spot me, he considers whether I&#39;m ready, nods and says, &#34;Alright, give it a shot. The chance of seriously injuring yourself is probably less than 60/40.&#34; He is joking, sort of, but it is true that many of the stunts I attempt are actually quite dangerous. And that is why I don&#39;t mess up. &lt;strong&gt;Without safety nets, I can&#39;t afford to fail.&lt;/strong&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
