<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>responsibility on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/responsibility/</link>
    <description>Recent content in responsibility on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/responsibility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Youthful Wisdom</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youthful-wisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youthful-wisdom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1277&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;gemsling on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gemsling/2620901357/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1277&#34; title=&#34;mature&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/mature-300x257.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;257&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Maturity has more to do with what types of experiences you&#39;ve had, and what you&#39;ve learned from them, and less to do with how many birthdays you&#39;ve celebrated.” - Anon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often tell me that I am exceptionally mature for my age. Ignoring the truthfulness of this statement, I&#39;ve always been curious what that means exactly. Generally, the implication is that adults are more mature than children, but even as a child, I knew several adults more emotionally unstable than I and who were far worse at taking care of themselves. That said, I also know a few youngsters who make me feel positively infantile. So how is it possible for a younger person to have more maturity than an older person?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Separating the (Young) Men from the Boys</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/separating-the-young-men-from-the-boys/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/separating-the-young-men-from-the-boys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/youngman.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-430&#34; title=&#34;youngman&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/youngman.jpg?w=207&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;207&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Growing up, my conception of what kind of man I would become was always very different from that of my peers. When I was in elementary school, I was emulating my idea of what responsible adults acted like, rather than trying to grow up to be like the high school kids. I didn&#39;t look forward to high school and college as times to party and sleep around, but instead as opportunities to start developing the skills and qualities I wanted to use as the foundation of my life as a responsible, formidable man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friends thought I was weird, and I thought I had made a huge mistake. I still wonder if I wouldn&#39;t have been better off just going with the flow and enjoying myself, instead of trying so hard to grow up.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
