<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>facing your fear on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/facing-your-fear/</link>
    <description>Recent content in facing your fear on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/facing-your-fear/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Just Face Your Fears, Learn to Love Them</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/dont-just-face-your-fears-learn-to-love-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/dont-just-face-your-fears-learn-to-love-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1203&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;epSos.de on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/epsos/4376727123/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1203&#34; title=&#34;Fear&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/Fear-300x168.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;168&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must not fear. Fear is the mind-killer. Fear is the little-death that brings total obliteration. I will face my fear. I will permit it to pass over me and through me. And when it has gone past I will turn the inner eye to see its path. Where the fear has gone there will be nothing. Only I will remain. &lt;em&gt;-Bene Gesserit Litany Against Fear, Frank Herbert&#39;s&lt;/em&gt; Dune&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say the thing that most scares us is the unfamiliar. We seem naturally wary of things that we don&#39;t know very well, even parts of ourselves that we haven&#39;t dealt with in a very long time. We also shy away from things we have simply never experienced before. Unfortunately, this includes many of the things we&#39;d like to live up to and achieve. So we have a problem; anyone who wants to grow and develop as a human being, to achieve their true potential (aka, their Warrior Spirit), must go from what they know, through what they don&#39;t know, and therefore, must face their fears.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
