<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>well-being on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/well-being/</link>
    <description>Recent content in well-being on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/well-being/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The One Thing You Can Do To Make Everything Better</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-one-thing-you-can-do-to-make-everything-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-one-thing-you-can-do-to-make-everything-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1850&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;tanakawho on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/28481088@N00/1069809120/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1850&#34; title=&#34;lotus&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/lotus-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He who has health, has hope. And he who has hope, has everything&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.thinkexist.com/quotation/he_who_has_health-has_hope-and_he_who_has_hope/149145.html&#34;&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;” - Proverb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Leave all the afternoon for exercise and recreation, which are as necessary as reading. I will rather say more necessary because health is worth more than learning.” - Thomas Jefferson&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the one thing you can do to improve almost every aspect of your life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be honest, I don’t know you, but the thing that makes the biggest difference in my day to day life is looking after my health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this means eating right, &lt;a title=&#34;Lessons Learned as a Trainer and Athlete&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/lessons-learned-as-a-trainer-and-athlete/&#34;&gt;exercising regularly and intensely&lt;/a&gt;, and getting enough sleep. It means I take my health into my own hands, instead of just accepting what the government or the media tells me. It’s your body; take the time to get to know it, what makes it happy, and what is good for it, instead of relying on people who have zero interest in your well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few of the really obvious effects looking after my health has had. Most of them have nothing to do with the body itself, but instead are reflections on the areas of life that we really live for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Time Spent Outdoors</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-benefits-of-time-spent-outdoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-benefits-of-time-spent-outdoors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_954&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;222&#34; caption=&#34;Source: ©Hεαṿεṉlÿ Phøτøģɾαρhÿ on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/oooheavenlyooo/3986200282/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-954&#34; title=&#34;nature&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/nature-222x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;222&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man&#39;s heart away from nature becomes hard.  &lt;em&gt;-Standing Bear&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The natural world is all around us. Every city is merely an island of human habitation amidst a vast sea of countryside and forests. A mere hour outside of New York, one of the biggest metropolises in the world, one can find beautiful and surprisingly isolated parks and hiking trails. The hills around LA are still pretty wild (apparently coyotes are a major concern out there). Most cities have parks, little spaces where the city&#39;s fabric is cut out to reveal the nature underneath, just waiting to burst through into sunlight. These are places people can go to escape the hustle of the city for a while. There is something calming and serene about nature. I always feel complete and more balanced when surrounded by trees, and there is a lot to be said for seeking out a regular connection with the outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
