<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>happiness on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/happiness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in happiness on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/happiness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wake Up: The Not-So-Secret Key to Happiness</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/wake-up-the-not-so-secret-key-to-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/wake-up-the-not-so-secret-key-to-happiness/</guid>
      <description>“People say that what we’re all seeking is a meaning for life. I don’t think that’s what we’re really seeking. I think that what we’re seeking is an experience of being alive, so that our life experiences on the purely physical plane will have resonances with our own innermost being and reality, so that we actually feel the rapture of being alive.”- Joseph Campbell
 We spend so much time worrying about the future or reliving the past that we rarely if ever experience the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Valuing Your Own Happiness Earns You More Respect</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-valuing-your-own-happiness-earns-you-more-respect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-valuing-your-own-happiness-earns-you-more-respect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;There is one thing that will destroy a person faster than anything else: inauthenticity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being devoted to a life that you do not have, instead of being present and engaged in the one that you do have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constantly putting off, day after day, the things you love.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never disagreeing for fear of offending.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing what you think you should. Being a ‘nice guy’ or a ‘good girl’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Living up to others expectations of you, instead of living up to your own standards for yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;The reason being inauthentic is so self-destructive is because it sends the message to yourself that your beliefs and principles aren&#39;t worth expressing, and therefore you aren&#39;t valuable or worth listening to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By presenting ourselves in a way that matches our values, however, we are telling ourselves and others that we think we are worthwhile.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;So, by simply doing the things we enjoy, saying the things we hold as true, and acting or presenting ourselves in the ways that reflect who we are, we can build our confidence and sense of purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Kinds of People, Three Kinds of Success. Which are You?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/three-kinds-of-people-three-kinds-of-success-which-are-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/three-kinds-of-people-three-kinds-of-success-which-are-you/</guid>
      <description>How do you define your personal success? When asked what you want in life, do you tell people the job you want to do, or the kind of company and environment you want to work for, or the effect you want to have on the world?
Yesterday, I was meeting with a mentor to figure out what I needed to do to be successful and happy in Boulder now that I&#39;ve quit my job, and to understand why I felt the need to quit my job in the first place (oh yeah, Mom and Dad, by the way, I quit my job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ingredients for an Excellent Day</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/ingredients-for-an-excellent-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/ingredients-for-an-excellent-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1691&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Advertise2win on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/advertise2win/5383858717/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1691&#34; title=&#34;happydog&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/happydog-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This dog is having a great day&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been trying to find a way to have consistently awesome days, and after much trial and error (most of it documented on this blog), I&#39;ve come up with the following list of activities that seem to contribute to days worth having. The elements are pretty open-ended, and allow for multiple interpretations or ways of meeting the requirements, but they help me make sure I cover all the important bases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are We Having Fun Yet?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/are-we-having-fun-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/are-we-having-fun-yet/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&#34;attachment_1557&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; caption=&#34;Dirceu Soares on Flickr&#34;][/caption]
Are you having fun?
I don&#39;t mean bounce-off-the-walls giddy. Nor do I mean partying until 3am every day.
But basically, do you enjoy your days? Do you get a kick out of your schedule? Do you have something interesting and new to excite you planned every day?
Do you want to get out of bed every morning?
A lot of my friends do not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happiness is a Choice</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/happiness-is-a-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/happiness-is-a-choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1199&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Jayel Aheram&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/aheram/2228606820/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1199&#34; title=&#34;smile&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/smile-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most People are about as happy as they make up their minds to be &lt;em&gt;- Abraham Lincoln&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/book-review-the-8020-principle/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The 80/20 Principle, &lt;/a&gt;I was struck by how many useful strategies are presented for increasing one&#39;s happiness. Having spent most of my young adult life pursuing happiness and learning what behaviors and life situations lead to happiness, I was not struck so much by the idea that you can cultivate happiness as by the new approaches to the old problem. I had always taken it for granted that I could be more or less happy, and that was in my control. So it came as a bit of a shock for me when the author spent the larger portion of the section on happiness trying to convince his readers that they happiness was something they could actually control. He cited all sorts of studies and authors showing that people have a say in their happiness level, that we are not simply at the mercy of circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life on a Whim</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/life-on-a-whim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/life-on-a-whim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; caption=&#34;Source: sea turtle on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3248/2875992891_14091ed494.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Happy Dog&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/2875992891_14091ed494.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve noticed that some of my best decisions are made on a whim. That is, the less I consider a decision, the better it turns out. My worst decisions are made with a minimum of consideration, and I made decent choices after careful thought. But the things that make me happiest tend to be done with zero forethought.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
