<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>careers on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/careers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in careers on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/careers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Outside the Box You Built Yourself</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/thinking-outside-the-box-you-built-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/thinking-outside-the-box-you-built-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1016&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;262&#34; caption=&#34;Steve Keys on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/boxes.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1016&#34; title=&#34;boxes&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/boxes-262x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;262&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There are people who put their dreams in a little box and say, &#34;Yes, I&#39;ve got dreams, of course I&#39;ve got dreams.&#34; Then they put the box away and bring it out once in awhile to look in it, and yep, they&#39;re still there.” -Emma Bombeck&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I was a little kid, I was taught that I could not support myself doing something fun that I loved. I would have to find a job that tediously &#39;contributed&#39; to society in order to make enough money so I&#39;d have the resources to spend my free time engaged in enjoyable &#39;hobbies&#39;. Life would always be a trade off between doing what you had to, based on what someone else deemed was a valuable use of your time, and doing what you wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&#39;ve begun to question the assumption that doing something you enjoy is a poor way to make money. Of course, if you&#39;re really lucky, you&#39;ll end up in a job you love, so money-making will be bearable, but the emphasis was on fitting yourself into a job, rather than the other way around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Should Blow it All to Travel</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-you-should-blow-it-all-to-travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-you-should-blow-it-all-to-travel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_743&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: DragonWoman on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/dragonwoman/31029572/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-743 &#34; title=&#34;china&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/china.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We know that travel is essential to a complete education. Traveling abroad teaches understanding of other people, cultures and communities, and these types of experiences offer young people a greater ability to be successful in today&#39;s global society. &lt;em&gt;- Michael Palmer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An old friend from my days interning at Forbes gave me some interesting advice today. As a well-established manager, she would have been able to make a very good argument for starting to seriously look at a career, putting down professional roots, building up my financial profile and really setting myself up for the long, steady path to independence and security. Instead, she pretty much recommended I risk it all and travel, try to work in some other countries, because, after all at my age and in this economic climate, there isn&#39;t much to lose. &lt;strong&gt;Take the big risks while you&#39;re young&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
