<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>minimalism on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/minimalism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in minimalism on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/minimalism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is Enough for You?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/what-is-enough-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/what-is-enough-for-you/</guid>
      <description>If you could boil your day down to one or two things, what would they be?
Yesterday, Anna and I met a father and husband in Boulder on a very unfortunate errand: bailing his 22-year-old son out of jail. He shared all sorts of stories about his life, his long marriage, and his career. He had spent time as a developer for schools, then as a contractor, but his real passion, he said, was restoring antique furniture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less is More in Health: Minimalist Hygiene Tips</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/save-money-be-really-healthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/save-money-be-really-healthy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/6508860689_92a82bb284.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2819&#34; alt=&#34;A Simple Glass of Water&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/6508860689_92a82bb284.jpg&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“As you simplify your life, the laws of the universe will be simpler; solitude will not be solitude, poverty will not be poverty, nor weakness weakness.” - Henry David Thoreau&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s no surprise to followers of ancestral living that, when it comes to health, less is often more. Of course, we mean less of the right things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;Less additives&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;Less sugar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;Less processing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less cushioning in our shoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less furniture (remember the evils of sitting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, we like living as close to our natural state as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote &lt;a title=&#34;The 6 Strangest Health Habits&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-6-strangest-health-habits/&#34;&gt;a post&lt;/a&gt; a while back about about my strange health habits that have made a big difference for me, and I realized that many of them also helped me save money. I used to have quite a lot of hygiene products in my never-ending attempts to maintain a healthy body. These included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;handsoap&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;bodywash&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;shampoo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;conditioner&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;shaving cream&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;aftershave&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;shaving razors and refills&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;laundry detergent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;dishwashing detergent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chemical deodorant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized that I was spending a lot of money on products that are basically unnecessary. Even eco-friendly products often have a lot of unnecessary stuff in them, and of course the &#39;green&#39; label justifies charging more for them. It didn&#39;t make sense to me that humans needed such complex chemicals just to stay clean. So I started learning about alternatives and DIY-recipes. I&#39;ve since reduced my products down to the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Merits of Minimalism</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-merits-of-minimalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-merits-of-minimalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1736&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;striatic on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/striatic/729822/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1736&#34; title=&#34;stuff&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/stuff-300x297.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;297&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have spent the last week helping my family move our home, which is partly why I&#39;ve been remiss in posting for so long. We are downsizing because the kids are out of the nest (even though I still live at home and my sister just moved back after college. Go figure). My parents are trying to save space and money, but doing so required us to come to grips with the fact that we have tons of stuff, massive quantities of things we didn&#39;t even remember we owned, from all over the world, much of it outdated and unusable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons in Minimalism from Camping</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/lessons-in-minimalism-from-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/lessons-in-minimalism-from-camping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1564&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; caption=&#34;f_r_e on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/garrulus/1743162782/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1564 &#34; title=&#34;backpack&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/backpack.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was but a wee lad, my dad used to drag me kicking and screaming into the woods to partake in an activity which, due to its lack of video games, easily available chocolate, and LEGOs, I was not too keen on. That activity was camping. As a kid, I hated it. Now, it is necessary to my spiritual well-being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Warrior Spirit</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-warrior-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-warrior-spirit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Hello World&#34;]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/20110331-213409.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/20110331-213409.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20110331-213409.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d like to inject a little more of me into my posts. After all, this blog was started by me as a sort of online journal. I was reluctant to assume that all my readers found my life all that interesting, but I thought I&#39;d just write about it. I am a storyteller, after all, not just an essayist. Since the story I know best is my own, I wanted to tell that story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the way, I got swept up by all these other great blogs that also tell stories, but which also provide lots of useful information besides. Somehow, the information stuck out more than the stories, and I focused on that. As a result, I feel that Warrior Spirit has kind of drifted from being personal to trying too hard to be useful. The result I think has been less connection with my readers. The blog has grown and grown, and for that I&#39;m thankful, but I feel a little like I&#39;ve sold out (except without the monetary rewards).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&#39;m going to try to tell more of my stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving Up the Nonessential</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/giving-up-the-nonessential/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/giving-up-the-nonessential/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Koalazymonkey on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2558/3707160352_114df38f61_z.jpg?zz=1&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3707160352_114df38f61_z.jpg?zz=1&#34; title=&#34;Blank Notebook&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last week, I&#39;ve sold my laptop and replaced it with an Apple iPad 2. This leaves me without a regular computer capable of such basic functions as running flash programs, storing more than a few hours of music and video, and playing the most interesting games out there. Instead, I&#39;ve got myself a tiny, super light tablet about 10&#34; large that I can take anywhere. And, even more important, I have no distractions anymore.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Fight For</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/what-i-fight-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/what-i-fight-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1251&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Beverly and Pack on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/walkadog/3560722399/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1251&#34; title=&#34;raising the flag&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/raising-the-flag-300x214.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is the observation here that our cause is the cause of all mankind, and that we are fighting for their liberty in defending our own” - Benjamin Franklin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout history, societies have always gone through cycles of establishment and revolution. The established order, originally meant as liberating, starts to become oppressive in its attempts to institutionalize itself. In turn, revolutionaries rise to oppose the system, to assert individuality and reinstate the balance. Sometimes they fail, sometimes they are incorporated into the existing order, and sometimes they overthrow the current order and establish their own system. We are at a time of revolution, though it is a quiet one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Branding Our Lives</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/branding-our-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/branding-our-lives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;mceTemp&#34; style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1039&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;194&#34; caption=&#34;Call to Adventure on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/logobaby.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1039&#34; title=&#34;logobaby&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/logobaby-194x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;194&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;It’s time to stop this madness. The corporation is a hungry beast, and we keep feeding it. Let’s walk away, and let it die from hunger. Let’s free ourselves, and create a world where living things are more important than profits.&#34; &lt;em&gt;-Leo Babauta, &lt;a href=&#34;http://mnmlist.com/corporations/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mnmlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make all your own food. Buy all your manufactured goods from individual craftsmen. Learn how to sew and knit. Do your own repairs. Build your own furniture or buy it from a local carpenter. Don&#39;t buy the latest fashion trends. Exercise on your own, at home, with no or very little equipment. Entertain yourself instead of watching TV and movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most Americans find these suggestions inconvenient, if not downright unpatriotic. We are conditioned to rely on corporations for our stuff and livelihoods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zen Habits Handbook for Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/zen-habits-handbook-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/zen-habits-handbook-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_950&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: kristofabrath on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kristofabrath/3206231510/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-950&#34; title=&#34;zen&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/zen-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smile, breathe, and go slowly &lt;em&gt;- Thich Nhat Hanh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when I was in college, drowning under the immense workload and the complexities of balancing my social life, personal life, and scholastic commitments, I stumbled upon a blog that saved my academic standing as well as my sanity. The blog is called Zen Habits, and it was a godsend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimalism in Writing: Getting to the Point</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/minimalism-in-writing-getting-to-the-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/minimalism-in-writing-getting-to-the-point/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/06/typewriter.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-628&#34; title=&#34;typewriter&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/typewriter.jpg?w=226&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;226&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I love to write. People know this about me, and my parents have long encouraged the habit. As a result, I used to get a lot of writing-themed books as gifts. One particular type of book always made me feel inadequate as a writer: speciality dictionaries, full of strange and esoteric words (even more esoteric than &#39;esoteric&#39;) that a well-educated shaper of the English language ought to master and use in everyday speech. The problem was, I didn&#39;t really care to learn all these new words. So the books sat on my shelf, collecting dust, because I kept telling myself that, one day, I&#39;d get around to memorizing all these new, important words and incorporating them into my writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m glad I never did.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Minimalist Warrior</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-minimalist-warrior/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-minimalist-warrior/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/lotus.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-523&#34; title=&#34;lotus&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/lotus.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;198&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I&#39;ve been playing God of War II (a video game, for the un-initiated). In this game, the main character, Kratos, begins the game as the recently appointed god of war, replacing Ares. He has all sorts of powers, wears nifty armor, and has a lot going on in his life. But he is not satisfied. Then, Zeus betrays him. There is a scene of Kratos&#39; armor falling apart, leaving him with nothing but a loincloth, some boots, and his weapons, which is the state he goes through most of the game in. He has a single purpose at that point: to enact vengeance on Zeus. Kratos is a relatively small guy, as far as Greek heroes go - in a face off with Theseus, the Thebian towers over Kratos. Most of Kratos&#39; enemies are decked out in fancy armor, carry ridiculous weapons (usually turned on them by the plucky Spartan), and have access to all sorts of assistance and special powers. Kratos is a minimalist. He powers his way through his environment, using his physical strength and his mental cunning, two simple blades, and little else.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
