<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jobhunting on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/jobhunting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jobhunting on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/jobhunting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why I Left My Job: To Start Again</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-i-left-my-job-to-start-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-i-left-my-job-to-start-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1177&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Stevie Rocco on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stevier/4114137266/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1177&#34; title=&#34;road&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/road-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To learn something new, take the path that you took yesterday.” - John Burroughs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was my last day at the CrossFit gym where I had worked for the past year as a coach and personal trainer. I decided several weeks ago to leave the gym and pursue other opportunities on my own, and I finally took the step of leaving. It was a difficult decision, not so much because of financial reasons, but more because I loved working with the amazing athletes and dedicated individuals who came to train with us. Nevertheless, I am excited to be moving forward with my plans, even though there is a great degree of apprehension regarding my financial security. I feel that sometimes we have to pull apart everything we&#39;ve built for ourselves to build something new, or backtrack the path we&#39;ve already been down to look for new turn-offs with a better idea of where we want to go this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Story</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/KhaledPortrait.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1068&#34; title=&#34;KhaledPortrait&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/KhaledPortrait-300x224.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;224&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“Today you are You, that is truer than true. There is no one alive who is Youer than You.” - Dr. Seuss&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the responses I got from all of you on that &lt;a href=&#34;http://polldaddy.com/s/444345CCC43313A2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;survey &lt;/a&gt;I sent out, most of the interest in what I write comes from knowing me. So I thought I&#39;d write out my story, so those of you who didn&#39;t know me before the blog can understand where I&#39;m coming from, where I get my stories and interpretations, and why I care so much about standing up to mediocrity and forging my own destiny.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Be Afraid to Reach for Your Goals</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dont-be-afraid-to-reach-for-your-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dont-be-afraid-to-reach-for-your-goals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_746&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: ~dip on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/dip108/388012741/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-746&#34; title=&#34;hand&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/hand-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People have a lot of preconceived notions about what they deserve: what they deserve to be called, what they deserve to have, what they deserve to be paid, who they deserve to love and be loved by. We set limits on our own potential, not because we want to hold ourselves back, but rather because we think it is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/why-we-love-the-status-quo/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;just way&lt;/a&gt;. The thought pattern might go like this: &#34;I&#39;ve only been writing regularly for a few weeks, so I don&#39;t deserve a published novel.&#34; &lt;strong&gt;Ironically, people often are afraid to reach for their goals, because they don&#39;t think they are worthy of them&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: normal;&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Should Blow it All to Travel</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-you-should-blow-it-all-to-travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-you-should-blow-it-all-to-travel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_743&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: DragonWoman on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/dragonwoman/31029572/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-743 &#34; title=&#34;china&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/china.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We know that travel is essential to a complete education. Traveling abroad teaches understanding of other people, cultures and communities, and these types of experiences offer young people a greater ability to be successful in today&#39;s global society. &lt;em&gt;- Michael Palmer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An old friend from my days interning at Forbes gave me some interesting advice today. As a well-established manager, she would have been able to make a very good argument for starting to seriously look at a career, putting down professional roots, building up my financial profile and really setting myself up for the long, steady path to independence and security. Instead, she pretty much recommended I risk it all and travel, try to work in some other countries, because, after all at my age and in this economic climate, there isn&#39;t much to lose. &lt;strong&gt;Take the big risks while you&#39;re young&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
