<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>leadership on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in leadership on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Be Accepted as a Leader</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-be-accepted-as-a-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-be-accepted-as-a-leader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3944&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/125H-e1424150911303.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;125H&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;288&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#34;I&#39;m the one chance you&#39;ve got of staying alive.&#34; - Clara Oswald, &lt;em&gt;Doctor Who&lt;/em&gt;, Season 8, &lt;em&gt;Flatline&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you&#39;ve run into this problem: You want to make a difference in the world by inspiring, motivating, and supporting the people around you, but you aren&#39;t in charge. You don&#39;t feel like anyone is paying attention to your ideas or giving you permission to start a new project that might take the business in a new direction, or even start a new company that would change the face of the town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you just keep on working at whatever you do, coloring in the lines, and dreaming about the day you get to take a stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a difficult place to be because you have great ideas and strong convictions, but you are afraid that if you take action on them, you will upset people. You aren&#39;t sure if they are happy where they are, and even if they aren&#39;t, change is always scary. You don&#39;t want to be the one to bring that on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the thing is, while change is scary, it is also inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might as well be the one to direct it and help people grow with it, rather than resist and stagnate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how can you get over the leadership hump to get others on board and make a difference?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Turned Down a Dream Job</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-i-turned-down-a-dream-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-i-turned-down-a-dream-job/</guid>
      <description>I was recently offered what seemed on the surface like a great job opportunity. It would have solved all my money problems, set me up for a good four or five years, and been a great resume builder.
But I said no.
It was not an easy decision. There&#39;s so much in our culture prioritizing money and career advancement. A solid, steady income often trumps all other concerns, and we usually excuse our friends and family for blowing off commitments because of work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six Practical Tips to be More Present and Engaged</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/six-practical-tips-to-be-more-present-and-engaged/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/six-practical-tips-to-be-more-present-and-engaged/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The greatest gift you can give someone is your attention&lt;/strong&gt;. Everything else follows from that. Being present is the key to developing an irresistible presence, but staying totally engaged is exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no shortcut--you have to build that mental muscle through directed practice and commit to using it--but there are some things you can do to make it a little easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Little Chieftain; Are You Waiting for Permission to Live?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-little-chieftain-are-you-waiting-for-permission-to-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-little-chieftain-are-you-waiting-for-permission-to-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/4822540384_173d27437c.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2834&#34; alt=&#34;The Chief&#39;s Headdress&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/4822540384_173d27437c.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;334&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The once was a tribe of people living in an ancient land. They chose from among their number one to lead them, a chief, who was the most skilled in hunting, diplomacy, and wisdom. He or she was to be a beacon for the tribe, a person to inspire a sense of belonging and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One year, as the current chief was dying, there were two candidates to replace her. Both boys were truly skilled in the art of warriorship, and both possessed wisdom beyond their years. They were of the same age, at the cusp of manhood, but one still acted like a little boy. He felt like someone or something had to give him permission to be a man. The other acted as if manhood were already his. He took an air of fatherhood around the children and acted like an equal among the elders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, the tribe still had trouble deciding, for both boys were exceptionally skilled and passed all the tests of intellect and insight. After a long day being interviewed, the two of them found themselves alone in the chief&#39;s room, the elders having retired to discuss. Sitting in the back of the room were the chieftain&#39;s robes and headdress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As boys are wont to do, they grew curious about that which is forbidden them, and finally they decided try on these magical garments. They had been fashioned for an adult, and clearly would fit neither boy, but they wanted to feel what it would be like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first boy threw the robe around his scrawny shoulders and lowered the headdress over his brow. His friend only barely managed to stifle a laugh, and truly the boy in the robes felt strange and uncomfortable. He hunched, as if trying to get away from the feathers that adorned his head. They robes didn&#39;t fit, physically or otherwise, but he assumed they would feel more comfortable over time, just as his bow had felt awkward until he had taken it on several hunts. He knew that if he were selected, the tribe&#39;s permission would give him the certainty he needed to fill the outfit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the other boy donned the garb, and the large robe slipped down his narrow shoulders. But when the first boy looked on his friend smiling and standing tall under the too-large headdress, he saw that this boy wore the cloak and feathers like they were already his. The way he stood, the way he bore them proudly instead of uncertainly, said that he could already see himself as the chief. Perhaps there were skills to be learned, but this boy was not shy of being called chief and being looked to for guidance. Though the garb didn&#39;t fit physically, it seemed to belong to this boy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first boy told his friend what he saw and he left the room to tell the elders he was withdrawing. And the little chief who had always been a chief led his tribe on to many great victories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;I’m Moving to Boulder&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/im-moving-to-boulder/&#34;&gt;Having arrived in Boulder&lt;/a&gt;, I set about trying to establish a life here. Income was (is) hard to come by. I live in a shared apartment, and I&#39;ve applied to a lot of part-time jobs to try to get things started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Live What You Preach: Maintaining Faith in my Move to Boulder&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/live-what-you-preach-maintaining-faith-in-my-move-to-boulder/&#34;&gt;It&#39;s pretty scary sometimes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I met a guy, not even my age, who goes to work in a suit and tie, who owns his own condo, and who doesn&#39;t just work because he needs a bit of money as he sets up for his next step, but who is a contributing member of society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I am quite mature in regards to psychology, emotional intelligence, and personal integrity, but &lt;strong&gt;in terms of my material prosperity, I still envision my life like a student, someone dependent, in transition.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
