<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self-improvement on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/self-improvement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in self-improvement on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/self-improvement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re Not Broken, So You Can&#39;t &#34;Fix&#34; Yourself</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youre-not-broken-so-you-cant-fix-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youre-not-broken-so-you-cant-fix-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When a computer gets old and starts to slow down, we know it is time to buy a new one. Computers can&#39;t grow, learn, or adapt, so once they have outlived their usefulness, developed too many bugs, or are simply broken, we scrap them. This makes sense because a computer performs a specific function, and if it can&#39;t do that, it is useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine for a moment if we treated humans like that. Wouldn&#39;t it be stupid if we just gave up on people or ourselves because of one or two bugs that tripped them up every now and then? Totally ridiculous, right? People, after all, grow and adapt. We can learn, and even if we are slow to learn, we can make adjustments for our weaknesses in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/3774175_73285f84a9.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2540&#34; title=&#34;Baby Jane&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3774175_73285f84a9-300x212.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;212&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yet, many people view themselves through the same standards they assess their computers, cars, and refrigerators.&lt;/strong&gt; Unfortunately, you can&#39;t just go out and buy a new psych, so what course of action is called for when you believe you are non-functional?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How we view life and ourselves determines how successful we will be in dealing with its challenges, and choosing to view ourselves through this particular lens does more harm than good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quit Your Whining</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/quit-your-whining/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/quit-your-whining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1951&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; caption=&#34;kaibara87 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kaibara/3496249511/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1951&#34; title=&#34;Whiny Cat&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3496249511_2d194b807f.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your intention everyday just to survive? Is your intention everyday just to make it through the world, because your interpretation is &#39;the world is so hard, so stressful, so chaotic, I hope I can just get through this day&#39;? Because if that&#39;s where you&#39;re at, that identity for you is small. - Brendon Burchard&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to whine...a lot. Practically every word out of my mouth was a complaint of some kind. I was either talking about my frustration over my homework load, kvetching over the constant barrage of e-mails, or just going on about random aches and pains and fatigue. The only information I had to share with anyone was about how something was bothering me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hardly conscious of my behavior; whining just seemed to be the natural thing to say, and after all, it seemed to me that most conversations were based around complaining. People would get together after work to basically whine about the difficult week. Guys would bond over complaining about their girlfriends, and women would commiserate over the poor quality of men in their lives. Most of the student conversations I heard were about academic frustration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I was not pleasant to be around, and my family made this very clear to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t want to be that guy nobody invites to parties (I was already that guy, and knew it wasn&#39;t fun). I didn&#39;t want to be the guy nobody could rely on who couldn&#39;t handle his own life. So I resolved to change what I thought was a seemingly simple habit of conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no idea how deep it went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rule I instituted was: if what I am about to say is something negative and simply expresses how I feel bad about something, with no suggestion of actually fixing the problem, I will keep my mouth shut.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With only moderate self-control, I did very well at this. It was merely a matter of keeping my lips sealed. Sometimes I found I had nothing to contribute to conversations, but at least I wasn&#39;t bringing people down anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I made a horrifying discovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Linchpin; and, How to Create a Self-Study Course to Master Anything</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-linchpin-and-how-to-create-a-self-study-course-to-master-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-linchpin-and-how-to-create-a-self-study-course-to-master-anything/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&#34;attachment_1872&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Vola Vale on Flickr&#34;][/caption]
“The best contribution one can make to humanity is to improve oneself.” - Anon
 I’ve always felt that learning is one of the best ways to improve oneself (I guess you could get philosophical and point out that self-improvement is essentially learning in one form or another). Reading books is one of the best ways to learn, which is why I include a lot of book reviews here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Can&#39;t You Have What You Want?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-cant-you-have-what-you-want/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-cant-you-have-what-you-want/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1750&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;AZRainman on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/azrainman/992631266/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1750&#34; title=&#34;Reach for the Clouds&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/reachfortheclouds-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day I find myself surrounded by people who are unhappy with their lot in life. They don&#39;t have the body they want, the job they want, the partner they want, or the skills they want. Every day they want to be something they aren&#39;t, and every day instad of making progress towards their dreams, they distract themselves or rationalize away their inability to have what they want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn to Love Pain</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learn-to-love-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learn-to-love-pain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1593&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Nathan Phillips on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/npphoto/4383990220/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1593&#34; title=&#34;pain&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/pain-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you could get past pain and discomfort by  accepting it and relaxing into it? I don’t mean that the pain goes away,  but rather that you become okay with it. You still feel it, but it  doesn’t bother you. You can get on with whatever it is you’re doing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
