<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>korea on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/korea/</link>
    <description>Recent content in korea on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/korea/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Epic Tale of the Triumph of Will Over Utter Stupidity</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/an-epic-tale-of-the-triumph-of-will-over-utter-stupidity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/an-epic-tale-of-the-triumph-of-will-over-utter-stupidity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on the travel blog I kept while living in Korea.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/DSC_4519-e1331562897868.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had pretty much given up around the 20km mark. My left arch had been cramping since I passed 10km and my feet felt like the road was molten asphalt. I was still moving my feet, but it was more of a shuffle as I gingerly placed each step carefully to avoid even the tiniest jolt to my worn out suspension. I glared resentfully at every pair of cushy, padded, motion-controlled sneakers that cruised by me, their owners floating on a soft cloud of running technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had wondered if running a marathon in my &#39;barefoot&#39; Merrell Trailgloves was a good idea, but it turned out to be much worse than I had imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was only my second marathon. The first one I had run in racing flats, and I didn&#39;t think there would be too much difference, but it turns out half an inch of foam was the difference between crippling pain and a challenging run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had also had a running partner the first time. My dad and I had jogged steadily around the streets of Philly, chatting and sharing observations about the city. Here, in South Korea, I was running alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I talked myself into putting one foot in front of the other. Somehow, I made it through the twenties and starting chipping away at kilometer 30, then 31, then 32. Each one seemed longer than the one before. With every...single...step my body wanted to stand still. &#34;Please let me walk, just two steps. I&#39;ll do anything!&#34; it begged me. Still I ran.&lt;img title=&#34;More...&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/trans.gif&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Seon Templestay in Korea</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-seon-templestay-in-korea/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-seon-templestay-in-korea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we get too caught up in the busyness of the world, we lose connection with one another - and ourselves. - Jack Kornfield&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2851&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;717&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSC_9400-Version-2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-2851 &#34; alt=&#34;Photo credit: Anna &amp;quot;Rocketpack&amp;quot; Pusack&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/DSC_9400-Version-2-1024x685.jpg&#34; width=&#34;717&#34; height=&#34;479&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photo credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rocketpackphoto.com&#34;&gt;Anna &#34;Rocketpack&#34; Pusack&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke abruptly in a pitch dark cell, wrapped in pre-dawn silence. Suddenly, the distant wooden bell that had woken me rang out again, accompanied by the ghostly chanting of a Korean Seon (Zen) monk whose duty it was to rouse fellow monks, visiting foreigners, and stubborn Korean teenagers. The sounds faded quickly, swallowed by the forests and mountains around us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was 4:00am. The world gave no indication that morning was in the schedule. I had come here exactly for the discipline of this simple temple life, but even I found it difficult to rouse myself this early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bell and the chanting monk came closer, moving out of the mystical realm into the waking world. It was time to get up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I folded my blankets, pulled on my jacket, slid out the heavy wooden door of my sleeping cell, and started up the mountain to join the others in a session of Buddhist chanting and meditation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stepping into a small, close shrine, I took my place at a meditation cushion. My girlfriend and I had been taught the day before how to do the introductory bows, and we went through them now, knees and backs aching. Soon, everyone had arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A monk rang a clapper and all was silent. Then, as abrupt and distinct as the lone wooden bell, chanting rang out and engulfed the room. We were carried away in its driving, insistent rhythm that thrummed like a force of nature through our bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spirit of Buddha awoke within us like a lotus, coaxed from sleep by the relentless, comforting chants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So began my templestay at Golgulsa Temple in Gyeong-ju, South Korea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned from a Year Living and Working in Korea</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-learned-from-a-year-living-and-working-in-korea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-learned-from-a-year-living-and-working-in-korea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;My year in Korea has come to its end. Friday was my last teaching day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I have done in the past, I like to look back as this chapter of my life comes to a close and review what I&#39;ve learned. Putting the experiences into a larger context helps me learn from my mistakes and consolidate my successes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot has happened in my first year of living completely independent of my parents, in a country that is literally on the other side of the world from my hometown. Here is what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since Joseph Campbell writes about the hero&#39;s journey, I thought he would be especially appropriate to help illustrate reflection on this rite of passage. So, this is a Campbell-themed post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livin&#39; La Vida Expat</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/livin-la-vida-expat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/livin-la-vida-expat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/3901537243_085c10c684.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2054&#34; title=&#34;Expat Living&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3901537243_085c10c684-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“Never write about a place until you&#39;re away from it, because that gives you perspective.&#34; -Ernest Hemingway&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an American expat living in South Korea. Glamourous, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up as an expat living in Kuwait and Dubai. My American dad hung out with Arabs and Westerners alike, so we had friends from all over. My sister and I went to an American school and were taught English at the expense of Arabic (actually, many wealthy Arabs sent their kids to the American school as well. It was the trendy thing to do). While most kids might have spent their lazy summers playing baseball at the neighborhood park or just playing in the street, we spent every day rambling around exclusive beach clubs. We were able to afford luxuries that we wouldn&#39;t have been able to have in the States, like a live-in nanny. I grew accustomed to a lifestyle that was very different from what I&#39;d find in America when we &#39;returned&#39;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Vintage Expat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I&#39;m a complete nerd, the word expat brings to mind &lt;strong&gt;Ernest Hemingway&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Gertrude Stein&lt;/strong&gt;, chilling at cafes in Paris where they can be &lt;a title=&#34;Get Out of the Box!&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/get-out-of-the-box/&#34;&gt;free to think&lt;/a&gt; their own thoughts which eventually find their way back home to change society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I&#39;m &lt;a title=&#34;We’re Going to Make It&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/were-going-to-make-it/&#34;&gt;living in Korea&lt;/a&gt;, I realize that the reality is more like my childhood in the Middle East. Being an expat is about escaping responsibility and living it up. It involves a surprising amount of alcohol (though I&#39;m sure Hemingway, at least, did not limit his imbibing to dainty French coffees), and a lot of partying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think this perception is limited to my experience in Korea. I just finished John Wood&#39;s book, &lt;em&gt;Leaving Microsoft to Change the World,&lt;/em&gt; and the author shares his commentary on the lifestyle of Microsoft expats living in Sydney and Beijing, which is one of &lt;strong&gt;glamour&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;escapism&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;entitlement&lt;/strong&gt;. Those who epitomize the lifestyle do it because they can live the high life, making a relatively high income and taking advantage of favorable economics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Wood&#39;s case, he and his girlfriend were both emblematic of the expat lifestyle in China. As a Microsoft employee, Wood had plenty of money, and living in China, which was less developed than it is today, he was able to have all sorts of luxuries he wouldn&#39;t get otherwise, such as a personal driver. His girlfriend had come from the rural Midwest and was so hooked on the glamorous life that she refused to go on vacations that didn&#39;t involve resorts and 4-star hotels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think I would be going too far to suggest that for many, living abroad is seen as an extended vacation with perks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing wrong with that, and if it occurs in a context of &lt;a title=&#34;Empty Your Cup: Accepting Ignorance to Learn&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/empty-your-cup-accepting-ignorance-to-learn/&#34;&gt;learning new perspectives&lt;/a&gt; living in a new country, all the better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six-Month Assessment: Now the Fun Starts</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/six-month-assessment-now-the-fun-starts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/six-month-assessment-now-the-fun-starts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“You’re on your own, and you know what you know, and you are the guy who’ll decide where to go” -- Dr. Seuss, Oh the Places You’ll Go!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve been living, on our own, in Korea for 6 months at this point, which is one half of our planned stay.  More than being a cultural experience, these past months have been an exploration of personal growth. My girlfriend and I have learned a lot about choosing our own paths and the little things that make a self-directed life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sure many of you are wondering how we’re doing at this critical juncture.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
