<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>commericial on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/commericial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in commericial on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/commericial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why I Left Paleo Behind, and Why I&#39;m Returning</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-i-left-paleo-behind-and-why-im-returning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-i-left-paleo-behind-and-why-im-returning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/3234878244_e7e5dbef88.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2338&#34; title=&#34;Walking Away&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3234878244_e7e5dbef88-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;They are asking us to pay more for less shoe, calling it a &#39;barefoot&#39; shoe, and we are happily handing over the money! -- Bryant Rolfe, to me, on a trail run with our new $100 Merrell Trailgloves&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got into Paleo, I came through Mark Sisson&#39;s Primal Blueprint. The MDA community was never exclusively about diet, but focused on a &lt;em&gt;lifestyle&lt;/em&gt; of health, vitality, and playfulness. Sure it was a bit tongue-in-cheek and insular, but it was a community with plenty of room for whatever your views might be. There were the hardcore, live-in-the-woods-naked eco-warriors, and there were those who simply wanted to sneak their Vibrams into their cubicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, I thought I ought to grow up and go Paleo. Primal seemed like a softer version of the real deal. I attended a Whole9 workshop at my CrossFit box. It didn&#39;t entirely mesh with what I knew about nutrition at the time from my study of Weston A. Price principles and the Primal Blueprint, but I signed on (since then, our beliefs about nutrition have come closer together). As my whole box went into it together, I was swept into the world of Paleo eating and CrossFit exercise, &lt;a title=&#34;Fitness is Not Health&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/fitness-is-not-health/&#34;&gt;two movements totally divorced from a holistic view on life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&#39;m sure the blame lies in how I implemented things, not in the methods themselves, but the way I saw the methods being presented, it didn&#39;t seem like there was much leeway. The segment of the community I was in, which I took to represent all of it, was decidedly narrow-minded.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
