<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>selfishness on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/selfishness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in selfishness on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/selfishness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When Is It Selfish to Help Others?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/when-is-it-selfish-to-help-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/when-is-it-selfish-to-help-others/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1924&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;234&#34; caption=&#34;UmmZ on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/34143066@N08/3381849047/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1924&#34; title=&#34;help&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3381849047_fc03a73068-234x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;234&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most significant lesson I ever learned in trust-based relationships is that all anybody asks for is respect. If you give them that, you have extended the greatest sign of love and compassion there is. If you don’t give them respect, you’re not really loving them. You’re simply looking after them, attached to them, or maybe even taking advantage of them in some way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you think this is obvious, but consider how many times we ‘love’ without giving respect: parents taking care of their children with no concern for what the child wants; codependent couples using each other to bolster their own self-esteem; men and women with a need to rescue their partner or be a hero; friends who hang out together because they look better in comparison to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;True respect, true compassion, involves the recognition that the other person is a complete, functional, human being&lt;/strong&gt;. Even if they need help in some things, they are still complete beings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
