<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>serve and protect on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/serve-and-protect/</link>
    <description>Recent content in serve and protect on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/serve-and-protect/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sheep, Wolves, and Sheepdogs</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/sheep-wolves-and-sheepdogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/sheep-wolves-and-sheepdogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the young shepherd lay asleep in the sun, his flock grazed peacefully on the lush slopes of the valley, nibbling on clover, alfalfa, and fescue. Their round bodies dotted the mountainside like so many clouds, merging and parting like the real things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without warning, two young wolves burst out of the forest and loped towards the flock. Sheep started bleating in panic and colliding in their panic to escape. The wolves drove right to its center, hoping to scatter it so they could pick off one or two stragglers who got caught in the open, but when the sheep parted, the hunters stopped dead. Waiting for them in the space they&#39;d cleared was a beast of a dog. It&#39;s white shaggy coat blended in with the sheep and so it had been guarding the herd from the inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sheepdog rose to its feet and stared at the wolves. Though it was big, it was still only a dog, and these wolves were wild and dangerous. Muzzles wrinkled back in growls, the three sized each other up. Two to one was not good odds, but the sheepdog did not back away. The wolves, realizing their advantage, stepped forward, heads held low to the ground, long yellow teeth bared. Still the sheepdog did not move but only raised its hackles.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
