<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inspirational on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/inspirational/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inspirational on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/inspirational/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ll Never Be Good Enough...Until You Are</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youll-never-be-good-enough-until-you-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youll-never-be-good-enough-until-you-are/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/05/barbell.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-574&#34; title=&#34;barbell&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/barbell.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;221&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an athlete, one of the most common de-motivators I deal with is the assertion, made either by myself or well-meaning friends trying to help me deal with frustration at limited progress, that professional and Olympic athletes (those I aspire to be like) are genetic abnormalities. Thus, I should not expect myself to perform at their level, and should not hold myself to similar expectations of progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, I have agreed with this statement. After all, I&#39;m just a genetically average human, right? Even with all the determination in the world (and I have plenty of that) I just don&#39;t have the right bone length, muscle fiber ratios, metabolic eccentricities, to make it to the big leagues. So I shouldn&#39;t even try, and certainly not become frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I realized I have no idea what my genetic make-up is. For all I know, I am an Olympic sprinter who just needs the right training to unleash his genetic potential. People tell me I&#39;m too tall to be a gymnast, too lanky to be a good lifter, but there have been unlikely champions in every sport imaginable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Perfect Day</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-perfect-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-perfect-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/100_0038.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-548&#34; title=&#34;A beautiful sunset&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/100_0038.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;So, I thought I&#39;d set down exactly where I want to end up in 10 years or so, so I can at least have a bit of direction, and know what I ought to be doing in my life to set myself on the right road, rather than just bump around aimlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Predawn Meditation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wake up just before dawn, energized and alert, in a house I built, and throw on a handmade parka before heading out the door barefoot and going for an early morning jog through the forest, which is only a few hundred yards from my front door. The air is damp but cool. I jog about ten minutes to my favorite rock overlooking a valley, facing the rising sun, where I sit and meditate as the sun comes up. I&#39;m cold, but it doesn&#39;t bother me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jogging back, I stop on the way to feed the chickens and the goats wandering the yard. The dog is awake by now, but not the rest of the family, and he comes out to help me rouse the animals, playfully yipping at the goats and nudging the sleepy hens. While I&#39;m out, I check the nests for eggs for breakfast. I finish tending to the animals and head inside to start preparing breakfast for the kids and the wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrity: There is more to Life than Winning...There&#39;s being Awesome!</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-there-is-more-to-life-than-winning-theres-being-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-there-is-more-to-life-than-winning-theres-being-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/handstand.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-493&#34; title=&#34;handstand&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/handstand.jpg?w=199&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Since the CrossFit sectionals I&#39;ve been feeling considerably less motivated about my training. You&#39;d think that making it to regionals would give me a message that I have some potential, and that I should work hard to realize it. Instead, I feel oppressed by the prospect of competing again. All my training is geared towards this one event, an event that has a very narrow definition of success (even by the standards of CrossFit), and in which I will undoubtedly be one of the smallest, puniest, guys there. Maybe I&#39;m over-dramatizing here, but I definitely feel like an underdog - I&#39;m young, relatively weak (most guys at these things can deadlift 400+ lbs, I&#39;m around 315lb on a good day), and pretty inexperienced. If it&#39;s all about who can move the most weight, I&#39;m screwed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traits of a Warrior: Persistence</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-persistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/penguin.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-489&#34; title=&#34;penguin&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/penguin.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;222&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, the workout at my gym was to determine at what weight you could do 10 non-stop power cleans (move a barbell from floor to shoulder in one motion). At 165lbs, my form began to slip and I dragged the knurled bar up my shins, several times, leaving my legs bloody and stinging. I failed the set, only getting 9. Pretty upset with myself, I went to the bathroom to clean up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was taping up my leg, I was thinking about calling it a day. But looking at my leg, I realized there wasn&#39;t any actual damage. All I&#39;d done was scrape some skin, and while it stung, it had no impact on my muscles&#39; ability to perform. I covered the wound in tape to protect it, and got back on the pad, and did the full set as if nothing had happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of times in our lives when we suffer dramatic and painful failures. Our usual response is to throw in the towel, grudgingly accept that we did our best, and nurse our wounded egos. But when we look back, it is clear that our egos were the only things that were really injured by our setback. Our ability to complete the task at hand has not been diminished in any way, we simply have decided, arbitrarily, that we have failed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Toughness, and the CrossFit Northeast Sectionals</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/mental-toughness-and-the-crossfit-northeast-sectionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/mental-toughness-and-the-crossfit-northeast-sectionals/</guid>
      <description>I just got back from two days of the most intense physical and mental challenges of my life, the CrossFit Northeast Sectionals, the first step on the road to the 2010 CrossFit games, the winners of which are considered the fittest man and woman on Earth.
I&#39;m too tired right now to write a detailed play-by-play, so right now, I just want to share some thoughts.
I was certainly one of the smaller guys going into this competition, and I have only been CrossFitting for a little over a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Point of the Clock</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-point-of-the-clock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-point-of-the-clock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/clock.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-462&#34; title=&#34;clock&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/clock.jpg?w=199&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, after our workout, Kristi, my coach, Nick, a fellow CrossFitter, and myself stuck around to discuss the upcoming sectionals.  Somewhere in the discussion, the topic of different gyms&#39; methodologies came up. The other Stamford-based CrossFit gym, Hybrid Fitness, believes that extreme strength is pretty much the fundamental requirement for a good athelete. As such, they utilize a lot of strongman programming and training. We do not, and generally we aren&#39;t as strong on average. Does that mean we are worse than them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Things Can Happen to Good People</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/bad-things-can-happen-to-good-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/bad-things-can-happen-to-good-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/accident.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-459&#34; title=&#34;accident&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/accident.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A lot of people who restrict their diet for the sake of health have little to console themselves with when they must forgo all the little pleasures in life. All they can do is remind themselves that they will be spared the debilitating chronic diseases that will likely afflict their less-disciplined friends. Unfortunetly (or not) it isn&#39;t that simple. Sometimes, those of us with the healthiest of habits end up the victim while our chain smoking, sugar-munching friends live their whole lives without the smallest issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just One Bite Won&#39;t Hurt, Will It?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/just-one-bite-wont-hurt-will-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/just-one-bite-wont-hurt-will-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/cake.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-452&#34; title=&#34;cake&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/cake.jpg?w=225&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Working at Zara has gotten me thinking about the ethical place of fashion (what, you mean you don&#39;t develop philosophical treatises when you fold clothes?). Basically, my dilemma is this: should I invest my time and money in looking stylish and thus promoting myself socially, potentially leading to financial and personal success as a result of my social finesse, or should I spare the environment and my checkbook by only buying functional, practical, and minimal clothing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epic Fail</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/epic-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/epic-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/failure.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-438&#34; title=&#34;failure&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/failure.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, I failed epically. The workout for today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many rounds as possible, in 10 minutes, of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 deadlifts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 hang cleans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 front squats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 push jerks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All with 95 lbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, it&#39;s a ton of work, and much of it involving very technical movements. I was aiming to complete 7 rounds (so 49 of everything) because the previous record was 6 and change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I completed 6 rounds with about a minute and a half left. I was already dying. My vision was blurry and my legs felt like jelly, but I pushed through the sets. I got to the push jerks with 30 seconds left and without taking any rest, started into them. As the clock ticked to 0 seconds, I became distanced from my body, aware of but not feeling the burning in every muscle (a sensation that I had never experienced before), until the very last rep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acknowledging My Spiritual Debts</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/acknowledging-my-spiritual-debts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/acknowledging-my-spiritual-debts/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&#34;attachment_427&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;180&#34; caption=&#34;Martin Prechtel&#34;][/caption]
An old friend sent me a link to a really profound article yesterday. The article is an interview with a Pueblo-turned-Mayan-shaman, Martin Prechtel. In the interview Prechtel discusses his relationship with the spiritual world of indigenous cultures that have a respect for, and connection to, the land and environment around them. He also draws some really ominous connections between the utter lack - some would say, outright denial - of spirituality in Western civilization and the cultural malaise we experience in the form of endemic depression, poverty, loneliness, and even physical ailment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons I&#39;ve Learned</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-ive-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lessons-ive-learned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/lesson.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-419&#34; title=&#34;lesson&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/lesson.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sometimes the lessons you learn are harsh, and sometimes they are just surprising, but there is no point in denying reality. So here are a few partially inconvenient truths I&#39;ve managed to internalize over the past few years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traits of a Warrior: Service</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout history, Warriors have been the guardians of their societies. They do not train and fight for the sake of it, or for senseless violence. Historical warriors have learned the arts of war in order to better protect their people and families, or to extend their reach of their chosen sovereign. Tribal warriors were the ones who put their lives on the line to defend their families. Knights and Samurai were the ones willing to die for their lords&#39; agenda.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
