<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>willpower on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/willpower/</link>
    <description>Recent content in willpower on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/willpower/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Willpower</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-willpower/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-willpower/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/willpowerbook.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-1796&#34; title=&#34;willpowerbook&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/willpowerbook.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;144&#34; height=&#34;220&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Life is full of paradox. Eating fat doesn’t make you fat. Running in shoes can be bad for your feet. Giving yourself free reign to express your every desire and emotion can mire your personal growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last one will require some explanation, especially since there is a lot of talk here on Warrior Spirit about the importance of listening to your heart and following your dreams, no matter what comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve just finished a book summarizing the psychological research on the topic of willpower and self-control. The book, &lt;em&gt;Willpower, &lt;/em&gt;by psychologists Roy F. Baumeister and John Tierney, is rife with examples of how the failure to set and follow limitations leads to a breakdown of character. It is mainly a survey of the research, but what makes it readable is the authors’ sincere interest in helping the reader, and the interviews with such characters as endurance artist David Blaine (who spent 63 hours encased in a block of ice in Times Square) and Amanda Palmer (known for her tabloid-friendly outbursts). The authors also draw examples on how willpower can be utilized from Ophrah, Eric Clapton and Henry Morton Stanley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epic Fail</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/epic-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/epic-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/failure.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-438&#34; title=&#34;failure&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/failure.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, I failed epically. The workout for today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many rounds as possible, in 10 minutes, of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 deadlifts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 hang cleans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 front squats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 push jerks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All with 95 lbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, it&#39;s a ton of work, and much of it involving very technical movements. I was aiming to complete 7 rounds (so 49 of everything) because the previous record was 6 and change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I completed 6 rounds with about a minute and a half left. I was already dying. My vision was blurry and my legs felt like jelly, but I pushed through the sets. I got to the push jerks with 30 seconds left and without taking any rest, started into them. As the clock ticked to 0 seconds, I became distanced from my body, aware of but not feeling the burning in every muscle (a sensation that I had never experienced before), until the very last rep.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
