<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>authenticity on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/authenticity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in authenticity on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/authenticity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why I Turned Down a Dream Job</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-i-turned-down-a-dream-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-i-turned-down-a-dream-job/</guid>
      <description>I was recently offered what seemed on the surface like a great job opportunity. It would have solved all my money problems, set me up for a good four or five years, and been a great resume builder.
But I said no.
It was not an easy decision. There&#39;s so much in our culture prioritizing money and career advancement. A solid, steady income often trumps all other concerns, and we usually excuse our friends and family for blowing off commitments because of work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Should be Unreasonable</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-you-should-be-unreasonable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-you-should-be-unreasonable/</guid>
      <description>What do people really mean when they say, &#34;Be reasonable!&#34;?
&#34;Don&#39;t do anything that will get you noticed. Play nice. Keep quiet. Stay normal, unobtrusive, inoffensive, and as safe and risk-free as possible.&#34;
But unreasonable people, who just ask for what they want, who don&#39;t tamp themselves down to fit in and avoid making waves...we are jealous of them. Why is that?
Because they break all the rules. Because they act freely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want to Be Irresistable? Be Authentic</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/want-to-grab-someones-attention-be-authentic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/want-to-grab-someones-attention-be-authentic/</guid>
      <description>The email exercise that went out last week was on the idea of developing your unique presence, that intangible quality that makes someone irresistible and inspiring.
The question ultimately comes down to whether you are engaged in the moment--are you present?--or whether you spend most of your time in your head, worrying, speculating, and second-guessing yourself.
If you do the latter, you can experience life fully and live in HD. You hold the key to happiness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life is Not a Dare. Don&#39;t Make it One</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/life-is-not-a-dare-dont-make-it-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/life-is-not-a-dare-dont-make-it-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just because a challenge exists doesn&#39;t mean we have to overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoah there! That doesn&#39;t sound like the indomitable Warrior Spirit, you might be thinking. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was training CrossFit, I remember putting off the training I wanted to be doing (gymnastics, martial arts, parkour, hiking and climbing) for the training I had been convinced was more hardcore/intense/effective/respectable. I was trying to win someone else&#39;s game for a prize I didn&#39;t even care about, just because it was a challenge issued in a way that got my attention and I have a demon about always being the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my quest to be great at fitness, I adopted CrossFit&#39;s standards and tried to master them, even though the end goal wasn&#39;t what I wanted. I kept telling myself that I would get around to the stuff I really cared about...once I finished this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, this approach to fitness was just one symptom of a deeper tendency to take everything as a challenge. Someone driving an expensive car was a dare to do better. Some guy walking down the street better dressed than I was a challenge. It was toxic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to live in the best city (which was always somewhere I was not)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to have the best girlfriend, which varied between hot, pretty, smart, independent, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to do the most important, best paying job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to be the best looking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to be the most spiritual, and the most patient&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to make the most money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these &#39;bests&#39; were things other people defined, or society in general defined. What made me happy and the &#39;best&#39; were not the same thing. And when I would occasionally attain &#39;the best,&#39; it was only a matter of time before someone else or some other segment of society would issue a new dare, and I&#39;d be dissatisfied again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Valuing Your Own Happiness Earns You More Respect</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-valuing-your-own-happiness-earns-you-more-respect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-valuing-your-own-happiness-earns-you-more-respect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;There is one thing that will destroy a person faster than anything else: inauthenticity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being devoted to a life that you do not have, instead of being present and engaged in the one that you do have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constantly putting off, day after day, the things you love.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never disagreeing for fear of offending.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing what you think you should. Being a ‘nice guy’ or a ‘good girl’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Living up to others expectations of you, instead of living up to your own standards for yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;The reason being inauthentic is so self-destructive is because it sends the message to yourself that your beliefs and principles aren&#39;t worth expressing, and therefore you aren&#39;t valuable or worth listening to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By presenting ourselves in a way that matches our values, however, we are telling ourselves and others that we think we are worthwhile.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;So, by simply doing the things we enjoy, saying the things we hold as true, and acting or presenting ourselves in the ways that reflect who we are, we can build our confidence and sense of purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret of Authentic Confidence</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-secret-of-authentic-confidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-secret-of-authentic-confidence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“When people do not respect us we are sharply offended; yet deep down in his private heart no man much respects himself.” -Mark Twain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life&#39;s eternal question: Do you gain self-respect when your worth is proven in the world, or do you prove your worth by cultivating honest self-respect? And can you fake it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve noticed a harmful trend in personal development literature, in every field from entrepreneurship to dating, recommending over-the-top confidence, arrogance, and sometimes outright lying. In an attempt to get shy quiet types like me to actually sell ourselves, these gurus assure us that pushy sales tactics are a perfectly legitimate way to interact with people. We need to get over our sqeamishness and man-up, whether it&#39;s bulldozing a client to close a deal or asserting dominance to &#39;pick up&#39; a date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I disagree. I think that kind of arrogance is symptomatic of people who lack real confidence and so have to rely on a facade of bravado.&lt;/strong&gt; There is certainly value in rehearsal, routines, and templates, but these should serve as a framework to human interaction, not the basis of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Built-in BS Detector&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t think anyone can tell the difference? The human brain is really good at making judgement about other people based on subtle body language clues that give away a person&#39;s true character. For example, after watching a 30 second silent clip of a teacher interacting with a student, research subjects were able to predict how well the teacher would do on their evaluation at the end of the semester. Similar results were found with political candidates (2 seconds of exposure) and doctors facing malpractice suits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is, we&#39;re really good at telling when people are inauthentic. (Whether we give credence to what we detect and actually act on our instinct is a matter of &lt;a title=&#34;Listen to Your Intuition: It Could Save Your Life&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/listen-to-your-intuition-it-could-save-your-life/&#34;&gt;trusting your intuition&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fake It &#39;til You Make It&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I&#39;ve also noticed that people tend to assume you have an accurate idea of your own value. That is, if you act like you&#39;re &#34;kind of a big deal,&#34; they&#39;ll treat you that way unless circumstances prove otherwise (they may still challenge or test you to check if you&#39;re bluffing, so don&#39;t actually lie). &lt;strong&gt;If you act like you&#39;re not capable or worthy of respect and responsibility, others will treat you accordingly, even if you&#39;re actual accomplishments suggest otherwise&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can I Preach It, if I Don&#39;t Live It?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/can-i-preach-it-if-i-dont-live-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/can-i-preach-it-if-i-dont-live-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1606&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;226&#34; caption=&#34;Mike Cattell on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mikecattell/4411829834/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1606&#34; title=&#34;pews&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/pews-226x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;226&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be too easy to be perfect all the time. It is  far more difficult to accept that you’re not perfect but to believe  that you have worthwhile things to say despite that, and to say those  things with conviction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the last two weeks, I’d been in a bit of a rut.  Things that used to excite me didn’t appeal to me anymore. Exercise,  gymnastics, trail running, and even writing all seemed tedious and  boring. All I wanted to do all day was go home and sleep, and when I got  home, I didn’t want to sleep. I was just generally out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also seemed to be messing up everything good in my life.  Professionally, I’d given up a lot of hours training to work on my  writing, with the result that I was pretty broke. My  iPad-as-laptop-replacement experiment was a failure, so I had to buy a  new laptop. My relationship with my girlfriend was in a rough patch,  which just makes everything else seems hellish. I wasn’t sleeping well,  and all I wanted to eat was peanut butter and jelly sandwiches, which  was a problem because I don’t keep jelly at my house and most bread  gives me indigestion. My room was a mess, and I was out of clean  underwear and floss (surprisingly discouraging, actually).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to say that things have improved, though I still  need to invest in some floss, but I wanted to talk a little bit about  the weirdness of being an inspirational writer and not always feeling  inspired.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
