<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>career success on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/career-success/</link>
    <description>Recent content in career success on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/career-success/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Traits of a Warrior: Persistence</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/traits-of-a-warrior-persistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/penguin.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-489&#34; title=&#34;penguin&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/penguin.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;222&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, the workout at my gym was to determine at what weight you could do 10 non-stop power cleans (move a barbell from floor to shoulder in one motion). At 165lbs, my form began to slip and I dragged the knurled bar up my shins, several times, leaving my legs bloody and stinging. I failed the set, only getting 9. Pretty upset with myself, I went to the bathroom to clean up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was taping up my leg, I was thinking about calling it a day. But looking at my leg, I realized there wasn&#39;t any actual damage. All I&#39;d done was scrape some skin, and while it stung, it had no impact on my muscles&#39; ability to perform. I covered the wound in tape to protect it, and got back on the pad, and did the full set as if nothing had happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of times in our lives when we suffer dramatic and painful failures. Our usual response is to throw in the towel, grudgingly accept that we did our best, and nurse our wounded egos. But when we look back, it is clear that our egos were the only things that were really injured by our setback. Our ability to complete the task at hand has not been diminished in any way, we simply have decided, arbitrarily, that we have failed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
