<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>passion on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/passion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in passion on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/passion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Hard Way to Do Anything Right</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-hard-way-to-do-anything-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-hard-way-to-do-anything-right/</guid>
      <description>What a discouraging headline for a blog post, right? Stick with me though, I promise you&#39;ll have something interesting to think about.
When I was transforming my fitness and my body, I had absolutely no clue what I was doing. I cringe remembering all the things I did wrong and all the ways I could have hurt myself.
But I also remember how determined I was. I was willing to do anything and everything necessary to accomplish my goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Post: Letting Go of Distractions to Simply Do What You Love</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/guest-post-letting-go-of-distractions-to-simply-do-what-you-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/guest-post-letting-go-of-distractions-to-simply-do-what-you-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3834&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/karatekick.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;karatekick&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a reader story from Claire Higgins, a coach, yoga instructor, and martial artist who is sharing her story of returning to the core of her passion for training: Karate itself. It&#39;s a great story illustrating how easy it can be to get pulled off track from doing the things we love in the name of supporting the things we love (like the classic case of a parent working so hard they don&#39;t see their family, justifying it all by saying it&#39;s for the family&#39;s well-being, when in fact, all they want is to spend more time together).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I entered personal training to get fitter for Karate (it was CrossFit inspired). Soon, I was expected to work out several times a week on top of a demanding Karate schedule, dedicated yoga practice and teaching, and driving 4 hrs a day for my last (very stressful) job. So I built a home gym, complete with an olympic bar that I didn&#39;t use often enough as I was so exhausted. My Karate performance improved a lot but I was so tired I felt miserable at training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal trainer was fabulous but my aim was never to get better at lifting or scoring bigger numbers. It was to swing a faster punch, build more stamina, and develop more explosive speed so that I could get my 2nd dan. My Karate teacher smiled patiently at me, explaining that the heavier weights, hanging, and handstands wouldn&#39;t help there. He recommended lighter weights, faster reps, and working out THROUGH Karate training, not FOR it. But for some reason, I couldn&#39;t yet change my mindset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Millennial Manifesto: The Responsibility to be Great</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-millennial-manifesto-the-passion-of-a-new-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-millennial-manifesto-the-passion-of-a-new-generation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are the Millennials. Constantly connected, over-educated, and fired with passion, we have been accused of laziness, entitlement, and narcissism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we are to inherit the world, a world that is more and more defined by change: entire business platforms rise and fall in the course of a few months. I have no doubt that history repeats itself, but with over 7 billion people, nations with the power to manufacture unfathomable quantities of goods, and an information network that rivals the human brain, I feel justified in saying &lt;strong&gt;the world we inherit will be unique in human history&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Brave New World&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all the negative adjectives thrown our way, one thing I have seen among my peers is a truly inspiring degree of passion, a desire to remake the world, to set their own rules and live by their own principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a powerful vision of a world far different than the one we were born into. Many of us have become distrustful of established power structures. We have seen the green revolution co-opted by corporate interests. Growing up in a globalized world has revealed to us that we cannot blindly pursue power without thought for the repercussions on the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything is vulnerable to questioning now&lt;/strong&gt;, and so many of my friends are unsatisfied with what life has given them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And lets be honest, life hasn&#39;t give them much. Youth unemployment in the US ranges from 20%-30% (depending on the study and the criteria), an abysmally high number. We are underemployed, not unemployable. We came of age into a world that didn&#39;t have a place for us, that couldn&#39;t utilize us, that expects us to wait idly on the sidelines and be grateful for placeholders like internships and volunteerism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That, right there, that&#39;s the sense of entitlement we&#39;re accused of. But shall we instead deign to accept meager returns? &lt;strong&gt;I think it&#39;s better to constantly be chafing at the bit, &lt;a title=&#34;Grow to Live: Why Constant Improvement is Necessary&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/grow-to-live-why-constant-improvement-is-necessary/&#34;&gt;striving for more&lt;/a&gt; and the chance to make an impact.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a way, Warrior Spirit is a blog for millennials: it admits a sense of higher purpose, the right to excellence, and even the &lt;a title=&#34;Are You in the 1%? You Should Be&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/are-you-in-the-1-you-should-be/&#34;&gt;responsibility to be great&lt;/a&gt;. At the same time, it asserts the importance of getting your hands dirty, doing the nitty-gritty, and having the pragmatic know-how to make our vision of the world a reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Passion Isn&#39;t Enough</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/passion-vs-skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/passion-vs-skill/</guid>
      <description>The three great essentials to achieve anything worth while are: Hard work, Stick-to-itiveness, and Common sense. - Thomas Edison
 No matter how determined you are in weightlifting or any sport, there are limits to your strength that are determined by your training. If you&#39;re a beginning lifter, it doesn&#39;t matter how badly you want it, you&#39;re not lifting 500lbs.
No matter how badly you want something or how hard you&#39;re willing to try, you can&#39;t get by on passion and verve alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Find Your Bliss: 3 Questions to Ask Yourself</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-find-your-bliss-3-questions-to-ask-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-find-your-bliss-3-questions-to-ask-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_3068&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/WDS2013.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-3068&#34; alt=&#34;Happy dancers at the closing party for WDS21013&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/WDS2013-300x199.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Happy dancers at the closing party for WDS21013[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s all well and good to tell people to follow their bliss, but how do you find the thing in the first place? If you haven&#39;t been following it, it probably wandered off years ago and is lost in someone&#39;s backyard howling all alone because you didn&#39;t follow it on the epic exploration of the neighborhood that would have led you to meet that cute neighbor you&#39;d fall in love with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, anyway, clearly you need to find it so you can follow it on to other adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the last weekend at the World Domination Summit, organized by Chris Guillebeau of &lt;a title=&#34;The Art of Non-Conformity&#34; href=&#34;http://chrisguillebeau.com/3x5/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Art of Non-Conformity&lt;/a&gt;, where I was inundated by awesomely inspiring speakers and ideas. As the name implies, the World Domination Summit is a gathering of people intent of making a big impact on the world by living fearlessly and pursuing their remarkable dreams in a conventional world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one of the talks was specifically about how to find your passion or purpose, but several of the speakers touched on the topic. Three ideas in particular seemed especially actionable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering a New Passion in Cooking</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/discovering-a-new-passion-in-cooking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/discovering-a-new-passion-in-cooking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2882&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;574&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSC_1430.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-2882  &#34; alt=&#34;Oh yes, I made that. More importantly, I can do it again&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/DSC_1430-1024x685.jpg&#34; width=&#34;574&#34; height=&#34;383&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Oh yes, I made that. More importantly, I can do it again[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve never considered myself a culinary person. I was never very good at picking up my mom&#39;s recipes as a kid, and I needed a cookbook and a measuring spoon to prepare grilled cheese (I&#39;m not exaggerating at all).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when I became more insistent on healthy eating in college, I had to learn basic cooking technique; if you insist on whole foods, you need to be able to prepare them yourself. This resulted in a lot of stir-fries at first. The only animal I was comfortable handling was fish. I slowly added a simple recipe and a few techniques to my repertoire (mostly via hurried phone calls to my mom, who demonstrated an amazing ability to rescue even my most ill-conceived cooking adventures).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned to cook red meat, I learned to braise, I learned to roast and broil and sauté. I learned knife technique and how to poach an egg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And then, somewhere along the line, I stopped looking up recipes&lt;/strong&gt;. Instead, I would imagine what I wanted to eat and mentally map out the steps to get there, complete with sequence of ingredients, temperature, cook times, heating techniques, and spices. I had done enough trial and error (the errors stuck the most) that I had created a cooking toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t realize I had crossed into amateur chefdom until recently, when I was able to have an informed conversation with a French-trained chef about flavor combinations and methods of preparation and ingredient quality. I think that may have been &lt;a title=&#34;Lessons Learned About Landing a Job in Boulder&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/lessons-learned-about-landing-a-job-in-boulder/&#34;&gt;why he hired me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I realized the recipes I was coming up with were getting fairly complex. Whereas before I might have settled on broiling a fish fillet and some chopped vegetables, now I was browning spiced chicken, caramelizing brussel sprouts, braising them for an hour in ale, and then crisping them under the broiler for the last 10 minutes, just because it seemed like it would be tasty that way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
