<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>children on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/children/</link>
    <description>Recent content in children on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/children/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5 Stories of A Little Boy in Nature</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/5-stories-of-a-little-boy-in-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/5-stories-of-a-little-boy-in-nature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSC_1618.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter  wp-image-2874&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_1618&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/DSC_1618-1024x685.jpg&#34; width=&#34;574&#34; height=&#34;383&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up this morning and sat on the edge of my futon to meditate, A&#39;s breathing setting the backdrop for my own deeper, regulated breath. I had finally managed to wake up early enough that the apartment was silent; there were no dogs scrabbling around in the kitchen, and our roommate was still asleep as well. I was determined to make the most of this time when it would be easier to focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After sitting, I picked up a book I&#39;d been intending to start for months, &lt;i&gt;Last Child in the Woods.&lt;/i&gt; I read a few pages into the first chapter, remembering stories my dad used to tell about exploring the forest just outside town, hunting squirrels with a rifle. The book is about the epidemic of what the author calls, &#34;nature deficit disorder,&#34; a condition arising from a severe and notable lack of interaction with the natural world in children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to think about my own experiences with nature and came up with very little. I had hated leaving my precious computer games and Nintendo as a child, but when I really thought about it, I did spend quite a lot of time outdoors. Some of my strongest memories were formed in the natural world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love Working with Kids</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-i-love-working-with-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-i-love-working-with-kids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1001&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;are you my rik? on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/areyoumyrik/308908809/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1001&#34; title=&#34;kids&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/kids-300x228.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;228&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I really need to know about how to live and what to do and how to be I learned in kindergarten. Wisdom was not at the top of the graduate school mountain, but there in the sand pile at school. &lt;em&gt;- Robert Fulghum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children give you a lot of perspective on life. They are impossible to keep in order, except when you do seemingly trivial and silly things. They seem very rude and uncouth most of the time, but the best way to get them to do what you want is simply to ask nicely. They remind you what&#39;s important in life, and the importance of friends, food, and enough rest. They also teach you how to appreciate the little things in life, like the wonder of floating on a surfboard in the sun (something I find endlessly tedious) and how stupid things can be really, legitimately funny.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
