<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mentors on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/mentors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mentors on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/mentors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Find Mentors</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-find-mentors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-find-mentors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3950&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/mentor-e1424929492734.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mentor&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;303&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an individual, you can accomplish a lot, but no matter what, you will always be limited by your available time and experience. Being able to learn from other people&#39;s experiences, wisdom, and skills is the key to fast-tracking your growth and capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mentors who have gathered around me have been so valuable in helping me move forward, take initiative, and untangle the many complex problems I&#39;ve faced starting businesses and creating positive change in my community. But I&#39;m not the only person for whom mentors have been important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of you probably know I&#39;m a history buff, and one of my favorite kinds of books to read is biography. This summer, I read &lt;em&gt;Titan, &lt;/em&gt;the biography of J. D. Rockefeller, this fall I read &lt;em&gt;Jobs,&lt;/em&gt; and I&#39;m currently about halfway through &lt;i&gt;The Autobiography of Andrew Carnegie.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all massively influential people who had far-reaching impact not only on their own times, but on future generations as well. And, even if they wouldn&#39;t admit it (Steve Jobs, maybe), they all had great mentors. Rockefeller and Carnegie gushed about the generosity of their mentors, and Carnegie in particular spoke of his early employer as the ideal of businessmen. The men who helped Rockefeller and Carnegie take their first steps in their careers were remembered fondly by both men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentors matter. They provide guidance when you are trying to figure out how to solve a problem. They provide motivation when you have to check in. They provide connections to their own networks as you are beginning to grow. They provide opportunity, often simply by giving you a place or a job to gain experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can get someone else to contribute a little bit of their hard-won experience to your own enthusiastic but naive efforts, you will leapfrog past many of the obstacles that slow others down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, mentors are vital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how do you go about surrounding yourself with a network of supportive people have both the desire and the ability to help you succeed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn to Stand Alone</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learn-to-stand-alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learn-to-stand-alone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_998&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;faungg on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/44534236@N00/3255156612/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-998&#34; title=&#34;tree&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/tree-300x201.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;Never tell your problems to anyone...20% don&#39;t care and the other 80% are glad you have them..&#34; &lt;em&gt;- Lou Holtz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most frustrating aspects of life is that whenever you become passionate about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/dont-be-afraid-to-reach-for-your-goals/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;pursuing some extraordinary goal&lt;/a&gt; or lifestyle, people waste no time in trying to hold you back. I find it odd that people rarely go out of their way to encourage your ambitions, but they will eagerly jump into a conversation to provide reasons you are wrong, might fail, or wasting your time. Especially if they have to change some aspect of their lives to accommodate you, they will do their utmost to convince you that your desire to run off and contribute to world peace will absolutely end their livliehoods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
