<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>presence on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/presence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in presence on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/presence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Six Practical Tips to be More Present and Engaged</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/six-practical-tips-to-be-more-present-and-engaged/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/six-practical-tips-to-be-more-present-and-engaged/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The greatest gift you can give someone is your attention&lt;/strong&gt;. Everything else follows from that. Being present is the key to developing an irresistible presence, but staying totally engaged is exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no shortcut--you have to build that mental muscle through directed practice and commit to using it--but there are some things you can do to make it a little easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Magical Power of Attention, Your Most Valuable Asset</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-magical-power-of-attention-your-most-valuable-asset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-magical-power-of-attention-your-most-valuable-asset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of us don&#39;t realize how powerful and valuable our attention is. As a result, we let it leak away and rarely bother to develop it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it so powerful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you put your attention on grows.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim Ferriss made this point in The 4-Hour Body when he showed that simply tracking your weight daily, without even attempting to make changes, led to consistent weight loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not necessarily saying there is some magical energy created by humans concentrating on specific things. It probably has to do with small micro-behaviors that start to accumulate when we have something in the forefront of our mind. Maybe constantly thinking about your weight leads your brain to subtly adjust weight-loss metabolic processes or change your appetite in small ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or maybe humans are magical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If You Don&#39;t Show Up, Life Won&#39;t Either</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/if-you-dont-show-up-life-wont-either/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/if-you-dont-show-up-life-wont-either/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Work is love made visible. - Khalil Gibran&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have run into two conflicting theories on how success works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You get lucky. Opportunities come along or they don&#39;t. You have to be in the right place at the right time or you just won&#39;t get very far. Some people have it, and some people don&#39;t.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Success is entirely dependent on your willingness to put in hard work and dedicate yourself to accomplishing what you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who lean on the first explanation usually don&#39;t see themselves as very abundant or successful. They feel a lot of frustration around their lives and their dreams, and so they claim that it&#39;s all luck to shirk responsibility for what they see as failing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a friend who has done really well, but he gives off a constant anxiety about losing it all. He uses the &#34;I got lucky&#34; argument in a way that absolves him of responsibility for his success, but my guess is he also doesn&#39;t want to think it would be his fault if things don&#39;t turn out well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other option is a more empowering viewpoint, but it is also often used to offer excuses. For example, insisting your success is based purely on your hard work might give you permission to ignore others&#39; needs and the realities of the world (market demands, consumer interests, quality of your services, importance of outside help and connections, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, of course there&#39;s a balance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want to Be Irresistable? Be Authentic</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/want-to-grab-someones-attention-be-authentic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/want-to-grab-someones-attention-be-authentic/</guid>
      <description>The email exercise that went out last week was on the idea of developing your unique presence, that intangible quality that makes someone irresistible and inspiring.
The question ultimately comes down to whether you are engaged in the moment--are you present?--or whether you spend most of your time in your head, worrying, speculating, and second-guessing yourself.
If you do the latter, you can experience life fully and live in HD. You hold the key to happiness.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
