<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nature on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/nature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nature on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/nature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Distraction and Fascination</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/distraction-and-fascination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/distraction-and-fascination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/fascinated.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2981&#34; alt=&#34;fascinated&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/fascinated.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;387&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature presents the young with something so much greater than they are; it offers an environment where they can easily contemplate infinity and eternity. - Richard Louv, &lt;em&gt;Last Child in the Woods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine two children. Both are staring wide-eyed at something, utterly entranced, mouths slightly open. Now back up from each kid and add some context: the first is staring at a TV set, and the second is staring at &lt;a title=&#34;5 Stories of A Little Boy in Nature&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/5-stories-of-a-little-boy-in-nature/&#34;&gt;a spider weaving its web&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between nature observation and watching TV?&lt;/strong&gt; Both involve sitting motionless for long periods of time, observing something else, without much interaction on your part beyond the sensory, and letting your mind get carried off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But one is distracting while one is fascinating, and I think that is an important distinction to make.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his book, &lt;em&gt;Last Child in the Woods, &lt;/em&gt;Richard Louv introduced me to the concept of fascination as that thing a natural setting does to children who have the free time and access to explore it. Fascination is what happens when children&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build tree houses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;play in the mud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;climb trees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make crowns out of daisies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or just lie in the grass and watch the clouds blow by</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lifting the Veil</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lifting-the-veil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/lifting-the-veil/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I was asked the question, &#34;Do you direct your experiences, or allow experiences to happen to you?&#34;
I had to pick an answer in the middle somewhere, because while I normally feel that I should take an active role in my life, lately I have felt that I am intended as an instrument for something. When I am doing the &#39;wrong&#39; thing, my life seems very difficult, like swimming upstream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Us vs. Nature: The Need for Understanding</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/usvnature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/usvnature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1427&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/100_0067.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1427&#34; title=&#34;Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/100_0067-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we had no choice but to destroy the natural world or destroy ourselves, which do you think we would pick? Let’s say that Nature has decided she has had enough. She won’t kill us outright, but she has determined to eliminate all aspects of our unsustainable lives, which means she sends her warriors to take out our property, vehicles, and infrastructure. Insects would lay waste to crops, sacrificing themselves to the pesticides, leaving organic foods untouched (assuming the crops themselves didn’t turn against us by simply refusing to produce). Rodents would flood our homes, tearing them apart from the inside, leaving us unscathed by demolishing everything manufactured, everything chemically-treated, everything unnatural. Trees and plants would suddenly demonstrate an uncanny determination to grow roots under, over, and into our buildings and roads, slowly but inexorably pulling them to pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Time Spent Outdoors</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-benefits-of-time-spent-outdoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-benefits-of-time-spent-outdoors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_954&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;222&#34; caption=&#34;Source: ©Hεαṿεṉlÿ Phøτøģɾαρhÿ on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/oooheavenlyooo/3986200282/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-954&#34; title=&#34;nature&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/nature-222x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;222&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man&#39;s heart away from nature becomes hard.  &lt;em&gt;-Standing Bear&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The natural world is all around us. Every city is merely an island of human habitation amidst a vast sea of countryside and forests. A mere hour outside of New York, one of the biggest metropolises in the world, one can find beautiful and surprisingly isolated parks and hiking trails. The hills around LA are still pretty wild (apparently coyotes are a major concern out there). Most cities have parks, little spaces where the city&#39;s fabric is cut out to reveal the nature underneath, just waiting to burst through into sunlight. These are places people can go to escape the hustle of the city for a while. There is something calming and serene about nature. I always feel complete and more balanced when surrounded by trees, and there is a lot to be said for seeking out a regular connection with the outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing What I Never Had: My Connection to the Real Food Community</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/missing-what-i-never-had-my-connection-to-the-real-food-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/missing-what-i-never-had-my-connection-to-the-real-food-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/countryside.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-478&#34; title=&#34;countryside&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/countryside.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I have an interesting relationship with the sustainable food community. I am deeply passionate about it, but I have never actually been a part of it. I can practically come to tears reading Mother Earth News and get lost in stories about people raising heritage chickens, constructing their own homes,, tending gardens, living in harmony with nature and experiencing a familial closeness that few Americans ever experience anymore. But I have never done any of these things. I think I grew some bean sprouts once in elementary school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this apparent lack of connection, every time I read these stories or talk with people who live these lives, I feel an unmistakable sense of nostalgia. It seems strange to feel nostalgic for something I&#39;ve never experienced, but I strongly &lt;em&gt;miss&lt;/em&gt; these things. I miss raising chickens, I miss knowing the names of the trees and what they are good for, I miss being in tune with the seasons. It is as if a quiet part of me, long dormant, stirs every time it hears something related to how things used to be. There is a spiritual connection to that life of harmony that is so powerful in me it almost hurts to live a life that is not in accordance to its desires. But where did it come from? Has it always been there, as a primordial connection to the land and community inherent in all humans? Or is it something that grew in me in response to the decay I see in our disharmonious world and the hope offered by a return to a different lifestyle whose values so closely mirror my deepest ideals?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
