<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lessons on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/lessons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lessons on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/lessons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3 Life-Changing Lessons from Meditating Daily</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/3-life-changing-lessons-from-meditating-daily/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/3-life-changing-lessons-from-meditating-daily/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Meditation is such a simple act--you just sit in one place and concentrate on your breathing--yet it is also extremely difficult. It can teach you so much about yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Over the years, I’ve gone through periods when I meditated regularly and times when I just couldn’t bring myself to sit on the cushion. Even when I was meditating, I’ve gone through periods when I was the easiest thing in the world, and I just couldn’t wait to sit. Other times, I would put it off as long as possible, then drag myself to the cushion, and every second felt like an unbearable eternity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Through all that, I’ve learned a lot of really powerful lessons from sitting and breathing. Three of them have helped me in many other areas of life:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My feelings don’t define me or my world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discomfort isn&#39;t always bad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Routine matters</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned from a Year Living and Working in Korea</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/lessons-learned-from-a-year-living-and-working-in-korea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/lessons-learned-from-a-year-living-and-working-in-korea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;My year in Korea has come to its end. Friday was my last teaching day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I have done in the past, I like to look back as this chapter of my life comes to a close and review what I&#39;ve learned. Putting the experiences into a larger context helps me learn from my mistakes and consolidate my successes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot has happened in my first year of living completely independent of my parents, in a country that is literally on the other side of the world from my hometown. Here is what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since Joseph Campbell writes about the hero&#39;s journey, I thought he would be especially appropriate to help illustrate reflection on this rite of passage. So, this is a Campbell-themed post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned from Walking Dogs and Cat Cuddling</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/lessons-learned-from-walking-dogs-and-cat-cuddling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/lessons-learned-from-walking-dogs-and-cat-cuddling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1257&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;LaurenKates on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/laurgasms/2998777031/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1257&#34; title=&#34;dogs and cats&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/dogs-and-cats-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Everyone needs a dog to adore him, and a cat to bring him back to reality” - Anon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&#39;ve been helping out at the CT Humane Society for a few months now, and have spent a lot of time with really adorable, heartbreakingly cute kitties and puppies that want nothing more than to play and be loved. Yeah, it&#39;s rough work, but someone&#39;s got to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&#39;ve learned a lot of important things from these animals, both from their suffering and the little joys they manage to find in life at the shelter. Here are some examples:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Appreciation</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/teacher-appreciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/teacher-appreciation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1247&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Abhijit Tembhekar on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/abhijittembhekar/3345977842/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1247&#34; title=&#34;apple&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/apple-300x201.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wax on, wax off. - Mr. Miyagi, the Karate Kid (1984)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warriors are always seeking to grow and learn new things, so it makes sense that we&#39;d have a lot of teachers in our life. As the year comes to a close and I contemplate my card list, I&#39;m realizing that most of the people on it are my teachers and mentors. In the past two years, I&#39;ve acquired an unusually large number of teachers, of exceptionally good quality, and I realize that all the growth and knowledge I&#39;ve acquired is largely thanks to their efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I&#39;ve Learned, This Year</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/things-ive-learned-this-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/things-ive-learned-this-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/lesson.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-419&#34; title=&#34;lesson&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/lesson.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some random things I&#39;m learning about/working through currently. Some of them are lessons and some are &#39;huh&#39; moments. Mainly I&#39;ve just wanted to get something up since I haven&#39;t updated in a bit, so this is what&#39;s going on in my life. Exciting I know...</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
