<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kettlebell on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/kettlebell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kettlebell on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/kettlebell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrity of Movement, and My First RKC Class</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-of-movement-and-my-first-rkc-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/integrity-of-movement-and-my-first-rkc-class/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/7400969208_010890b9c21.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright  wp-image-2231&#34; title=&#34;Cheetah Run&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/7400969208_010890b9c21.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“Like a graceful vase, a cat, even when motionless, seems to flow.” - George F. Will&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always espoused the importance of &lt;a title=&#34;Move and Be Free&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/move-and-be-free/&#34;&gt;good quality movement&lt;/a&gt;, but it wasn&#39;t until I attended my first RKC Kettlebell class that I got to experience how Integrity of Movement can be taught and conveyed through a comprehensive program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RKC class, which stands for Russian Kettlebell Certification, was taught completely in Korean (because I live in Korea right now), but that wasn&#39;t a huge problem because the coaches were so well-versed in observing and correcting body-mechanics. They had a huge arsenal of tactile cues and could spot an anterior-tilted pelvis across the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 90-minute class focused on just one movement: the kettlebell swing. For those who have done it, it seems like a fairly simple movement: just swing the kettlebell, using your hips, and keep your back straight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&#39;d been teaching kettlebell swings the way I was taught at my CrossFit Level 1 cert for two years. I&#39;ve been doing them regularly for about four years. I had seen all sorts of variations, and I thought I had it down. I was very, very wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
