<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>barefoot running on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/barefoot-running/</link>
    <description>Recent content in barefoot running on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/barefoot-running/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Epic Tale of the Triumph of Will Over Utter Stupidity</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/an-epic-tale-of-the-triumph-of-will-over-utter-stupidity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/an-epic-tale-of-the-triumph-of-will-over-utter-stupidity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on the travel blog I kept while living in Korea.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/DSC_4519-e1331562897868.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had pretty much given up around the 20km mark. My left arch had been cramping since I passed 10km and my feet felt like the road was molten asphalt. I was still moving my feet, but it was more of a shuffle as I gingerly placed each step carefully to avoid even the tiniest jolt to my worn out suspension. I glared resentfully at every pair of cushy, padded, motion-controlled sneakers that cruised by me, their owners floating on a soft cloud of running technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had wondered if running a marathon in my &#39;barefoot&#39; Merrell Trailgloves was a good idea, but it turned out to be much worse than I had imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was only my second marathon. The first one I had run in racing flats, and I didn&#39;t think there would be too much difference, but it turns out half an inch of foam was the difference between crippling pain and a challenging run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had also had a running partner the first time. My dad and I had jogged steadily around the streets of Philly, chatting and sharing observations about the city. Here, in South Korea, I was running alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I talked myself into putting one foot in front of the other. Somehow, I made it through the twenties and starting chipping away at kilometer 30, then 31, then 32. Each one seemed longer than the one before. With every...single...step my body wanted to stand still. &#34;Please let me walk, just two steps. I&#39;ll do anything!&#34; it begged me. Still I ran.&lt;img title=&#34;More...&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/trans.gif&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forays in Barefoot Running</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/forays-in-barefoot-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/forays-in-barefoot-running/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1570&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;chumley80 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/29937348@N05/5247371406/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1570&#34; title=&#34;Runners Feet&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5247371406_ffb0cc0563-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve started barefoot running. Not just going out to the mail in my bare feet. Not jogging in light shoes. Full on, running down the road with no shoes on, barefoot running. So far my maximum distance is about 3/4 mile, and I&#39;m taking it slowly, but it is addictive, and holding back is the hardest part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break Out of Your Comfort Zone</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/break-out-of-your-comfort-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/break-out-of-your-comfort-zone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1549&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Pink Sherbet Photography on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pinksherbet/2822640646/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1549&#34; title=&#34;comfort&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/comfort-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever noticed that moving to college is just as uncomfortable and awkward as moving back home afterwards? Or that starting a new job is just as nerve-wracking as being unemployed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But eventually, we get used to the new routine, and we wonder how we ever got along without it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is the wonder - and frustration - of human adaptation: &lt;strong&gt;we can feel comfortable doing things we hate and supremely out of our element doing things we love and want to do&lt;/strong&gt;.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Way to Run</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-new-way-to-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-new-way-to-run/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;350&#34; caption=&#34;Source: José Goulão on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2658/3842497008_ddb28df478.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; &#34; title=&#34;Usain Bolt&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3842497008_ddb28df478.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;350&#34; height=&#34;233&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running is probably the most basic of human movements, besides walking. As an exercise, its benefits and usefulness are unparalleled. If I had to give up all but one mode of exercise, the one I&#39;d keep would be running in all its glorious manifestations: contemplative jogs, serene trail runs, tense hustles, heart-about-to-explode sprints. It is my favorite physical activity involving clothes (most of the time). Because it is so closely related to walking, we take to it pretty naturally. Nobody has to learn how to run in the way we learn how to swim or bike. You simply put one foot in front of the other, faster and faster and faster.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
