<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>childhood on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/childhood/</link>
    <description>Recent content in childhood on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/childhood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Moving Well Can Make You Confident and Popular</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/two-reasons-play-is-a-big-deal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/two-reasons-play-is-a-big-deal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2744&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;]&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2744&#34; alt=&#34;Monkeybars in Japan are 3D&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/307846_683428511794_1406122075_n1-e1358867196564.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;335&#34; /&gt; Monkeybars in Japan are 3D[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I was doing some research for an article I&#39;m writing on play as exercise, and I needed a photograph of a playground. Of course, that meant I had to test out the playground, which got me thinking on &lt;a title=&#34;Fitness is Play&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/fitness-is-play/&#34;&gt;how central the playground was in my daily life when I was a kid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Movement as a Rite of Passage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The American School of Dubai, where I went to elementary school, had a pretty awesome playground. The front consisted of three corridors of hanging traverse: there was a line of monkey bars flanked on both sides by lines of hanging rings. The rings on the left were short and closely spaced, while those on the right had much larger spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember &lt;a title=&#34;Your Mountain is Waiting. Do You Dare Conquer it?&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/your-mountain-is-waiting-do-you-dare-conquer-it/&#34;&gt;aspiring&lt;/a&gt; to complete the full set on the right side, like all the big kids. Every day, before school, at recess, and after school, I would practice swinging from the rings. Some days I would just do the short rings, to build confidence, but I usually gave the long rings a shot. I would patiently wait my turn in line with the big kids, enduring sneers and ridicule (I don&#39;t honestly remember), until I came to the front of the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart would catch. After waiting in line for agonizing minutes, would I now waste all of that by falling to the sand in &lt;a title=&#34;But What if You Fail?&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/but-what-if-you-fail/&#34;&gt;failure&lt;/a&gt; after one measly swing?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
