<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>productivity on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in productivity on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Non-Productive Actions that Make You Powerfully Effective</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/non-productive-actions-that-make-you-powerfully-effective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/non-productive-actions-that-make-you-powerfully-effective/</guid>
      <description>I learn a lot from my mornings. They usually set the tone for my day.
For example, last week, I missed my morning run and meditation most days. On the weekend, today and yesterday, I managed to make those both happen. The difference was pretty noticeable.
Sometimes, I have to make a choice between getting work done and going out for my run. My first instinct is to do the work, but that&#39;s actually not as significant an investment in my performance and my day as running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Productivity</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-art-of-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-art-of-productivity/</guid>
      <description>“It&#39;s not so much how busy you are, but why you are busy. The bee is praised. The mosquito is swatted.” - Mary O&#39;Connor
 There is no real connection between work done and productivity. Some of the most productive things people do, which bring the most joy, money, insight, efficiency, or whatever, take very little time and effort.
And some of the most useless things take all day to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The One Thing You Can Do To Make Everything Better</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-one-thing-you-can-do-to-make-everything-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-one-thing-you-can-do-to-make-everything-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1850&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;tanakawho on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/28481088@N00/1069809120/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1850&#34; title=&#34;lotus&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/lotus-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He who has health, has hope. And he who has hope, has everything&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.thinkexist.com/quotation/he_who_has_health-has_hope-and_he_who_has_hope/149145.html&#34;&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;” - Proverb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Leave all the afternoon for exercise and recreation, which are as necessary as reading. I will rather say more necessary because health is worth more than learning.” - Thomas Jefferson&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the one thing you can do to improve almost every aspect of your life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be honest, I don’t know you, but the thing that makes the biggest difference in my day to day life is looking after my health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this means eating right, &lt;a title=&#34;Lessons Learned as a Trainer and Athlete&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/lessons-learned-as-a-trainer-and-athlete/&#34;&gt;exercising regularly and intensely&lt;/a&gt;, and getting enough sleep. It means I take my health into my own hands, instead of just accepting what the government or the media tells me. It’s your body; take the time to get to know it, what makes it happy, and what is good for it, instead of relying on people who have zero interest in your well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few of the really obvious effects looking after my health has had. Most of them have nothing to do with the body itself, but instead are reflections on the areas of life that we really live for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking your productive potential; reshape your standards to fit your goals</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/unlocking-you-productive-potential-reshape-your-standards-to-fit-your-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/unlocking-you-productive-potential-reshape-your-standards-to-fit-your-goals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1740&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;190&#34; caption=&#34;seier+seier on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/seier/2164161632/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1740&#34; title=&#34;biggoals&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/biggoals-190x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;190&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post from Eric Fulwiler, an Account Executive at VaynerMedia, am NYC digital agency specializing in social. He blogs at &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ericfulwiler.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog.ericfulwiler.com&lt;/a&gt;, and you can find him on Twitter @EFulwiler.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do we find certain  activities easier than others? It&#39;s so easy for us to sit down and watch a 3-hour baseball game (at least, for some of us), but it&#39;s so hard for us to sit down for 3 hours and write a Powerpoint presentation. Part of it is certainly because baseball is more entertaining than Powerpoint (again, for some of us), but the bigger issue here is the standards and expectations that we have created for ourselves. We have standards embedded within our mentality that dictate the ease and attractiveness of certain activities. We have chosen to believe that baseball is easier than Powerpoint. And these choices have resulted in standards that frequently present obstacles to our personal or professional productivity. But for those of us who accept that we can control these standards, we can realign them to further our goals, and significantly increase our productivity and potential.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enjoying Downtime</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/enjoying-downtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/enjoying-downtime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1677&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;audi_insperation on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/audiinsperation/518551748/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1677&#34; title=&#34;happycat&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/happycat-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning to enjoy my downtime has been one of the most  difficult challenges I’ve had to face in my recent life. I have always  felt a need to fill every spare minute of my time with some project, so I  tend to have a lot of things going on at the same time. The problem  with that is I never feel like I have the right to just sit and enjoy  myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worry Less, Do More</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/worry-less-do-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/worry-less-do-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1601&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;211&#34; caption=&#34;Bark on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/barkbud/4257136773/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1601&#34; title=&#34;Try Not to Worry So Much&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/worry-211x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;211&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since finishing the CrossFit sectionals, I’ve been taking a  break from fitness for the last two weeks. Basically I have tried to  relax about fitness and just do what I feel like in terms of exercise  and nutrition. I expected to lose some ground with my training, but I  felt that I was due for a break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The funny thing is I have actually gotten stronger and  faster. I recently ran a few quarter-mile intervals and put up some of  my fastest times ever. My front lever has become so solid I can do  bicycle crunches while holding myself horizontal. Clearly, I just needed  some rest to develop the latent strength. Leading up to sectionals, I  was so uptight about workouts and diet, and I did pretty well, but now  that I’ve stopped worrying so much, I seem to be doing just as well  anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It seems that I do just as well (or better) not worrying about stuff and I do when I worry.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why worry?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving Up the Nonessential</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/giving-up-the-nonessential/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/giving-up-the-nonessential/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Koalazymonkey on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2558/3707160352_114df38f61_z.jpg?zz=1&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3707160352_114df38f61_z.jpg?zz=1&#34; title=&#34;Blank Notebook&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last week, I&#39;ve sold my laptop and replaced it with an Apple iPad 2. This leaves me without a regular computer capable of such basic functions as running flash programs, storing more than a few hours of music and video, and playing the most interesting games out there. Instead, I&#39;ve got myself a tiny, super light tablet about 10&#34; large that I can take anywhere. And, even more important, I have no distractions anymore.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tired of Tardiness</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/tired-of-tardiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/tired-of-tardiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1323&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;blue2likeyou on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/29254399@N08/3187186308/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1323&#34; title=&#34;clock&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/clock1-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last two days, I&#39;ve done a pretty poor job of keeping on top of my own schedule. I&#39;ve been rushing around to everything, have been late to two very important appointments, and haven&#39;t had the mental clarity to focus on getting anything done. I offer my apologies to all affected, including the readers of my blog. It&#39;s not much in the way of consolation, but I&#39;ve been suffering more than those I let down; my ability to get enough food and sleep has been pretty well undermined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to Keep it All Together</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/trying-to-keep-it-all-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/trying-to-keep-it-all-together/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1295&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;madaboutasia on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/teducation/2591726789/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1295&#34; title=&#34;juggler&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/juggler-300x243.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;243&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have often been times in my life when things seemed largely out of control. Everything seemed to be just out of my grasp. There was too much on my plate, I wasn&#39;t doing the things I wanted to, I wasn&#39;t moving my life in the direction I wanted to go. Basically, everything was going haywire. At those times, I have always found myself with two possible responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patience</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/patience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1226&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;WasabiDoobie on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wasabidoobie/2448490111/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1226&#34; title=&#34;patience&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/patience-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Genius is only a greater aptitude for patience.” - George-Louis Leclerc de Buffon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have had a lot of waiting to do as my plans start to gain momentum. There are long periods during which nothing seems to bear any fruit. Farm to Table went silent for a long time, with almost no new comments or community engagement, leading me to get very discouraged. I was lacking motivation in my workouts and didn&#39;t really feel like I was making any progress. My blog seemed to be wallowing in obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, all of sudden things started to move very quickly, and I realized that it was the quiet times when things were starting to move towards a tipping point. I am getting a lot of people reaching out to connect over Farm to Table, there is a new energy in my training, and I am making all sorts of friends while reconnecting with old ones. It&#39;s almost more than I can handle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The 80/20 Principle</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-the-8020-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/book-review-the-8020-principle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1194&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;104&#34; caption=&#34;By Richard Koch&#34;]&lt;a style=&#34;&amp;amp;quot;border: none;&#34; href=&#34;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0385491743?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=warrspir-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0385491743&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img border=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; src=&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1194&#34; title=&#34;The 80/20 Principle&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/51Q7Y-piN-L._SL160_.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;104&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s an amazing, and disturbing, truth: 80% of anything that gets accomplished in your life comes from only 20% of your effort or time. 80% of your grades come from 20% of your studying. 80% of your productivity at work (and therefore the value of your income) comes from only 20% of actual time spent working. 80% of my quality writing is done in only 20% of the time I spend trying to write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea - that most of what gets done is due to a minority of the causes - is the basis behind the 80/20 principle. The book, by Richard Koch, explains this concept and then illustrates what the 80/20 principle means for your real, everyday life. The subtitle, &#34;the secret of success by achieving more with less,&#34; is a pretty enticing promise, and I believe that Koch delivers on this promise. &lt;strong&gt;This book will change the way you see the world, and should be read by anyone interested in achieving their potential&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Your Own Time</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/making-your-own-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/making-your-own-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1183&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;psyberartist on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/clocks.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1183&#34; title=&#34;clocks&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/clocks-300x269.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;269&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our body is a well-set clock, which keeps good time, but if it be too much or indiscreetly tampered with, the alarm runs out before the hour” -Joseph Hall&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I left my gym. Cross Country season is over. I have absolutely no set, recurring commitments at the moment. I haven&#39;t had this much freedom to pick my own activities since...before preschool. The scary part is that I&#39;m &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;completely at a loss of what to do. Without any boundaries on how I use my time, I would have expected myself to go completely crazy and panic at the prospect of no external structure. Instead, I see before myself a blank canvas, and I&#39;ve got a lot more colors to paint with than I ever have before. My day is mine to use as I see fit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zen Habits Handbook for Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/zen-habits-handbook-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/zen-habits-handbook-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_950&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: kristofabrath on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kristofabrath/3206231510/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-950&#34; title=&#34;zen&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/zen-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smile, breathe, and go slowly &lt;em&gt;- Thich Nhat Hanh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when I was in college, drowning under the immense workload and the complexities of balancing my social life, personal life, and scholastic commitments, I stumbled upon a blog that saved my academic standing as well as my sanity. The blog is called Zen Habits, and it was a godsend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Beat Procrastination</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-beat-procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-beat-procrastination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_789&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Source: CraigGrocott on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/craigweb/2887922337/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-789&#34; title=&#34;procrastination&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/procrastination-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Do it now! can affect every phase of your life. It can help you do the things you should do but don&#39;t feel like doing. It can keep you from procrastinating when an unpleasant duty faces you. But it can also help you do those things that you want to do. It helps you seize those precious moments that, if lost, may never be retrieved.” - &lt;em&gt;Napoleon Hill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading my blog today, but I have to ask, is there something more important you have to do that you are putting off by checking in? (Or perhaps reading my blog is the most important thing you have to do today, in which case I&#39;m flattered :)). &lt;strong&gt;Procrastination, the sacred art of putting things off to the last minute, is one of the biggest productivity killers in our lives, and also one of the biggest sources of stress and anxiety&lt;/strong&gt;. It is a learned habit, one that can really mess with your sense of well-being and mental health. It cuts into all aspects of our lives, from reading, to shopping, to paying bills, to exercising. So why do we procrastinate, and how can we eliminate this habit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliminating Distractions</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/eliminating-distractions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/eliminating-distractions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_702&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: tychay on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/tychay/3333787096/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-702&#34; title=&#34;cleandesk&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/cleandesk.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;_mcePaste&#34;&gt;If while washing dishes, we think only of the cup of tea that awaits us, thus hurrying to get the dishes out of the way as if they were a nuisance, then we are not &#34;washing the dishes to wash the dishes.&#34; What&#39;s more, we are not alive during the time we are washing the dishes.... While drinking the cup of tea, we will only be thinking of other things, barely aware of the cup in our hands. Thus we are sucked away into the future -and we are incapable of actually living one minute of life. - Naht Hahn, &lt;em&gt;Miracle of Mindfulness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern technology is a wonderful thing. It gives us access to more information than we could possibly ever hope to read and understand. It connects us to people all over the world and lets us share ideas and conversations with them on a whim. It puts the entirety of human knowledge at our fingertips. As a college student, I was infinitely grateful for the fact that I could do almost all my research and class readings online without having to spend hours in the bookstacks looking for texts. At the click of a button, I could bring to my attention the latest psychological research and in the same breath skim an article on current events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
