<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>the perfect day on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/the-perfect-day/</link>
    <description>Recent content in the perfect day on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/the-perfect-day/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Perfect Day</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-perfect-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-perfect-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/100_0038.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-548&#34; title=&#34;A beautiful sunset&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/100_0038.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;So, I thought I&#39;d set down exactly where I want to end up in 10 years or so, so I can at least have a bit of direction, and know what I ought to be doing in my life to set myself on the right road, rather than just bump around aimlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Predawn Meditation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wake up just before dawn, energized and alert, in a house I built, and throw on a handmade parka before heading out the door barefoot and going for an early morning jog through the forest, which is only a few hundred yards from my front door. The air is damp but cool. I jog about ten minutes to my favorite rock overlooking a valley, facing the rising sun, where I sit and meditate as the sun comes up. I&#39;m cold, but it doesn&#39;t bother me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jogging back, I stop on the way to feed the chickens and the goats wandering the yard. The dog is awake by now, but not the rest of the family, and he comes out to help me rouse the animals, playfully yipping at the goats and nudging the sleepy hens. While I&#39;m out, I check the nests for eggs for breakfast. I finish tending to the animals and head inside to start preparing breakfast for the kids and the wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
