<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mindset on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/mindset/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mindset on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/mindset/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A 10 Minute Exercise that Will Change Your Day</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-10-minute-exercise-that-will-change-your-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/a-10-minute-exercise-that-will-change-your-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3907&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/watch-e1421889550877.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;watch&#34; width=&#34;698&#34; height=&#34;210&#34; /&gt;Imagine what your life would be like and what you&#39;d accomplish if you started &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; day full of passion, purpose and drive. Not just a few days a month, or a few hours of each day, but every hour of every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re probably thinking that&#39;d be great, but it&#39;s not realistic. After all, moods and mindsets are fickle, and people are either born with drive or they&#39;re not, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found myself asking the same question recently, and I decided to see if I could find an answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all my research on high achieving individuals, from the ultra-wealthy to the ultra-accomplished, I noticed that the biggest difference was their mindset. They ask different kinds of questions and see the world in a different way than the majority of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For an example of this, check out &lt;a title=&#34;KhanAcademy Interviews Elon Musk&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vDwzmJpI4io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sal Khan&#39;s interview of Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It dawned on me that an essential technique for increasing people&#39;s capabilities was to find a way for them to consistently elevate their mindset. Each day spent in a state of openness to possibility compounds on the previous ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is, for most of us, our mindset is determined by our mood, which is often determined by the events of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed a way to make sure that every day started with an empowered mindset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Warrior Mindset Part 2: Transform Challenges Into Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-warrior-mindset-part-2-transform-challenges-into-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-warrior-mindset-part-2-transform-challenges-into-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2737&#34; alt=&#34;&#39;Iron Knights&#39; patrol the Arghandab&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5418579692_5b570e142d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shawn Rhodes, founder of Shoshin Consulting, is a traveler, teacher and above all, a lifelong student. After growing up in the mountains training in martial arts and eastern philosophy, he followed his own warrior&#39;s calling and joined the U.S. Marines. There, he accompanied infantry Marines through two combat tours in Iraq, documenting their trials and victories for international news outlets like CNN and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-2723&#34; alt=&#34;rhodessmaller&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/rhodessmaller-e1358734605767-150x150.jpg&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;TIME. While living and fighting alongside this tribe of modern-day warriors, he discovered the link between the warrior&#39;s path and mastery in life. He returned to the U.S. with the passion to share a vision of what humans are capable of when they embrace their own inner warrior and return to a mindset where all paths are possible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is the second in a three-part series on The Warrior&#39;s Path. Each installment will explore the evolution of the warrior mindset. Rooted in ancient methods warriors followed for thousands of years, adopting this mindset can help anyone to regain balance, direction, and control of their health, success, and life.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/part-i-of-the-warrior-mindset-turn-problems-into-challenges/&#34;&gt;the first part &lt;/a&gt;of this series, readers learned how to use the ancient mindset of the warrior to see life in a new way. Instead of viewing the world as a place that acts upon our lives, we learned everyone has the ability to choose how to process situations. &lt;b&gt;Seeing each problem in life as a challenge to shift our mindset is the first stage of warriorhood.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second installment of this series, we will learn the next stage in the evolution of the warrior mindset is &lt;strong&gt;turning those challenges into opportunities, and why it’s the supreme form of power&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, many people - especially young men - get stuck in the first stage of a warrior’s development. They’ve learned to see the problems in their lives as challenges, but they make a key mistake that freezes their development: they see each challenge as a threat and a test of their strength. We’ve all seen the chest-puffing and rooster dance from two guys at the bar or on the schoolyard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Need to Prove&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m convinced, after seeing firsthand people spend months trying to kill each other in modern war, that much of the violence in this world comes from people feeling threatened and wanting to protect what they see as ‘theirs‘: their life, their property, their ideologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These folks aren’t operating from the mindset of mature warriors; they are approaching their lives like a guard defending a castle, afraid of the walls crumbling at any moment. Without their bravado and one-upmanship, others might discover just how fragile their self-image really is. People frozen in this stage may be extremely skilled fighters, but they rush blindly into battles without examining the playing field for the best - and easiest - ways to win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one of the most famous texts outlining the warrior mindset - The Hagakure - its author Yamamoto Tsunemoto likens a skilled warrior on the battlefield to a hawk taking down a single bird in a flock. Experienced warriors focus their minds on a task - or an opponent - and are unconcerned with the opinions of others in the flock or social circle. &lt;b&gt;Instead, they are more concerned with performance than they are with proving their competence. &lt;/b&gt;This makes them extremely effective at whatever they set their minds to, whether it’s being a fighter or an artist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;If you are young and still exploring your relationship to your world by comparing your strength against others, the sooner you move past needing to prove yourself, the sooner you can embrace a deeper kind of power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make a Dream Come True</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-make-a-dream-come-true/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-make-a-dream-come-true/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/?attachment_id=2693&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2693&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter  wp-image-2693&#34; alt=&#34;Achieving Goals Feels Good&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/66728_700953401774_1869754869_n1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;592&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn&#39;t very often that we get to cross out a big goal in our lives, but that is exactly what I did at the end of November. I&#39;d been dreaming of &lt;a title=&#34;Freeing the Zoo Humans: Why I Want to Become a MovNat Instructor&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/movnat-instructor/&#34;&gt;becoming a MovNat trainer&lt;/a&gt; since I heard about the method in 2009. Around April of last year, when MovNat announced they were offering trainer certifications, I finally decided to make this dream a reality. I couldn&#39;t afford the certification with what I was making as an ESL teacher; I would have to raise the money by &lt;a title=&#34;Lessons Learned on Finishing My First Book&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/lessons-learned-on-finishing-my-first-book/&#34;&gt;writing and promoting&lt;/a&gt; an eBook, which I published in September of 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By November of 2012, I had raised enough from donations for the eBook (as well as a few t-shirt sales) to sign up for my MovNat trainer certification in March 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a long road to get there, but the most valuable thing I got out of the whole experience won&#39;t be the MCT certification itself. &lt;strong&gt;Instead, it is the confidence that I can affect my life without permission from anyone else&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quit Your Whining</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/quit-your-whining/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/quit-your-whining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1951&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; caption=&#34;kaibara87 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kaibara/3496249511/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1951&#34; title=&#34;Whiny Cat&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3496249511_2d194b807f.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your intention everyday just to survive? Is your intention everyday just to make it through the world, because your interpretation is &#39;the world is so hard, so stressful, so chaotic, I hope I can just get through this day&#39;? Because if that&#39;s where you&#39;re at, that identity for you is small. - Brendon Burchard&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to whine...a lot. Practically every word out of my mouth was a complaint of some kind. I was either talking about my frustration over my homework load, kvetching over the constant barrage of e-mails, or just going on about random aches and pains and fatigue. The only information I had to share with anyone was about how something was bothering me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hardly conscious of my behavior; whining just seemed to be the natural thing to say, and after all, it seemed to me that most conversations were based around complaining. People would get together after work to basically whine about the difficult week. Guys would bond over complaining about their girlfriends, and women would commiserate over the poor quality of men in their lives. Most of the student conversations I heard were about academic frustration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I was not pleasant to be around, and my family made this very clear to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t want to be that guy nobody invites to parties (I was already that guy, and knew it wasn&#39;t fun). I didn&#39;t want to be the guy nobody could rely on who couldn&#39;t handle his own life. So I resolved to change what I thought was a seemingly simple habit of conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no idea how deep it went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rule I instituted was: if what I am about to say is something negative and simply expresses how I feel bad about something, with no suggestion of actually fixing the problem, I will keep my mouth shut.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With only moderate self-control, I did very well at this. It was merely a matter of keeping my lips sealed. Sometimes I found I had nothing to contribute to conversations, but at least I wasn&#39;t bringing people down anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I made a horrifying discovery.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
