<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self-control on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/self-control/</link>
    <description>Recent content in self-control on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/self-control/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Willpower</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-willpower/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-willpower/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/willpowerbook.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-1796&#34; title=&#34;willpowerbook&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/willpowerbook.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;144&#34; height=&#34;220&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Life is full of paradox. Eating fat doesn’t make you fat. Running in shoes can be bad for your feet. Giving yourself free reign to express your every desire and emotion can mire your personal growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last one will require some explanation, especially since there is a lot of talk here on Warrior Spirit about the importance of listening to your heart and following your dreams, no matter what comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve just finished a book summarizing the psychological research on the topic of willpower and self-control. The book, &lt;em&gt;Willpower, &lt;/em&gt;by psychologists Roy F. Baumeister and John Tierney, is rife with examples of how the failure to set and follow limitations leads to a breakdown of character. It is mainly a survey of the research, but what makes it readable is the authors’ sincere interest in helping the reader, and the interviews with such characters as endurance artist David Blaine (who spent 63 hours encased in a block of ice in Times Square) and Amanda Palmer (known for her tabloid-friendly outbursts). The authors also draw examples on how willpower can be utilized from Ophrah, Eric Clapton and Henry Morton Stanley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happiness is a Choice</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/happiness-is-a-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/happiness-is-a-choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1199&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Jayel Aheram&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/aheram/2228606820/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1199&#34; title=&#34;smile&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/smile-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most People are about as happy as they make up their minds to be &lt;em&gt;- Abraham Lincoln&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/book-review-the-8020-principle/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The 80/20 Principle, &lt;/a&gt;I was struck by how many useful strategies are presented for increasing one&#39;s happiness. Having spent most of my young adult life pursuing happiness and learning what behaviors and life situations lead to happiness, I was not struck so much by the idea that you can cultivate happiness as by the new approaches to the old problem. I had always taken it for granted that I could be more or less happy, and that was in my control. So it came as a bit of a shock for me when the author spent the larger portion of the section on happiness trying to convince his readers that they happiness was something they could actually control. He cited all sorts of studies and authors showing that people have a say in their happiness level, that we are not simply at the mercy of circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
