<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>questions on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/questions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in questions on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/questions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Can I do This?: A Question to Improve Performance on Everything</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/can-i-do-this-a-question-to-improve-performance-on-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/can-i-do-this-a-question-to-improve-performance-on-everything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3855&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/question-e1418143667521.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;question&#34; width=&#34;761&#34; height=&#34;566&#34; /&gt;Perhaps you&#39;ve heard the old advice that it&#39;s important to psych yourself up before a big test or meeting. Remind yourself how awesome you are! Tell yourself, &#34;I can do this! I&#39;m a rockstar!&#34; Maybe you&#39;ve even done this, despite all feelings to the contrary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve ever been in an airplane during extreme turbulence, you don&#39;t want to overhear your pilot insisting, &#34;I can do this! Yeah!&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they are talking at all, you want to hear specific actions that they will be taking to make things better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a reason for this. Our minds actually interpret insistent statements like these as a sign that there is something really wrong. After all, if you were confident, you wouldn&#39;t even need to bother with the motivation at all, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it turns out there&#39;s a better way to motivate yourself, one that feels less like a desperate plea to convince yourself of something you just don&#39;t believe, and that actually helps you do better, rather than simply feel better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask the simple question, &#34;Can I do this?&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hard Questions</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-hard-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-hard-questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;He hated his job. The sterile thin air that assaulted him as soon as he walked into his office made him sick, and he was on edge until the minute he finally went home. He couldn’t stand his boss, didn’t have any friends among his co-workers, and found his job tedious. It was even affecting his life outside of work: it took him hours to unwind and he winced every time his phone chimed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;His wife knew how bad it was for him, but the one time she had brought it up, he refused to talk about it, instead picking a fight. It wasn’t worth the anger, she decided, but she couldn’t stand watching him suffer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;One day, he came home in a rage, railing against his incompetent boss and some problem his wife couldn’t follow. She calmed him down, but then he just beat up on himself for not being able to handle the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Finally, exasperated, she asked, “Why do you stay? Why do you put yourself through this?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;The automatic answer that almost escaped his lips was, “For us! I do this so we can live a comfortable life!” But he knew that wasn’t the real reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;A part of him knew the real answers. They had to do with winning his father’s respect, with his fear of starting over, with the fact that his sense of identity was tied up with his work. He knew the real reasons had nothing to do with ‘being a good partner’ or ‘supporting his family’. &lt;strong&gt;The real reasons were all things he didn’t want to believe were true about himself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;So he never asked himself the hard questions that would bring the real reasons to light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It was easier to suffer, he decided, than to admit he had made a mistake.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
