<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>status quo on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/status-quo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in status quo on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/status-quo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Get Out of the Box!</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/get-out-of-the-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/get-out-of-the-box/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1793&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;sxld on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/sxld/6123441787/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1793&#34; title=&#34;inthebox&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/inthebox-300x198.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;198&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are people living very happily right now without a home. There are people enjoying life floating on a boat or migrating from place to place with all their belongings on the backs of steppe ponies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are happy, successful people without stable, secure, 9-5 jobs. There are happy, fulfilled people working in mailrooms, stockrooms, and vast libraries, with minimal human interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are folks who are do all their work at night, hardly ever see the light of day, and who are perfectly healthy and well adjusted. There are some people, who do bring value to their communities, who live without any money at all, relying on their own ingenuity and the charity of their friends to get by, or they live as part of a self-sustaining community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a slightly more radical note, there are people getting a really good education without going to school and who have their dream jobs without ever finishing college, despite what our parents told us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn to Stand Alone</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learn-to-stand-alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learn-to-stand-alone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_998&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;faungg on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/44534236@N00/3255156612/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-998&#34; title=&#34;tree&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/tree-300x201.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;Never tell your problems to anyone...20% don&#39;t care and the other 80% are glad you have them..&#34; &lt;em&gt;- Lou Holtz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most frustrating aspects of life is that whenever you become passionate about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/dont-be-afraid-to-reach-for-your-goals/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;pursuing some extraordinary goal&lt;/a&gt; or lifestyle, people waste no time in trying to hold you back. I find it odd that people rarely go out of their way to encourage your ambitions, but they will eagerly jump into a conversation to provide reasons you are wrong, might fail, or wasting your time. Especially if they have to change some aspect of their lives to accommodate you, they will do their utmost to convince you that your desire to run off and contribute to world peace will absolutely end their livliehoods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
