<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>abundance on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/abundance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in abundance on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/abundance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Abundance and Scarcity Thinking</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/abundance-and-scarcity-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/abundance-and-scarcity-thinking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; caption=&#34;Source: incurable_hippie on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3289/2596821107_15c018ec9f.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Abundance&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/2596821107_15c018ec9f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;182&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to get really sleepy around 9pm. This drives my friends crazy, since that is when they normally hang out, and it is about when I start thinking about turning in. They wonder why I&#39;m so energetically spent all the time, and my answer, ironically, is that it&#39;s because I exercise a lot. Besides that, I would explain that I have to get up at 5am a couple times a week, or 6:30 at the latest. This was an excuse I&#39;d use for myself as well, to justify my general desire to do less and sleep more. I just didn&#39;t have the energy to spare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I learned a lesson from a good friend, who actually recently joined my gym. He shows up to all my morning classes, and all the other morning classes, and &lt;em&gt;he &lt;/em&gt;is the one who is always trying to keep me up past 9pm. We were hanging out, late by my standards, and I was acting tired. When someone commented on it, I slipped into my usual explanation and my friend immediately jumped in to say that he got up at the same time every day. That shut me up pretty quick.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
