<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>maturity on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/maturity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in maturity on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/maturity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Am I Too Young to Matter?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/am-i-too-young-to-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/am-i-too-young-to-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2017&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/221737671_c0383274df.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-2017&#34; title=&#34;Sad Baby&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/221737671_c0383274df-225x300.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/steelmore/221737671/&#34;&gt;Just Taken Pics on Flickr&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You can only be young once. But you can always be immature.” -Dave Barry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently had a conversation on Twitter in which I was sharing some insights on health and life. My conversation partner thought that I was making some very good points, and all was going well. Then she revealed that she is married with kids, and suddenly I thought, &#34;What wisdom can I offer this person, who has seen so much more of life than I?&#34; I was embarrassed, even though she had agreed with my ideas and said that her experiences confirmed them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized that I have a belief that I cannot offer much to the world because I am so young. All of my ideas have only been around a short time, and the hard trial of years hasn&#39;t yet tested their worth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But is my youth really that much of a handicap?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I share my insights on life, there is a voice in my head saying people older than me might dismiss my ideas because I&#39;m only 25. They might wonder how much I could possibly have gleaned from my life in that short time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I&#39;m encouraging happiness, I worry they will think that I haven&#39;t accepted that life is hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I&#39;m talking about difficulty, I worry they will think that I have an entitlement complex, that I expect the world to be handed to me because I&#39;m young and don&#39;t yet know how to do hard work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s really no way to win over stubborn old people (especially when you&#39;re not sure they really think that way at all).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aging Gloriously</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/aging-gloriously/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/aging-gloriously/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1784&#34; align=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;me&amp;#39;nthedogs on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/66176388@N00/5194802905/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1784&#34; title=&#34;stag&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/stag-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember in Bambi how much of a wimp Bambi was as a young buck? Compared to his father, the king of the forest, he was still just a whelp, even though technically a fully grown deer. His father, on the other hand, was a fully mature stag, quite literally an embodiment of the spirit of the forest. How often do we see out own parents that way: at the peak of their power, rather than in decline?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youthful Wisdom</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youthful-wisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youthful-wisdom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1277&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;gemsling on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gemsling/2620901357/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1277&#34; title=&#34;mature&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/mature-300x257.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;257&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Maturity has more to do with what types of experiences you&#39;ve had, and what you&#39;ve learned from them, and less to do with how many birthdays you&#39;ve celebrated.” - Anon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often tell me that I am exceptionally mature for my age. Ignoring the truthfulness of this statement, I&#39;ve always been curious what that means exactly. Generally, the implication is that adults are more mature than children, but even as a child, I knew several adults more emotionally unstable than I and who were far worse at taking care of themselves. That said, I also know a few youngsters who make me feel positively infantile. So how is it possible for a younger person to have more maturity than an older person?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
