<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WDS2013 on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/wds2013/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WDS2013 on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/wds2013/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Find Your Bliss: 3 Questions to Ask Yourself</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-find-your-bliss-3-questions-to-ask-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-to-find-your-bliss-3-questions-to-ask-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_3068&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/WDS2013.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-3068&#34; alt=&#34;Happy dancers at the closing party for WDS21013&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/WDS2013-300x199.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Happy dancers at the closing party for WDS21013[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s all well and good to tell people to follow their bliss, but how do you find the thing in the first place? If you haven&#39;t been following it, it probably wandered off years ago and is lost in someone&#39;s backyard howling all alone because you didn&#39;t follow it on the epic exploration of the neighborhood that would have led you to meet that cute neighbor you&#39;d fall in love with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, anyway, clearly you need to find it so you can follow it on to other adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the last weekend at the World Domination Summit, organized by Chris Guillebeau of &lt;a title=&#34;The Art of Non-Conformity&#34; href=&#34;http://chrisguillebeau.com/3x5/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Art of Non-Conformity&lt;/a&gt;, where I was inundated by awesomely inspiring speakers and ideas. As the name implies, the World Domination Summit is a gathering of people intent of making a big impact on the world by living fearlessly and pursuing their remarkable dreams in a conventional world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one of the talks was specifically about how to find your passion or purpose, but several of the speakers touched on the topic. Three ideas in particular seemed especially actionable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
