<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Inflicted Wounds: The Gulf of Mexico Oil Spill</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/self-inflicted-wounds-the-gulf-of-mexico-oil-spill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/self-inflicted-wounds-the-gulf-of-mexico-oil-spill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/05/oilspill.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-571&#34; title=&#34;oilspill&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/oilspill.jpg?w=199&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I generally don&#39;t follow current events in much detail and prefer to stay uninvolved in politics. If I had my way, I&#39;d require all children to be educated on the importance of the natural world, at the expense of more &#39;practical&#39; subjects, but I tend to maintain some distance from most environmental issues, simply because they tend to be so heartbreaking, with so many angry people on both sides. To get emotionally involved would be like asking for a stress-induced heart attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I read an article in Time about the Deep Horizon disaster. I had known what was going on, but was not aware of the extent of the damage. Reading it was like watching a horror movie; it was so horrific I wanted to cover my eyes, but something compelled me to keep reading, to subject myself to the terrible scenes and let the images of the ecological disaster crowd my mind. I felt my heart grow cold with fear for all the environmental damage that would and has occurred, all the diversity that would be lost and perhaps never recovered. I felt anger at the people who had allowed this to happen: the oil companies and our government. But most of all, I felt a deep sadness. How terrible that our civilization has come to this habit of destroying its most beautiful environments and coastlines for the sake of a few more years of dirty, smoggy convenience.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
