<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>practice on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/practice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in practice on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/practice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Hard Way to Do Anything Right</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-hard-way-to-do-anything-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-hard-way-to-do-anything-right/</guid>
      <description>What a discouraging headline for a blog post, right? Stick with me though, I promise you&#39;ll have something interesting to think about.
When I was transforming my fitness and my body, I had absolutely no clue what I was doing. I cringe remembering all the things I did wrong and all the ways I could have hurt myself.
But I also remember how determined I was. I was willing to do anything and everything necessary to accomplish my goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Foundation of Empowered Living</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-foundation-of-empowered-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-foundation-of-empowered-living/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first task of the aspiring hero is to train her body. Only when she has learned how to master the external world can she begin the far more difficult task of mastering the internal world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;The Entrepreneurial Benefits of Healthy Living&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-entrepreneurial-benefits-of-healthy-living/&#34;&gt;I&#39;ve talked before about how success-oriented types tend to discount the importance of health&lt;/a&gt;. We tell ourselves that we need to put in as much work as we can, now, when we&#39;re young and resilient. Once we&#39;ve earned our leisure time, we will make up for all the lost sleep, convenient food, drinking, and hours spent hunched in front of a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We tend to ignore just how much this neglect is impacting our ability to do quality work right now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to talk about the importance of fitness in particular, and why a &lt;strong&gt;physical practice&lt;/strong&gt; is so essential to mastering yourself and unleashing your true potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training my body, becoming stronger and more coordinated, has had a huge impact on my sense of &lt;a title=&#34;How Moving Well Can Make You Confident and Popular&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/two-reasons-play-is-a-big-deal/&#34;&gt;self-confidence&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title=&#34;Practicing Courage Through Movement&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/practicing-courage-throught-movement/&#34;&gt;courage&lt;/a&gt;, and I believe it is an essential thing for any aspiring Warrior to find peace with his or her body. Your body is not just who you are, but it is also your mode of expression in the world. Learn to cultivate it, to appreciate it, and to &lt;a title=&#34;Listen to Your Intuition: It Could Save Your Life&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/listen-to-your-intuition-it-could-save-your-life/&#34;&gt;trust it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Training Ground for the Spirit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many epics, myths, and legends, young heroes spend their early training in physical preparation. This isn&#39;t because the physical is more important than the mental and the spiritual, but because it is the most basic realm we must master.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can a hero expect to overcome the more challenges of ideas, thoughts, principles, motivation, and loyalty if they cannot manage their own bodies and move through the world? &lt;strong&gt;Physical competence is a foundational prerequisite for mental and spiritual competencies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
