<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>athletics on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/athletics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in athletics on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/athletics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Limits of My Experience</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learning-the-limits-of-my-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learning-the-limits-of-my-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;mceTemp&#34; style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1035&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Johan J.Ingles-Le Nobel on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jingleslenobel/4326713557/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1035&#34; title=&#34;river&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/river-300x204.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;204&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As I have said, the first thing is to be honest with yourself. You can never have an impact on society if you have not changed yourself... Great peacemakers are all people of integrity, of honesty, but humility.” -&lt;em&gt;Nelson Mandela&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went for a 5k run today, the first I&#39;ve undertaken in over a year. Despite all the intense anaerobic exercise I do at CrossFit, the fact that I can run a 5:05 mile, and my powerful legs, I found it extremely difficult. So difficult, in fact, that I walked near the end and got a time that was worse than my best high school time. My ankles are sore and I feel more beat up than usual. But really, I&#39;m not that surprised I didn&#39;t do as well as I thought I could. After all, I may be a very well-rounded athlete, but I know that distance running has become a definite area of neglect in my training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Athleticism Good for Your Health?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/is-athleticism-good-for-your-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/is-athleticism-good-for-your-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; caption=&#34;Source: RobW_ on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/48/136462415_5455bf750a.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Statue of an Athlete from the Ancient Olympic Games&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/136462415_5455bf750a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent visit to my sports doctor, brought on by yet another overuse injury, prompted me to wonder if being an athlete is actually good for one&#39;s health and fitness. After all, the only reason I was at the doctor was because I am an athlete. I had injured my shoulder on a leisurely kayak tour of a small Connecticut lake. The shoulder was prone to such a pansy injury because I regularly engage in extreme fitness, aka, CrossFit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you are probably wondering, as was I, how can an athlete with shoulders capable of doing multiple strict muscle-ups be completely incapacitated by something as tame as kayaking? I honestly don&#39;t have an answer. But the experience got me to wondering about the distinctions between fitness, health, and athleticism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Brain is Making You Weak</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/your-brain-is-making-you-weak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/your-brain-is-making-you-weak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/06/brain.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-611&#34; title=&#34;brain&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/brain.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;There&#39;s a lot in the fitness community on how diet and exercise impact fitness and strength, and even a fair amount on sleep. Less discussed is the impact of mental state and the way the nervous system can interact with muscles to have a huge impact on athletic performance and strength. Since I&#39;ve been reading some alternative theories lately, I thought I&#39;d share some things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nervous Inhibition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s an interesting fact: by default, the nervous system limits muscle tension to 30% of what the associated tendons can bear. So if you can only lift 100lbs, it&#39;s not because your muscles are weak, it&#39;s because your brain is holding you back to protect the tendons. Probably the biggest factor limiting how strong we are is our own nervous system keeping our muscles down to protect us. Another related phenomenon is that the brain will inhibit agonist (primary mover) muscles if it perceives the antagonist is weak, in order to protect the joint. For example, your bicep will be inhibited if your triceps is weak because the brain will worry that, should things get out of hand, the triceps won&#39;t be able to counteract the bicep force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Engine is Bigger than Yours: Efficiency vs. Effectiveness in CrossFit</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-engine-is-bigger-than-yours-efficiency-vs-effectiveness-in-crossfit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-engine-is-bigger-than-yours-efficiency-vs-effectiveness-in-crossfit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/060910_1718_myengineisb1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt;Generally, when presented with any given task, we seek out the most efficient way to complete that task. The less time it takes, the less effort involved, the better. Not so often do we ask ourselves whether we&#39;re doing the right task or not. Is what we are doing actually the most effective way to reach our goals, or is it just busy-work? A Honda is more efficient than a Ferrari, but a Ferrari will get your where you&#39;re going much, much faster, making it more effective if your goal is saving time in transit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
