<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zen on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/zen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zen on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/zen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Seon Templestay in Korea</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-seon-templestay-in-korea/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/a-seon-templestay-in-korea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we get too caught up in the busyness of the world, we lose connection with one another - and ourselves. - Jack Kornfield&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2851&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;717&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSC_9400-Version-2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-2851 &#34; alt=&#34;Photo credit: Anna &amp;quot;Rocketpack&amp;quot; Pusack&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/DSC_9400-Version-2-1024x685.jpg&#34; width=&#34;717&#34; height=&#34;479&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photo credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rocketpackphoto.com&#34;&gt;Anna &#34;Rocketpack&#34; Pusack&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke abruptly in a pitch dark cell, wrapped in pre-dawn silence. Suddenly, the distant wooden bell that had woken me rang out again, accompanied by the ghostly chanting of a Korean Seon (Zen) monk whose duty it was to rouse fellow monks, visiting foreigners, and stubborn Korean teenagers. The sounds faded quickly, swallowed by the forests and mountains around us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was 4:00am. The world gave no indication that morning was in the schedule. I had come here exactly for the discipline of this simple temple life, but even I found it difficult to rouse myself this early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bell and the chanting monk came closer, moving out of the mystical realm into the waking world. It was time to get up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I folded my blankets, pulled on my jacket, slid out the heavy wooden door of my sleeping cell, and started up the mountain to join the others in a session of Buddhist chanting and meditation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stepping into a small, close shrine, I took my place at a meditation cushion. My girlfriend and I had been taught the day before how to do the introductory bows, and we went through them now, knees and backs aching. Soon, everyone had arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A monk rang a clapper and all was silent. Then, as abrupt and distinct as the lone wooden bell, chanting rang out and engulfed the room. We were carried away in its driving, insistent rhythm that thrummed like a force of nature through our bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spirit of Buddha awoke within us like a lotus, coaxed from sleep by the relentless, comforting chants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So began my templestay at Golgulsa Temple in Gyeong-ju, South Korea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empty Your Cup: Accepting Ignorance to Learn</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/empty-your-cup-accepting-ignorance-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/empty-your-cup-accepting-ignorance-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1828&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Neal on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/31878512@N06/4748872561/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1828&#34; title=&#34;teacup&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/teacup-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A university professor went to visit a famous Zen master. While the master quietly served tea, the professor talked about Zen. The master poured the visitor&#39;s cup to the brim, and then kept pouring. The professor watched the overflowing cup until he could no longer restrain himself. &#34;It&#39;s overfull! No more will go in!&#34; the professor blurted. &#34;You are like this cup,&#34; the master replied, &#34;How can I show you Zen unless you first empty your cup.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently moved to South Korea to teach English to kids for a year. Adjusting to the new culture has been both humorous and challenging; things that I usually consider very simple have become extremely difficult. Basics of living—eating healthy, exercising regularly, and even basic hygiene—have new rules and best practices that I just don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve had to accept that I really don’t know how to do much around here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Right Action, Right Intent</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/right-action-right-intent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/right-action-right-intent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1232&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Alice PopKorn on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alicepopkorn/1676300378/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1232&#34; title=&#34;meditation&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/meditation-300x222.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;222&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;We make sacred pact. I promise teach karate to you, you promise learn. I say, you do, no questions.&#34; -Mr. Miyagi, Karate Kid (1984)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad has been baking a lot of bread recently, experimenting with different ingredients and developing his own unique style of bread. When I read his cookbook, I found out why. Instead of simply giving him a bread recipe, the author of his book explains what each step is intended to accomplish: the various factors that determine how much flour to use, how long to let the bread rise, why you let the bread rise, and what occurs in the dough during baking. It borders on chemistry, but the result is that my dad has a much better grasp of why each step must be taken, and can make adjustments to get his desired effect. If he wants to get a crispier crust, he knows what to change and how to compensate to avoid ruining his loaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zen Habits Handbook for Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/zen-habits-handbook-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/zen-habits-handbook-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_950&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: kristofabrath on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kristofabrath/3206231510/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-950&#34; title=&#34;zen&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/zen-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smile, breathe, and go slowly &lt;em&gt;- Thich Nhat Hanh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when I was in college, drowning under the immense workload and the complexities of balancing my social life, personal life, and scholastic commitments, I stumbled upon a blog that saved my academic standing as well as my sanity. The blog is called Zen Habits, and it was a godsend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Listening</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-importance-of-listening/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-importance-of-listening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_729&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: Ro/wererabbit on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wererabbit/3613513307/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-729&#34; title=&#34;listening&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/listening.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we talk about something, we just talk about something, just the positive or the negative side, without trying to express some intellectual, one-sided idea. And we listen without trying to figure out some intellectual understanding, without trying ot understand from just a one-sided view. &lt;em&gt;- Shunryu Suzuki&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine recently wrote a Facebook note in which he mentioned some thoughts on conversations. Specifically, he maintained that it was better to have few conversations, because most people aren&#39;t very good at having conversations. Most people, states my friend, will be quick to follow random tangents in any discussion, never really making any headway on the issue you&#39;d like to discuss. In the end, they are more concerned with their own agenda than participating in the conversation at hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returning to the Dojo: The Importance of Martial Arts</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_713&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; caption=&#34;Source: Pieter Baert on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pietel/15322162/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-713&#34; title=&#34;karate&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/karate2.jpg?w=201&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was a child I have had this instinctive urge for expansion and growth. To me, the function and duty of a quality human being is the sincere and honest development of one&#39;s potential. - Bruce Lee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I attended my first class of American Kenpo Karate in over five years. My old teacher told me in an e-mail to bring my old Gi, which I had kept, anticipating an eventual return to the art. When I went to dig it out from a trunk under my bed, I found my old belts, one soft, well-worn, and white, and the other stiff and bright, un-faded yellow. I grabbed the white belt and headed to class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I stepped into the dance studio where the class was being held, my old instructor, taller and leaner than I remembered, looked at me without recognition. It &lt;em&gt;had &lt;/em&gt;been a long time. He was shocked at the growth he saw in me and had trouble connecting the old Khaled with the one who stood before him. And then he looked down and saw I was wearing my old white belt and asked, &#34;Where&#39;s your belt?&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliminating Distractions</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/eliminating-distractions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/eliminating-distractions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_702&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: tychay on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/tychay/3333787096/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-702&#34; title=&#34;cleandesk&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/cleandesk.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;_mcePaste&#34;&gt;If while washing dishes, we think only of the cup of tea that awaits us, thus hurrying to get the dishes out of the way as if they were a nuisance, then we are not &#34;washing the dishes to wash the dishes.&#34; What&#39;s more, we are not alive during the time we are washing the dishes.... While drinking the cup of tea, we will only be thinking of other things, barely aware of the cup in our hands. Thus we are sucked away into the future -and we are incapable of actually living one minute of life. - Naht Hahn, &lt;em&gt;Miracle of Mindfulness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern technology is a wonderful thing. It gives us access to more information than we could possibly ever hope to read and understand. It connects us to people all over the world and lets us share ideas and conversations with them on a whim. It puts the entirety of human knowledge at our fingertips. As a college student, I was infinitely grateful for the fact that I could do almost all my research and class readings online without having to spend hours in the bookstacks looking for texts. At the click of a button, I could bring to my attention the latest psychological research and in the same breath skim an article on current events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do-It-Yourself Living</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/do-it-yourself-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/do-it-yourself-living/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_687&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Source: Rob Joyce &amp;amp; Alex on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/09/diy.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-687&#34; title=&#34;DIY&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/diy.jpg?w=199&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;“The only Zen you find on tops of mountains is the Zen you bring there” - Robert M. Pirsig&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I have lately started reading the very inspirational &lt;em&gt;Zen Mind, Beginner&#39;s Mind&lt;/em&gt;, by Shunryu Suzuki. This book is a collection of essays on Zen and it is both calming and enlightening to read. One of the overriding themes is the fact that Zen is not something external or alien to us. It already exists within us, in the nature of our minds, bodies, and spirits. Enlightenment is not found in some faraway spiritual realm, or even down the road. Rather, it is right there in your grasp. It is your grasp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Minimalist Warrior</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-minimalist-warrior/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-minimalist-warrior/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/lotus.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-523&#34; title=&#34;lotus&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/lotus.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;198&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I&#39;ve been playing God of War II (a video game, for the un-initiated). In this game, the main character, Kratos, begins the game as the recently appointed god of war, replacing Ares. He has all sorts of powers, wears nifty armor, and has a lot going on in his life. But he is not satisfied. Then, Zeus betrays him. There is a scene of Kratos&#39; armor falling apart, leaving him with nothing but a loincloth, some boots, and his weapons, which is the state he goes through most of the game in. He has a single purpose at that point: to enact vengeance on Zeus. Kratos is a relatively small guy, as far as Greek heroes go - in a face off with Theseus, the Thebian towers over Kratos. Most of Kratos&#39; enemies are decked out in fancy armor, carry ridiculous weapons (usually turned on them by the plucky Spartan), and have access to all sorts of assistance and special powers. Kratos is a minimalist. He powers his way through his environment, using his physical strength and his mental cunning, two simple blades, and little else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-zen-and-the-art-of-motorcycle-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-zen-and-the-art-of-motorcycle-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>I recently completed the book Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance, by Robert M. Pirsig, which, contrary to its name, is not a book about Zen or motorcycle maintenance, except in a very roundabout way.
The book is set in the motorcycle roadtrip of a father, the narrator, and his son, Chris, but the real meat of the book is contained in a series of chataquas, or talks, investigating a philosophical conundrum central to Western thought.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
