<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>principles on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/principles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in principles on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/principles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Guilt by Association; Chained to the Wrong Job</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/guilt-by-association-chained-to-the-wrong-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/guilt-by-association-chained-to-the-wrong-job/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#34;There Is A Voice Inside Of You&lt;br /&gt;
That Whispers All Day Long,&lt;br /&gt;
&#34;I Feel That This Is Right For Me,&lt;br /&gt;
I Know That This Is Wrong.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;
No Teacher, Preacher, Parent, Friend&lt;br /&gt;
Or Wise Man Can Decide&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s Right For You- Just Listen To&lt;br /&gt;
The Voice That Speaks Inside.&#34; - Shel Silverstein&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/7550109580_08554ef572.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2454&#34; title=&#34;Chained to your job&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/7550109580_08554ef572-247x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;247&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Today, my employer did something that got me really angry. I&#39;m not going to go into details, because even though she doesn&#39;t read English and I wouldn&#39;t mind that much if I got fired at this point, it would still be kind of underhanded to do it publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;However, today&#39;s events did teach me a very important lesson about integrity: When I work for someone, a group, or a company, I need to make sure their values are in line with my own, otherwise I risk putting my efforts and energy into causes that I either don&#39;t care about, or that I am totally opposed to.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you work for an organization, your efforts are directed towards achieving that organization&#39;s ends. Sometimes, this is great. With the multiplier effect of a dedicated community, your small contribution can have much larger effects than it otherwise would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if you don&#39;t agree with what your organization is doing, then your energy is applied to something you would otherwise oppose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is why &lt;a title=&#34;The 3 Things You Need for a Complete Life (my mother agrees)&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/3-things-complete-life/&#34;&gt;Awareness &lt;/a&gt;is extremely important in ensuring that you live the life you want. If you don&#39;t pay attention to the implications of your actions, then you end up being taken for a ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living on Principle</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/living-on-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/living-on-principle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1357&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;ground.zero on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/groundzero/96516632/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1357&#34; title=&#34;determination&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/determination-300x171.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;171&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have habits outside the norm, people look at you funny, even when they admire what you do. I avoid sugar at all costs. Everyone I know thinks this is a good idea in terms of nutrition and health, something they&#39;d hypothetically like to do, but they don&#39;t really envision themselves as able to give up sugar. It is just too far outside of the normal American dietary experience. My friends ask wistfully how they can lose weight or have my energy levels. I tell them, don&#39;t eat sugar, and they respond with, &#34;I wish I could do that, but I just couldn&#39;t give up sugar. I love it too much. How can you live without eating sugar?&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
