<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>discomfort on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/discomfort/</link>
    <description>Recent content in discomfort on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/discomfort/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Two Ways to Play the Game of Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/two-ways-to-play-the-game-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/two-ways-to-play-the-game-of-life/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Now we&#39;re going to do front flips from high up.&#34; My coach pointed at three platforms and the crash mat below them. &#34;You can do either the 2 foot, the 4 foot, or the 6 foot, whichever you&#39;re comfortable with.&#34;
We all went for the 4 foot platform. It wasn&#39;t so high and scary as the 6 foot, but it was bigger than the 2 foot so we felt like we were pushing ourselves a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Skill You&#39;ll Ever Learn</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-most-important-skill-youll-ever-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-most-important-skill-youll-ever-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Go eagerly where the fear is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are at a party. Across the snack table, you notice a small crowd gathering around an underdressed guy in jeans and a t-shirt. He turns out to be a well-known science-fiction book agent. Just the person you are looking to meet since finishing your novel. You want to talk to that person. But he looks busy, probably wouldn&#39;t appreciate &lt;em&gt;another &lt;/em&gt;awestruck peon, and you wouldn&#39;t get much talk time anyway. You are convinced it would be a waste of time. So you decide to ask the host for his e-mail address on your way out and write later. You have very good reasons not to introduce yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then...as you turn back to the friends you came with, you wonder, why are you even making reasons? You aren&#39;t making that effort for anyone else in the room. Just this one guy who it would be a great idea &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;to talk to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&#39;s when you know: if you leave this party without introducing yourself, you will leave defeated. You will have found exactly the thing that you need to do to move forward, and shied away from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The things you need to do to move forward are always the things you fear doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn to Love Pain</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learn-to-love-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/learn-to-love-pain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1593&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Nathan Phillips on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/npphoto/4383990220/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1593&#34; title=&#34;pain&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/pain-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you could get past pain and discomfort by  accepting it and relaxing into it? I don’t mean that the pain goes away,  but rather that you become okay with it. You still feel it, but it  doesn’t bother you. You can get on with whatever it is you’re doing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
