<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cost of living on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/cost-of-living/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cost of living on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/cost-of-living/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Much Do You Cost? How Much Do You Create?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-much-do-you-cost-how-much-do-you-create/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-much-do-you-cost-how-much-do-you-create/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/3544855402_ef3c3c980d.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2165&#34; title=&#34;Expensive Foundations&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3544855402_ef3c3c980d-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I am an expensive human being, for better or worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not expensive because I live lavishly. I am expensive because, in social and ecological terms, I cost a lot to produce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My education took place at a university, supported by a huge staff of underpaid workers who themselves would never have the chance to study in the classrooms they cleaned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My fitness training took place in expensive gyms where only very determined or very wealthy people could afford to train,  which were stocked with equipment shipped across the world from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My nutrition, on Paleo, was supported by the deaths of more animals than I care to count (with such a strong reliance on protein) and costly exotic fruits and vegetables (like coconut oil).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My writing takes place on a MacBook Air, one of the most expensive pen-and-paper substitutes in existence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a financial point of view, I don&#39;t spend too much. From a resource perspective, however, I consume a lot. &lt;strong&gt;Of all the 7+ billion humans on Earth, I am easily among the costliest for the planet to maintain&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cost of Living</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-cost-of-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-cost-of-living/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2134&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/DSC_6310.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-2134&#34; title=&#34;Small Hostel&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/DSC_6310-200x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The cramped but lovely hostel we stayed at in Kyoto[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a short post, because I&#39;m in Kyoto and don&#39;t want to be spending too much time on my computer, but something I&#39;ve experienced in Japan has got me to thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything here is very small&lt;/strong&gt;: the houses, the cars, the trains, the towels. There is a mentality that we should not use more than we need. That applies to space, food, money and resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Japan is not a developing country. It is fairly affluent. It &lt;em&gt;is &lt;/em&gt;expensive to live here, but that hasn&#39;t always been the case, and many of the small buildings are much older than Japan&#39;s current situation. It wouldn&#39;t be beyond the Japanese to have SUVs lining the streets, towering apartment complexes with massive floorplans, and showers with hot water that didn&#39;t need to be prepared ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I know Japan has a lot of problems, and the Japanese do some pretty atrocious things (like massacre dolphins), but I&#39;m going to go out on a limb and suggest that you can have respect for resources without unreasonable hatred of cetaceans. The two are not necessarily linked to each other.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, I&#39;m comparing Japan to America, where everyone aspires to a half-acre lot with a 40,000 sq. ft. pre-fab house sitting atop a hill, with an SUV or two in the driveway. &lt;strong&gt;Towels are big, meals are big, and everything is cheap, so it doesn&#39;t matter if you waste it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nothing is cheap here in Japan, and that is a strong reminder to use things wisely and only buy what you need&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
