<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>determination on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/determination/</link>
    <description>Recent content in determination on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/determination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This Isn&#39;t Going to Be Easy, Is It?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/this-isnt-going-to-be-easy-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/this-isnt-going-to-be-easy-is-it/</guid>
      <description>Chi Ku (Eat Bitter) -Chinese proverb, meaning, &#34;to endure hardship to attain a goal&#34;
 I have been in Boulder almost a full year now, and it hasn&#39;t been easy.
I came here thinking it was meant to be. I would show up, tell people that I taught natural movement, and BAM, the money would start rolling in. I would be surrounded by nature and like-minded people, be in the midst of deepening my understanding of ecopsychology, and helping others connect with nature and their bodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Life Gets in the Way, What do You Do?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/when-life-gets-in-the-way-what-do-you-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/when-life-gets-in-the-way-what-do-you-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/bigrock.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3150&#34; alt=&#34;bigrock&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/bigrock-300x225.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Om Gam Ganapataye Namaha -Mantra to Ganesh, Remover of Obstacles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s the day before, and you&#39;ve committed to turning over a new leaf. Exercise, productivity, healthy eating, and overflowing compassion, starting tomorrow morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But to fit it in, you&#39;ll need to get up a bit earlier than usual. No problem, as going to bed early is part of your plan too. Off to bed at 9pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then your neighbor&#39;s dog gets loose in the middle of the night and her barking keeps you up for an hour. You wake up groggy when your alarm goes off at 6am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life Gets in the Way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, fueled by the passion of the untried, you make it out for your morning run. It&#39;s rough getting started, but once you hit your stride, your pace blows off the early morning cobwebs, and you return home invigorated and encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At work, you dive right in to your to-do&#39;s, rather than checking your e-mail, chatting with your coworkers, and adjusting your seat as usual. By 11am, you&#39;re on track to finish your required work so that you can work on that special project of your own that will get you ahead in the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, Mr. Garfield comes by with a request that you attend an &#34;emergency meeting&#34; right after lunch. Checking your schedule, you figure you can handle the slight delay and still stay on track if you eat at your desk. But, while you&#39;re doing that, Sarah comes by and says that she&#39;s going out of town tomorrow so she&#39;d like to discuss that important project with you over lunch. There goes your lunch break.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Instant Under the Bar</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/an-instant-under-the-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/an-instant-under-the-bar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1274&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Marc-Andre Casavant on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/casavant/4415188448/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1274&#34; title=&#34;olylift&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/olylift-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, over the course of something like two hours and 15-20 failed attempts, I managed to snatch 165 lbs, which is significant because that is my bodyweight (a snatch is an Olympic weightlifting movement in which you take a bar from the ground to overhead in one motion). I had set a bodyweight snatch as a goal almost a year ago, and had gotten to 160 lbs long before, but that elusive 5 lbs seemed impossible. Yesterday, I decided I would nail it, and in the end, it was mostly this determination that made the difference, rather than any actual performance improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
