<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>heroism on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/heroism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in heroism on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/heroism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Atlas Smiled</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/atlas-smiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/atlas-smiled/</guid>
      <description>The story of the titan Atlas is traditionally one of oppression. As punishment for his defiance of the Olympian gods, Atlas is imprisoned by Zeus, condemned to carry the sky on his shoulders for all eternity. He gets a brief respite when he convinces Heracles to carry the load, but is quickly tricked back into his chains. And so he stands, crushed by the weight of the sky, for all of his immortal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Everyday Hero</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-everyday-hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-everyday-hero/</guid>
      <description>What does heroism mean to you?
For some people, heroism is about showing up for their families. Maybe you make a comfortable income, but getting home late and never having the chance to tuck your kids into bed makes you feel empty and hollow.
For others, it&#39;s the other way around: you take care of the home and family, but you want to have a bigger impact in the wider community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Adventure Next Door</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-adventure-next-door/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-adventure-next-door/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3917&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/mundane-e1422321898327.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mundane&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;321&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently visited the Hemingway House in Key West, where I got to see glimpses of the life of a very interesting man. He lived during a period full of historically significant events, but walking through his house, I could imagine the years crawling quietly by, much as they seem to in my own home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hemingway, however, didn&#39;t just hang out at home. His walls were full of photos of places he&#39;d been and things he&#39;d done, artifacts from his travels, and all the indicators of a life well-spent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine that the average person in 1940, when Hemingway published &lt;em&gt;For Whom the Bell Tolls,&lt;/em&gt; thought it was a fairly mundane time. There was a world war going on, sure, but we in America have essentially been at war since 2001, and in 1940, mainland America had never been directly threatened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, 1940 seems like a romantic era full of heroes and drama, but in reality, it was the individuals, like Hemingway, who brought the heroism and drama to the times. I imagine he would have thought our time was full to the brim with adventure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heroes are Rare</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/heroes-are-rare/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/heroes-are-rare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/3468969774_2e1327b481.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2123&#34; title=&#34;Ancient Hero&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3468969774_2e1327b481-e1343308708728.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“A hero is someone who has given his or her life to something bigger than oneself.” -Joseph Campbell&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heroes are rare. That&#39;s why we tell legends about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heroes do the things nobody else can do, the things nobody else has the courage or the will to do. Heroes do the hard things.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without heroes, society sits on auto-pilot because we are kept &lt;a title=&#34;The 3 Things You Need for a Complete Life (my mother agrees)&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/3-things-complete-life/&#34;&gt;unaware&lt;/a&gt;. Nobody fights to see the truth. And when the truth surfaces anyway--the problems society can no longer hide--there is nobody with the intention or the &lt;a title=&#34;The Compete Human Being&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-compete-human-being/&#34;&gt;integrity &lt;/a&gt;to stand up, do the work, and change it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; heroes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could be a hero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;But heroes are rare for a reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Ordinary Heroes: Me and My Dad in the Storm of 2010</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/two-ordinary-heroes-me-and-my-dad-in-the-storm-of-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/two-ordinary-heroes-me-and-my-dad-in-the-storm-of-2010/</guid>
      <description>This past week has been pretty hard on everyone in Southwestern Connecticut. My dad and I had a little adventure of our own, which I wanted to share, not so much because I want people to know as because I want to write it down somewhere. This blog has become my journal, so here it is.
Just a Regular Day in Connecticut Around mid-afternoon last Saturday, our power went out. My mom had just pulled a chicken out of the oven, and was braising a boar loin, so we were pretty upset at the inconvenience, but weren&#39;t especially concerned.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
