<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/self/</link>
    <description>Recent content in self on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/self/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re Not the One Who Will Achieve Your Dreams</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youre-not-the-one-who-will-achieve-your-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/youre-not-the-one-who-will-achieve-your-dreams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“The recipe for perpetual ignorance is: Be satisfied with your opinions and content with your knowledge.” -Elbert Hubbard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We know what we are, but know now what we may be.” - William Shakespeare&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/6527715119_b568570ab2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2499&#34; title=&#34;The Illusion of the Self&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/6527715119_b568570ab2-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest obstacles to accomplishing our greatest dreams and goals is the fear of growth. We are unwilling to change, even in a positive way, because growth is painful. Even when we get stronger as a result, we tend to shy away from the necessary discomfort that comes with the process of improving ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After all, growth only comes as the result of learning to deal with challenges that are slightly beyond us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem is that,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;in order to accomplish our goals, we must grow.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we didn&#39;t need to grow, we would already be doing what we dream about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on our particular dream, the kind of change and growth we need will be different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to get stronger, faster, healthier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to make more connections and meet more people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to gain deeper insight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to learn new ideas and master new theories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to see the world in a slightly different way that empowers us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to play a bigger game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We need to be comfortable with the things that scare us at the moment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To a large extent, that last one covers all the others, and it is significant because it is integral to our sense of who we are. &lt;strong&gt;Our fears create our limiting image of ourselves&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Does it Mean to &#34;Be Yourself?&#34;</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1936&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;MSVG on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/msvg/5084966203/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1936&#34; title=&#34;Look at Yourself&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5084966203_de436b21b5-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are content to be simply yourself and don&#39;t compare or compete, everyone will respect you. -Lao Tsu&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know why it is so hard to be myself, but it seems to be the biggest challenge I have faced in life. From what I read of others’ journeys, it is a universal struggle. Not only is it difficult, it is fraught with dead ends, false trails, and misleading half-truths. For many of us, we don’t even realize we are not being ourselves. We think we are acting spontaneously and expressing a creative individuality, but in fact we are mimicking some idea of individuality or are simply repeating old habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does it mean to ‘be yourself?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think ‘being yourself’ is the kind of thing you can talk about directly. It is the subject of Buddhist meditation, the mystic’s search for communion with the divine, and an entire literature of spiritual, scientific, and cultural studies. So, to explain what I think it means to ‘be yourself’ I will resort to an example.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
