<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>travel-hacking on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/travel-hacking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in travel-hacking on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/travel-hacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nine Days in Portugal for $1525</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/nine-days-in-portugal-for-1525/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/nine-days-in-portugal-for-1525/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/porto.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1662&#34; title=&#34;porto&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/porto-300x200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;My girlfriend and I just returned from a nine day trip to  Portugal, in which we stayed at the Sheraton Lisboa, a number of  hostels, toured Lisbon and Porto for two days each, and spent two days  at the fishing village of Peniche. We ate really, really well (a little  too well actually), usually at restaurants with a few home-cooked meals.  We took trams and buses and trains all over the place, and spent a day  exploring an island off the coast. We also spent a day in Barcelona,  Spain, on our way to Portugal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And we did is all for $1525 per person&lt;/strong&gt;. Considering  how poorly we managed our money, I think that is a pretty good deal,  and it includes all incidentals. The cost of airfare getting to Portugal  and back was only $725 per person, and accommodation was less than $200  per person for the whole trip. If you cooked more of your own meals at  hostels, or weren’t so ditzy about navigating public transportation,  your incidentals would have been lower than ours (about $600).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering that I am only occasionally employed, it seems that if we can make this happen, anyone should be able to do it too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this seems ridiculously affordable, I thought I’d share how we did it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
