<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nervous system on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/nervous-system/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nervous system on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/nervous-system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Your Brain is Making You Weak</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/your-brain-is-making-you-weak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/your-brain-is-making-you-weak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/06/brain.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-611&#34; title=&#34;brain&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/brain.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;There&#39;s a lot in the fitness community on how diet and exercise impact fitness and strength, and even a fair amount on sleep. Less discussed is the impact of mental state and the way the nervous system can interact with muscles to have a huge impact on athletic performance and strength. Since I&#39;ve been reading some alternative theories lately, I thought I&#39;d share some things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nervous Inhibition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s an interesting fact: by default, the nervous system limits muscle tension to 30% of what the associated tendons can bear. So if you can only lift 100lbs, it&#39;s not because your muscles are weak, it&#39;s because your brain is holding you back to protect the tendons. Probably the biggest factor limiting how strong we are is our own nervous system keeping our muscles down to protect us. Another related phenomenon is that the brain will inhibit agonist (primary mover) muscles if it perceives the antagonist is weak, in order to protect the joint. For example, your bicep will be inhibited if your triceps is weak because the brain will worry that, should things get out of hand, the triceps won&#39;t be able to counteract the bicep force.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
