<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>energy on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/energy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in energy on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/energy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My 2015 Strategy Part 2: The Logistics of Being Awesome</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-2-the-logistics-of-being-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-2-the-logistics-of-being-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3880&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/timeclock-e1420568994227.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;timeclock&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;245&#34; /&gt;Last week, I shared &lt;a title=&#34;My 2015 Strategy Part 1: Dreams and Aspirations&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/my-2015-strategy-part-1-dreams-and-aspirations/&#34;&gt;my overarching strategy for 2015&lt;/a&gt; and how I got there, with a simple, but very helpful exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, I was planning to talk about specific actions and the structures I&#39;m going to put into place to support my plans, but it became a longer article than I&#39;d expected. So, I&#39;m going to limit it to logistics now, and actions on Thursday, because dreams without action will stay that way, and action without logistics will fizzle out real fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Quick Definitions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize not everyone here is a military history buff (or UPS admirer), so you may not be entirely familiar with what logistics are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, logistics are the support systems that enable an army to do its job. This includes things like food, transportation systems, and even lifestyle. The best trained Navy SEAL is useless without the entire support system that puts him in the right place to start his mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your personal life, it is important to create a system to support you. This includes things like your habits, your environment, and your routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good logistics are just as essential as good strategy and good tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Logistics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with last week&#39;s post was that I didn&#39;t account for time, energy, or financial resources; I simply wrote down everything I want to do in the next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this week, I&#39;ll show you how to handle the rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Inflicted Wounds: The Gulf of Mexico Oil Spill</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/self-inflicted-wounds-the-gulf-of-mexico-oil-spill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/self-inflicted-wounds-the-gulf-of-mexico-oil-spill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/05/oilspill.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-571&#34; title=&#34;oilspill&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/oilspill.jpg?w=199&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I generally don&#39;t follow current events in much detail and prefer to stay uninvolved in politics. If I had my way, I&#39;d require all children to be educated on the importance of the natural world, at the expense of more &#39;practical&#39; subjects, but I tend to maintain some distance from most environmental issues, simply because they tend to be so heartbreaking, with so many angry people on both sides. To get emotionally involved would be like asking for a stress-induced heart attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I read an article in Time about the Deep Horizon disaster. I had known what was going on, but was not aware of the extent of the damage. Reading it was like watching a horror movie; it was so horrific I wanted to cover my eyes, but something compelled me to keep reading, to subject myself to the terrible scenes and let the images of the ecological disaster crowd my mind. I felt my heart grow cold with fear for all the environmental damage that would and has occurred, all the diversity that would be lost and perhaps never recovered. I felt anger at the people who had allowed this to happen: the oil companies and our government. But most of all, I felt a deep sadness. How terrible that our civilization has come to this habit of destroying its most beautiful environments and coastlines for the sake of a few more years of dirty, smoggy convenience.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
