<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>campbell on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/campbell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in campbell on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/campbell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pursue Your Bliss with Integrity</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/pursue-your-bliss-with-integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/pursue-your-bliss-with-integrity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is it that makes it so hard for us to pursue our dreams? Why is it so frustrating to pull together all the elements of our lives in order to move in the direction we so fervently want to go?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Follow Your Bliss - Joseph Campbell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Campbell compared the internal psychological journey of our lives with classic myths that have accompanied humans throughout history: from Genesis to Robin Hood, Coyote to Quetzalcoatl, &lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, the stories that move us all share common themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campbell believed that these themes were reflections of the stages of human development: if we have the &lt;a title=&#34;5 Ways to Boost Your Courage Right Now!&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/5-ways-to-boost-your-courage-right-now/&#34;&gt;courage&lt;/a&gt; to face up to our psychic dragons and to descend into the dark caves and underworlds of our fears and insecurities, we can face the challenges that allow us to become true heroes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we lack that courage, then we stagnate, never living up to our potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;&#34;&gt;This begs the question of what directs our growth. Campbell&#39;s answer would be that it is our dreams, aspirations, and passions, the thing that we were put on this earth to do, that drive us. Follow your bliss unerringly and with commitment, and you will surely become the hero of your myth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the myths, the greatest treasures are kept in the darkest caves, guarded by the most fearsome monsters. &lt;strong&gt;Likewise, attaining our bliss requires us to &lt;a title=&#34;Insecurity, the Root of All Evil&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/insecurity-the-root-of-all-evil/&#34;&gt;face our most ingrained fears&lt;/a&gt; and negative habits&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
