<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>holidays on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/holidays/</link>
    <description>Recent content in holidays on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/holidays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Happy Holidays from Warrior Spirit, and Looking Back with Gratitude</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/happy-holidays-from-warrior-spirit-and-looking-back-with-gratitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/happy-holidays-from-warrior-spirit-and-looking-back-with-gratitude/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3866&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/winterroad-e1419626354443.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;winterroad&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;269&#34; /&gt;Dear Reader,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank you for your continued support in 2014. Every year, I take the opportunity of the holidays to express my gratitude to everyone who has impacted my life in the last twelve months, and since this blog is a big part of my life, you&#39;re one of those people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been a very rough year for me. After the success of launching my first ebook in 2012 and gaining a big following in 2013, I let my expectations get out of control. I got frustrated and the quality of my writing suffered. I lost focus. I feel like Warrior Spirit has lost a lot of what made it a great blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Good&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, there were a lot of good things that happened, too. I got engaged, which was a big step for me, reignited my love of games, am taking a chess class (see below), and started work on my novel, which is now almost halfway written. I managed to pay down half of my credit card debt and began working with a money, career, and business coach to take my lofty ambitions and give them some focus. I started an internship, increased my income, and established a regular meditation practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it&#39;s been a good year, but the biggest hole has been the spotty posting here. I know (because you&#39;ve told me) that Warrior Spirit provides a lot of value for its readers, and that gives me a lot to work with. So I&#39;ve committed to getting back to twice-a-week postings, which seems to be the sweet spot based on previous years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Warrior Spirit in 2015&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assert that anyone can become a hero in his or her community and life, the kind of person that changes the world for those they care about. I have always wanted to support people in doing that by helping them live up to their greatest potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now, in 2015, I am making the blog all about that and committing to taking concrete, specific action on helping you achieve your goals, whatever they are, by empowering you to be the best you can be.&lt;/strong&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Holidays from Warrior Spirit</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/happy-holidays-from-warrior-spirit-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/happy-holidays-from-warrior-spirit-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2624&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;224&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/happy-holidays-from-warrior-spirit-2/img_0001/&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2624&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-2624&#34; alt=&#34;Christmas at our house is a pretty small affair&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/IMG_0001-224x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;224&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Christmas at our house is a pretty small affair[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, the holidays at the end of the year are my time for reflection and spiritual recuperation after a long year full of activity and constant growth. This year in particular was especially exhilarating. The work that went into &lt;a title=&#34;Lessons Learned on Finishing My First Book&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/lessons-learned-on-finishing-my-first-book/&#34;&gt;writing my book&lt;/a&gt; and promoting it while teaching English in Korea was extremely taxing emotionally and mentally, and when it was done, I found it difficult to keep up that pace of work (hence the drop off in social media and general writing activity). There was never really a chance to rest, since A and I were still working and traveling: we visited Jeju Island, flew back to the States for a wedding, visited the DMZ, did a three day templestay, and went on a whirlwind tour of the Middle East (more on those things to come).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While these activities did involve some physical work, they were most taxing mentally. We were always on the run, always desperate for a good night&#39;s sleep, living a largely nomadic existence, constantly working under looming deadlines, worried about missing buses, trains, planes. It was intense, and the demands of &lt;a title=&#34;Keeping it Together; The Importance of Good Life Posture&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/keeping-it-together-the-importance-of-good-life-posture/&#34;&gt;maintaining proper life posture&lt;/a&gt; became much more difficult under the constantly shifting circumstances. We were on our own most of the time, reliant on our own resources and disconnected from our families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&#39;ve been looking forward to this quiet holiday season for several months.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
