<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>positivepsych on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/positivepsych/</link>
    <description>Recent content in positivepsych on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/positivepsych/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re Not Broken, So You Can&#39;t &#34;Fix&#34; Yourself</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/youre-not-broken-so-you-cant-fix-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/youre-not-broken-so-you-cant-fix-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When a computer gets old and starts to slow down, we know it is time to buy a new one. Computers can&#39;t grow, learn, or adapt, so once they have outlived their usefulness, developed too many bugs, or are simply broken, we scrap them. This makes sense because a computer performs a specific function, and if it can&#39;t do that, it is useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine for a moment if we treated humans like that. Wouldn&#39;t it be stupid if we just gave up on people or ourselves because of one or two bugs that tripped them up every now and then? Totally ridiculous, right? People, after all, grow and adapt. We can learn, and even if we are slow to learn, we can make adjustments for our weaknesses in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/3774175_73285f84a9.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2540&#34; title=&#34;Baby Jane&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/3774175_73285f84a9-300x212.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;212&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yet, many people view themselves through the same standards they assess their computers, cars, and refrigerators.&lt;/strong&gt; Unfortunately, you can&#39;t just go out and buy a new psych, so what course of action is called for when you believe you are non-functional?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How we view life and ourselves determines how successful we will be in dealing with its challenges, and choosing to view ourselves through this particular lens does more harm than good.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
