<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>college on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/college/</link>
    <description>Recent content in college on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/college/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pigeonholing Myself</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/pigeonholing-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/pigeonholing-myself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/pigeon.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-507&#34; title=&#34;pigeon&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/pigeon.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In high school, we have so many dreams and activities. In order to be competitive for college, we fill our transcripts with a crazy variety of activities: math club, Boy Scouts, flying lessons, karate, cross country, guitar, piano lessons. This is in addition to our classes, which tend to cover a wide range of subjects: precalc, biology, English, painting. Then in college, we start off with a fairly broad range of topics to study, and as we move towards our major, the subjects narrow down to one or two: psychology and international studies of the Middle East. Then, after college, we get a job and are expected to become experts in one single field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to consider myself a renaissance man, with interests in a wide range of activities, but I&#39;m not so sure anymore. After all, I spend so much of my time studying fitness and in training. My conversations with people tend to gravitate towards talk about health, fitness, and nutrition. Last night while bartending,  a guy at the bar wanted to watch the NFL draft, and I had no clue how to have a conversation with him. I never really followed or understood football, but it made be wonder if I&#39;m either out of touch with society or simply too narrow in my interests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: I am Charlotte Simmons</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-i-am-charlotte-simmons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-i-am-charlotte-simmons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&amp;lt;iframe src=&amp;quot;http://rcm.amazon.com/e/cm?lt1=_blank&amp;amp;bc1=000000&amp;amp;IS2=1&amp;amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;amp;fc1=000000&amp;amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;amp;t=warrspir-20&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;p=8&amp;amp;l=as1&amp;amp;m=amazon&amp;amp;f=ifr&amp;amp;md=10FE9736YVPPT7A0FBG2&amp;amp;asins=0312424442&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;width:120px;height:240px;&amp;quot; scrolling=&amp;quot;no&amp;quot; marginwidth=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; marginheight=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt; &#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; title=&#34;Book Cover&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/charlotte-simmons.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;233&#34; height=&#34;350&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just finished Tom Wolfe&#39;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&amp;lt;iframe src=&amp;quot;http://rcm.amazon.com/e/cm?lt1=_blank&amp;amp;bc1=000000&amp;amp;IS2=1&amp;amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;amp;fc1=000000&amp;amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;amp;t=warrspir-20&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;p=8&amp;amp;l=as1&amp;amp;m=amazon&amp;amp;f=ifr&amp;amp;md=10FE9736YVPPT7A0FBG2&amp;amp;asins=0312424442&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;width:120px;height:240px;&amp;quot; scrolling=&amp;quot;no&amp;quot; marginwidth=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; marginheight=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt; &#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I am Charlotte Simmons&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; a disturbingly accurate depiction of modern American college life. The book is set in the fictional Ivy League University of Dupont, in Pennsylvania, and follows the first year of high school prodigy Charlotte Simmons. Charlotte, having won every award conceivable in high school, arrives at college with high expectations but finds herself overwhelmed by a world that cares more about social standing than academic achievement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Take Nothin’ from Nobody</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/don%e2%80%99t-take-nothin%e2%80%99-from-nobody/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/don%e2%80%99t-take-nothin%e2%80%99-from-nobody/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m currently reading Tom Wolfe&#39;s &lt;em&gt;I am Charlotte Simmons, &lt;/em&gt;a magnificently detailed and richly described look at American college life. One of the main characters, Hoyt, is at the top of the college social ladder, a frat boy. His big claim to fame is the accidental witnessing of the visiting governor of California in a compromising situation, and a subsequent confrontation with the governor&#39;s bodyguard. The bodyguard challenged Hoyt and his friend, but instead of backing down, Hoyt took the question seriously, responding to the bodyguard &#34;what do you two think you&#39;re doing?&#34; with an honest answer. His confidence in his right to be there caught the bodyguard off guard, getting him angry enough to attack the boys, to his ultimate detriment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Was Going to College a Mistake?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/was-going-to-college-a-mistake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/was-going-to-college-a-mistake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am in the midst of reading &lt;em&gt;Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance &lt;/em&gt;by Robert M. Pirsig&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;and the author spends a lot of time talking about the educational system in the United States, indeed, all of Western civilization. As a recent college graduate, this is something I&#39;ve actually questioned a lot myself. I don&#39;t know about most of my peers, but I never really thought of college as a necessity, or even a forgone conclusion. When I applied to college, I did it in the context of an expectation - I went to a college-prep school and was at the top of my class, everybody at that school expected me to go to college - but I personally did not necessarily want to go to college. I chose to go, consciously, because I was convinced that it would help me achieve my goals. I did, however, entertain other options.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
