<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>psychology on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/psychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in psychology on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why We Avoid Pursuing Our Dreams, and 3 Strategies to Get Motivated</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-we-avoid-pursuing-our-dreams-and-3-strategies-to-get-motivated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/why-we-avoid-pursuing-our-dreams-and-3-strategies-to-get-motivated/</guid>
      <description>Nothing ventured, nothing gained. - Anon
 I marvel at how easy it is for me to do everything except the thing that I dream about: writing a novel. I can blog all day, train, teach fitness and self-defense, promote and market and teach myself Javascript. I make plans and schedules to make these things happen. But for some reason, I have a lot of trouble bringing the same discipline to bear on writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warrior Spirit Evolves</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/warrior-spirit-evolves/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/warrior-spirit-evolves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay...I&#39;ve really got it this time. Seriously. &lt;strong&gt;I now know what this blog is about&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, I&#39;ve said that a lot before, but this time it&#39;s real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check it out. See that snazzy new subtitle. This blog isn&#39;t about me anymore (well, I guess it will always kind of be about me). It&#39;s about &lt;em&gt;Us&lt;/em&gt;, trying to make ourselves the best we can be, so that we can be the most awesome, helpful, revolutionary, world-changing people we can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow Your Own Path</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/follow-your-own-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/follow-your-own-path/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1268&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;198&#34; caption=&#34;anjamation on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/anjamation/2774936688/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1268&#34; title=&#34;celestial path&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/celestial-path-198x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;anjamation on Flickr&#34; width=&#34;198&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Your vision will become clear only when you look into your heart. Who looks outside, dreams. Who looks inside, awakens.” - Carl G. Jung&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reading an excerpt out of a book by Carl Jung last night, and was interested to find a concept that parallels one of the ideas in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/four-books-that-changed-my-life-this-summer/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Hero with a Thousand Faces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Namely, that every individual must find and undergo their own path to individual self-actualization, rather than being able to follow some generalized path. This probably explains why we can spend so much time reading how-to&#39;s and inspirational blogs and never actually get around to doing something; we are reading about someone else&#39;s hero journey, and trying to take it as the direction for our own. Jung&#39;s point was that there is no universal psychological concept that can be applied to every person&#39;s situation and specific problem, despite the modern trend to try to put everyone under a general diagnosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m not Broken, and I Don&#39;t Need to be Fixed</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/im-not-broken-and-i-dont-need-to-be-fixed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/im-not-broken-and-i-dont-need-to-be-fixed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/vitruvian.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1235&#34; title=&#34;vitruvian&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/vitruvian-300x247.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;247&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“The human soul, as a part of the movement of life, is endowed with the ability to participate in the uplift, elevation, perfection, and completion.” -Alfred Adler&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A consumerist society survives off the needs of its members. Thus, it has an interest in convincing the people that they need a wide variety of things and services, else they risk unhappiness and inadequacy. And what better way to support this kind of information campaign than to train people that they are inherently flawed from birth, destined to always come up short without the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/branding-our-lives/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;gracious help of external products and services&lt;/a&gt;, doomed to chronic disease without the newest fad in health foods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choose Your Words Carefully</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/choose-your-words-carefully/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/choose-your-words-carefully/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1023&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Horia Varlan on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/horiavarlan/4536148364/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1023&#34; title=&#34;The word Go made from jigsaw puzzle pieces&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/word-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;We cannot always control our thoughts, but we can control our words, and repetition impresses the subconscious, and we are then master of the situation.&#34; - Florence Scovel Shinn Artist, Teacher and Author&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The words we use to convey our thoughts and describe our lives influence the way we see the world to a greater extent than most of us realize. It may not seem like a big difference, but choosing to use one word or descriptor over another can help you overcome negative or constraining worldviews. Think about how you talk about your goals. Do you refer to them as dreams or as concrete objectives? Do you talk to yourself in the first or second person? Do you refer to other people using condescending terms (&#39;girls&#39; for all women)? Such subtle changes in the language you use will, over time, change the way you think about people and how others deal with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Time Spent Outdoors</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-benefits-of-time-spent-outdoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-benefits-of-time-spent-outdoors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_954&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;222&#34; caption=&#34;Source: ©Hεαṿεṉlÿ Phøτøģɾαρhÿ on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/oooheavenlyooo/3986200282/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-954&#34; title=&#34;nature&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/nature-222x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;222&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man&#39;s heart away from nature becomes hard.  &lt;em&gt;-Standing Bear&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The natural world is all around us. Every city is merely an island of human habitation amidst a vast sea of countryside and forests. A mere hour outside of New York, one of the biggest metropolises in the world, one can find beautiful and surprisingly isolated parks and hiking trails. The hills around LA are still pretty wild (apparently coyotes are a major concern out there). Most cities have parks, little spaces where the city&#39;s fabric is cut out to reveal the nature underneath, just waiting to burst through into sunlight. These are places people can go to escape the hustle of the city for a while. There is something calming and serene about nature. I always feel complete and more balanced when surrounded by trees, and there is a lot to be said for seeking out a regular connection with the outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Beat Procrastination</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-beat-procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-beat-procrastination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_789&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; caption=&#34;Source: CraigGrocott on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/craigweb/2887922337/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-789&#34; title=&#34;procrastination&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/procrastination-199x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Do it now! can affect every phase of your life. It can help you do the things you should do but don&#39;t feel like doing. It can keep you from procrastinating when an unpleasant duty faces you. But it can also help you do those things that you want to do. It helps you seize those precious moments that, if lost, may never be retrieved.” - &lt;em&gt;Napoleon Hill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading my blog today, but I have to ask, is there something more important you have to do that you are putting off by checking in? (Or perhaps reading my blog is the most important thing you have to do today, in which case I&#39;m flattered :)). &lt;strong&gt;Procrastination, the sacred art of putting things off to the last minute, is one of the biggest productivity killers in our lives, and also one of the biggest sources of stress and anxiety&lt;/strong&gt;. It is a learned habit, one that can really mess with your sense of well-being and mental health. It cuts into all aspects of our lives, from reading, to shopping, to paying bills, to exercising. So why do we procrastinate, and how can we eliminate this habit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Integrity: The Complete Human</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-meaning-of-integrity-the-complete-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-meaning-of-integrity-the-complete-human/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_767&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;Source: poeticaldistractions on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/visualpoeticaldistractions/3481595328/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-767&#34; title=&#34;david&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/david-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“The truth of the matter is that you always know the right thing to do. The hard part is doing it.” - General Norman Schwarzkopf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is largely about the development of character. The most important quality of character is integrity, because without it, character has no meaning. So what is integrity, anyway? The word is vaguely defined in most discussions, and looking back over my posts, I realize I have never actually clarified what it is I am talking about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-zen-and-the-art-of-motorcycle-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/book-review-zen-and-the-art-of-motorcycle-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>I recently completed the book Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance, by Robert M. Pirsig, which, contrary to its name, is not a book about Zen or motorcycle maintenance, except in a very roundabout way.
The book is set in the motorcycle roadtrip of a father, the narrator, and his son, Chris, but the real meat of the book is contained in a series of chataquas, or talks, investigating a philosophical conundrum central to Western thought.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
