<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>new year on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/new-year/</link>
    <description>Recent content in new year on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/new-year/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My 2015 Strategy Part 1: Dreams and Aspirations</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-1-dreams-and-aspirations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/my-2015-strategy-part-1-dreams-and-aspirations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3875&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/newyear-e1420164792163.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;newyear&#34; width=&#34;698&#34; height=&#34;280&#34; /&gt;At the end of 2014, I sat down and wrote down all the things I would do if time and money were no issue. It&#39;s a really helpful exercise in figuring out what your mission in life is and where you find fulfillment, one I&#39;ll share in the Exercise section in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I thought, &#34;Okay, so I&#39;ll have a list of things that I can start thinking about doing, SOMEDAY.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Mission&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it turned out that most of the things I wanted to do didn&#39;t require time or money at all. Here&#39;s what I ended up writing, abridged:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;I would write a genre-bending science-fiction novel....I would travel to Tibet, hike the Himalayas, have tea with the Dalai Lama, and encounter a snow leopard in the wild...I would become a valuable resource for all of my friends, providing support, resources, and strategy to help them achieve their goals and dreams...I would travel back to Korea to study with my Krav Maga teacher for an extended sabbatical, and also go to Japan to study with a living ninjutsu master....I would read all the classics...I would find a way to see my friends face-to-face, or at least have more phone conversations, especially with the ones who have stuck with my for years....I would spend more time in nature, camping more than once a year....I would rekindle my love of gaming, playing more RPGs, computer strategy games, and card games with friends....I would get back into flying regularly....Start a business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I distilled those dreams down into the following list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a novel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See Tibet, meet the Dalai Lama, and see a snow leopard in the wild&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Become a martial arts master -- Krav Maga, Kenpo, Ninjutsu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend more face-to-face time with friends and become a valuable support to them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play more games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend more time in nature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start a business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of these, the one that resonated the most and seemed the most central to my idea of success and fulfillment was being there for my friends and supporting people. So that is my mission: &lt;strong&gt;to help the people in my life achieve their dreams by showing them how to be heroic in their own lives and communities.&lt;/strong&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forget the Resolution! Set a Challenge!</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/forget-the-resolution-set-a-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/forget-the-resolution-set-a-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/forget-the-resolution-set-a-challenge/418636_674776395704_416458635_n1/&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2646&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wp-image-2646 aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;418636_674776395704_416458635_n(1)&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/418636_674776395704_416458635_n1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;581&#34; height=&#34;389&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Resolutions are boring. I resolve to behave better this year, blah, blah, blah... This is a whole new &lt;em&gt;YEAR &lt;/em&gt;we&#39;re talking about, not just the turn of an hourglass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s so great about a resolution anyway? Sure, it&#39;s an opportunity to start anew, to take a stab at &lt;a title=&#34;You’re Not Broken, So You Can’t “Fix” Yourself&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/youre-not-broken-so-you-cant-fix-yourself/&#34;&gt;fixing something that you think is broken&lt;/a&gt; about yourself, to be better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why do we want to be better? Is it just to feel good about ourselves? Or are we &lt;a title=&#34;You Can’t Afford to be Attached to Your Health, So Make it About Others&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/you-cant-afford-to-be-attached-to-your-health-so-make-it-about-others/&#34;&gt;trying to accomplish something greater&lt;/a&gt; in our lives than self-satisfaction?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you want to lose weight, or gain muscle, or workout more, or write more, or become financially independent, or eat more local food, or get a promotion, or learn a new language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All attainable goals, great things for anyone to do. Which is fine. If you are aiming for mediocrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we need - what &lt;em&gt;you &lt;/em&gt;need - is something epic, something grand, something game-changing, something that matters to you specifically, something for which you in particular were destined.&lt;/strong&gt; Your bliss, to use the terminology of Joseph Campbell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you follow your bliss... doors will open where you would not have thought there would be doors; and where there wouldn&#39;t be a door for anyone else. - Joseph Campbell&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You don&#39;t need another resolution. You need a challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Holidays from Warrior Spirit</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/happy-holidays-from-warrior-spirit-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/happy-holidays-from-warrior-spirit-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2624&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;224&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/happy-holidays-from-warrior-spirit-2/img_0001/&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2624&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-2624&#34; alt=&#34;Christmas at our house is a pretty small affair&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/IMG_0001-224x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;224&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Christmas at our house is a pretty small affair[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, the holidays at the end of the year are my time for reflection and spiritual recuperation after a long year full of activity and constant growth. This year in particular was especially exhilarating. The work that went into &lt;a title=&#34;Lessons Learned on Finishing My First Book&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/lessons-learned-on-finishing-my-first-book/&#34;&gt;writing my book&lt;/a&gt; and promoting it while teaching English in Korea was extremely taxing emotionally and mentally, and when it was done, I found it difficult to keep up that pace of work (hence the drop off in social media and general writing activity). There was never really a chance to rest, since A and I were still working and traveling: we visited Jeju Island, flew back to the States for a wedding, visited the DMZ, did a three day templestay, and went on a whirlwind tour of the Middle East (more on those things to come).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While these activities did involve some physical work, they were most taxing mentally. We were always on the run, always desperate for a good night&#39;s sleep, living a largely nomadic existence, constantly working under looming deadlines, worried about missing buses, trains, planes. It was intense, and the demands of &lt;a title=&#34;Keeping it Together; The Importance of Good Life Posture&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/keeping-it-together-the-importance-of-good-life-posture/&#34;&gt;maintaining proper life posture&lt;/a&gt; became much more difficult under the constantly shifting circumstances. We were on our own most of the time, reliant on our own resources and disconnected from our families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&#39;ve been looking forward to this quiet holiday season for several months.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
