<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>literacy on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/literacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in literacy on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/literacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You May Be Illiterate</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/you-may-be-illiterate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/you-may-be-illiterate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Could you imagine turning in a resume that listed, &#34;Can read and write,&#34; as one of your notable skills? The idea is laughable, but at one point in history, that was a huge accomplishment and alone could secure you a job far above your station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the day, by which I mean the early Middle Ages, if you weren&#39;t born into the nobility, there were few ways to move up in the world. Military service was one option, but only worked in some places and times. Trade and mercantilism was another, but it required at least some capital to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the most reliable ways was to learn how to read and write, to become literate&lt;/strong&gt;. It was a skill that was in extremely high demand--it was necessary for the conduct of the state and trade--and it was somewhat rare. Those who could convey, prepare, and understand written instructions were entrusted with important information and tasks and granted access to a world of continued learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, literacy became more or less universal. There were those who were more and less literate, but in general, anyone could read a book and write a letter, so you needed something more in order to be of value to those shaping society (or to shape it yourself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came the age of computing (there were probably some other steps in there) and a thing arose called computer literacy. This involved being able to interact with a computer. The computer literate were not necessarily programmers, but they could operate a program and knew how to type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being computer literate opened up a lot of opportunities for you. Companies needed operators and you had a good chance of getting a job even if you weren&#39;t actually knowledgeable in the company&#39;s particular field. Just as a lowly, but literate, peasant might get a job as a merchant&#39;s bookkeeper, a kid who could troubleshoot Microsoft Office might work for a local bank without any financial expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lately, computer literacy has gone the way of word literacy: it has become universal and therefore taken for granted&lt;/strong&gt;. Computer literacy is expected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
