<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>defiance on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/defiance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in defiance on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/defiance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The End of Adventure</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-end-of-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-end-of-adventure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1931&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;ButterflySha in Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/butterflysha/140523563/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1931&#34; title=&#34;stay in line&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/stay-in-line-300x121.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;121&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you wait to do everything until you&#39;re sure it&#39;s right, you&#39;ll probably never do much of anything.” -Win Borden&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To really experience life, you&#39;re going to have to get out of line first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I studied Arabic in Jordan, I initially applied to go through a program. It was quite a prestigious program, and it promised all sorts of  exciting (pre-arranged) adventures in addition to a language study at the University of Jordan. The brochure also stressed how safe it was and how secure the travelling student would be, even as they learned to step outside their comfort zone on a study abroad program. I had my misgivings, but when I got a phone call letting me know I was accepted, I was very excited...until the lady got to the part about the cost of the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having lived in the Middle East, I knew that the costs were inflated. I asked if I could just stay with my family there and spare them the living expenses, but the woman (quickly getting annoyed with me for daring to suggest I might have a better experience through other channels) explained that it would detract from the experience. This didn&#39;t answer my question, and she ended the conversation by saying that if I didn&#39;t pay soon, they would give the spot to someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never followed up with that group. I simply signed up for the University of Jordan&#39;s Arabic program directly. Of course, there were some bumps in the road because of that, but when I showed up with twenty or so other students who hadn&#39;t finalized their registrations, I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; had to &#34;step out of my comfort zone&#34; to speak for all of them and cow the program director into letting us all join the program a day late. That would never have happened if I&#39;d went with the &#39;secure&#39; program.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
