<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>excitement on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/excitement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in excitement on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/excitement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Adventure Next Door</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-adventure-next-door/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-adventure-next-door/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3917&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/mundane-e1422321898327.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mundane&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;321&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently visited the Hemingway House in Key West, where I got to see glimpses of the life of a very interesting man. He lived during a period full of historically significant events, but walking through his house, I could imagine the years crawling quietly by, much as they seem to in my own home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hemingway, however, didn&#39;t just hang out at home. His walls were full of photos of places he&#39;d been and things he&#39;d done, artifacts from his travels, and all the indicators of a life well-spent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine that the average person in 1940, when Hemingway published &lt;em&gt;For Whom the Bell Tolls,&lt;/em&gt; thought it was a fairly mundane time. There was a world war going on, sure, but we in America have essentially been at war since 2001, and in 1940, mainland America had never been directly threatened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, 1940 seems like a romantic era full of heroes and drama, but in reality, it was the individuals, like Hemingway, who brought the heroism and drama to the times. I imagine he would have thought our time was full to the brim with adventure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
