<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>comfort on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/comfort/</link>
    <description>Recent content in comfort on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/comfort/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How a Pair of Jeans Taught Me to Be Myself</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-a-pair-of-jeans-taught-me-to-be-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/how-a-pair-of-jeans-taught-me-to-be-myself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3923&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/Jeans-e1422508471220.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jeans&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;246&#34; /&gt;One day, I needed new pants. The jeans I&#39;d been wearing were so torn up I was ashamed to wear them. I went to Macy&#39;s and bought the jeans I thought I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; own: Levi&#39;s 501s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was so enamored of the label that I didn&#39;t even consider other options, determined to fit into this arbitrary definition of &#39;cool&#39; even if it felt miserable, which it did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have weird proportions. I&#39;m tall and lanky with a narrow waist, which is difficult enough (try finding 31x34 pants anywhere). Add to that the fact that my thighs and glutes are big for my size thanks to weightlifting and I&#39;m impossible to fit. I felt like the Tin Man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I stubbornly biked around in my Real Jeans, feeling good about my authentic denim and that little red tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until the hip pain started and I had to admit that I couldn&#39;t sacrifice my comfort to fit into a pair of pants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was one pair of pants I&#39;ve owned that actually felt and looked really good. They were prAna jeans, which I could get from a local store. They were expensive, had spandex in them, and were so self-consciously stylish, there was no way I could wear them, but I decided to try them on anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living on Principle</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/living-on-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/living-on-principle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1357&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;ground.zero on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/groundzero/96516632/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1357&#34; title=&#34;determination&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/determination-300x171.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;171&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have habits outside the norm, people look at you funny, even when they admire what you do. I avoid sugar at all costs. Everyone I know thinks this is a good idea in terms of nutrition and health, something they&#39;d hypothetically like to do, but they don&#39;t really envision themselves as able to give up sugar. It is just too far outside of the normal American dietary experience. My friends ask wistfully how they can lose weight or have my energy levels. I tell them, don&#39;t eat sugar, and they respond with, &#34;I wish I could do that, but I just couldn&#39;t give up sugar. I love it too much. How can you live without eating sugar?&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
