<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>college grads on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/college-grads/</link>
    <description>Recent content in college grads on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/college-grads/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Give Direction to Your Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-give-direction-to-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/how-to-give-direction-to-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/05/compass.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-562&#34; title=&#34;compass&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/compass.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;When we enter college, we have no idea what we want to do with our lives. We get to spend the next four years discovering our interests academically, finding our social niche, and figuring out our professional futures so that when we graduate...we still have no idea what we want to do with our lives. The problem is multi-faceted, but hinges on the fact that college is not a reflection of the real world. The subjects are not applied as they would be, the social life is completely unique, and the reward system does not reflect how people find fulfillment outside of college. Furthermore, there is a lot of pressure in college to do what is best for our academic or professional future, and too often the focus is on short term requirements to meet various grant or internship criteria, not personal happiness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Job Offers, and Professional Integrity</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/more-job-offers-and-professional-integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/more-job-offers-and-professional-integrity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://khaledallen.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/office.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-513&#34; title=&#34;office&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/office.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;175&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Too much of a good thing can be problematic. Such is the case with job offers. I was recently offered a position at Forbes, where I have been helping out on the social media team in exchange for experience. I very much appreciated the offer, and my first instinct was to immediately accept. But I had made other commitments that I didn&#39;t feel entirely comfortable walking away from on such short notice. So I declined the offer. I&#39;ve gotten reactions ranging from disbelief, to surprise, to admiration, to declarations of my stupidity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
