<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>compassion on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/compassion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in compassion on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/compassion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Change the World from the Inside Out</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/change-the-world-from-the-inside-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/change-the-world-from-the-inside-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2782&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;576&#34;]&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-2782 &#34; alt=&#34;Meditation is time well-spent; it tempers the soul to face the challenges of the world&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/418990_684481541514_706652743_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;576&#34; height=&#34;386&#34; /&gt; Meditation is time well-spent; it tempers the soul to face the challenges of the world. &lt;em&gt;Credit: Anna Pusack&lt;/em&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Peace comes from within. Do not seek it without.” - Buddha&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In high school, I entertained lofty notions of fixing many of the world’s problems. However, I did not feel up to the task. Despite my ambitions, I felt fearful and weak. Whenever I contemplated tackling the big issues, I saw them as far beyond my capabilities. &lt;strong&gt;But instead of focusing on increasing my capabilities, I instead tried to think of ways I could tackle these challenges with just what I had at the time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result was that I felt constantly overwhelmed. In high school, I spent most of my time despairing how ineffective I was. In college, I did what a lot of people do: I stopped caring and focused on enjoying my life, often through distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I &lt;a title=&#34;The Night That Changed My Life&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-night-that-changed-my-life/&#34;&gt;received a Warrior calling&lt;/a&gt; that brought my life back on track. As I started training my body, and developing emotional and mental strength, I found myself becoming more confident and outgoing. Problems that had overwhelmed me no longer did, and I felt a noticeable increase in my sense of effectiveness. My grades improved, even as I took on more extra-curricular activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A New Path for a Wimpy Kid&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picking up on this, I looked for other areas in which I could cultivate inner strength. After college, I returned to my study of self-defense and systematically improved my people skills. The following year, I set my sights on &lt;a title=&#34;Empty Your Cup: Accepting Ignorance to Learn&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/empty-your-cup-accepting-ignorance-to-learn/&#34;&gt;living and working in Korea&lt;/a&gt; to foster the ability to live independantly. I took on the challenges of expanding this blog and &lt;a title=&#34;Warrior Spirit Principles of Holistic Health&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/store/warrior-spirit-principles-of-holistic-health/&#34;&gt;writing a book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All this was done with an eye towards increasing my sense of empowerment and convincing myself that &lt;a title=&#34;Your Mountain is Waiting. Do You Dare Conquer it?&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/your-mountain-is-waiting-do-you-dare-conquer-it/&#34;&gt;my dreams were within my grasp&lt;/a&gt; and, perhaps more importantly, worth pursuing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The result has been a tremendous increase in my strength of purpose and my faith in my ability to effect positive change in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Holidays from Warrior Spirit</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/happy-holidays-from-warrior-spirit-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/happy-holidays-from-warrior-spirit-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_2624&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;224&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/happy-holidays-from-warrior-spirit-2/img_0001/&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-2624&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-2624&#34; alt=&#34;Christmas at our house is a pretty small affair&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/IMG_0001-224x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;224&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Christmas at our house is a pretty small affair[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, the holidays at the end of the year are my time for reflection and spiritual recuperation after a long year full of activity and constant growth. This year in particular was especially exhilarating. The work that went into &lt;a title=&#34;Lessons Learned on Finishing My First Book&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/lessons-learned-on-finishing-my-first-book/&#34;&gt;writing my book&lt;/a&gt; and promoting it while teaching English in Korea was extremely taxing emotionally and mentally, and when it was done, I found it difficult to keep up that pace of work (hence the drop off in social media and general writing activity). There was never really a chance to rest, since A and I were still working and traveling: we visited Jeju Island, flew back to the States for a wedding, visited the DMZ, did a three day templestay, and went on a whirlwind tour of the Middle East (more on those things to come).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While these activities did involve some physical work, they were most taxing mentally. We were always on the run, always desperate for a good night&#39;s sleep, living a largely nomadic existence, constantly working under looming deadlines, worried about missing buses, trains, planes. It was intense, and the demands of &lt;a title=&#34;Keeping it Together; The Importance of Good Life Posture&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/keeping-it-together-the-importance-of-good-life-posture/&#34;&gt;maintaining proper life posture&lt;/a&gt; became much more difficult under the constantly shifting circumstances. We were on our own most of the time, reliant on our own resources and disconnected from our families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&#39;ve been looking forward to this quiet holiday season for several months.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
