<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>karate on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/karate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in karate on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/karate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Night That Changed My Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-night-that-changed-my-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-night-that-changed-my-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; title=&#34;Karate Kid&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/Photo1-e1325776082759.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;485&#34; /&gt;Wax On. Wax Off. - Mr Miyagi, Karate Kid&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a repost from my adventure blog, &lt;a title=&#34;A Story Worth Telling&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Story Worth Telling&lt;/a&gt;. This story seemed relevant to both sites, so I thought I&#39;d share it here too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as I love travelling, I don&#39;t necessarily think that travelling automatically leads to good stories, and ultimately, I don&#39;t want this to be a travel blog. Stories comes from overcoming all sorts of challenges. It just so happens that most of the time, travelling forces us to step outside of our comfort zone and face new challenges. Like masses of rowdy Korean children or &lt;a title=&#34;The Garbage Bag Hunt&#34; href=&#34;http://wp.me/p1Zk76-3m&#34;&gt;strangely elusive garbage bags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I have a few stories worth telling that have nothing to do with travelling. The best stories are about a turning point or a moment that changed everything. Here is one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was sitting up alone, way after everyone else had gone to sleep, watching a movie on TV that had me completely riveted. I had just gotten back to the States after spending the summer of my junior year of college in Jordan studying Arabic. In Jordan, I had started exercising after being totally sedentary for most of college, but after getting home, I had fallen off the wagon, and I was in only slightly better shape than I had been when I left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie I was watching was &lt;em&gt;The Karate Kid, &lt;/em&gt;and it set me down a course that has completely changed almost everything about me, from my body, to the way I see the world, my belief in my own judgement, and my ability to talk to girls.&lt;img title=&#34;More...&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/trans.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>True Mastery Questions Everything</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/true-mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/true-mastery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1768&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;kaibara87 on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kaibara/2756361218/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1768&#34; title=&#34;sidekick&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/sidekick-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My karate instructor is an independent thinker. In a field that is basically defined by its adherence to tradition, his insistence on questioning everything is pretty gutsy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returning to the Dojo: The Importance of Martial Arts</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/returning-to-the-dojo-the-importance-of-martial-arts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_713&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; caption=&#34;Source: Pieter Baert on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pietel/15322162/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-713&#34; title=&#34;karate&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/karate2.jpg?w=201&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was a child I have had this instinctive urge for expansion and growth. To me, the function and duty of a quality human being is the sincere and honest development of one&#39;s potential. - Bruce Lee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I attended my first class of American Kenpo Karate in over five years. My old teacher told me in an e-mail to bring my old Gi, which I had kept, anticipating an eventual return to the art. When I went to dig it out from a trunk under my bed, I found my old belts, one soft, well-worn, and white, and the other stiff and bright, un-faded yellow. I grabbed the white belt and headed to class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I stepped into the dance studio where the class was being held, my old instructor, taller and leaner than I remembered, looked at me without recognition. It &lt;em&gt;had &lt;/em&gt;been a long time. He was shocked at the growth he saw in me and had trouble connecting the old Khaled with the one who stood before him. And then he looked down and saw I was wearing my old white belt and asked, &#34;Where&#39;s your belt?&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
