<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>communication on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/communication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in communication on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Listening</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-importance-of-listening/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-importance-of-listening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_729&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;Source: Ro/wererabbit on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wererabbit/3613513307/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-729&#34; title=&#34;listening&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/listening.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we talk about something, we just talk about something, just the positive or the negative side, without trying to express some intellectual, one-sided idea. And we listen without trying to figure out some intellectual understanding, without trying ot understand from just a one-sided view. &lt;em&gt;- Shunryu Suzuki&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine recently wrote a Facebook note in which he mentioned some thoughts on conversations. Specifically, he maintained that it was better to have few conversations, because most people aren&#39;t very good at having conversations. Most people, states my friend, will be quick to follow random tangents in any discussion, never really making any headway on the issue you&#39;d like to discuss. In the end, they are more concerned with their own agenda than participating in the conversation at hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Would You Even Be Able to Say that to my Face?</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/would-you-even-be-able-to-say-that-to-my-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/would-you-even-be-able-to-say-that-to-my-face/</guid>
      <description>Just found this interestging article in Times online, entitled, &#34;Does Facebook Replace Face Time or Enhance It?&#34; Considering I write a blog, which i share on Facebook and Twitter and which has engendered intersting duscussion at times, I thought I&#39;d comment.
The gist of the article is a dilemma between whether Facebook causes people to avoid interacting in real time or if it improves their real life relationships. The author describes his relationship with an old friend, which has degenerated to the point where she hasn&#39;t returned a phone call in over a year, but has poked him, sent him facebook gifts, and interacted in the various mini-games and applications on Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
