<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gavindebecker on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/gavindebecker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gavindebecker on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/gavindebecker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Listen to Your Intuition: It Could Save Your Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/listen-to-your-intuition-it-could-save-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/listen-to-your-intuition-it-could-save-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Listen to your intuition. It will tell you everything you need to know. - Anthony J. D&#39;Angelo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/brainhalves.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3144&#34; alt=&#34;brainhalves&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/brainhalves-300x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;He stood out among the other men at the table. He had a sense of practiced confidence about him, and whenever he spoke to the event facilitator--the only woman in the room--his responses seemed too playful, too well-rehearsed, and she laughed as if on cue. When it was his turn to introduce himself to the group, a label popped unsolicited into my head: pickup artist. I filed it to verify in time, and sure enough, he revealed that to be his background. Later during the workshop, he made vague reference to some challenges he was working on, without actually defining them. That voice in my head immediately supplied the details: trouble with commitment. Again, as the class progressed, he revealed that to be exactly his difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve never considered myself to be a great judge of people. In college, I&#39;d meet particularly jovial people at parties thinking they were simply really happy, only to be told later that they were obviously drunk. I figured that if I couldn&#39;t identify the telltale signs of something so blatant as drunkenness, I should never trust my judgements about people.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
