<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>risk on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/risk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in risk on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/risk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Two Ways to Play the Game of Life</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/two-ways-to-play-the-game-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/two-ways-to-play-the-game-of-life/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Now we&#39;re going to do front flips from high up.&#34; My coach pointed at three platforms and the crash mat below them. &#34;You can do either the 2 foot, the 4 foot, or the 6 foot, whichever you&#39;re comfortable with.&#34;
We all went for the 4 foot platform. It wasn&#39;t so high and scary as the 6 foot, but it was bigger than the 2 foot so we felt like we were pushing ourselves a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous but Safe</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dangerous-but-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dangerous-but-safe/</guid>
      <description>Utah&#39;s Canyonlands National Park contains some of the most beautiful and harsh landscape in the world, so when I had the chance to bike and camp through it last month, I was excited to explore the terrain away from the campsite. That first evening, I headed up a rocky slope within sight of camp to really experience the landscape up close.
When I got back, it turned out I had upset one of the people I was traveling with, who saw my actions as foolishly dangerous, citing the possibility of me slipping or a tumbling rock causing me to fall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellectual Honesty</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/intellectual-honesty/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/intellectual-honesty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since starting this blog, I have constantly run into the problem of how honest to be with my readers. My parents are constantly asking me to tone down certain things, to refrain from sharing personal details of my life I think are important to understanding my thought process. I don&#39;t really know where to draw the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a conversation the other day with a friend who works in advertising. She is very supportive of my blogging, and every time I come up with an interesting idea, she encourages me to blog it, to share it with the world. My latest idea was somewhat risque, to put it lightly, but she said that was precisely the point. By being open and honeset about the truth of my life, I would be able to achieve a degree of integrity in my intellectual and emotional life that had eluded me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
