<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mental strategies on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/mental-strategies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mental strategies on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/mental-strategies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Fear: Part 2: Tactics to Quell Fear</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-nature-of-fear-part-2-tactics-to-quell-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-nature-of-fear-part-2-tactics-to-quell-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;I must not fear.&lt;br /&gt;
Fear is the mind-killer.&lt;br /&gt;
Fear is the little-death that brings total obliteration.&lt;br /&gt;
I will face my fear.&lt;br /&gt;
I will permit it to pass over me and through me.&lt;br /&gt;
And when it has gone past I will turn the inner eye to see its path.&lt;br /&gt;
Where the fear has gone there will be nothing.&lt;br /&gt;
Only I will remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt;, Frank Herbert&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;The Nature of Fear: Part 1, Fear is a Choice&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-nature-of-fear-part-1-fear-is-a-choice/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click here to read part 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my first night alone in the woods, I had learned that fear is a choice. It came from the fact that I often saw myself as a victim, someone who was generally vulnerable to others&#39; whims and the world&#39;s catastrophes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be thinking, &#34;Of course you were vulnerable! You were alone, asleep, in the forest! If something had happened, there would have been no way to get help.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, I&#39;m much more vulnerable on a highway, where the chance of injury in a way I cannot respond to is much higher. I &lt;em&gt;perceived&lt;/em&gt; myself as vulnerable in the woods, but it&#39;s not a fact of the situation. A tiger doesn&#39;t feel threatened alone in a forest. It is the thing that makes others feel threatened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, the first step to overcoming the fear of sleeping alone in the woods was realizing that my fear was the result of how I chose to view myself and the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That enabled me to question it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step, and the project for the second night, was actually learning to quell fear. As the sun set for the second time on my trip, I wasn&#39;t any less afraid than I had been the night before, but I was more confident in my ability to handle the anxiety that might come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until I saw the signs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the privy were three scrawled notes, memorials to those who had passed away in the last year. Those three letters--R.I.P.--have a lot of power to set an overactive imagination in a particular direction. I imagined that my campsite was the lurking place of a serial killer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much for my confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as I lay in my tent that night, I came up with a few strategies to deal with the new terror.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
