<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self-growth on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/self-growth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in self-growth on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.onrender.com/tags/self-growth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Money is a Gift; Lessons Learned in Business</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/money-is-a-gift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/money-is-a-gift/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1892&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; caption=&#34;stevendepolo on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stevendepolo/3703145222/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1892&#34; title=&#34;gifts&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/gifts-300x200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently been burned in two business interactions that left me hurting both financially and personally. Not only did I lose money, I felt taken advantage of and cheapened. I invited my clients to undervalue my hard work by undervaluing it myself. It’s a hard pill to swallow, but I realize it’s all part of the learning process, and the more I delve into business, the more I realize how much &lt;a title=&#34;The Principles of ‘Good’ Business&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/the-principles-of-good-business/&#34;&gt;good business&lt;/a&gt; relies on good character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why My Favorite Students are the Most Difficult</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-my-favorite-students-are-the-most-difficult/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/why-my-favorite-students-are-the-most-difficult/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/brickwall.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1875&#34; title=&#34;brickwall&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/brickwall-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“When we long for life without difficulties, remind us that oaks grow strong in contrary winds and diamonds are made under pressure” - Peter Marshall&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an English teacher, I deal with kids of all ability levels. There are the star students who do all the homework, even the assignments you don’t really expect anyone to do, answer all the questions perfectly, and are polite, engaged and generally perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there are the students who fall asleep in class, which is a good day because when they are awake they are disruptive, harassing other students, yelling for no apparent reason, and making the classroom a living hell. Trying to teach them is like talking to a brick wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guess which students I appreciate more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bad ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not at first. The first few weeks working as a teacher, I loathed dealing with them. I wanted to just ignore their failing grades and total lack of understanding, but the little voice in my head said that, as the teacher, I should go over and help, even if it wouldn’t make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it did make a difference. In fact, it made a big difference. The kids improved (slightly) but their attitudes improved a lot. They tried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More importantly, I improved as a teacher&lt;/strong&gt;. I started to get a sense of what worked and what didn’t. If I could learn to motivate the worst students, I would be that much better at motivating everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And honestly, I could teach the best students with my eyes closed (actually, they can teach themselves). Unfortunately, as teachers it is so tempting to give all our attention to the good students, since they clearly appreciate and value us. But now, with my new perspective on the frustrating kids, I actually enjoy working with them. When I bring that kind of energy to the interaction, it makes it more pleasant for everyone, and then they start to make an effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Serving Others in Personal Growth</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-importance-of-serving-others-in-personal-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.onrender.com/archive/the-importance-of-serving-others-in-personal-growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1188&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;Forest Runner on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jimbaker/70750719/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1188&#34; title=&#34;A Helping Hand&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/A-Helping-Hand-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is literally true that you can succeed best and quickest by helping others to succeed.” -Napoleon Hill&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much about the Warrior Spirit is centered around independence and self-sufficiency. I talk a lot about the need to stick to our own convictions and believe in our own dreams. There is a lot of standing up against the tide of mediocrity that tries to bring us back into the fold, a lot of fighting for our best lives and the life we want. So it may come as a bit of a shock when I say that a true Warrior is not complete if he only pursues his own goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the purpose of developing the self is so that you can serve others better.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
