<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>opportunity on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/opportunity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in opportunity on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/opportunity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Warrior Mindset Part 2: Transform Challenges Into Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-warrior-mindset-part-2-transform-challenges-into-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/the-warrior-mindset-part-2-transform-challenges-into-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2737&#34; alt=&#34;&#39;Iron Knights&#39; patrol the Arghandab&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/5418579692_5b570e142d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shawn Rhodes, founder of Shoshin Consulting, is a traveler, teacher and above all, a lifelong student. After growing up in the mountains training in martial arts and eastern philosophy, he followed his own warrior&#39;s calling and joined the U.S. Marines. There, he accompanied infantry Marines through two combat tours in Iraq, documenting their trials and victories for international news outlets like CNN and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-2723&#34; alt=&#34;rhodessmaller&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/rhodessmaller-e1358734605767-150x150.jpg&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;TIME. While living and fighting alongside this tribe of modern-day warriors, he discovered the link between the warrior&#39;s path and mastery in life. He returned to the U.S. with the passion to share a vision of what humans are capable of when they embrace their own inner warrior and return to a mindset where all paths are possible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is the second in a three-part series on The Warrior&#39;s Path. Each installment will explore the evolution of the warrior mindset. Rooted in ancient methods warriors followed for thousands of years, adopting this mindset can help anyone to regain balance, direction, and control of their health, success, and life.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/part-i-of-the-warrior-mindset-turn-problems-into-challenges/&#34;&gt;the first part &lt;/a&gt;of this series, readers learned how to use the ancient mindset of the warrior to see life in a new way. Instead of viewing the world as a place that acts upon our lives, we learned everyone has the ability to choose how to process situations. &lt;b&gt;Seeing each problem in life as a challenge to shift our mindset is the first stage of warriorhood.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second installment of this series, we will learn the next stage in the evolution of the warrior mindset is &lt;strong&gt;turning those challenges into opportunities, and why it’s the supreme form of power&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, many people - especially young men - get stuck in the first stage of a warrior’s development. They’ve learned to see the problems in their lives as challenges, but they make a key mistake that freezes their development: they see each challenge as a threat and a test of their strength. We’ve all seen the chest-puffing and rooster dance from two guys at the bar or on the schoolyard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Need to Prove&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m convinced, after seeing firsthand people spend months trying to kill each other in modern war, that much of the violence in this world comes from people feeling threatened and wanting to protect what they see as ‘theirs‘: their life, their property, their ideologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These folks aren’t operating from the mindset of mature warriors; they are approaching their lives like a guard defending a castle, afraid of the walls crumbling at any moment. Without their bravado and one-upmanship, others might discover just how fragile their self-image really is. People frozen in this stage may be extremely skilled fighters, but they rush blindly into battles without examining the playing field for the best - and easiest - ways to win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one of the most famous texts outlining the warrior mindset - The Hagakure - its author Yamamoto Tsunemoto likens a skilled warrior on the battlefield to a hawk taking down a single bird in a flock. Experienced warriors focus their minds on a task - or an opponent - and are unconcerned with the opinions of others in the flock or social circle. &lt;b&gt;Instead, they are more concerned with performance than they are with proving their competence. &lt;/b&gt;This makes them extremely effective at whatever they set their minds to, whether it’s being a fighter or an artist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;If you are young and still exploring your relationship to your world by comparing your strength against others, the sooner you move past needing to prove yourself, the sooner you can embrace a deeper kind of power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
