<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>experts on Khaled Allen</title>
    <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/experts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in experts on Khaled Allen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaledallen.github.io/tags/experts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3 Reasons You Shouldn&#39;t Make Your Own Decisions</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/3-reasons-you-shouldnt-make-your-own-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/3-reasons-you-shouldnt-make-your-own-decisions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/deciding.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-3183&#34; alt=&#34;deciding&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/deciding-300x225.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I was recently looking for a good meal replacement option to make sure I get enough calories and protein on days when I don&#39;t have the time to prepare a good meal. While this may seem like a non-issue, I&#39;ve made a commitment to only eating whole foods, so it&#39;s a bit trickier than it seems. I know how to make this decision, because I&#39;ve done it before and I&#39;m certainly qualified, as a person who knows what&#39;s best for himself and as a trainer with a lot of experience dealing with nutrition. Yet, despite all that, my first inclination was to ask around with my trainer buddies, to check Paleo/Primal blogs, and to put the question to Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Even with the knowledge that I would make the best decision for myself without any input, I still wanted someone else to make the decision for me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I&#39;m the kind of person that &lt;a title=&#34;Insecurity, the Root of All Evil&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/insecurity-the-root-of-all-evil/&#34;&gt;questions my thinking&lt;/a&gt; process (in case you haven&#39;t picked up on that by now), I wanted to figure out why I felt the need to ask around. After all, I have rarely asked for input on what I should be doing for my own training. Ask 50 trainers what you should be doing and you&#39;ll get 50 different answers; it&#39;s really something you need to decide for yourself. Once you&#39;ve done that, then find a trainer who can help you reach that goal. I find it&#39;s better to make my own decisions and my own mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not saying outside input isn&#39;t valuable. When you want to learn something, definitely seek out qualified teachers. I saw that Gold Medal Bodies was teaching a lot of people to do previously unattainable gymnastics skills, so I got &lt;a title=&#34;Review of Gold Medal Bodies Floor 1 Training Program&#34; href=&#34;http://www.khaledallen.com/warriorspirit/review-of-gold-medal-bodies-floor-1-training-program/&#34;&gt;one of their programs&lt;/a&gt;. But when you&#39;re making a decision, you already have all the information you need, and you know yourself well enough to know what&#39;s good for you, then asking for additional input is just pushing it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, why was I hesitating and looking for outside opinions? I came up with a few answers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m No Expert...And I Don&#39;t Want to Be</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/im-no-expert-and-i-dont-want-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/im-no-expert-and-i-dont-want-to-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1626&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; caption=&#34;kevinpoh on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kevinpoh/3650866967/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1626&#34; title=&#34;Tai Chi Master&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/master-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started this blog, I had no aspirations to do  anything more than share my thoughts about life and the world. I figured some of the things I was going through might be  interesting to others, mainly my family. I didn’t really set out to tell  anyone how to live their life or even provide advice. I was just  sharing my experience of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This differs markedly from how blogs are getting used these days as a platform to establish the author as an expert with no other credentials besides the blog itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Trust the Experts</title>
      <link>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dont-trust-the-experts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaledallen.github.io/archive/dont-trust-the-experts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&#34;attachment_1553&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;281&#34; caption=&#34;HA! Designs - Artbyheather on Flickr&#34;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hadesigns/2211510558/sizes/m/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1553 &#34; title=&#34;Venerable Expert&#34; src=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}/assets/2211510558_c43cf4bd3c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;281&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was a child, I had an annoying tendency to question everything my teachers told me. This got me sent to the principle on more than one occasion. As an adult, I tried to suppress this habit and like the rest of us, very quickly became enamored of experts. Until last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After spending a few months working with so-called fitness experts, I was finally ready to become one myself by getting my Level 1 CrossFit trainer certification. I drove the presenters insane with my questions, because I knew that they were oversimplifying, leaving stuff out, or were just plain wrong. I had done my own research, from a number of different sources, and come to my own conclusions. I was not ready to drink the Kool-Aid, no matter how expertly prepared or convincingly presented.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
